<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- OPML generated by OPML Editor v10.1b19 on Wed, 22 Dec 2021 16:02:08 GMT -->
<opml version="2.0">
	<head>
		<title>Scripting News</title>
		<dateCreated>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 16:02:05 GMT</dateCreated>
		<dateModified>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 16:02:08 GMT</dateModified>
		<ownerName>Dave Winer</ownerName>
		<ownerId>http://davewiner.com/</ownerId>
		<expansionState>1</expansionState>
		<vertScrollState>1</vertScrollState>
		<windowTop>631</windowTop>
		<windowLeft>1087</windowLeft>
		<windowBottom>831</windowBottom>
		<windowRight>1472</windowRight>
		</head>
	<body>
		<outline text="April 2005" created="Fri, 01 Apr 2005 05:00:02 GMT">
			<outline text="April 30" created="Sat, 30 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="This evening's &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnApr30.mp3&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; is 17 minutes of a tropical thunderstorm over the Atlantic Ocean. The piece I referred to but didn't explain was &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.scripting.com/2002/05/13/monocultureAnArtifcactOfThe20thCentury&quot;&gt;Monoculture&lt;/a&gt;, it asked if it's a 20th century artifact. (I think it is.) And the Raymond Poort clip from the Daily Source Code is &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2004/10/09#When:5:42:36PM&quot;&gt;archived here&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sun, 01 May 2005 01:23:53 GMT" name="thisEveningsAHrefhttpmp3morningcoffeenotescomcnapr30mp3podcastaIs17MinutesOfATropicalThunderstormOverTheAtlanticOceanThePieceIReferredToButDidntExplainWasAHrefhttpdavenetscriptingcom20020513monocultureanartifcactofthe20thcenturymonocultureaItAskedIfItsA20thCenturyArtifactIThinkItIsAndTheRaymondPoortClipFromTheDailySourceCodeIsAHrefhttparchivescriptingcom20041009when54236pmarchivedHerea" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnApr30.mp3"/>
				<outline text="I booked a quick trip to NYC, leaving Monday morning, staying thru Tue night.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://steverubel.typepad.com/micropersuasion/&quot;&gt;Steve Rubel&lt;/a&gt; is planning a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.micropersuasion.com/2005/04/scoble_rubel_ho.html&quot;&gt;dinner&lt;/a&gt; at 6PM. &lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/&quot;&gt;Robert Scoble&lt;/a&gt; is in town Mon night too. Sounds like it's going to be a big dinner. Yahoo!" created="Sat, 30 Apr 2005 15:41:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/30/RSSGreenOnWhite.gif&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;59&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named RSSGreenOnWhite.gif&quot;&gt;While at Steve's site, I noticed a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.micropersuasion.com/2005/04/yahoo_web_searc.html&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; about Yahoo search and RSS. First let me say, good job Yahoo! I love the way you guys are embracing RSS. Now, here's a way to provide an &lt;i&gt;even more&lt;/i&gt; useful feed version of a search. Only return things that you found in the last xxx days. RSS is good at providing news, most aggregators do a poor job with &quot;feeds&quot; that don't contain news. This is why services like PubSub are so useful, they age their database, it only contains new stuff. That's a good fit for RSS. We have another format that's great for stuff that doesn't change often, timeless stuff. You'll be hearing more about that sooon." created="Sat, 30 Apr 2005 15:44:45 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/05/01/national/01alamos.html?ex=1272600000&amp;en=de7c4ba51273f8af&amp;ei=5090&amp;partner=rssuserland&amp;emc=rss&quot;&gt;NY Times&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;A blog rebellion among scientists and engineers at Los Alamos, the federal government's premier nuclear weapons laboratory, is threatening to end the tenure of its director.&quot;" created="Sun, 01 May 2005 02:03:05 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/magazine/4497239.stm&quot;&gt;BBC&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;In March, we registered 16.5 million click-throughs to reports from RSS feeds, and our target is 10% of our traffic driven by RSS by the end of this year.&quot;" created="Sat, 30 Apr 2005 14:47:06 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/04/30#a521&quot;&gt;Jason Calcanis explains&lt;/a&gt; why he feels ads belong in RSS feeds. " created="Sun, 01 May 2005 02:09:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://napsterization.org/stories/archives/000439.html&quot;&gt;Mary Hodder&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Food is not scalable.&quot;" created="Sat, 30 Apr 2005 18:39:24 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I heard about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wftv.com/news/4434445/detail.html&quot;&gt;last launch of a Titan&lt;/a&gt; missle from Florida, about twelve hours too late. NASA needs a special RSS feed for residents of Florida." created="Sat, 30 Apr 2005 13:17:17 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/04/30/technology/30apple.html?ex=1272513600&amp;en=7cc0ad54117bc197&amp;ei=5090&amp;partner=rssuserland&amp;emc=rss&quot;&gt;NY Times&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;It is not possible, aside from things unimagined, to damage his reputation,&quot; said Mitchell Kertzman, a partner at Hummer Winblad Venture Partners in San Francisco. &quot;Steve is on such a roll in both of his companies, he's earned the right to do whatever he wants.&quot;" created="Sat, 30 Apr 2005 12:36:11 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://infocommerce.typepad.com/infocommerce/2005/04/google_racing_t.html&quot;&gt;InfoCommerce&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Google's recent decision to introduce advertising options not tied to keywords is a watershed event for the company. In one fell swoop, it is moving beyond the formula that made it unique and exciting -- relevancy coupled with pay-for-performance pricing -- and crossing over into the traditional world of cost-per-thousand advertising.&quot;" created="Sat, 30 Apr 2005 12:28:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Morning coffee notes" created="Sat, 30 Apr 2005 05:54:41 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://inessential.com/?comments=1&amp;postid=3076&quot;&gt;Brent Simmons&lt;/a&gt; describes the one-click subscribing mechanism in Safari. I agree it's a big step forward, but it doesn't go all the way, because there are three cases it doesn't cover. 1. What if your aggregator isn't on the desktop, what if you use My Yahoo or Bloglines? This mechanism doesn't cover that, unless of couse the centralized app provides some kind of proxy that runs on the desktop. 2. What if you use more than one aggregator? 3. What if you don't use a Mac? &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Sat, 30 Apr 2005 05:28:01 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I did something smart yesterday, recognizing the symptoms of this cold as being exactly the same as the one I had at the end of last year, and then had again early this year, I went to the doctor and got the same anitbiotic that wiped it out last time. The result is that I already feel the healing, instead of getting worse, I'm getting better. Just in time for the big 5-0 which is now less than two days away. If there's anything I wanted to get done in my 40s now's the time to get busy!" created="Sat, 30 Apr 2005 05:32:30 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Speaking of which, a sad note, going back to my teens, I've always had a message from my uncle, The Great VaVaVoom, welcoming me to my new decade. He was 9.5 years older, so for a brief half-year every decade we'd both be in our teens, twenties, thirties and forties. It was a silly little thing, but it's the little things, esp the silly ones that seem to mean the most. This year on my 50th I'll have to pretend he's calling to welcome me, from the great dope-smoking beach in the sky. " created="Sat, 30 Apr 2005 05:34:36 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I listened to the whole Ron Bloom-Adam Curry strategy-cast thing yesterday. I'm sure I'll have more thoughts, but the primary one was, who is Ron Bloom, and why should he be the arbiter of what's cool in podcasting? Basically, I don't take professional gigs because of people like Ron Bloom, people who don't practice the art, who only think about how to make money off it. I don't object to making money, hardly, but I do object to &lt;i&gt;only&lt;/i&gt; being concerned about making money. It's the same way I feel about venture capitalists who set up shop in RSS-land thinking it's just like SMTP. Huh. No it's not, and the fact that you think so says that all you're going to contribute are business models that you're going to eventually go to Congress to get laws passed to protect. Ron Bloom is a media exec. Sure, they're coming. Ron says so. Run the other way, says Dave. That's what I did. " created="Sat, 30 Apr 2005 05:39:01 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 29" created="Fri, 29 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Better Bad News: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.betterbadnews.com/27&quot;&gt;Really Simple Suggestion Woos Syndorati 1000&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 29 Apr 2005 22:41:52 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://free2.angeltowns.com/winer/googlenews.png&quot;&gt;You gotta&lt;/a&gt; be able to laugh at yourself. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Fri, 29 Apr 2005 21:56:52 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://sdk.typepad.com/trust/2005/04/bcommitting_jou.html&quot;&gt;Staci Kramer&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I've been asked to lead the Journalism session at BlogNashville, a daunting task.&quot;" created="Fri, 29 Apr 2005 20:12:52 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/29/podstrat.jpg&quot;&gt;Like&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.normaugustinus.com/&quot;&gt;many&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/29/podstrat2.gif&quot;&gt;others&lt;/a&gt; I've been whiling away the hours trying to download the much-awaited Adam Curry and Ron Bloom &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.curry.com/2005/04/29#a7132&quot;&gt;StrategyCast 2.0&lt;/a&gt; to find out what the strategy is. Postscript: I've downloaded and listened to the whole thing. " created="Fri, 29 Apr 2005 14:58:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I've got a really bad cold today, coughing, sniffling, sneezing, not enthusiastic about anything. " created="Fri, 29 Apr 2005 12:46:35 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 28" created="Thu, 28 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/04/28#a483&quot;&gt;Today's big news&lt;/a&gt; is that we have full support for RSS in weblogs.com. Popular services like Technorati and Feedster build on its output." created="Thu, 28 Apr 2005 14:19:55 GMT"/>
				<outline text="A Morning Coffee Notes &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnApr28.mp3&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; done on the Archos on the beach, while tanning. Only ten minutes, but packed with stuff about weblogs.com, ipodder.root, KYOU and podcasting for love. " created="Thu, 28 Apr 2005 21:18:05 GMT" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnApr28.mp3"/>
				<outline text="More news. I'm going to &lt;a href=&quot;http://blognashville.org/&quot;&gt;BlogNashville&lt;/a&gt; at the end of next week, where I'll lead a discussion on a topic near to my heart. How can we work together in the USA even when we disagree. Nashville's a good place for that, and I'm a southern boy these days, but still have my blue state values. " created="Thu, 28 Apr 2005 20:47:11 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gigaom.com/2005/04/28/yahoo-online-news-sites-and-blogs/&quot;&gt;Om Malik&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;One of the main reasons people started turning away from network/broadcast television to niche cable networks is because of the homogenous, brain dead presentation and uniformity of content. I see exactly the same thing happen today.&quot;" created="Thu, 28 Apr 2005 23:57:05 GMT"/>
				<outline text="On Sunday as I was preparing to leave Seattle, Lake Washington was quiet, like glass, and no was stirring but some birds. So I got out the camera and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/movies/lakeWashingtonAtDawn.mov&quot;&gt;made a movie&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 28 Apr 2005 23:44:44 GMT"/>
				<outline text="This evening, as the sun was setting behind the beach, the light was just perfect, the colors so vivid, the sounds so tropical. So I got out the camera and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/movies/beachAtSunset.mov&quot;&gt;made a movie&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 28 Apr 2005 23:45:41 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/04/28/technology/circuits/28pogue-email.html&quot;&gt;David Pogue&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I have to admit that it's Safari's RSS feature that has changed my daily routine the most. It's turned me into a fan of RSS--something that, because of the hassle and overhead, I never stuck with before.&quot;" created="Thu, 28 Apr 2005 21:57:43 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/04/28#a487&quot;&gt;Advertising in RSS&lt;/a&gt; is just starting now, for all practical purposes. If we wanted to, as an industry, reject the idea, we could." created="Thu, 28 Apr 2005 17:55:51 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://home.planet.nl/~nhavd/clog/2005/04/28.htm#a1429&quot;&gt;Niek Hockx unsubs&lt;/a&gt; from feeds with ads. " created="Thu, 28 Apr 2005 14:26:40 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Here's what Engadget's feed &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/28/eng.gif&quot;&gt;looks like&lt;/a&gt; in my aggregator today. The good news is that now the ads aren't garbled and incomprehensible as they &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2004/10/14#When:6:51:39AM&quot;&gt;were&lt;/a&gt; before. The bad news is that Engadget is kind of like a feed of ads for me, already. I know the products they write about aren't paying them for placement (right?) but as a scanner, which is how I read in my aggregator, with my finger on the scrollbar, moving up and down quickly, the ads are disrupting my flow. I'm pretty sure that's the idea, but as Niek points out, these feeds are optional for me, if one starts becoming a bother, I can quickly get rid of it. These days there's no shortage of feeds vying for my attention. I don't know how this is going to shake out, but I'd like to get a message through to advertisers who are paying for placements in RSS feeds, try coming up with your own feeds, and route around Google and Jason, what the heck, it's worth a try? The cost of serving your own feeds is infinitesmal. What's the barrier?" created="Thu, 28 Apr 2005 14:31:54 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/28/askNot.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/28/jfk.jpg&quot; width=&quot;64&quot; height=&quot;77&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named jfk.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kyouradio.com/website.php&quot;&gt;The KYOU website goes up&lt;/a&gt;, which raises an interesting question -- what happens if a submitted podcast has a commercial in it? Another thought, I was trying to work something like this out for bloggers with a very big flow website last fall, but it didn't work out. Instead of looking for submissions, we'd go trawling for the good stuff and surprise people. Nothing like having 10 million fresh newbies show up at a blog that had 10,000 readers the day before, eh? Maybe we were just &lt;i&gt;teeny&lt;/i&gt; bit ahead of the times. It was going to revolutionize news. It still could happen. Probably will." created="Thu, 28 Apr 2005 12:58:46 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0107946/2005/04/28.html#a4005&quot;&gt;Ed Cone&lt;/a&gt; has become a regular on MSNBC." created="Thu, 28 Apr 2005 12:49:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lonepixel.com/johnm/archives/2005/04/some_thoughts_o.html&quot;&gt;John Martin&lt;/a&gt; outlines the issues of outlining software. " created="Thu, 28 Apr 2005 08:36:32 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 27" created="Wed, 27 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/27/grouchy.jpg&quot; width=&quot;108&quot; height=&quot;186&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named grouchy.jpg&quot;&gt;Interesting comment &lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.weblogs.com/2005/04/27#clarifrication&quot;&gt;here on Doc Searls's weblog&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://netmeme.org/blog/archives/000143.html#000143&quot;&gt;Brian Field-Elliot&lt;/a&gt;. He says he's coming to like my abrasive clarity more and more. I'm glad because I want people to like me, but it's not my first priority. We're all born wanting to be liked. Consider the baby born with genes disposing itself to &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; be liked,. What are the chances that baby lives long enough to procreate? That's why we all aim to please. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulandrews.com/&quot;&gt;Paul Andrews&lt;/a&gt; noted that some people say they don't like me but he doesn't understand why, because in person I'm so likeable. Well I like myself, that's a start, and so does Paul, so that's two. But I think some people just don't want to hear what other people really think. Weren't we all raised in a century where perception was more important than reality? Well, I want to change that, and sure that's going to be abrasive, can't help it. And saying I have an abrasive clarity is possibly the nicest thing anyone has ever said about me, that's what I aspire to. Thanks!" created="Wed, 27 Apr 2005 22:37:54 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/news/digiwood/0,1412,67344,00.html&quot;&gt;Wired&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The world's first all-podcast radio station will be launched on May 16 by Infinity Broadcasting, the radio division of Viacom.&quot;" created="Wed, 27 Apr 2005 22:07:46 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/04/27#a479&quot;&gt;Shimon Rura wants&lt;/a&gt; an MIT World podcast. &lt;i&gt;Me too!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Wed, 27 Apr 2005 20:53:46 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://calacanis.weblogsinc.com/entry/1234000980041566/&quot;&gt;Jason Calcanis reports&lt;/a&gt; that there are Google ads in his RSS feed. " created="Wed, 27 Apr 2005 20:18:05 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Is it just me or is it kind of crass that the first way they acknowledge RSS is by putting ads in it. Six years and &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt; is what they came up with? We used to like Google, actually we &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2002/01/10#yupTheUsersCared&quot;&gt;loved&lt;/a&gt; them, they were the good guys, the ones who made the Web better because they got the big picture. When they started to draw out of it, we said okay, they earned the right. Now, they didn't put &lt;i&gt;anything&lt;/i&gt; into RSS before they started to take out. Negative points for Google as a don't-be-evil netizen." created="Wed, 27 Apr 2005 20:18:44 GMT"/>
				<outline text="As usual, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rexblog.com/2005/04/27#a6590&quot;&gt;Rex Hammock&lt;/a&gt; reads my mind." created="Wed, 27 Apr 2005 23:04:43 GMT"/>
				<outline text="In 1995, in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://webmonkey.wired.com/davenet/95/37/index4a.html&quot;&gt;column&lt;/a&gt; in Hotwired, I wrote: &quot;Apple have should run the JFK ad: 'Ask not what the Internet can do for you; ask what you can do for the Internet.' Here's an important point: Netscape should run that ad, too.&quot; They didn't. " created="Thu, 28 Apr 2005 00:57:37 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/27/cc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;85&quot; height=&quot;65&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named cc.jpg&quot;&gt;My credit card expires soon, so they sent a new one. A sticker on the front says I have to call an 800 number to activate it. No big deal, I dial the number, expecting it to be entirely automated. After entering some numbers, and a pause, I was surprised when a human came on, and asked for my name, verifying, among other things, that David is spelled D-A-V-I-D. I thought there must be some kind of problem, maybe they're doing a voice match or something, then a long pause, and the human said &quot;we're waiting.&quot; Then after another long pause she asked if everything was spelled correctly on the card. I said it was, and asked if her computer was slow today. She responded with something that sounded computerish. Then after another pause she started trying to sell me something. I said no way. Waited some more and she started selling again. I began to wonder if this was a human at all. I asked if my card had been activated, she said she thought so. Thought so? Don't you work at the credit card company? No. " created="Wed, 27 Apr 2005 17:54:04 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://fmqb.com/Article.asp?id=81411&quot;&gt;Infinity Broadcasting&lt;/a&gt; has announced the creation of &quot;KYOURADIO, the world's first podcasting radio station with content created exclusively by its listeners.&quot;" created="Wed, 27 Apr 2005 17:51:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rexblog.com/2005/04/27#a6579&quot;&gt;Rex Hammock&lt;/a&gt; has an update on BlogNashville, coming up next week, in Nashville, of course. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Wed, 27 Apr 2005 16:54:25 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://pda.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;PDA users&lt;/a&gt;, there's a new PDA-friendly rendering of Scripting News. " created="Wed, 27 Apr 2005 14:21:59 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/booksearch/isbnInquiry.asp?userid=fk75hm9Ac9&amp;isbn=0471720836&amp;itm=1&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/27/jobsbook.jpg&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;98&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named jobsbook.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;There's a new unauthorized &lt;a href=&quot;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/booksearch/isbnInquiry.asp?userid=fk75hm9Ac9&amp;isbn=0471720836&amp;itm=1&quot;&gt;Steve Jobs biography&lt;/a&gt; coming out called iCon, which has to be one of the cutest names ever. It's a double double entendre. Wow. Does it stand for icon, the cute little graphics that made the Mac so famous, or does it mean Jobs is a con artist, as in the reality distortion field which is almost as famous as the icons? Jobs must get a percentage of the book sales because he's hyping it by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.engadget.com/entry/1234000077041478/&quot;&gt;banning&lt;/a&gt; all books from the publisher in Apple stores. He makes a fantastic subject for story-telling, check out Randall Stross's bio of Jobs, &lt;a href=&quot;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/booksearch/isbnInquiry.asp?userid=fk75hm9Ac9&amp;isbn=0689121350&amp;itm=1&quot;&gt;The Next Big Thing&lt;/a&gt;, written in the early 90s, before his comeback. It's a great story of the culture of Silicon Valley." created="Wed, 27 Apr 2005 14:04:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Note to the publisher of the new bio, I'd love to get a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/dave/profiles/sendMail?usernum=1&amp;referer=http://www.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;review copy&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Wed, 27 Apr 2005 14:19:30 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://paolo.evectors.it/2005/04/27.html#a2498&quot;&gt;Paolo enjoyed&lt;/a&gt; the French blogging conference he participated in earlier this week. Lots of Americans made the trip to Paris. Hasta la vista baby. Oops. Wrong language! &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Wed, 27 Apr 2005 14:01:26 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.avnonline.com/index.php?Primary_Navigation=Web_Exclusive_News&amp;Action=Print_Article&amp;Content_ID=224302&quot;&gt;AVN Online&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;If the prospect of hundreds of thousands of Catholics being redirected to your site is making you salivate, don’t fret.&quot;" created="Wed, 27 Apr 2005 13:57:05 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.podbat.com/2005/04/27.html#a44&quot;&gt;Kosso uncovers&lt;/a&gt; a Nokia 4GB MP3 phone. Now dat's gul. Funny thing is, mate, now that I've been tawkin so much wid me pal Kosso, I fynd meself theenkeeeng in Bweetish. " created="Wed, 27 Apr 2005 13:38:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.simonwaldman.net/2005/04/google-the-rampant-ad-machine-whats-a-publisher-to-do&quot;&gt;Simon Waldman&lt;/a&gt;, an exec at The Guardian, calls Google the &quot;rampant ad machine,&quot; and says &quot;there is no way that traditional media organisations can compete at this pace.&quot;" created="Wed, 27 Apr 2005 12:26:06 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Yahoo has an API for their new My Web feature. I have a couple of &lt;a href=&quot;http://geeks.opml.org/2005/04/27#a43&quot;&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt; and a question here." created="Wed, 27 Apr 2005 12:48:46 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 26" created="Tue, 26 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="A new &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnApr26.mp3&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; on idea processing and how it's different from productivity software. Thinking behind the OPML editor I'm working on. " created="Wed, 27 Apr 2005 01:06:42 GMT" name="aNewAHrefhttpmp3morningcoffeenotescomcnapr26mp3podcastaOnIdeaProcessingAndHowItsDifferentFromProductivitySoftwareThinkingBehindTheOpmlEditorImWorkingOn" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnApr26.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ysearchblog.com/archives/000104.html&quot;&gt;Yahoo&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Today, we launched a 'My Web', a new personal search engine fully integrated with Yahoo! Search.&quot;" created="Wed, 27 Apr 2005 00:23:15 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archos.com/products/overview/pma_400_pro.html?sid=j2232kykbj2yo3kb4ss2k3&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/26/archos.jpg&quot; width=&quot;75&quot; height=&quot;66&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named archos.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Now that I have a PDA with builtin wifi, I had to have a &lt;a href=&quot;http://pda.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;PDA-friendly version&lt;/a&gt; of Scripting News. I'll be making improvements to it over time. It's built on the OPML version of Scripting News, so I'll be able to do the same for other sites that have OPML versions of their content. It'll be especially useful for a new kind of linkblog that I think (hope) will become more popular when my OPML editor comes out. " created="Tue, 26 Apr 2005 18:41:06 GMT"/>
				<outline text="You've heard of PR, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.idi.net/internet/blogger.vtml&quot;&gt;now there's BR&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Oy.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Tue, 26 Apr 2005 14:30:57 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.longhornblogs.com/robert/archive/2005/04/26/13905.aspx&quot;&gt;News of Google ads in RSS&lt;/a&gt; comes from a seemingly unlikely place. " created="Tue, 26 Apr 2005 14:21:15 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/04/26#a470&quot;&gt;Really Simple Syndication&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I don't care for ads in RSS, because...&quot;" created="Tue, 26 Apr 2005 13:12:05 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://napsterization.org/stories/archives/000434.html&quot;&gt;Mary Hodder demos&lt;/a&gt; how, once you've been part of an unconference, there's no going back. " created="Tue, 26 Apr 2005 11:16:24 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/26/palm.gif&quot; width=&quot;45&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named palm.gif&quot;&gt;In the northeast US it goes from winter to summer in the space of a month. It's still a bit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weather.com/weather/local/02138?lswe=02138&amp;lwsa=WeatherLocalUndeclared&quot;&gt;chilly&lt;/a&gt;, now, in mid-late April, coming up on the one period of guaranteed comfortable weather, and it may last just two or three weeks before the first blast of heat, and it generally doesn't let up up until the leaves start turning in the fall. In northeast Florida, by contrast, the weather has been quite comfortable since I got here in late February, highs in the 70s, generally, you rarely need a sweater, maybe a jacket, but nothing very heavy. And it's still in the comfort zone, now, as we head into May. At some point it's going to get hot, for sure, and then of course come the hurricanes. They say you really can't call yourself a Floridian until you stick it out through a hurricane season. I haven't decided yet. " created="Tue, 26 Apr 2005 22:22:39 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/entry/2005/04/26.html#2559&quot;&gt;Rogers&lt;/a&gt; is &quot;eating Chunky Monkey directly out of the container.&quot;" created="Tue, 26 Apr 2005 13:03:04 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 25" created="Mon, 25 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opml.org/2005/04/25#a53&quot;&gt;Scripting News in OPML&lt;/a&gt;, in the right &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/25/opmlicon.gif&quot;&gt;margin&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 26 Apr 2005 02:15:19 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2004/04/25#greetingsFromCentralEurope&quot;&gt;One year ago&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Why do \you tune into Radio Dave?&quot;" created="Tue, 26 Apr 2005 00:00:22 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newsgator.com/news/archive.aspx?post=56&quot;&gt;Newsgator raised $6 million&lt;/a&gt; in its third round of venture capital, most of it came from my old friend Rich Levandov at Masthead Ventures in Boston. Congrats to everyone involved." created="Mon, 25 Apr 2005 20:39:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boston.com/business/technology/articles/2005/04/24/the_year_of_living_wirelessly/&quot;&gt;Boston Globe&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Are we ready for a Wi-Fi city?&quot;" created="Mon, 25 Apr 2005 20:29:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://weblog.blogads.com/comments/P1029_0_1_0/&quot;&gt;Henry Copeland&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;BusinessWeek predicts corporate takeover of blogs.&quot;" created="Mon, 25 Apr 2005 15:16:32 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://openraw.org/&quot;&gt;OpenRAW&lt;/a&gt; is a &quot;group of photographers and other interested people advocating the open documentation of digital camera RAW files.&quot;" created="Mon, 25 Apr 2005 13:43:53 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Flying with Uma" created="Mon, 25 Apr 2005 11:50:09 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/25/billAndKiddo.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/25/uma.jpg&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;86&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;20&quot; vspace=&quot;8&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named uma.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I couldn't get enough of Kill Bill, so I bought DVDs of both movies and watched every bit on the flight home, including The Making of Kill Bill, an interview with Quentin T, and all the trailers. I'm all the more convinced that it should be a chick cult movie, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cinepad.com/reviews/thelma.htm&quot;&gt;Thelma and Louise&lt;/a&gt;, and I wondered why it's not. It's a revenge movie, totally, and it's all about the women gettin even with the men. Or more accurately, The Man. Something inside me is very satisfied watching the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.effect.net.au/geeen/supanova2004sydney/SupanovaSyd2004%20034%20cosplay%20Kill%20Bill.jpg&quot;&gt;blonde&lt;/a&gt; Uma Thurman, who it turns out &lt;i&gt;really was pregnant&lt;/i&gt; in the central scene of the movie, work her way through all the women (and one man) fronting for Bill, and then get to Bill himself, with the help of, well, I don't want to spoil the plot in case you haven't seen it. Definitely one of the best movies ever made, imho, of course. " created="Mon, 25 Apr 2005 11:50:14 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Dinner with Paul Andrews" created="Mon, 25 Apr 2005 11:45:27 GMT">
					<outline text="Did I mention I had dinner with Paul Andrews in Kirkland on Friday. I connected him with Rogers Cadenhead, who, whilst I was busy swirling around Seattle was on national television, due to a twist of fate, he had become an expert on the topic of the new Pope Benedict! Can't make this stuff up. Even weirder is the trail to his celebrity came through Scripting News, which informed NetCraft which informed the Washington Post which led to The Today Show and on and on. Matt Haughey says blogs are part of mainstream media, and I suppose, in a strange sense he's right. The stream, as it were, begins in places like Scripting News, where we scout for the big guys. And we take back our heroes, like Rogers, when the Mainstream gals and guys are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/entry/2005/04/25.html#2558&quot;&gt;finished&lt;/a&gt; with them. We're all one big interconnected Happy Family, we are. " created="Mon, 25 Apr 2005 11:45:38 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Good morning everybody" created="Mon, 25 Apr 2005 11:33:19 GMT">
					<outline text="It's weird to wake up on the east coast. I mean right on the east coast. I'm looking out the window of my workspace (the dining room table) and looking at the eastern edge of the continenent, and the western edge of the Atlantic Ocean. Yesterday morning I woke up looking at Lake Washington, which through a series of locks and Puget Sound and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strait_of_Juan_de_Fuca&quot;&gt;Strait of Juan de Fuca&lt;/a&gt; are waters of the Pacific. To get here by water from there you'd have to go around the horn of Africa. Or you could fly on Delta via Atlanta, as I did yesterday." created="Mon, 25 Apr 2005 11:33:24 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 24" created="Sun, 24 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://marc.blogs.it/archives/2005/04/ourmediaorg_sta.html&quot;&gt;Marc Canter&lt;/a&gt; points out that ourmedia.org has &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geeked.org/archives/ourmedia-rss-feeds/&quot;&gt;RSS feeds&lt;/a&gt;. But it's even better than that, it has &lt;i&gt;podcast&lt;/i&gt; feeds. Only one thing is a little odd, they're version 0.92, not 2.0, which means they might not work with some podcast clients. They could change the version to 2.0 and then they would surely work with all clients. Anyway, after his skepticism about podcasting it's good to see Marc and his partners get into it. " created="Mon, 25 Apr 2005 01:21:44 GMT"/>
				<outline text="8:30PM Eastern: Arrived safely at the beach." created="Mon, 25 Apr 2005 00:28:24 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/24/domino.gif&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;65&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named domino.gif&quot;&gt;Wow. I get to disagree with &lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2005/04/23.html#a9919&quot;&gt;Scoble&lt;/a&gt; and say that Ballmer is right. Microsoft, as a corporation, should never take a stand on a political issue, as they have, and if it took pressure from a conservative preacher to get them to change their position, then so be it. I've had a chance to be on the other side of this, not being able to buy a product that I wanted to buy because (I thought incorrectly) that the company was supporting anti-abortion political groups. The company was Domino's Pizza, and in the midwest, it's the best &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.madisonclick.com/dir/index.stx/Entertainment/Restaurants/Pizza&quot;&gt;pizza you can get&lt;/a&gt;, but I had to do without because the conventional wisdom was wrong. It was the owner of the company who was anti-abortion, which is his right, as it is Ballmer's right to support gay rights. But people should be able to use Microsoft products without having to support political causes they don't. It's especially important because Microsoft has monopolies, and has even been convicted of antitrust. In other words, people may not even have a realistic choice. They are about to close the doors on the airplane so I won't be able to edit this before I get home. Oh well, here goes! Saving..." created="Sun, 24 Apr 2005 20:32:52 GMT"/>
				<outline text="4:20PM Eastern: This is a first. I'm online on an airplane parked at gate A18 in Atlanta. The service is T-Mobile. Got my 40 minute hike in the airport, not the nicest place to walk, but it worked." created="Sun, 24 Apr 2005 20:19:54 GMT"/>
				<outline text="7AM Pacific: Checking mail at Gate A14 at Sea-Tac. Excellent T-Mobile wifi. Drinking a Tully's ice coffee. " created="Sun, 24 Apr 2005 13:59:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/entry/2005/04/24.html#2557&quot;&gt;Rogers Cadenhead&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I wasn't prepared to be famous for 24 hours, but now that my weblog traffic has subsided to normal levels, I can relate some of the experience.&quot;" created="Sun, 24 Apr 2005 14:01:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="You think?" created="Sun, 24 Apr 2005 11:59:01 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.zdnet.com/Gillmor/?p=85&quot;&gt;Steve Gillmor&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I’m really suffering from Post Gillmor Gang Disorder.&quot;" created="Sun, 24 Apr 2005 11:45:41 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Tell me something I didn't know. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Sun, 24 Apr 2005 11:59:18 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Note to universe. Please get Steve and his pals back on the air. I'm suffering." created="Sun, 24 Apr 2005 12:07:18 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Travel day morning no-coffee notes" created="Sun, 24 Apr 2005 11:49:08 GMT">
					<outline text="Today's a travel day, starting now, at 4:45AM Pacific. My flight leaves Seattle in three hours, change planes in Atlanta, arrive in Jacksonville, then drive for 1.5 hours before arriving at the beach, assuming all goes well, knock wood, praise Murphy. Add three hours for time zones, and I should get home in time for Sixty Minutes. I'll get my daily walk in Atlanta. " created="Sun, 24 Apr 2005 11:46:56 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/24/washington.gif&quot; width=&quot;125&quot; height=&quot;81&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named washington.gif&quot;&gt;I had a very stimulating visit with Microsoft, and decided to stay in the US for my 50th birthday, only eight days away. I'll go to England toward the end of the month. Reason --&gt; I want to spend two or three weeks working on the outliner. It's overdue. It got the kernel changes it needed, thanks to Dave Luebbert. Of course it's still a bit rough, and it will be when the beta is made publicly available, but it works, it has the right window dressing, now the furniture needs to be brought in (not all of it) and then it's time to sweep the floors, before the occupants arrive and put dishes in the cabinets and pictures on the wall. I want to get back to working with users as a software developer. I miss it. A lot." created="Sun, 24 Apr 2005 11:49:02 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Dave Luebbert and I had a great visit too. He called last night to talk some about the outliner. He wanted to know if an item could be routed to more than one category. I said it could. He said he had listened to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cnMar29.mp3&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; with my dad, and like everyone else who heard it, was charmed. IPSTIQ all the way. Kosso says that to me all the time. It turns out he's friends with Phil Toronne. Phil and Beth are really smart, really nice, charming, honest. But if you listened to yesterday's podcast you know that too. " created="Sun, 24 Apr 2005 11:54:25 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Had dinner last night with Chris Pirillo and Ponzi. She's from North Carolina. That means she's from Cackalacky and a Tarheel. Forgot to say that to her. We talked about Julie Leung, and Gnomedex. I'm going to get a special deal for Scripting News readers. You gotta go, it's going to be a great show. I told Chris about the outliner. He did a little jumping up and down thing. It's good. I'm going to talk about the outliner here in June. And in England in May. And New York. Maybe elsewhere. " created="Sun, 24 Apr 2005 12:04:16 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Okay now I have to shut this thing and get out of here, go to the airport and get on the plane. " created="Sun, 24 Apr 2005 11:57:59 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Namaste y'all!" created="Sun, 24 Apr 2005 11:58:14 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 23" created="Sat, 23 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnApr23.mp3&quot;&gt;Starbucks coffee notes&lt;/a&gt; podcast with Phil Torrone of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.makezine.com/blog/&quot;&gt;Make Mag&lt;/a&gt;, and Beth Goza of Microsoft, in Kirkland, WA." created="Sat, 23 Apr 2005 21:21:24 GMT" name="aHrefhttpmp3morningcoffeenotescomcnapr23mp3starbucksCoffeeNotesaPodcastWithPhilTorroneOfAHrefhttpwwwmakezinecomblogmakeMagaAndBethGozaOfMicrosoftInKirklandWa" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnApr23.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://clientandserver.com/archives/001031.html&quot;&gt;Client and Server&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;If belly-achin' were baseball, Seattle would be the Dominican Republic and the Yankees all in one.&quot;" created="Sat, 23 Apr 2005 18:32:37 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.docuverse.com/blog/donpark/EntryViewPage.aspx?guid=da6ff5cb-1413-480d-8b70-1d798ad578ac&quot;&gt;Don Park&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;What is the point of wearing a skirt if you are going to wear underwear?&quot;" created="Sat, 23 Apr 2005 04:36:32 GMT"/>
				<outline text="In defense of Vic's company" created="Sat, 23 Apr 2005 19:39:19 GMT">
					<outline text="Vic Gundotra: &lt;a href=&quot;http://vicgundotra.com/InDefenseOfTheCompanyILove.aspx&quot;&gt;In defense of the company I love&lt;/a&gt;." category="/Technology/Microsoft,/Politics,/Fun/Books" created="Sat, 23 Apr 2005 12:39:19 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I just spent a half-week at Microsoft, jammed full of meetings and ideas and brilliance, more of my energy and intelligence was used in these 2.5 days than usually is used in a full month of my time. In my experience, this only happens at Microsoft. I don't know why. Harvard is not so intense, Silicon Valley pushed me very far away; when I used to visit IBM in the 80s they would put me in a hermetically sealed room in Boca Raton and people would fly from Texas and California to meet with me. " created="Sat, 23 Apr 2005 19:34:37 GMT"/>
					<outline text="There's a lot of good at Microsoft. It shares ideas, takes risks, and while they second-guess themselves all the time like the huge company they are, there's still a shred of the balls-out seat-of-the-pants let's-get-it-done attitude in which the company was founded. " created="Sat, 23 Apr 2005 19:44:02 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I've been visiting Microsoft since 1981. There is something consistent, even as they grew so remarkably and there's a lot to admire and respect in the people and culture of the company." created="Sat, 23 Apr 2005 19:44:12 GMT"/>
					<outline text="On the other hand, I still am very angry with Microsoft for its attack of the Web in the 90s. But their presence in technology is so huge, that's only one side of it. Without Microsoft, these days, there would be no balance to Google, no reason for Google to grow up and believe me, we're waiting for them to do just that, as we waited for Netscape. " created="Sat, 23 Apr 2005 19:40:45 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I wish Microsoft hadn't screwed up SOAP, but at least they didn't screw with XML-RPC. And I absolutely adore the gentle and respectful way they've adopted RSS. " created="Sat, 23 Apr 2005 21:48:20 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 22" created="Fri, 22 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Believe it or not, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/olivepress/6693399/&quot;&gt;person on the left&lt;/a&gt;, wearking a skirt, is a man. " created="Sat, 23 Apr 2005 00:20:08 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/ethan/2005/04/22#a888&quot;&gt;Ethan Zuckerman&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;A journalist emailed asking why the Christian Science Monitor has such disproportionate influence in the blogosphere.&quot;" created="Fri, 22 Apr 2005 21:49:32 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Apple, a longtime member of Team RSS, adds &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/support/rss/&quot;&gt;new support&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 22 Apr 2005 21:07:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.audible.com/rss/&quot;&gt;Audible joins Team RSS&lt;/a&gt;. It's good to see them get on board. The feeds are kind of weird, the obfuscated kind, where the content is hidden. Once you do a view-source, there are some strange elements and redirects. But the content is interesting, like the New York Times best sellers list. I don't think the Times itself publishes it. " created="Fri, 22 Apr 2005 18:21:54 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://yahoo.businessweek.com/magazine/content/05_18/b3931001_mz001.htm&quot;&gt;BusinessWeek&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The innovation that sends blogs zinging into the mainstream is RSS.&quot;" created="Fri, 22 Apr 2005 18:33:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hyperorg.com/blogger/mtarchive/003925.html&quot;&gt;David Weinberger&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I quit.&quot;" created="Fri, 22 Apr 2005 21:05:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/04/22#a1030&quot;&gt;Scoble&lt;/a&gt; and his Microsoft and &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamrss.com/&quot;&gt;RSS Team&lt;/a&gt; badges." category="/Technology/Microsoft" created="Fri, 22 Apr 2005 12:34:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.podbat.com/2005/04/22.html#a35&quot;&gt;Podbat&lt;/a&gt; alpha devcast #4." created="Fri, 22 Apr 2005 14:23:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Lake Washington movies: &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/movies/speedboat1.mov&quot;&gt;speedboat 1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/movies/speedboat2.mov&quot;&gt;speedboat 2&lt;/a&gt;." category="/Fun/Travel" created="Fri, 22 Apr 2005 12:45:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/technology/4472549.stm&quot;&gt;BBC&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;A copy of the original Electronics magazine in which Moore's Law was first published has turned up under the floorboards of a Surrey engineer.&quot;" created="Fri, 22 Apr 2005 13:21:02 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 21" created="Thu, 21 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podscope.com/&quot;&gt;Podscope&lt;/a&gt; is the first search engine that indexes the &lt;i&gt;content&lt;/i&gt; of podcasts. It actually understands what's being said. This is leading edge stuff in 2005, and a great addition to the set of podcasting tools." created="Thu, 21 Apr 2005 11:21:57 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/columnists/2005/04/21/cz_sw_0421whitmore.html?partner=rss&quot;&gt;Sam Whitmore&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Just when we grasped what blogging was all about, along came podcasting, which in some ways is even more disruptive and exciting as blogging.&quot;" created="Thu, 21 Apr 2005 11:12:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/movies/lakeWashington.mov&quot;&gt;Lake Washington&lt;/a&gt; from the window of my east side hotel room. " created="Fri, 22 Apr 2005 01:51:25 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/21/pope.jpg&quot; width=&quot;75&quot; height=&quot;85&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named pope.jpg&quot;&gt;For what it's worth, and seriously, no joke -- I don't think Rogers should give benedictxvi.com to the Vatican. I think the domain should be used for an independently-authored weblog about the policies and actions of the new Pope by someone who is expert in the papacy and independent of the Catholic Church. Imho, it's not about heaven and hell, eternal damnation or Rogers's grandmother. The church is a hugely powerful political, social and economic force, its actions are controversial and deserve some visibility, and MSM &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/04/02#When:5:28:45PM&quot;&gt;isn't&lt;/a&gt; doing its job. And for the new Pope, it's a chance to participate in history. It's the kind of thing you might imagine his predecessor really going for, until of course it got a story he didn't want it to get. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Thu, 21 Apr 2005 14:06:24 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/04/21#a1011&quot;&gt;My second monitor&lt;/a&gt; is back in Florida, the one that connects into my laptop which is here with me in Florida. WinAmp thinks it's running on the second monitor. I tried rebooting (several times) and changed the screen properties to tell the OS there is no second monitor. Every otiher app I was running &quot;over there&quot; has figured it out. I know, Windows sucks, but what do I do?" created="Thu, 21 Apr 2005 15:30:54 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Paul Jones suggests &lt;a href=&quot;http://folkstreams.net/&quot;&gt;Folkstreams&lt;/a&gt;, &quot;These are documentaries on American folk practices including BB King and the Blues, visionary painter Minnie Evans , and others.&quot;" created="Thu, 21 Apr 2005 11:23:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://jrobb.mindplex.org/2005/04/20.html&quot;&gt;John Robb&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I am OK folks. Thanks for the concern.&quot;" created="Thu, 21 Apr 2005 11:25:15 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.organizedshopping.com/blog/archives/001295.html&quot;&gt;Sean O'Rourke&lt;/a&gt; asks if there is &quot;a 'politeness' revisit tag for RSS?&quot;" created="Thu, 21 Apr 2005 11:16:16 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rexblog.com/2005/04/20#a6514&quot;&gt;Pope&lt;/a&gt; Rogers Cadenhead I." created="Thu, 21 Apr 2005 05:23:40 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/entry/2005/04/20.html#2554&quot;&gt;The new Pope&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Popesquatters have to be multilingual too.&quot;" created="Thu, 21 Apr 2005 05:34:02 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 20" created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="I was &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/04/19#When:7:20:40AM&quot;&gt;hermetically sealed&lt;/a&gt; in Atlanta, not so in Seattle. I have a room on Lake Washington with a view of the mountains, it's a sunny warm day here (still, although it's 10:15PM in the east). Time for dinner!" created="Thu, 21 Apr 2005 02:15:28 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadence90.com/wp/?p=3768&quot;&gt;Lisa Williams&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Hey, TV Guide: it’s not a podcast unless it has RSS.&quot;" created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 22:04:08 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/20/killbill.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/20/uma.jpg&quot; width=&quot;45&quot; height=&quot;62&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named uma.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I watched Kill Bill on the flight out, and realized it's not only a great movie, it's a great chick movie, and a super-violent one at that. Count the number of men who kill women (zero) vs the number of men killed by women (at least 100). Anyway, Quentin Taratino is a genius. I love his movies. " created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 21:33:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/searchhistory/login&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;My Search History lets you easily view and manage your search history from any computer.&quot;" created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 21:23:40 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://manila95beta.userland.com/&quot;&gt;UserLand&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;This is a public beta site for reviewing and discussing features and documentation to be released with Manila 9.5.&quot;" created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 21:17:40 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://searchenginewatch.com/searchday/article.php/3499046&quot;&gt;Search Engine Watch&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Google has rolled out a seriously cool search history feature that automatically keeps track of all of your web searches and every page that you view from search results.&quot;" created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 21:13:46 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/20/boo.gif&quot; width=&quot;73&quot; height=&quot;73&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named boo.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fortune.com/fortune/technology/articles/0,15114,1050065,00.html&quot;&gt;Fortune says Bill Gates is riled&lt;/a&gt; and he's making a Google killer. Yeah Fortune always says stuff like that, but it's never been true. Bill Gates does get riled, or simulates getting riled, but what really happens is the other guys get scared and blink and then he wins by default. But that was when Gates was young and feisty and more convincing. And when he had Ben Slivka who wore shorts and ate red meat, not the people working on the search engine at MSN these days. Give me a break. Those guys freak out if you raise your voice. All Google has to do is say Boo and they'll spend a year getting over it." created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 21:54:13 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I can't believe Bill Gates is being &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.seattlepi.nwsource.com/microsoft/archives/004698.html?wbfrom=rss&quot;&gt;considered&lt;/a&gt; by the Discovery Channel as the &quot;greatest American.&quot; A long time ago he took over other people's ideas (this was before software patents), and then once he cleared the field of all competition, went on permanent vacation. Just shows how much we're about perceptions, if he wins the award what they really mean is he's the greatest &lt;i&gt;impersonation&lt;/i&gt; of a great American. " created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 21:05:55 GMT"/>
				<outline text="There's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://podcasting.meetup.com/7/&quot;&gt;Cleveland podcaster's&lt;/a&gt; meetup tonight. " created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 21:01:49 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Noon Pacific: Arrived safely in Seattle. " created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 19:02:05 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/news/culture/0,1284,67278,00.html&quot;&gt;Wired&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;If the newly elected pope wants his own website, he'll have to talk to Rogers Cadenhead first.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Makes sense.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 10:12:48 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/camoby/3070115/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/20/archos.jpg&quot; width=&quot;75&quot; height=&quot;66&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named archos.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Okay I'm really getting the hang of the&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/camoby/3070115/&quot;&gt; Archos PMA430&lt;/a&gt;, but there's one thing I can't figure out. It only plays MPEG4 format videos. &lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/04/20#a997&quot;&gt;Where&lt;/a&gt; do you get those? I don't have any. I have a cross-country plane flight later today, and a good net connection now. Where do I go?" created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 06:33:10 GMT"/>
				<outline text="We've had some kind of problem with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/changes.xml&quot;&gt;changes.xml&lt;/a&gt; on weblogs.com. I've posted a &lt;a href=&quot;http://newhome.weblogs.com/2005/04/20#a1209&quot;&gt;note&lt;/a&gt; here, and will keep it updated as I find out more. Update: The change I made appears to have worked. " created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 06:55:20 GMT"/>
				<outline text="It's 51 degrees in Redmond" created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 06:33:52 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.25hoursaday.com/weblog/PermaLink.aspx?guid=7c0dfbad-d09b-422a-88c6-ec0b72dece22&quot;&gt;A must-read piece&lt;/a&gt; about Microsoft by Dare Obasanjo. " created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 06:20:48 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://minimsft.blogspot.com/2005/04/who-aint-john-galt.html&quot;&gt;Mini-Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;[There was] a reason for talented folks leaving in droves during the Internet boom: money. As folks left for start-ups, Microsofties would give them a cheery goodbye and (if they were good) say (once they were out of earshot), 'They'll be back.'&quot;" created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 06:21:48 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The weather in Redmond: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weather.com/weather/local/USWA0367?from=search_city&quot;&gt;51 degrees and clear&lt;/a&gt;. I arrive mid-day." created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 06:28:36 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="From the We-All-Can-Be-Popes Department" created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 06:04:24 GMT">
					<outline text="Since we believe any one of eight million people who have weblogs could break the biggest story of our generation, what could be wrong with each of us leading our own major religion? Exactly. So in that spirit, in &lt;i&gt;espirito doityourselfus,&lt;/i&gt; I proclaim myself Pope Dave Winer I. At your service! &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 06:06:46 GMT"/>
					<outline text="And by the power vested in me I hearby acknowledge your holiness, your eminence, your Popeness. It works for everyone, male or female, rich or poor, African, American, Asian, Australian and European. You want to be The Pope? You got it baby!" created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 06:08:03 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.scripting.com/1998/07/08/theMagicOfWindows&quot;&gt;7/8/98&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The BusinessWeek article referred to me as President Winer.&quot;" created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 06:11:21 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.davosnewbies.com/2005/04/19#anotherPapalChoice&quot;&gt;Via Lance Knobel&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;They've elected Larry Summers as Pope.&quot;" created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 06:13:58 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/20/pope.jpg&quot; width=&quot;75&quot; height=&quot;85&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named pope.jpg&quot;&gt;"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 19" created="Tue, 19 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Eight years ago: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/matt/scriptingTutorial/&quot;&gt;Matt Neuburg's Frontier scripting tutorial&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 01:39:44 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Hey I'm using my new Archos with wifi to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opera.com/pressreleases/en/2005/01/11/&quot;&gt;browse&lt;/a&gt; Scripting News. If all goes well, I'll link a photo of it into this item. Okay the picture didn't come out so good. But trust me, it's &lt;i&gt;coooool!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 00:23:53 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/articles/A2061-2005Apr19.html&quot;&gt;Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;A spokesperson for the US Conference of Bishops declined to speculate on whether the Vatican would ask Cadenhead to transfer ownership of BenedictXVI.com and the other potential papal name addresses he controls. Messages left with the Vatican's embassy in Washington were not returned.&quot;" created="Tue, 19 Apr 2005 23:57:59 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Rogers even got a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boingboing.net/2005/04/19/picking_the_popes_do.html&quot;&gt;link from Boing Boing&lt;/a&gt;. I wonder if they know he's a friend of mine. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 00:36:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/firstArchosRecording.mp3&quot;&gt;My first audio recording&lt;/a&gt; from the Archos. I had the recording level set way too high. Sorry for the distortion." created="Wed, 20 Apr 2005 00:07:20 GMT" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/firstArchosRecording.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://informationweek.com/story/showArticle.jhtml?articleID=160903186&quot;&gt;Rogers Cadenhead&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I'm not the only baptized Catholic who gets geeked about this process.&quot; " created="Tue, 19 Apr 2005 21:16:54 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rexblog.com/comments?u=rex&amp;p=6496&amp;link=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.rexblog.com%2F2005%2F04%2F19%23a6496#a6500&quot;&gt;Nashville gathering&lt;/a&gt; to focus on educating bloggers. " created="Tue, 19 Apr 2005 17:39:17 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://jrobb.mindplex.org/&quot;&gt;John Robb&lt;/a&gt; hasn't posted in 14 days. Hope everything is okay. I posted a comment on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xlogs.net/?p=58&quot;&gt;Dann Sheridan's site&lt;/a&gt; asking if he knows what's up. " created="Tue, 19 Apr 2005 21:22:51 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Hello everybody. This is your midday report. Guess what there's a new pope. No one knows who it is or what his name will be, but we're monitoring the situation, and will break in to regular scheduled program with breaking news. " created="Tue, 19 Apr 2005 16:37:59 GMT"/>
				<outline text="More news -- the new pope is speaking. It's Rat-zinger. Pope Benedict." created="Tue, 19 Apr 2005 16:43:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/entry/2005/04/18#2552&quot;&gt;Rogers wins&lt;/a&gt;, he has http://www.benedictxvi.com/. " created="Tue, 19 Apr 2005 16:47:49 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Jeff Sandquist gets a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jeffsandquist.com/ImBackWithChannel9.aspx&quot;&gt;promotion&lt;/a&gt;. Pope Jeff I?" created="Tue, 19 Apr 2005 16:43:48 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.podbat.com/2005/04/19.html#a30&quot;&gt;Podbat reports&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.google.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Google Maps&lt;/a&gt; for the UK is online. Cool-e-o. Now I can go to the UK. Seriously it's looking like I may go for my birthday and the election. Where should I stay? Hmm." created="Tue, 19 Apr 2005 14:51:03 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/04/19#a445&quot;&gt;Niklaus Coukouma&lt;/a&gt; is a Live Journal developer who has been grappling with issues raised by users who don't want their writing re-published elsewhere, using their RSS feed as a source." created="Tue, 19 Apr 2005 13:18:28 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/04/14#whatsUpWithAbeSimpson&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/19/abe.gif&quot; width=&quot;107&quot; height=&quot;58&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named abe.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Getting ready to go for my morning walk in downtown Atlanta. I'm hermetically sealed in a hotel, when I look out the window I see a huge courtyard, where it's 72 degrees every day of the year, winter or summer, rain or shine. So to find out what the weather is outside, I have to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weather.com/weather/local/USGA0028?from=search_city&quot;&gt;turn&lt;/a&gt; to the World Wide Web. Isn't the 21st century amazing! (That's an ironic joke, by the way, not really very funny I'm afraid.) Good thing I looked, it's 50 degrees outside. Brrr. Better wear a sweater and a jacket." created="Tue, 19 Apr 2005 11:20:40 GMT"/>
				<outline text="John Stanforth &lt;a href=&quot;http://stanforth.org/geekview/2005/20050418-archos-pma430-perfect-mobile-platform.html&quot;&gt;wonders&lt;/a&gt; about my &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/04/18#When:10:55:44PM&quot;&gt;Archos&lt;/a&gt;, which I &lt;i&gt;won't&lt;/i&gt; be taking on the walk. Instead I'm taking the crappy $49 flash player. I find the Archos intimidating. " created="Tue, 19 Apr 2005 11:26:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://lennpryor.blogs.com/lenn/2005/04/goodbye_microso.html&quot;&gt;Lenn Pryor&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I recently accepted a new job and have resigned my post as Director, Platform Evangelism at Microsoft after almost 8 years with the company. I am joining Skype and the family and I will be moving to the UK. I have taken a position on the product and services team at Skype.&quot; As a Skype user it'll be good to know someone on the inside. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Tue, 19 Apr 2005 10:55:56 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I met Lenn in Palm Springs in January 1998. I wrote about the trip in this &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.scripting.com/1998/01/28/asGoodAsItGets&quot;&gt;DaveNet piece&lt;/a&gt;. He's &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/search/default?q=lenn&quot;&gt;appeared&lt;/a&gt; on Scripting News quite a few times." created="Tue, 19 Apr 2005 11:09:23 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 18" created="Mon, 18 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/18/archos.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/18/archosSmall.gif&quot; width=&quot;125&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named archosSmall.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Well, I waited and waited for the Archos, and finally at 5PM, I had to go to the airport, without the new toy. Wouldn't you know, as I was was pulling out of the driveway, there was the UPS truck! I ripped open the package, charged the battery while driving to the airport, and managed to copy some MP3s across on the flight to Atlanta. It plays the music fine. There are so many doo-dads and connectors that ship with it. I've only begun to scratch the surface. In an act that's only symbolic, I copied my Frontier environment to the system. Of course it can't run it. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Tue, 19 Apr 2005 02:55:44 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Scripting.Com in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thetwowayweb.com/discuss/msgReader$642?mode=day&quot;&gt;ASCII art&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 19 Apr 2005 02:42:50 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://ryantate.com/Updates/Apr182005.html&quot;&gt;Ryan Tate observes&lt;/a&gt; that neither Adobe or Macromedia are involved in The Two-Way Web. It's true. They've had so much time to get on board, it's a wonder that they haven't. " created="Tue, 19 Apr 2005 02:40:32 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Sydney Morning Herald: &lt;a href=&quot;http://smh.com.au/articles/2005/04/18/1113676683378.html?from=rss&amp;oneclick=true&quot;&gt;Podcasts make waves for radio&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 19 Apr 2005 02:45:44 GMT"/>
				<outline text="10:30PM Eastern: Arrived safely in Atlanta." created="Tue, 19 Apr 2005 02:35:51 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://sandhill.typepad.com/sandhill_trek/2005/04/bloggo_adornome.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/18/elsie_button.gif&quot; width=&quot;76&quot; height=&quot;77&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named elsie_button.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I'm off to Atlanta tonight, then to Seattle on Wednesday morning, return to Florida on Sunday. It's an exciting trip with lots of cool technology. Most of the meetings are confidential, so I probably won't be able to report much that's specific. I have lots of time on Friday and Saturday to catch up with Seattle friends. Maybe a group dinner? If so, we'll have to do it without Scoble, since he's in San Jose this weekend." created="Mon, 18 Apr 2005 19:40:35 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://opensource.weblogsinc.com/entry/1234000413040421/&quot;&gt;Scott Granneman&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I don’t like it when large corporations make wide-ranging decisions for users that disadvantage those that the corporations choose not to favor.&quot;" created="Mon, 18 Apr 2005 18:07:15 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/entry/2005/04/18#2552&quot;&gt;Rogers Cadenhead&lt;/a&gt; is domain name speculating on the name of the next pope. Personally, if by some weird twist of fate they name &lt;i&gt;me&lt;/i&gt; the next pope, I will choose the &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/18/harry.jpg&quot;&gt;name&lt;/a&gt; Pope Harry Truman II. " created="Mon, 18 Apr 2005 15:01:42 GMT"/>
				<outline text="MarketWatch: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marketwatch.com/news/story.asp?guid=%7B3B04AC26%2DE1ED%2D4FA3%2D8E72%2D9C493CADC469%7D&amp;dist=rss&amp;siteid=mktw&quot;&gt;Adobe Systems to buy Macromedia&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;$3.4 billion.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 18 Apr 2005 09:30:45 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/18/heh.gif&quot; width=&quot;87&quot; height=&quot;48&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;20&quot; vspace=&quot;8&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named heh.gif&quot;&gt;Off the top of my head, who cares? At one time both companies had some &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/search/default?q=mojo&quot;&gt;mojo&lt;/a&gt;, to borrow a term from Yahoo, but those days are long-gone. Remember all the hooplah over the Allaire-Macromedia acquisition, and all the synergies that were supposed to happen. Hmmm. Did any happen? BusinessWeek didn't &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessweek.com/investor/content/aug2002/pi2002089_8261.htm&quot;&gt;think&lt;/a&gt; so. Will any happen here? Heh. Slightly more exciting than Microsoft's acquisition of Groove." created="Mon, 18 Apr 2005 09:38:19 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Phillip Torone has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.makezine.com/blog/archive/2005/04/makediycast_our.html&quot;&gt;new podcast&lt;/a&gt;, at Make Mag." created="Mon, 18 Apr 2005 11:44:28 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Four years ago: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.scripting.com/2001/04/17/theWebIsAWritingEnvironment&quot;&gt;The Web is a Writing Environment&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Amazingly the print publishers are pulling back from the Web, as if to say 'Whew glad that's over.' Fundamental mistake.&quot;" created="Mon, 18 Apr 2005 06:41:13 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gigaom.com/2005/04/17/wimax-according-to-intel-arrives/&quot;&gt;Om Malik&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The marketing blitz makes you wonder if this time Intel’s finally figured out how to make a communication chip!&quot;" created="Mon, 18 Apr 2005 06:43:26 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I had lunch with a Republican yesterday, a thoughtful one, and came away with a fair amount more hope than I did going into it." created="Mon, 18 Apr 2005 06:44:12 GMT"/>
				<outline text="3AM on the east coast is midnight on the west, 8AM in London." created="Mon, 18 Apr 2005 06:52:21 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 17" created="Sun, 17 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://essaysfromexodus.scripting.com/pictures/viewer$544&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/17/wisteria.jpg&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;65&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named wisteria.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stomaphagus.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;From Dan Hale&lt;/a&gt; comes news that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buckfamily.org/cgi-bin/blosxom.cgi/life/brianbuck1.comments&quot;&gt;Brian Buck died&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/04/08&quot;&gt;April 8&lt;/a&gt;. I wrote a condolence on the Buck family weblog: \&quot;Brian was a smart, generous and inspiring person, before he had cancer, he was a programming colleague, after, we &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/search/default?q=brian+buck&quot;&gt;followed&lt;/a&gt; his struggle, &lt;a href=&quot;http://outhere.com/brian/weblog/&quot;&gt;written&lt;/a&gt; so openly, so personally and realistically. I'm so sorry he's gone now, I was hoping we'd have his company, his inspiration, for many years to come.\&quot; He was 33." created="Sun, 17 Apr 2005 09:47:57 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://outhere.com/brian/weblog/2003/01/22.html#a130&quot;&gt;Brian Buck&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;It was never my intention to get cancer.&quot; &lt;i&gt;And die.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Sun, 17 Apr 2005 21:28:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Rogers put together a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/entry/2005/04/17.html#2551&quot;&gt;remembrance&lt;/a&gt; of Brian Buck." created="Sun, 17 Apr 2005 19:56:35 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://business.timesonline.co.uk/article/0,,9071-1568961_1,00.html&quot;&gt;Rupert Murdoch&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Some digital natives do even more than blog with text -- they are blogging with audio, specifically through the rise of podcasting -- and to remain fully competitive, some may want to consider providing a place for that as well.&quot;" created="Sun, 17 Apr 2005 12:16:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/17/murdoch.jpg&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;88&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named murdoch.jpg&quot;&gt;We don't get no respect from Google, we don't get no respect from the EFF, but we &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; get respect, tons of it, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk/2162658.stm&quot;&gt;Rupert Murdoch&lt;/a&gt;. Now who do you think gets it, the tech industry, or...? Heh. My bet is, I hope, clear. The techies have an inflated sense of self-importance. The information system of the WORLD is changing, Murdoch sees that, and sees himself as an immigrant (all of us who were reared in the centralized information &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.scripting.com/2002/05/13/monocultureAnArtifcactOfThe20thCentury&quot;&gt;system&lt;/a&gt; of the 20th century are), and because of that, understands that he has much to learn. The young minds of the tech industry aren't young enough to be rooted in the transition, or old enough to get that a transition is taking place, and that they are building on a foundation that's eroding. If they were aware, Google would be pushing RSS instead of resisting it, and the EFF would be protecting the integrity of our work, instead of helping Google undermine it. We have a &lt;i&gt;chance&lt;/i&gt; for a revolution, it's just a chance, Murdoch gets this, so the barriers are probably going up, as we speak. We, the little people, need to work together, now, like we really mean it. " created="Sun, 17 Apr 2005 14:48:12 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2001/04/17#tuesdayLunchWithAProgrammer&quot;&gt;Four years ago&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;All programmers want to tell you How It Works. In excruciating detail. As if you cared. Try to be patient.&quot;" created="Sun, 17 Apr 2005 20:38:48 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Richard MacManus: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/002698.php&quot;&gt;RSS and the Big 3&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 17 Apr 2005 21:52:49 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://geeks.opml.org/2005/04/17#a23&quot;&gt;Working on the OPML editor&lt;/a&gt;, I'm trying to figure out how to have the app come to the front on startup on Windows. Any clues would be much appreciated. Source &lt;a href=&quot;http://sourcelisting.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;listings&lt;/a&gt; are here." created="Sun, 17 Apr 2005 21:47:27 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The delivery &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ups.com/&quot;&gt;service&lt;/a&gt; says they'll not make it on Monday, so my new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,1759,1780005,00.asp?kc=PCRSS02129TX1K0000530&quot;&gt;toy&lt;/a&gt; won't arrive till Tuesday, when I will be in Atlan-tay, on my way to See-at-tay. So no happiness till the week next. Sad Davey." created="Sun, 17 Apr 2005 14:44:06 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/technology/4448807.stm&quot;&gt;BBC&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Photographs of North America's most significant landmarks and locations, including the Grand Canyon, Alcatraz and Mount Rushmore are being given a fresh perspective thanks to a tool by Google.&quot;" created="Sun, 17 Apr 2005 10:20:55 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Library Stuff &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.librarystuff.net/2005/04/discovery-channel-goes-rss.html&quot;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; that the Discovery Channel has 4 new &lt;a href=&quot;http://dsc.discovery.com/utilities/rss/rss.html&quot;&gt;RSS feeds&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sun, 17 Apr 2005 04:52:26 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 16" created="Sat, 16 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/16/winamp.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/16/winampsmall.gif&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; height=&quot;177&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;20&quot; vspace=&quot;8&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named winampsmall.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnApr16.mp3&quot;&gt;Today's podcast&lt;/a&gt; is Part II of answers to Shel Israel's questions for the book he's working on with Robert Scoble. Also a bit of music from USA for Africa (1985). One of my neighbors is sitting outside my window, so I felt self-conscious. No matter, I speak my mind anyway. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Sat, 16 Apr 2005 17:34:57 GMT" name="aHrefhttpimagesscriptingcomarchivescriptingcom20050416winampgifimgSrchttpimagesscriptingcomarchivescriptingcom20050416winampsmallgifWidth140Height177Border0AlignrightHspace20Vspace8AltaPictureNamedWinampsmallgifaaHrefhttpmp3morningcoffeenotescomcnapr16mp3todaysPodcastaIsPartIiOfAnswersToShelIsraelsQuestionsForTheBookHesWorkingOnWithRobertScobleAlsoABitOfMusicFromUsaForAfrica1985OneOfMyNeighborsIsSittingOutsideMyWindowSoIFeltSelfconsciousNoMatterISpeakMyMindAnyway" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnApr16.mp3"/>
				<outline text="Happiness is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.winamp.com/&quot;&gt;WinAmp&lt;/a&gt;. Now that I'm switching to the Archos (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,1759,1780005,00.asp?kc=PCRSS02129TX1K0000530&quot;&gt;it&lt;/a&gt; arrives on Monday), I can start phasing out iTunes. I've never figured out how it works, if you can believe that. So when I came across an &quot;ogg&quot; file and found that WinAmp could play it, I grabbed a copy. I forgot how nice it is! " created="Sat, 16 Apr 2005 22:52:16 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Bill Gross's new search engine is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.snap.com/&quot;&gt;Snap.Com&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sat, 16 Apr 2005 18:28:19 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Microsoft's Jim Allchin &lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2005/04/15.html#a9868&quot;&gt;had dinner&lt;/a&gt; with some bloggers in SF last night. It was set up by Scoble. Now, while it's true that Microsoft has embraced blogging to a greater extent than any other big corporation that I'm aware of, it's totally &lt;i&gt;un&lt;/i&gt;bloglike to make a dinner invite-only, and keep it a secret until after it's happened. " created="Sat, 16 Apr 2005 13:58:34 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/16/abe.gif&quot; width=&quot;105&quot; height=&quot;57&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named abe.gif&quot;&gt;Totally coincidentally, I mentioned Allchin in a comment on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.docuverse.com/blog/donpark/EntryViewPage.aspx?guid=81e6c567-fc29-4b97-a1a3-a8a39d0da678&quot;&gt;Don Park's blog&lt;/a&gt;, yesterday. Hey, Don should have been at that dinner. He could have talked about Korean &lt;a href=&quot;http://marc.blogs.it/archives/2005/04/gotta_have_kim.html&quot;&gt;food&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.docuverse.com/blog/donpark/EntryViewPage.aspx?guid=6dee89c2-23e7-45e2-b217-1a9d72fbb0de&quot;&gt;music&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.docuverse.com/blog/donpark/EntryViewPage.aspx?guid=0e779685-8c7a-40d7-8734-c611dc98b009&quot;&gt;theater&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.docuverse.com/blog/donpark/EntryViewPage.aspx?guid=eb91f8c1-ed8e-4c5e-ad89-f6c29a3a2904&quot;&gt;Win32 APIs&lt;/a&gt;. Not surprisingly, Marc Canter &lt;a href=&quot;http://marc.blogs.it/archives/2005/04/im_off_of_scobl.html&quot;&gt;thinks&lt;/a&gt; he should have been there too (even though he's in Korea now). See what I mean about invite-only blogger dinners? You wind up creating fewer friends, more nagging. (I won't say enemies, too much is made of that. You can't fight a war with fingers and eyeballs, or can you?) Okay this post is long enough now to host the rotated Abe Simpson &lt;i&gt;du jour.&lt;/i&gt; " created="Sat, 16 Apr 2005 14:02:59 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Interesting comments on yesterday's &lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/04/15#a979&quot;&gt;beach pictures&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sat, 16 Apr 2005 09:09:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://rc3.org/cgi-bin/less.pl?arg=6909&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/16/viagra.gif&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;63&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;VIAGRA&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;" created="Sat, 16 Apr 2005 13:35:05 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 15" created="Fri, 15 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Essay: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/04/15#a439&quot;&gt;Yahoo, Microsoft and Google in RSS&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 15 Apr 2005 17:23:07 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.outer-court.com/archive/2005-04-15-n65.html&quot;&gt;Google Blogoscoped&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;While Google is often late in the game, it equally often then releases something &lt;i&gt;infinitely&lt;/i&gt; better than what competitors are doing at that time.&quot;" created="Fri, 15 Apr 2005 21:42:42 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://geeks.opml.org/2005/04/15#a16&quot;&gt;Introducing MyCommentSpamBuddy&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;If you're running a weblog, comment spam may be one of the biggest irritants you have to deal with. Until now Manila and its underlying discussion group software hasn't had any automatic defenses against comment spam.&quot;" created="Fri, 15 Apr 2005 09:00:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Went for a drive on the beach today. &lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/04/15#a979&quot;&gt;Pictures&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/movies/drivingOnTheBeach.mov&quot;&gt;Movie&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 15 Apr 2005 23:25:54 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Engadget: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.engadget.com/entry/1234000950040347/&quot;&gt;How would you change the iPod?&lt;/a&gt;" created="Fri, 15 Apr 2005 19:45:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.byte.org/blog/_archives/2005/4/14/581666.html&quot;&gt;Ross Rader&lt;/a&gt; is hosting a Toronto Podcasting dinner, next Tues. " created="Fri, 15 Apr 2005 14:59:04 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.docuverse.com/blog/donpark/EntryViewPage.aspx?guid=81e6c567-fc29-4b97-a1a3-a8a39d0da678&quot;&gt;Don Park&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;He can throw large rocks very accurately.&quot;" created="Fri, 15 Apr 2005 13:08:02 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Actually I throw &lt;a href=&quot;http://muppets.go.com/games/muppets-flyinggonzo.html&quot;&gt;Gonzos&lt;/a&gt;, not rocks. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Fri, 15 Apr 2005 13:38:57 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.podbat.com/base/tradesushi/050414_tsushi01_scoble.mp3&quot;&gt;I did a podcast&lt;/a&gt; over Skype a couple of nights ago &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.podbat.com/2005/04/15.html#a19&quot;&gt;with Kosso&lt;/a&gt; and we used SkypeOut to call Scoble, which worked &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; well. It's pretty long and rambly, and goofy and techy. It's podcast number two with Kosso, the pod-bad-man, with a new brand for every day of the month. The brand &lt;i&gt;du jour&lt;/i&gt; is Trade Sushi. It's like Trade Secrets, but with Sushi. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Fri, 15 Apr 2005 11:06:06 GMT" type="link" url="http://mp3.podbat.com/base/tradesushi/050414_tsushi01_scoble.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2003/04/15#When:12:36:29PM&quot;&gt;Two years ago&lt;/a&gt; today Microsoft got its &quot;foot in the blogging door&quot; by hiring Scoble. " created="Fri, 15 Apr 2005 12:12:12 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/15/abe.gif&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;73&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named abe.gif&quot;&gt;I've got a new NetGear router, and once again BitTorrent is running at a snail's pace. I had this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thetwowayweb.com/2005/03/09#a525&quot;&gt;problem in March&lt;/a&gt;, mapping the BT ports to my laptop cured the problem and made the downloads run hugely fast. I've done the same with the new router, and the downloads are intermittently fast, but mostly snail-like slow, about 6K per second, on a high speed line capable of over 400K per second. I've tried it on lots of downloads, so I don't think the problem is with the net. I'm running 4.0.1 on Windows. If you have an idea, add a comment &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thetwowayweb.com/2005/03/09#a525&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, please; and thanks!" created="Fri, 15 Apr 2005 09:55:58 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Russell Beattie: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.russellbeattie.com/notebook/1008419.html&quot;&gt;Linux for Human Beings&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 15 Apr 2005 09:39:53 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Jason Lefkowitz sends a pointer to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.philhendrieshow.com/mediacenter.html&quot;&gt;Phil Hendrie podcast&lt;/a&gt;, which he describes thus: &quot;A nationally syndicated comedy talk show. It's really funny -- like a parody of the stupid talk shows.&quot;" created="Fri, 15 Apr 2005 08:46:10 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/dir/davesWorld/history/previousHeaderGraphics/aWetGreenLaneInWoodside&quot;&gt;New header graphic&lt;/a&gt;. A wet green lane in Woodside. " created="Fri, 15 Apr 2005 08:56:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Getting credit without patents" created="Fri, 15 Apr 2005 09:39:24 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://snltranscripts.jt.org/75/75gupdate.phtml&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/15/emily.jpg&quot; width=&quot;45&quot; height=&quot;53&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named emily.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;BTW, I'm offering my &lt;a href=&quot;http://geeks.opml.org/stories/storyReader$17&quot;&gt;comment spam buddy&lt;/a&gt; under the &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/&quot;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Sharealike license,&lt;/a&gt; with a special request. It may be that this is a new way to fight comment spam. If it is, I would like credit for discovering it. I consider this one final attempt to work openly without patenting every innovation. I've been asking for help with this for years. Now on the other hand, if it's not new, as &lt;a href=&quot;http://snl.jt.org/char.php?i=181&quot;&gt;Emily Litella&lt;/a&gt; said, &quot;Never mind.&quot; &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Fri, 15 Apr 2005 09:02:02 GMT"/>
					<outline text="A great example is this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newcitychicago.com/chicago/4267.html&quot;&gt;Newcity Chicago article&lt;/a&gt; which, once again, gives Adam Curry credit for my work. He doesn't say anything to correct them, that's his problem. The reporter's problem is that he's passing on lies. It's endemic, that's why you have a virtual industry of credit-takers, leeches feeding off the creativity of others, and they get away with it because the reporters are complicit. So please, I have no patience for people who lecture us about the thorough research that the pros supposedly do, if they ever do it, it's a very rare thing. " created="Fri, 15 Apr 2005 09:05:25 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 14" created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="A Morning Coffee Notes &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnApr14.mp3&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; for the day before Tax Day in the USA. A virtual interview with Shel Israel, co-author of The Red Couch." created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 23:20:14 GMT" name="aMorningCoffeeNotesAHrefhttpmp3morningcoffeenotescomcnapr14mp3podcastaForTheDayBeforeTaxDayInTheUsaAVirtualInterviewWithShelIsraelCoauthorOfTheRedCouch" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnApr14.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/pressoffice/pressreleases/stories/2005/04_april/14/pod.shtml&quot;&gt;Press release&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The BBC is to podcast up to 20 more radio shows – including sections of the Today programme and selected Radio 1 speech content - as it extends its download trial, it was announced today.&quot;" created="Fri, 15 Apr 2005 01:19:29 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gizmodo.com/gadgets/laptops-pcs/apple/apple-osx-tiger-developer-trading-cards-039992.php&quot;&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I apologize for any times I might have implied that Apple wasn't run by total dorks.&quot;" created="Fri, 15 Apr 2005 02:41:08 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.punknews.org/article.php?sid=12222&amp;mode=thread&amp;order=0&amp;thold=0&quot;&gt;Punk News&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Addison's Marc Alghini discovered the band via a podcast from Ohio based indie-rock webzine Donewaiting.com.&quot;" created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 22:11:07 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Canada.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.canada.com/technology/story.html?id=aee801f8-1e91-4725-b747-2b3c228c2ac9&quot;&gt;Ottawa's premier podcasters&lt;/a&gt;." created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 21:27:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Marc Canter's &lt;a href=&quot;http://marc.blogs.it/archives/2005/04/gotta_have_kim.html&quot;&gt;tour&lt;/a&gt; of Korean food -- in Korea." created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 23:58:11 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/stories/storyReader$978&quot;&gt;I'm fed up&lt;/a&gt; with Gender Spam, too. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 21:15:47 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Little-known fact, there's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://audio.weblogs.com/feeddebug.html&quot;&gt;debugger&lt;/a&gt; for podcast feeds; it tells you if a feed will work with audio.weblogs.com, and if not, why. " created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 19:41:41 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I found a lovely &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/radio2/shows/sounds70s/?focuswin&quot;&gt;radio program&lt;/a&gt; on the BBC, Sounds of the 70s, poifect for a guy about to turn 50. It's done by a grizzled old British &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/radio2/shows/sounds70s/biography.shtml&quot;&gt;guy&lt;/a&gt;, opinionated, no commercials, great songs. Wowo. The Internet is still cool. " created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 19:46:29 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.blogware.com/blog/_archives/2005/4/14/581558.html&quot;&gt;Tod Maffin&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The owner of two radio stations in Wyoming said it has sold the stations and is concentrating on podcasting.&quot;" created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 19:09:39 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Upcoming travel, all tentative: Seattle, Atlanta, San Jose, New York, London. I want to be in Europe on May 2, for the Big Five-Oh. " created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 16:57:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://podcastercon.org/wiki/doku.php?id=home:what_is_open_space_technology&quot;&gt;Brian Russell&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Open Space conferences have no keynote speakers, no pre-announced schedules of workshops, no panel discussions, no organizational booths. Instead, sitting in a large circle, participants learn in the first hour how they are going to create their own conference. Almost before they realize it, they become each other’s teachers and leaders.&quot;" created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 17:16:45 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I've got my spam defense tool for Frontier/Manila documented, tested and ready to go, pending approval from a few people who are reviewing it. I have it running on two servers now, and the software it was created from has been running almost six months. But a little more burn-in can't hurt. " created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 17:01:48 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thenation.com/outrage/index.mhtml?pid=2324&quot;&gt;The Nation&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;DeLay always has the same pathetic excuse: liberals.&quot;" created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 14:18:55 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/entry/2005/04/14#2548&quot;&gt;Rogers Cadenhead&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The end result looks like the out-of-wedlock love child of LiveJournal and de.licio.us.&quot;" created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 14:17:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Steve May, via email: &quot;I've been attending conferences for 30-plus years and it always pissed me off that speakers and panelists either didn't speak on the promoted topic or used the opportunity to bore us with a shameless commercial for their product or service.&quot;" created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 13:19:27 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Thanks to Chris Pirillo" created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 10:44:26 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/misc/abeSimpsonWavs/gayles.wav&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/14/abe.gif&quot; width=&quot;93&quot; height=&quot;87&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named abe.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;After running the &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/04/13#mrPickyAndMrCoward&quot;&gt;bit&lt;/a&gt; about Mr Picky yesterday, I got several emails saying that there are others who say the same thing -- &quot;If Dave's there, I won't be.&quot; So it seems likely that &lt;a href=&quot;http://chris.pirillo.com/&quot;&gt;Chris Pirillo&lt;/a&gt; was under the same kind of pressure when he invited me to keynote &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnomedex.com/updates/&quot;&gt;Gnomedex&lt;/a&gt;, and that makes me all the more appreciative of his support. Thanks Chris!" created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 10:41:15 GMT"/>
					<outline text="And to everyone else, listen to what I do at Gnomedex, I'm sure it'll be recorded. People slime me and it's not fair. I work hard at conferences to make sure everyone gets good value. I work for the &quot;audience,&quot; a term that needs updating in the age of the blog. There are always a few people who feel otherwise. As they say in France, c'est la vie!" created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 10:46:23 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="What's up with Abe Simpson?" created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 10:48:45 GMT">
					<outline text="For the last few days I've been rotating Abe Simpson through Scripting News. I've been asked what this means. Here's what it means. Nothing. " created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 10:48:51 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Is it a comment on the post it's next to? No. Is it related? Only in that it's next to it. Why do you do it? I like it. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 10:49:25 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I like to put the picture next to a big post with lots of text that needs a little visual relief. Since Abe is my favorite Simpson's character, and I want to see what he looks like from every angle, that's where I'm going for visual relief, these days, in &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/dir/davesWorld/weblogarchive/2005/April&quot;&gt;April 2005&lt;/a&gt;. Next month it'll be something else. " created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 10:59:39 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The issue of who's my favorite Simpson was raised in a radio &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/templates/rundowns/rundown.php?prgId=13&amp;prgDate=6-Apr-05&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with Brad Bird, one of the producers, who said that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.silverbox.com/krusty/&quot;&gt;Krusty&lt;/a&gt; the Clown is his favorite. Krusty's good, but no one is more soulfully &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/misc/abeSimpsonWavs/gayles.wav&quot;&gt;pathetic&lt;/a&gt; than Grandpa Abe Simpson. " created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 10:51:02 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="A true story about Joan Baez" created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 11:30:44 GMT">
					<outline text="I lived in a nice &lt;a href=&quot;http://essaysfromexodus.scripting.com/stories/storyReader$78&quot;&gt;house&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://essaysfromexodus.scripting.com/stories/storyReader$94&quot;&gt;with&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;a href=&quot;http://essaysfromexodus.scripting.com/stories/storyReader$630&quot;&gt;garden&lt;/a&gt; on three beautiful acres &lt;a href=&quot;http://essaysfromexodus.scripting.com/stories/storyReader$247&quot;&gt;by&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://essaysfromexodus.scripting.com/stories/storyReader$93&quot;&gt;a&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://essaysfromexodus.scripting.com/stories/storyReader$573&quot;&gt;creek&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;http://essaysfromexodus.scripting.com/stories/storyReader$404&quot;&gt;Woodside&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://essaysfromexodus.scripting.com/stories/storyReader$69&quot;&gt;California&lt;/a&gt;, from 1992 to 2003. I sold it to one of my neighbors, who used my land to add to his, which, according to Woodside's zoning regulations, allowed him to build a bigger house, which he wanted to do. " created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 11:30:50 GMT"/>
					<outline text="My old house, built in 1929, with thick walls that kept the house cool in summer, a fantastic place to throw parties, and a place that could be pretty lonely, at the end of a long driveway, was deleted shortly after the deal was done." created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 13:26:00 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Anyway, one day, a couple of years before I moved, the phone rings, I pick it up and a woman at the other end says &quot;Hello this is Joan Baez.&quot; I knew she was a neighbor, but we had never spoken. I guess I was too nervous, star-struck. She's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vanguardrecords.com/Baez/Home.html&quot;&gt;famous&lt;/a&gt; folk-rock star, dated Bob Dylan, played at Woodstock, stuff like that. She said she was going to get baby sheep (or goats?) to live in her yard and they would make a lot of noise at first because they were separated from their mothers, but eventually they'd calm down, and she wanted to let all the neighbors know." created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 11:31:58 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I said okay, no problemmo, but why are you getting sheep? " created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 11:34:42 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&quot;I've always wanted them,&quot; she said." created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 11:38:20 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 13" created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="New feature on audio.weblogs.com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/04/13#a134&quot;&gt;Click-tracking&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 11:25:46 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnApr13.mp3&quot;&gt;A singing podcast&lt;/a&gt;, my rendition of &lt;i&gt;It's A Small World.&lt;/i&gt; As usual, appreciate the philosophy. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 12:49:50 GMT" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnApr13.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/04/13#a133&quot;&gt;Need help&lt;/a&gt; with audio.weblogs.com?" created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 10:42:37 GMT"/>
				<outline text="News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.com.com/Blog+censorship+gains+support/2100-1028_3-5670096.html?part=rss&amp;tag=5670096&amp;subj=news&quot;&gt;Blog censorship gains support&lt;/a&gt;." created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 01:51:02 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://upload.video.google.com/video_faq.html&quot;&gt;Google Video Upload&lt;/a&gt; &quot;lets you submit videos electronically.&quot;" created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 23:02:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/04/13#a144&quot;&gt;By now a bunch of people&lt;/a&gt; have had a chance to review Google Video Upload. What do you think? What were you first experiences?" created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 23:08:49 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bluestein.com/archives/2005/04/crosspost_here.html&quot;&gt;Richard Bluestein&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;These big media guys are going to become the art police.&quot;" created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 23:17:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.podbat.com/2005/04/14.html#a18&quot;&gt;Kosso&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Spoilers ahoy!&quot;" created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 01:16:59 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/13/abe.gif&quot; width=&quot;87&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named abe.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/discuss/msgReader$142?mode=day&quot;&gt;McD Tracy&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Neat little hack, Dave. Keep 'em coming.&quot; Actually I &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; have another neat little hack to offer Frontier system managers, maybe even later today. It's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.userland.com/directory/3541/tools&quot;&gt;Tool&lt;/a&gt; that keeps your DGs free of comment spam. It really works. Not sure if they have anything like it in MovableType-Land. In any case, the existing comment spam defenses in Frontier and Manila aren't working, I seek to improve that situation. " created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 15:46:42 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogher.org/2005/04/announcing_blog.html&quot;&gt;BlogHer&lt;/a&gt; is a conference about women &amp; blogging, 7/30, Santa Clara." created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 19:05:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.syndisphere.com/&quot;&gt;Syndisphere&lt;/a&gt;, a term first used by Steve Gillmor, has legs. On &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/04/10#When:5:46:42PM&quot;&gt;Sunday&lt;/a&gt; it had 0 Google hits, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;q=syndisphere&amp;btnG=Google+Search&quot;&gt;today&lt;/a&gt; it has 124. " created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 15:31:35 GMT"/>
				<outline text="GoDaddy has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://radiogodaddy.com/gdshop/radio_rss_get.asp&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; feed. " created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 15:34:49 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Oh for the days when political correctness didn't rule public discourse. Consider the Randy Newman song, &lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/shortPeople.txt&quot;&gt;Short People&lt;/a&gt; (1978). &quot;They got little noses and tiny little teeth. They wear platform shoes on their nasty little feet.&quot; " created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 22:49:08 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The NYC podcasting &lt;a href=&quot;http://podcasting.meetup.com/33/events/4456520/&quot;&gt;meetup&lt;/a&gt; is on April 20, 701 Seventh Ave." created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 15:29:13 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boingboing.net/2005/04/13/unhappy_disneyland_v.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/13/disneyLandGuy.jpg&quot; width=&quot;45&quot; height=&quot;59&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named disneyLandGuy.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Cory Doctorow has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boingboing.net/2005/04/13/unhappy_disneyland_v.html&quot;&gt;picture&lt;/a&gt; of unhappy people at Disneyland. He says it's eerie and that's true. I've never understood why people like Disneyland so much. I've always really disliked the place. What nailed it for me was getting stuck in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://disneyworld.disney.go.com/wdw/parks/attractionDetail?id=ItsASmallWorldAttractionPage&quot;&gt;It's A Small World&lt;/a&gt; ride with all the puppets &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niehs.nih.gov/kids/lyrics/smworld.htm&quot;&gt;singing&lt;/a&gt; for hours, while they tried to figure out how to get us out. When they finally got the ride working, as compensation, they offered us more tickets. That was absolutely the last thing I wanted. Get me outa here. " created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 12:09:52 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.weblogs.com/2005/04/13#nanoentertainment&quot;&gt;Doc Searls&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;When it's over, you can't help repeating, for the rest of your life, a song that you hate.&quot;" created="Thu, 14 Apr 2005 02:54:28 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Mr Picky and Mr Coward" created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 11:38:18 GMT">
					<outline text="A friend confirmed something that I kind-of suspected. There's at least one person who has told at least one conference organizer that he won't come if I'm also invited. The person has name, of course, but I don't think I should say who it is, at this time. " created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 11:31:59 GMT"/>
					<outline text="If the conference organizer goes for that, they've done me a favor, because I wouldn't want to support a conference that allowed people to exclude others in this way. Further, people who make such demands should be scared that they'll be outed. That they're not, says a lot about this stupid little thing we call an industry. " created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 11:38:14 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Another related item, there was an anonymous posting in the comments on one of my sites recently that called into question the integrity of someone other than myself, in a demeaning way. The person took the challenge seriously, asked for help finding out who the poster was, and we're pretty sure we know who it is. Like 99.9 percent sure. It's that tiny sliver of doubt that makes me not want to expose the person." created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 11:39:12 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Observation -- it's pretty gutless to challenge someone's integrity and not put your name on it. And it's pretty stupid to do so and leave a trail back to your desktop that a moderately skilled programmer could follow." created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 11:42:02 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 12" created="Tue, 12 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/04/08#a946&quot;&gt;Today's news&lt;/a&gt;, I'm a keynote discussion leader at Gnomedex in June." created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 00:58:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,1759,1780005,00.asp?kc=PCRSS02129TX1K0000530&quot;&gt;This is the PDA/music player&lt;/a&gt; I bought today. It does &lt;i&gt;everything.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 03:06:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newyorker.com/talk/content/articles/050418ta_talk_surowiecki&quot;&gt;New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;To paraphrase John Paul Getty: If you owe the bank a hundred dollars, you’ve got a problem. If you owe the bank three trillion dollars, the bank’s got a problem.&quot;" created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 03:23:41 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.musicpodcasting.org/&quot;&gt;The Association of Music Podcasting&lt;/a&gt; was &quot;formed in January 2005 to unite podcasters who play legally available independent music.&quot;" created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 00:17:19 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.minnesota.publicradio.org/features/2005/04/12_hughesa_wifi/?rsssource=1&quot;&gt;Minnesota Public Radio&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The city of Minneapolis is receiving proposals to develop city-wide, wireless Internet access.&quot;" created="Tue, 12 Apr 2005 23:24:51 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/changes/&quot;&gt;Meetup.Com now charges&lt;/a&gt; a fee of $19 per month per group." created="Tue, 12 Apr 2005 22:39:13 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Buy.Com has &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buy.com/rss/default.asp&quot;&gt;RSS feeds&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Wed, 13 Apr 2005 02:36:49 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.re.org/tom/cartoons/old/maggot.jpg&quot;&gt;Joe, I can't help&lt;/a&gt; but think you're a blood-sucking maggot. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Tue, 12 Apr 2005 20:28:15 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marketwatch.com/news/story.asp?guid=%7B010B82D2%2D4FEF%2D4186%2D893C%2D675085A028DE%7D&amp;dist=rss&amp;siteid=mktw&quot;&gt;CBS&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Blogger is hosting an estimated 8 million blogs.&quot;" created="Tue, 12 Apr 2005 17:51:57 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://geeks.opml.org/2005/04/12#a13&quot;&gt;Here's another free code&lt;/a&gt; release for Frontier server systems. The viewPodcastBox macro shows a RSS 2.0 feed with enclosures in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/09/freshCastsBox.gif&quot;&gt;box&lt;/a&gt; in a web page. I used this macro &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/&quot;&gt;podcatch.com&lt;/a&gt; to show the fresh podcasts from &lt;a href=&quot;http://audio.weblogs.com/&quot;&gt;audio.weblogs.com&lt;/a&gt;. It's very much like the more general &lt;a href=&quot;http://macros.userland.com/basic/viewRssBox&quot;&gt;viewRssBox&lt;/a&gt; macro, but tuned to the display of podcast feeds." created="Tue, 12 Apr 2005 15:04:04 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.socialtext.net/loicwiki/index.cgi?internet_2_0&quot;&gt;April 25 in Paris&lt;/a&gt;, Loic LeMeur is hosting Internet 2.0 conference. Lots of Americans are heading over to France for this event. " created="Tue, 12 Apr 2005 14:40:24 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/12/abe.gif&quot; width=&quot;78&quot; height=&quot;105&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named abe.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newmediamusings.com/&quot;&gt;JD Lasica&lt;/a&gt; is on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wamu.org/programs/dr/05/04/12.php&quot;&gt;Diane Rehm Show today&lt;/a&gt;, 10AM Eastern, talking about radio. I listened to it. My notes, taken in real-time, follow. Oy, old JD isn't doing a very good job of explaining it. First he says radio is dead, and doesn't know it. No fucking way that's true, it's an incredibly entrenched distribution mechanism. It's going to change, for sure, but that's not the same thing as going away! Now, the moderator questions why 100 stations isn't enough, how many stations can one person listen to. Exactly, but maybe I want to listen to a station that only a small number of people want to listen to. Broadcast radio, commercial or non-commercial, can't handle that. Narrowcasting is what podcasting is for. And btw, how are we going to get anywhere when it's all Adam Curry. He's the poster-child for the flow of the big media model to narrowcasting. Does not compute. I'm sure Adam actually knows this, btw, that he's sold out to the dark side. Eventually we'll have a good laugh about this, maybe at Gnomedex." created="Tue, 12 Apr 2005 10:01:45 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/technology/4435809.stm&quot;&gt;BBC&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Eight US newspapers and the Associated Press agency have thrown their support behind three bloggers sued by Apple.&quot;" created="Tue, 12 Apr 2005 10:29:08 GMT"/>
				<outline text="See you at Gnomedex?" created="Tue, 12 Apr 2005 09:20:22 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2004/09/20#a74&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/12/allusers.jpg&quot; width=&quot;85&quot; height=&quot;107&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named allusers.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I don't go to many industry conferences these days, but this year's &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.gnomedex.com/&quot;&gt;Gnomedex&lt;/A&gt;, in &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.bellharbor.org/&quot;&gt;Seattle&lt;/A&gt;, June 23-25, is shaping up as a gotta-be-there event. I could tell when the guys on the Starbucks &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMar31.mp3&quot;&gt;Coffee Notes&lt;/a&gt; (March 31 in NYC) asked if I was going. Then &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.kosso.com/&quot;&gt;Kosso&lt;/A&gt;, who lives in London (that's in Europe!) asked if I was going. By then I was already working with &lt;A href=&quot;http://chris.pirillo.com/blog&quot;&gt;Chris&lt;/A&gt;, but I wanted to leave it a tease, so I said nothing.&amp;nbsp;With &amp;nbsp;the help of Steve Gillmor, who was at BloggerCon III,&amp;nbsp;we worked&amp;nbsp;out a plan to include a taste of &lt;EM&gt;un&lt;/EM&gt;conference at the beginning of Gnomedex, to help get the &quot;audience&quot; out of their seats, sharing their ideas. You know, just like blogs. And it's cool because I get to go back to Seattle, where I spent four happy months at the end of 2004. I'm totally looking forward to Gnomedex, and thanks to Chris and Ponzi for extending the very generous invitation to &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.gnomedex.com/updates/2005-04.phtml#027358&quot;&gt;keynote&lt;/A&gt;! I can't wait." created="Tue, 12 Apr 2005 09:19:44 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2004/09/20#a74&quot;&gt;Pictures taken&lt;/a&gt; on the Seattle waterfront, where the Gnomedex will be held in late June this year." created="Tue, 12 Apr 2005 09:17:42 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/04/08#a946&quot;&gt;A place to comment&lt;/a&gt;, let's start the discussion now." created="Tue, 12 Apr 2005 09:20:50 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 11" created="Mon, 11 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/11/abe.gif&quot; width=&quot;71&quot; height=&quot;108&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named abe.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/technology/4421707.stm&quot;&gt;BBC article about RSS&lt;/a&gt;, with extensive quotes from Yours Truly. It's a good piece, imho. &quot;Automated web surfing.&quot; It's so cool that they got a picture of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://seattlepi.nwsource.com/food/124839_dine04.html&quot;&gt;sushi belts&lt;/a&gt;. Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/04/11#a421&quot;&gt;place&lt;/a&gt; to comment." created="Mon, 11 Apr 2005 12:54:59 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://geeks.opml.org/2005/04/11#a10&quot;&gt;A new demo script&lt;/a&gt; for Frontier geeks that shows how to manage a huge dataset in an all-Frontier application." created="Mon, 11 Apr 2005 20:18:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Wow, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oreillynet.com/pub/a/network/2005/04/11/rsdp.html&quot;&gt;someone at O'Reilly&lt;/a&gt; has the Really Simple religion. Right on. " created="Tue, 12 Apr 2005 00:45:25 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/04/11/politics/11letter.html?ex=1270872000&amp;en=c229fbecc4aec5c6&amp;ei=5090&amp;partner=rssuserland&quot;&gt;NY Times&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Mr Bush has had his Apple iPod since July, when he received it from his twin daughters as a birthday gift. He has some 250 songs on it, a paltry number compared to the 10,000 selections it can hold.&quot;" created="Mon, 11 Apr 2005 18:31:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Clue: Someone ought to give him a TiVO." created="Mon, 11 Apr 2005 22:10:34 GMT"/>
				<outline text="A random observation. Today Google News found three articles that contained my name. &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/11/googlenews.gif&quot;&gt;Screen shot&lt;/a&gt;. One was the BBC article above, and the other two were on blogs. Their rules don't work, blogs get through. They're suckers for certain kinds of site names. It's Yahoo all over again, what a mess, so unweblike, back to gatekeepers. I know Google News is useful, I use it, but something is wrong about it." created="Mon, 11 Apr 2005 22:14:49 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podshows.com/&quot;&gt;Podshows&lt;/a&gt; are the future? Heh. Maybe. " created="Mon, 11 Apr 2005 19:14:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Okay, I'm stumped. Every XML parser I throw this &lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/notwellformedxml.xml&quot;&gt;file&lt;/a&gt; at says it's not well-formed, but I can't see the problem. If you see it, please send me an &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/dave/profiles/sendMail?usernum=1&amp;referer=http://www.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;. For extra credit, skip the ad hominems. &lt;i&gt;Postscript: Robert Sayre gets the prize, being first to find the problem; it &lt;i&gt;immediately&lt;/i&gt; revealed the programming error in my code. Runner-up to Gardner von Holt. These guys either have very good eyes and minds, or very good tools, or both. &lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 11 Apr 2005 15:10:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/04/08#a946&quot;&gt;Watch this space&lt;/a&gt; for an announcement, real soon now." created="Mon, 11 Apr 2005 09:12:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.starbucks.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/11/bucks.gif&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;65&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named bucks.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.micropersuasion.com/2005/04/has_the_rss_wag.html&quot;&gt;Steve Rubel asks&lt;/a&gt; if the RSS wagon has stalled and quotes me from our Starbuckian &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMar31.mp3&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; in NYC on March 31. I posted a comment stating a new theory: RSS is waiting for its killer app, one that will drive adoption by non-core geek types. I'm pretty sure I know some or all of the attributes of this app. No point describing it, people don't listen. Maybe I should raise the money to make it. Or maybe I've gotten too lazy? &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Mon, 11 Apr 2005 09:03:41 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/discuss/msgReader$839?mode=topic&quot;&gt;If you're shopping&lt;/a&gt; for an iPod alternative, the readers of Scripting News have some ideas for you." created="Mon, 11 Apr 2005 13:17:29 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2005/04/10.html#a9853&quot;&gt;Scoble is right&lt;/a&gt;, this Tiger Woods &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jaffejuice.com/2005/04/tiger_did_it_ak.html&quot;&gt;ace shot&lt;/a&gt; would make a great Nike commercial. I've mirrored the WMV &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/movies/justDidIt.wmv&quot;&gt;file&lt;/a&gt; on my unmetered server." created="Mon, 11 Apr 2005 07:53:56 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/11/pulitzerPhoto.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/11/iraqPollWorker.jpg&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;70&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named iraqPollWorker.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;NY Times: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/04/11/business/media/11photo.html?ex=1270872000&amp;en=bb8e6450d0d50164&amp;ei=5090&amp;partner=rssuserland&quot;&gt;Blogs Incensed over Pulitzer Photo Award&lt;/a&gt;. Could you imagine the Times running an article about negative letters to the editor?, but today there's an article about bloggers who aren't pleased with a choice for the Pulitzer Prize and the way the Times reported it. It's a vivid demo of the progress we've all made, the Times included. Now the former audience is part of the news, as it should be, and not as numbers in polls, but as people with ideas. The reporters and editors always were in the story, but didn't acknowledge it, now at least they admit it's possible. This article is interesting from so many angles. " created="Mon, 11 Apr 2005 07:19:53 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 10" created="Sun, 10 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.podbat.com/2005/04/10.html#a8&quot;&gt;Podbat has a new blog&lt;/a&gt;. This one looks semi-permanent. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Sun, 10 Apr 2005 23:55:20 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.zdnet.com/Gillmor/index.php?p=78&amp;part=rss&amp;tag=feed&amp;subj=zdblog&quot;&gt;Steve Gillmor&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Syndisphere.&quot;" created="Sun, 10 Apr 2005 21:46:42 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Me dumb. Me make mistake. Syndisphere is not a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.googlewhack.com/&quot;&gt;googlewhack&lt;/a&gt;. It is however, a term that &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/10/notAGoogleWhack.gif&quot;&gt;Google doesn't&lt;/a&gt; have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;q=syndisphere&quot;&gt;any hits&lt;/a&gt; for. And of course that will change. Steve Gillmor has the first use of this term which is certain to become part of the terminology of the Internet. " created="Sun, 10 Apr 2005 22:37:04 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2002/04/09#l6bf748b3c8e2c68c99d254617c111558&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/10/abe.gif&quot; width=&quot;75&quot; height=&quot;111&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named abe.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webpronews.com/news/ebusinessnews/wpn-45-20050410BloggersChancetoGetonOprah.html&quot;&gt;Steve Rubel&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;A couple of weeks ago I wrote an open letter to Oprah Winfrey encouraging her to invite bloggers on her show.&quot;" created="Sun, 10 Apr 2005 20:27:33 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2002/04/10&quot;&gt;Three years ago today&lt;/a&gt;, the NY Times and UserLand announced a deal that would lead to the Times' support of RSS. Here's the &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.scripting.com/2002/04/10/newYorkTimesAndUserland&quot;&gt;essay&lt;/a&gt; I wrote that day. This was clearly a milestone in the life of RSS and weblogs. " created="Sun, 10 Apr 2005 20:10:07 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gizmodo.com/gadgets/portable-media/archos/archos-av402-av700-and-gmini-xs-100-039243.php&quot;&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Could it be that Archos is going to release some products that aren't ugly?&quot;" created="Sun, 10 Apr 2005 15:48:13 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I've been playing with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://beta.exalead.com/search/C=0MlEAZXhhbGVhZAA%3d/?U=&amp;C=0MlEAZXhhbGVhZAA%3D&amp;2q=&amp;q=google&quot;&gt;French search engine&lt;/a&gt; called Exalead." created="Sun, 10 Apr 2005 16:36:58 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gigaom.com/2005/04/09/technorati-losing-its-way/&quot;&gt;Om Malik pulls&lt;/a&gt; links to several interesting stories about Technorati." created="Sun, 10 Apr 2005 09:47:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/10/dancerKeller.gif&quot; width=&quot;22&quot; height=&quot;22&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;Dancing Wes&quot;&gt;Every year on this day I say happy birthday to &lt;a href=&quot;http://wmf.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;Wes Felter&lt;/a&gt;, because (duh) April 10 is his birthday, #27 if I'm not mistaken. " created="Sun, 10 Apr 2005 20:03:34 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2005/04/10.html#a9849&quot;&gt;Scoble&lt;/a&gt;, maybe we should ask the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogherald.com/&quot;&gt;Blog Herald&lt;/a&gt;, which is already in Google News, to let us write an occasional piece for them. I'm not going to change the format of Scripting News for Google, that's just wrong. " created="Sun, 10 Apr 2005 10:13:13 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/dir/davesWorld/history/previousHeaderGraphics/coffeeCupAndFriends&quot;&gt;New header graphic&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Coffee cup and friends.&quot;" created="Sun, 10 Apr 2005 04:14:19 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 9" created="Sat, 09 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2003/04/09&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/09/saddam.jpg&quot; width=&quot;84&quot; height=&quot;124&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named saddam.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theage.com.au/news/Music/Welcome-to-the-wide-world-of-the-podosphere/2005/04/09/1112997222784.html?oneclick=true&quot;&gt;Here's a BigPub article&lt;/a&gt; about podcasting that gives credit to &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/lydon/&quot;&gt;Chris Lydon&lt;/a&gt; with an assist from me. That's closer to the truth that all the other articles. Chris did the interviews, with technical help from Bob Doyle, and I did the overall concept, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/blogs/audio/lydonRss.xml&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; and promotion. Those really were the first podcasts. I didn't write iPodder as they suggest, I wrote the aggregator in Radio, which iPodder is patterned after. " created="Sat, 09 Apr 2005 21:23:41 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/04/10/nyregion/10hillary.html?ex=1270785600&amp;en=a0b1bfb275f29177&amp;ei=5090&amp;partner=rssuserland&quot;&gt;NY Times&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Mr Finkelstein's personal life made headlines Saturday after he said he had married his longtime male partner in a civil ceremony in Massachusetts, a move that startled some of his associates, given his history with the Republican Party.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Hmmm.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Sat, 09 Apr 2005 20:46:30 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://essaysfromexodus.scripting.com/pictures/viewer$265&quot;&gt;A scene from&lt;/a&gt; my house in Woodside, on this &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2000/04/09&quot;&gt;day&lt;/a&gt; in Y2K. This might &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/09/coffeeCupAndFriends.jpg&quot;&gt;make&lt;/a&gt; a good header?" created="Sat, 09 Apr 2005 17:30:16 GMT"/>
				<outline text="There's a new &quot;fresh podcasts&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/#freshStuff&quot;&gt;box&lt;/a&gt; on podcatch.com, showing the ten newest casts from audio.weblogs.com. &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/09/freshCastsBox.gif&quot;&gt;Screen shot&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sat, 09 Apr 2005 16:15:48 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Dave Wilson, a NYC VC, &lt;a href=&quot;http://avc.blogs.com/a_vc/2005/04/its_the_feed_st.html&quot;&gt;recommends&lt;/a&gt; FeedBurner for RSS ads." created="Sat, 09 Apr 2005 13:01:21 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/events/SignalNoiseBBFINAL.pdf&quot;&gt;Practical Guide to Fair Use&lt;/a&gt;, written for non-lawyer consumption, by Christina Olson, a Harvard Law School student, via John Palfrey." created="Sat, 09 Apr 2005 10:46:04 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://stanforth.org/worldview/2005/20050408-west-wing-2.html&quot;&gt;John Stanforth&lt;/a&gt; on the West Wing of late. Warning, there are some spoilers in his writeup, which explains why the season finale was so satisfying. We're also grateful that the writers didn't hold the big decision till next year (that would have been awful) but did leave us a juicy tidbit to debate, which character is going to Federal prison for ten years. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Sat, 09 Apr 2005 10:29:11 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 8" created="Fri, 08 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Steve Rubel: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.micropersuasion.com/2005/04/65_local_tv_sta.html&quot;&gt;65 Local TV Stations Now RSS Enabled&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 08 Apr 2005 22:01:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Yahoo has feeds for &lt;a href=&quot;http://rss.movies.yahoo.com/dvd/topsellers.xml&quot;&gt;top-selling DVDs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://rss.movies.yahoo.com/dvd/newthisweek.xml&quot;&gt;new releases&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 08 Apr 2005 22:12:13 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/discuss/msgReader$105?mode=day&quot;&gt;A cold shower&lt;/a&gt; &quot;of reality&quot; from one Anne Onymous. Odeo has at least one friend, even though he or she doesn't have a name. " created="Sat, 09 Apr 2005 03:16:20 GMT"/>
				<outline text="RSS: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/04/08#a419&quot;&gt;When does it become a standard?&lt;/a&gt;" created="Sat, 09 Apr 2005 02:02:13 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.zdnet.com/Berlind/index.php?p=45&quot;&gt;David Berlind&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Have you given much thought to the formula you'll be using to add metadata into the ID3 tags that go along with your MP3 files?&quot;" created="Sat, 09 Apr 2005 00:05:21 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2003/04/08#When:11:39:39PM&quot;&gt;Two years ago&lt;/a&gt;, a late-season snow storm in Cambridge." created="Sat, 09 Apr 2005 00:02:22 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shreddies.org/gmaps/&quot;&gt;Google Sightseeing&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Why bother seeing the world for real?&quot;" created="Fri, 08 Apr 2005 23:47:04 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://weird-al-yankovic.lyrics-songs.com/lyrics/42663/&quot;&gt;Today's song&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Would you believe he had an eye infection?&quot;" created="Fri, 08 Apr 2005 23:44:48 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Ironically, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salon.com/books/int/2005/04/07/paglia/index.html&quot;&gt;Camille Paglia speaks&lt;/a&gt; hastily in Salon, saying that blogs are not written with care for the individual word. Thanks to Ed Cone for &lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0107946/2005/04/08.html#a3847&quot;&gt;calling her&lt;/a&gt; on that. " created="Fri, 08 Apr 2005 13:44:02 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/Columnists/Column/0,5673,1454932,00.html&quot;&gt;Polly Toynbee&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Genuflecting before this corpse is scarcely different to parading past Lenin: they both put extreme ideology before human life and happiness, at unimaginable human cost.&quot; Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.davosnewbies.com/2005/04/08#crueltyAndHypocrisyAtTheVatican&quot;&gt;DavosNewbies&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 08 Apr 2005 12:37:17 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/lydon/2003/08/18#a249&quot;&gt;Chris Lydon&lt;/a&gt; did a fantastic audio &lt;a href=&quot;http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/ml/output.pl/35410/download/toynbee.mp3&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with Polly Toynbee in August 2003, about the BBC, the war in Iraq. Quite timely with the British election coming up." created="Fri, 08 Apr 2005 12:39:41 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://essaysfromexodus.scripting.com/pictures/viewer$544&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/08/wisteria.jpg&quot; width=&quot;130&quot; height=&quot;130&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named wisteria.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;" created="Sat, 09 Apr 2005 00:03:39 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 7" created="Thu, 07 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/04/07#a38&quot;&gt;Feature/comparison chart for Odeo&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Now that we have an idea of what Odeo is, we can take a guess as to what the equivalent community tools are, and the open formats and protocols that are relevant.&quot;" created="Thu, 07 Apr 2005 12:06:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/movies/tornadoWatch.mov&quot;&gt;Tornado watch&lt;/a&gt; on the beach. It's even freakier than it looks." created="Thu, 07 Apr 2005 20:38:03 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scott.userland.com/2005/04/07.html#a424&quot;&gt;According to Scott Young&lt;/a&gt;, a new version of Manila is in the works." created="Thu, 07 Apr 2005 22:15:11 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/7422823/&quot;&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;'People are watching all over the world to determine whether a city of 135 square miles can become one big hot spot,' Philadelphia Mayor John Street told reporters.&quot;" created="Fri, 08 Apr 2005 01:38:42 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldwind.arc.nasa.gov/&quot;&gt;World Wind&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Zoom from satellite altitude into any place on Earth.&quot;" created="Thu, 07 Apr 2005 23:34:25 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The Encyclopedia Britannica &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.britannica.com/eb/dailycontent/rss&quot;&gt;supports RSS&lt;/a&gt;." category="/Technology/Formats and Protocols/RSS" created="Thu, 07 Apr 2005 19:52:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/07/zawodnyBig.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/07/zawodnySmall.gif&quot; width=&quot;57&quot; height=&quot;67&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named zawodnySmall.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.msmobiles.com/mobilephonefan/a/1341/daily-comic-strip-16.html&quot;&gt;Another comic strip&lt;/a&gt; from the MS Mobile Phone Fan, including yours truly, wondering why Yahoo doesn't listen to me. It also features &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremy.zawodny.com/blog/archives/004453.html&quot;&gt;Jeremy Zawodny&lt;/a&gt;. And for what it's worth, I don't think &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/03/23#moreAboutEvilornot&quot;&gt;Yahoo is evil&lt;/a&gt;, they're just a BigCo, hell-bent on world domination, or at least this part of it. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Thu, 07 Apr 2005 21:59:08 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.zdnet.com/Berlind/index.php?p=43&quot;&gt;David Berlind&lt;/a&gt;: What's a podcaster to do when his iPod breaks?" created="Thu, 07 Apr 2005 18:21:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I bought a cheap &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/07/128sa.jpg&quot;&gt;MP3 player&lt;/a&gt; at Target to hold me over. $50." created="Thu, 07 Apr 2005 18:11:03 GMT"/>
				<outline text="A fun German &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.people.freenet.de/duffysworld/april.html&quot;&gt;strip tease game&lt;/a&gt;. Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://paolo.evectors.it/2005/04/07.html#a2482&quot;&gt;Paolo&lt;/a&gt;." created="Thu, 07 Apr 2005 18:00:02 GMT"/>
				<outline text="CBS: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marketwatch.com/news/yhoo/story.asp?source=blq/yhoo&amp;siteid=yhoo&amp;dist=yhoo&amp;guid=%7B0A7BD02C%2D8282%2D4A25%2DAF45%2DCFA9824621CD%7D&quot;&gt;Microsoft claims 4.5 million bloggers&lt;/a&gt;." created="Thu, 07 Apr 2005 17:52:08 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blugg.opml.org/2005/04/07#a15&quot;&gt;Kosso&lt;/a&gt; has a link to an OPML file of all the BBC feeds." created="Thu, 07 Apr 2005 15:36:25 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/07/news-banana.gif&quot; width=&quot;33&quot; height=&quot;35&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;20&quot; vspace=&quot;8&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named news-banana.gif&quot;&gt;Last night's West Wing, the season finale, was excellent, confirming my belief that they have two crews that alternate, one awful, and the other fantastic. I don't want to spoil it for anyone who hasn't yet watched it, but it's great, full of emotion and surprise. Maybe in the end not so much surprise, but still..." created="Thu, 07 Apr 2005 15:01:26 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/entertainment/4419939.stm&quot;&gt;MTV announces&lt;/a&gt; an Internet &quot;channel.&quot; Now just link the new programs into an RSS 2.0 feed with enclosures and they're making history." created="Thu, 07 Apr 2005 11:16:48 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/news/culture/0,1284,67138,00.html&quot;&gt;Wired&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Lately, it seems like almost every time you tune into your favorite Blogger-hosted blog to catch up on the latest gossip, meme, political diatribe or cybersnark, you find that the site is frozen in time. Or, there are multiple posts with identical content.&quot;" created="Thu, 07 Apr 2005 10:54:22 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Om Malik: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gigaom.com/2005/04/05/six-million-and-one-paris-hilton-now-podcasting/&quot;&gt;Paris Hilton Now Podcasting&lt;/a&gt;." created="Thu, 07 Apr 2005 09:21:04 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/&quot;&gt;I started a site&lt;/a&gt; for discussion of new stuff in the podcasting community, and it's off to a great start. Thanks for all the good energy everybody!" created="Thu, 07 Apr 2005 08:47:08 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/07/dance34.gif&quot; width=&quot;164&quot; height=&quot;126&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Dancing Korean Leaders&quot;&gt;" created="Thu, 07 Apr 2005 22:07:05 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 6" created="Wed, 06 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/04/06#a4&quot;&gt;Notes on where&lt;/a&gt; we're at in podcasting. Comments are welcome." created="Wed, 06 Apr 2005 21:22:56 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Steven Erat, who works at Macromedia, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/discuss/msgReader$15?mode=day&quot;&gt;explains his experience&lt;/a&gt; with podcasting. At times like this I used to say &quot;bing!&quot; These are exciting times, you can see lights going on in a lot of new places. &lt;i&gt;Bing!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Thu, 07 Apr 2005 00:37:42 GMT"/>
				<outline text="iPodLounge &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipodlounge.com/ipodnews_comments.php?id=6872_0_7_0_C&quot;&gt;interviews&lt;/a&gt; Evan Williams about Odeo." created="Wed, 06 Apr 2005 20:40:11 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Telegraph: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.telegraph.co.uk/news/main.jhtml?xml=/news/2005/04/07/wcann07.xml&quot;&gt;Cannabis may stop heart disease&lt;/a&gt;." created="Thu, 07 Apr 2005 00:09:26 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Duncan Riley &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogherald.com/2005/04/06/yahoo-360-reviewed/&quot;&gt;reviews&lt;/a&gt; Yahoo 360." created="Wed, 06 Apr 2005 22:51:56 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/04/06#a7&quot;&gt;Sam Whitmore asks&lt;/a&gt; for ideas for a Forbes article about podcasting." created="Wed, 06 Apr 2005 22:35:29 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/06/davedl.gif&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;128&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named davedl.gif&quot;&gt;I got my Florida driver's license today. My old California license expires in a few weeks. The new one expires in 2011. Now there's a foreign concept. The eye test was interesting. You put your face against a pair of lenses. &quot;Read line five,&quot; said the examiner. I breathed a sigh of relief, I could read it. Two groups of five letters each. I read them aloud. The examiner asked if I could read the third group. I couldn't see a third group. She asked if I had any sight in my left eye at all. I explained that I did, but there was a big blurry spot in the middle. She checked a box and said I could only drive cars with a left-side mirror. No problemmo. Whew. " created="Wed, 06 Apr 2005 18:47:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2005/04/06.html#a9821&quot;&gt;Scoble&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The digital photography space continues to heat up.&quot;" created="Wed, 06 Apr 2005 17:33:25 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://simone.blogs.it/2005/04/02.html&quot;&gt;Simone Bettini&lt;/a&gt; is in Rome, &lt;a href=&quot;http://paolo.evectors.it/2005/04/06.html#a2480&quot;&gt;waiting&lt;/a&gt; in line to see PJPII." created="Wed, 06 Apr 2005 17:36:01 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.micropersuasion.com/2005/04/why_google_is_s.html&quot;&gt;Steve Rubel&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Feeds may be Google's greatest enemy.&quot;" created="Wed, 06 Apr 2005 17:19:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/philg/2005/04/06#a7981&quot;&gt;Greenspun&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;People pay $2 million for the privilege of living in an environment free of Republicans.&quot;" created="Wed, 06 Apr 2005 13:13:26 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconbeat.com/entries/2005/04/05/feedburner_raises_7_million_fills_coffers.html&quot;&gt;SJ Merc reports&lt;/a&gt; that Feedburner raised $7 million. " created="Wed, 06 Apr 2005 13:03:24 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/04/06/opinion/06wed1.html?ex=1270440000&amp;en=9afa8f77ac395949&amp;ei=5090&amp;partner=rssuserland&quot;&gt;NY Times editorial&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The Republicans' campaign against the judiciary hit rock bottom on Monday when Senator John Cornyn stood up in the chamber and excused violence.&quot;" created="Wed, 06 Apr 2005 10:20:56 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.faulkingtruth.com/Articles/Words/1021.html&quot;&gt;Today's song&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Big hat, no cattle. Big boat, no paddle.&quot;" created="Wed, 06 Apr 2005 13:15:20 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 5" created="Tue, 05 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.docuverse.com/blog/donpark/EntryViewPage.aspx?guid=6744e802-6a07-4507-b952-30cb40684928&quot;&gt;Don Park&lt;/a&gt; on Google's satellite maps. I'm reminded of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/online/story/0,3605,1448381,00.html&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; in the Guardian where they said Yahoo had captured Google's mojo. Heh. " created="Wed, 06 Apr 2005 01:15:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/04/05#a856&quot;&gt;Okay, I'm embarassed&lt;/a&gt; to admit that I've never been able to figure out how to create a new user on Windows 2000 or Windows 2003. " created="Wed, 06 Apr 2005 00:58:45 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Good howto &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.windowsdevcenter.com/pub/a/windows/2005/04/05/create_podcasts_with_pc.html&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; on podcasting at O'Reilly." created="Tue, 05 Apr 2005 23:27:37 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnn.com/2005/SHOWBIZ/books/04/05/hunter.thompson.ap/index.html?section=cnn_topstories&quot;&gt;AP&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Hunter S Thompson's ashes will be blasted from a cannon mounted inside a 53-foot-high sculpture of the journalist's 'gonzo fist' emblem.&quot;" created="Tue, 05 Apr 2005 23:25:05 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/05/koolaid.gif&quot; width=&quot;97&quot; height=&quot;126&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named koolaid.gif&quot;&gt;It's time for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/04/05#a839&quot;&gt;new MP3 player&lt;/a&gt; for Uncle Davey." created="Tue, 05 Apr 2005 20:44:22 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Really weird, my Yahoo 360 photo was rejected. So I looked up the rules. It can't be more than 3MB, it has to be a JPEG and it can't be porn. Feh. I tried resubmitting and it was accepted. " created="Tue, 05 Apr 2005 21:07:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/04/02#When:5:28:45PM&quot;&gt;My endless infomercial bit&lt;/a&gt; has gotten a lot of pick-up, the latest being Howard Kurtz's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/nation/columns/kurtzhoward/&quot;&gt;column&lt;/a&gt; in the Washington Post. He even included the sarcastic swipe at pro-jos. &quot;Now would be a great opportunity for some of the real reporting the pros are so famous for.&quot; Good work." created="Tue, 05 Apr 2005 17:11:48 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.engadget.com/entry/1234000677038935/&quot;&gt;Engadget reports&lt;/a&gt; what everyone who heard the Pew report knows -- they inflated the number of people listening to podcasts. " created="Tue, 05 Apr 2005 14:52:50 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Congratulations to the University of North Carolina basketball team, the Tarheels, who won the national championship last night. I didn't watch the game, college basketball isn't my thing, but I spent a fun week with the bloggas of the Piedmont in February. Yay Tarheels. Go team!" created="Tue, 05 Apr 2005 12:32:12 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://dictionary.reference.com/search?q=tarheel&quot;&gt;Tarheel&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;A native or resident of North Carolina.&quot;" created="Tue, 05 Apr 2005 12:34:05 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/technology/4412125.stm&quot;&gt;According to the BBC&lt;/a&gt; and others Google is starting a video-blogging service, where they store and serve the video (or so it seems) index it, or create transcripts. It's set to launch in the next few days. It would be great if they offered free storage and bandwidth for audio as well." created="Tue, 05 Apr 2005 12:19:57 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/04/04#a661&quot;&gt;Yesterday I offered to invite people&lt;/a&gt; who requested invites to Yahoo 360 until I ran out. Apparently you don't run out. There is a limit of 100 outstanding invites, but as soon as one accepts an invite you can invite another. My balance hasn't dipped below 50. So now the limiting factor is my ability to do the clerical &lt;a href=&quot;http://message.360.yahoo.com/invites/compose.html&quot;&gt;work&lt;/a&gt; to process the requests for invites. I've already processed more than 100. " created="Tue, 05 Apr 2005 12:27:35 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 4" created="Mon, 04 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Today is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.scripting.com/2002/04/04/fourYearsOfXmlrpc&quot;&gt;seventh birthday&lt;/a&gt; of XML-RPC." created="Tue, 05 Apr 2005 01:23:37 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.scripting.com/2001/04/04/aBusyDevelopersGuideToSoap11&quot;&gt;Four years ago&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Keep your interfaces where we can see them.&quot;" created="Tue, 05 Apr 2005 01:21:49 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://nytimes.blogrunner.com/annotated/nytimes.com/about.html&quot;&gt;The Annotated New York Times&lt;/a&gt; tracks &quot;blog postings that cite articles published by The New York Times.&quot; Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.micropersuasion.com/2005/04/blog_puts_the_n.html&quot;&gt;Steve Rubel&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 05 Apr 2005 00:17:02 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boston.com/business/articles/2005/04/02/groove_backers_left_short/&quot;&gt;According to the Boston Globe&lt;/a&gt;, Microsoft paid $120 million for Groove. " created="Mon, 04 Apr 2005 22:52:47 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thetwowayweb.com/2005/04/04#a602&quot;&gt;2WW&lt;/a&gt;: I applied to have Scripting News included in Google News, and got the rejection notice earlier today. " created="Mon, 04 Apr 2005 17:26:58 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/04/ibmpc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;85&quot; height=&quot;84&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;20&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named ibmpc.jpg&quot;&gt;I'm living in a new place as of yesterday, an apartment, the first time I've lived in one in a long time. It's on the first floor. Above me is a family with a kid. They seem to be moving furniture all the time. I have a hard time imagining how people could spend so much time moving furniture. Me, I never move furniture, except perhaps when I'm getting up from a desk or a dining table, when I push the chair back. But that's it. Otherwise I accept furniture location as-is. I'm not a control freak about furniture location, as my upstairs neighbors appear to be. " created="Mon, 04 Apr 2005 17:51:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/misc/emailSubscribe&quot;&gt;The overnight emails&lt;/a&gt; haven't been going out for some time, not sure how long. Just a configuration problem oin the server. I'm going to have to keep my eye on this one. In the meantime, sorry that the people who read Scripting News via email have missed some of the new stuff. " created="Mon, 04 Apr 2005 16:26:57 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremy.zawodny.com/blog/archives/004414.html&quot;&gt;Jeremy Zawodny says&lt;/a&gt; he's out of invites for Yahoo 360, but I'm not. Post a comment &lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/04/04#a661&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and I'll send out invites until I run out. " created="Mon, 04 Apr 2005 16:48:28 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.soxaholix.com/tp/2005/04/is_that_a_casab.html&quot;&gt;Soxaholix&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Even in his final barely alive days, JP2 was more animated than the lifeless Red Sox last night.&quot;" created="Mon, 04 Apr 2005 15:51:25 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://accordionguy.blogware.com/blog/_archives/2005/4/4/552277.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/04/fox.jpg&quot; width=&quot;45&quot; height=&quot;48&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named fox.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gizmodo.com/gadgets/announcements/were-hiring-an-editor-038020.php&quot;&gt;Gizmodo is hiring an editor&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;...a person who knows gadgetry in specific and technology in general like the back of their hand, can write their way out of a paper bag, and is full of excitement about working for an editor who is increasingly fed up with the pointless tail-chasing and money-grubbing hypocrisy of the worldwide technology market.&quot;" created="Mon, 04 Apr 2005 14:01:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.docuverse.com/blog/donpark/EntryViewPage.aspx?guid=1d1a9515-0b24-4368-99fe-ec373b65c34e&quot;&gt;Don Park&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;10 days since I quit smoking.&quot;" created="Mon, 04 Apr 2005 14:04:26 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://paolo.evectors.it/2005/04/04.html#a2475&quot;&gt;Paolo Valdemarin&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Podcasting is not for me.&quot;" created="Mon, 04 Apr 2005 14:17:48 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.megnut.com/2005/04/soon-to-be-even-more-french&quot;&gt;Megnut&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I look for a phone card not to put in the phone but to press the numbers on the phone to use.&quot;" created="Mon, 04 Apr 2005 14:06:24 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 3" created="Sun, 03 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pewinternet.org/pdfs/PIP_podcasting.pdf&quot;&gt;Pew Internet&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;6 million American adults have listened to podcasts.&quot;" created="Mon, 04 Apr 2005 01:29:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnApr3.mp3&quot;&gt;Today's Morning Coffee Notes&lt;/a&gt; is an interview with Florida neighbor and author Jerry Vass, marketing guru, future blogger and podcaster. " created="Sun, 03 Apr 2005 19:01:06 GMT" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnApr3.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rexblog.com/2005/04/03#a6362&quot;&gt;Rex Hammock&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;There's art hanging in the Louvre and art hanging on my refrigerator. There's photography on the cover of Vogue and in my iPhoto library and films that win Oscars and videos of babies learning to crawl.&quot;" created="Sun, 03 Apr 2005 19:20:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I certainly make my share of enemies (that's one of my &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/04/02#When:5:23:46PM&quot;&gt;goals&lt;/a&gt;, after all) but I do have &lt;a href=&quot;http://alexanders.typepad.com/thinksum/2005/04/april_fools_win.html&quot;&gt;some fans&lt;/a&gt; too. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Sun, 03 Apr 2005 19:37:34 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Speaking of making enemies, is it just me or is anyone else suspicious of a supposedly &lt;a href=&quot;http://battellemedia.com/archives/001390.php&quot;&gt;independent analyst&lt;/a&gt; who refers to the CEO of Google as Eric. Any chance of some footsie going on here?" created="Sun, 03 Apr 2005 19:49:59 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.petersons.com/podcasts/&quot;&gt;Peterson's&lt;/a&gt;, the college guide company, has gotten into podcasting." created="Sun, 03 Apr 2005 13:42:50 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://yakushitsu.blogspot.com/2005/04/why-i-read-dave-winers-posts.html&quot;&gt;Koan Bremner&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;A good measure of a person's contribution to a debate is less the friends he keeps, and more the enemies he makes:&quot;" created="Sun, 03 Apr 2005 13:39:47 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/03/heh.gif&quot;&gt;It's pretty funny&lt;/a&gt;, after all the attempts to trick Google into putting relevant ads on audio.weblogs.com, they decide it's about astronomy because the word &quot;universe&quot; appears in the page title. It may be time to give up. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Sun, 03 Apr 2005 13:54:24 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/dir/davesWorld/history/previousHeaderGraphics/britishColumbiaMountains&quot;&gt;New header graphic&lt;/a&gt;. Mountains in British Columbia." created="Sun, 03 Apr 2005 14:04:46 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The Accoridon Guy has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://accordionguy.blogware.com/blog/_archives/2005/4/3/548667.html&quot;&gt;great pic&lt;/a&gt; of PJPII." created="Sun, 03 Apr 2005 14:10:33 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 2" created="Sat, 02 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="BBC: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/world/europe/4399715.stm&quot;&gt;Pope John Paul II dead at 84&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sat, 02 Apr 2005 22:22:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2005/04/02.html#a9799&quot;&gt;Scoble&lt;/a&gt; is a man of respect. &quot;My co-author Shel Israel gave me heck for being too nice to my fellow bloggers.&quot; Right on. Too much footsie in the blogosphere. Enough. Just the facts please. Enough telling me about your friends. Make some new enemies for a change. " created="Sat, 02 Apr 2005 22:23:46 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/02/thepope.gif&quot; width=&quot;75&quot; height=&quot;88&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named thepope.gif&quot;&gt;Listening to the endless radio &quot;coverage&quot; of the Pope's death, it's remarkable how unbalanced it is. They have priests, saying we all know deep inside the Pope was right about everything. Hello. Earth to Catholics. The Pope was a good PR guy, but come on, he was &lt;i&gt;against birth control.&lt;/i&gt; The Catholics actually burned condoms in AIDS-plagued Africa. Now would be a great opportunity for some of the real reporting the pros are so famous for. Instead they're running an endless infomercial for the Catholic Church. Hey the Catholics are the church of sin and hell, fire and brimstone. If ever there were an opportunity to be balanced this is it. No more footsie? Heh, yeah sure. " created="Sat, 02 Apr 2005 22:28:45 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rexblog.com/2005/04/02#a6357&quot;&gt;Rex Hammock&lt;/a&gt; isn't playing footsie. &quot;Do I really need all that crap portalized?&quot; Tell it like it is bro." created="Sat, 02 Apr 2005 22:32:33 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/entry/2005/04/02.html#2532&quot;&gt;Rogers Cadenhead&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Every time commercial developers create an innovative new software category, as Netscape, UserLand Software and Pyra Labs did in weblogging and syndication, open source coders follow behind with software that makes it harder to earn a living in that niche.&quot;" created="Sat, 02 Apr 2005 22:35:16 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.darrenbarefoot.com/archives/002518.html&quot;&gt;Why&lt;/a&gt; Darren Barefoot isn't smoking the podcasting dope. " created="Sat, 02 Apr 2005 21:54:24 GMT"/>
				<outline text="5PM Eastern: I've arrived safely back at the beach in Florida. Had a great time in NYC, look forward to going back soon. " created="Sat, 02 Apr 2005 21:48:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://fury.com/article/2122.php&quot;&gt;Kevin Fox&lt;/a&gt; on a Ben Hammersley &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/online/story/0,3605,1448381,00.html&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; in the Guardian. &quot;The trouble is that his datapoints are pretty selective, and in some cases are flat-out incorrect.&quot; " created="Sat, 02 Apr 2005 12:46:40 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Reviewing the Yahoo 360 launch, after the fact" created="Sat, 02 Apr 2005 10:48:07 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/03/29#yahoo360ShowsUpSorta&quot;&gt;The launch&lt;/a&gt; of Yahoo 360 seems so long ago, but it was just six days. How did it go? This &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.makeyougohmm.com/20050330/1639/&quot;&gt;screed&lt;/a&gt; nails it. Invite-only, exclusive, two-tier marketing of beta services, a tradition started by Google (as far as anyone knows) don't work. It only worked for Gmail because there was great anticipation, the idea was new (the method of marketing, that is), and you could use Gmail to communicate with people who didn't use Gmail. " created="Sat, 02 Apr 2005 10:43:13 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Everything about &lt;a href=&quot;http://360.yahoo.com/&quot;&gt;Yahoo 360&lt;/a&gt; is for members only, and in the first few hours of its life in the blogosphere, &lt;i&gt;most people couldn't get in.&lt;/i&gt; Now, after it's launched, there's no way to see anything other than a ghost town. Maybe that's all there is, maybe not. But for a service like this, the appearance of being a ghost town is just as bad as actually being one. " created="Sat, 02 Apr 2005 10:49:20 GMT"/>
					<outline text="All this fuss for a service that most people thought was a poor cousin to Flickr that &lt;i&gt;Yahoo bought&lt;/i&gt; just before rolling out 360. It's a disaster epic on the scale of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0072308/&quot;&gt;The Towering Inferno&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0069113/&quot;&gt;The Poseidon Adventure&lt;/a&gt;. They did everything wrong, and worked really hard at it." created="Sat, 02 Apr 2005 10:50:12 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/02/toweringposter.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/02/toweringinferno.gif&quot; width=&quot;125&quot; height=&quot;66&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named toweringinferno.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Moral of the story, big companies don't have mojo, they can't, and it's not fair to make that the issue. They can, however, make the trains run on time, and at that Yahoo does quite well. But they should leave the innovation to small, nimble, motivated devteams with nothing to lose and no corporate hierarchy to please. Hire a business school prof to do a case study for you. It's never worked differently in Silicon Valley, yet this is a lesson Silicon Valley keeps relearning. The next revolution isn't on stage at Esther's or SXSW or even Etech -- those were the &lt;i&gt;last&lt;/i&gt; revolutions. " created="Sat, 02 Apr 2005 10:50:45 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 1" created="Fri, 01 Apr 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Yet another New York coffee notes &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnApr1.mp3&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt;, this one with Kosso, live from the bar in the Millenium UN Plaza Hotel. Tools for creating podcast feeds in Flash, and lots of other random stuff. Goofy and technical." created="Fri, 01 Apr 2005 16:35:39 GMT" name="yetAnotherNewYorkCoffeeNotesAHrefhttpmp3morningcoffeenotescomcnapr1mp3podcastaThisOneWithKossoLiveFromTheBarInTheMilleniumUnPlazaHotelToolsForCreatingPodcastFeedsInFlashAndLotsOfOtherRandomStuffGoofyAndTechnical" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnApr1.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/04/01#a391&quot;&gt;An open letter&lt;/a&gt; to everyone about everything that matters." created="Fri, 01 Apr 2005 20:53:41 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/googlegulp/faq.html#5&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;You mean we should cripple a perfectly useful feature just because of a little bad PR?&quot;" created="Fri, 01 Apr 2005 20:19:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://rawstory.com/exclusives/byrne/lautenberg_letter_delay_schiavo_401.htm&quot;&gt;According to The Raw Story&lt;/a&gt;, Senator Frank Lautenberg (D-NJ) sent a &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/01/lautenbergLetterToDeLay.gif&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/a&gt; to Tom DeLay saying his comments about judges in the Schiavo case may violate Federal criminal law. Not an April Fool joke." created="Fri, 01 Apr 2005 18:58:45 GMT"/>
				<outline text="New York Newsday &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newsday.com/news/ny-rss.htmlstory&quot;&gt;supports RSS&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 01 Apr 2005 14:15:21 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://spaces.msn.com/members/siteexperts/PersonalSpace.aspx&quot;&gt;Scott Isaacs&lt;/a&gt;, an architect at Microsoft, explains the new weblogs.com &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/msn/&quot;&gt;listing&lt;/a&gt; for MSN Spaces. For me, it's fascinating to watch the idea percolate through the Spaces community. This kind of &quot;anchor&quot; page is an essential part of the bootstrap of a blogging community." created="Fri, 01 Apr 2005 14:16:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/04/01#kosso&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/04/01/kosso.jpg&quot; width=&quot;45&quot; height=&quot;54&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;20&quot; vspace=&quot;8&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named kosso.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/04/01#a650&quot;&gt;Pictures&lt;/a&gt; from last night's dinner with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kosso.com/&quot;&gt;Kosso&lt;/a&gt; at the 2nd Avenue Deli. He's the Flash podcasting guy from the BBC, who just happened to be in NY this week. While we were hanging out in front of the Starbucks on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.yahoo.com/maps_result?ed=4Ewyy.p_0Tp2czGi25dKAIVBWPdgsbqPlZOg&amp;csz=New+york%2C+ny&amp;country=us&amp;new=1&amp;name=&amp;qty=&quot;&gt;corner&lt;/a&gt; of 2nd Ave and 9th St, a woman on a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.segway.com/&quot;&gt;Segway&lt;/a&gt; pulled up to the red light, waited for it to change and then continued downtown. Makes kind of an interesting &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/movies/secondAvenueSegway.mov&quot;&gt;movie&lt;/a&gt;, I thought." created="Fri, 01 Apr 2005 09:59:44 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Anniversaries" created="Fri, 01 Apr 2005 09:26:38 GMT">
					<outline text="Today is April Fool's Day, so look out for some laughs." created="Fri, 01 Apr 2005 09:26:42 GMT"/>
					<outline text="But in all seriousness, today is also the birthday of two of my creations, Scripting News and Frontier." created="Fri, 01 Apr 2005 09:26:55 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Frontier was started in April 1988, 17 years ago. If it were a human being, it would be well into puberty, capable of reproducing, driving a car, getting ready to leave home. It's appropriate that in its 17th year it gained its &lt;a href=&quot;http://kernel.scripting.com/2004/09/28#a20&quot;&gt;independence&lt;/a&gt; in a formal way, being licensed under the GPL, and is now ready for anything the universe wants to do with it." created="Fri, 01 Apr 2005 09:33:30 GMT"/>
					<outline text="On this &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/1997/04/01&quot;&gt;day&lt;/a&gt; in 1997 I did my first weblog post at www.scripting.com. 8 years is a long &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/dir/davesWorld/onThisDayIn&quot;&gt;run&lt;/a&gt; for a weblog. Scripting News was the inspiration for many of the mainstays of the blogging world, and they in turn inspired others, and on and on. This has been the template for growth, and it's a good one. Every new blog begets more new blogs. That mine was the root for so many is the accomplishment I'm most proud of. " created="Fri, 01 Apr 2005 09:29:28 GMT"/>
					<outline text="So Year Nine begins. A little older, perhaps a little wiser? Let's have fun, still diggin, and namaste y'all!" created="Fri, 01 Apr 2005 09:32:18 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Cory Doctorow responds" created="Fri, 01 Apr 2005 09:15:24 GMT">
					<outline text="I got an email from Cory Doctorow saying that my theoretical republishing of his book -- giving myself authorship credit, offering it for sale, and seeking distribution -- would be &quot;fraudulent.&quot; So we know that Cory has a line. We're making progress. (Note I'm not going to publish his email, he can do that if he likes, and I'd like it if he would.)" created="Fri, 01 Apr 2005 09:01:48 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Now, as I've said so many times (one more time won't hurt), I don't like it when a big heartless company takes my work and modifies it in a way that makes it hard to tell what they wrote and what I wrote. I'm concerned that if I let this company do it, then another company is going to, and another and pretty soon they're going to be competing on the basis of how &quot;useful&quot; they make my work, again without my permission, and with no compensation to me. I'm concerned that they may make changes I don't agree with, or even worse, change the meaning of what I wrote so as to confuse people about what I think. I quit working for a big publication because they were doing this, I went independent so my writing could have integrity, so it could truly represent what I think, to the best of my ability. Cory, Google crossed &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; line. To use your terminology, they're doing something fraudulent by passing off their derivative work as mine. " created="Fri, 01 Apr 2005 09:09:57 GMT"/>
					<outline text="BTW, I say &quot;I think,&quot; when stating an opinion. Cory and his colleagues (who mostly are not lawyers) state their legal opinion as fact. He also says &quot;As you know&quot; before saying something that I don't even agree with. That's just plain disrespectful, and makes discourse more difficult." created="Fri, 01 Apr 2005 09:14:50 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			</outline>
		</body>
	</opml>
