<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- OPML generated by OPML Editor v10.1b19 on Wed, 22 Dec 2021 16:02:12 GMT -->
<opml version="2.0">
	<head>
		<title>Scripting News</title>
		<dateCreated>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 16:02:08 GMT</dateCreated>
		<dateModified>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 16:02:12 GMT</dateModified>
		<ownerName>Dave Winer</ownerName>
		<ownerId>http://davewiner.com/</ownerId>
		<expansionState>1</expansionState>
		<vertScrollState>1</vertScrollState>
		<windowTop>631</windowTop>
		<windowLeft>1087</windowLeft>
		<windowBottom>831</windowBottom>
		<windowRight>1472</windowRight>
		</head>
	<body>
		<outline text="May 2005" created="Sun, 01 May 2005 05:00:02 GMT">
			<outline text="May 31" created="Tue, 31 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="9:15PM Eastern: Arrived at the beach. Tired. " created="Wed, 01 Jun 2005 01:15:56 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cinematical.com/2005/05/30/love-cinematical-style/&quot;&gt;The idea&lt;/a&gt; of using Netflix data to get a date is getting some play. " created="Wed, 01 Jun 2005 01:14:10 GMT"/>
				<outline text="5:45PM Eastern: Arrived safely in Orlando. Using the free wifi in the airport while waiting for baggage. Very civilized. Boston take note." created="Tue, 31 May 2005 21:48:06 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lessig.org/blog/archives/002926.shtml&quot;&gt;Larry Lessig&lt;/a&gt; on amateurism." created="Tue, 31 May 2005 21:49:29 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://politicalwire.com/archives/2005/05/31/deep_throat_revealed.html&quot;&gt;More&lt;/a&gt; on Deep Throat from Taegan Goddard." created="Tue, 31 May 2005 21:50:44 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Good afternoon. I'm checked in at Boston's Logan Airport, gate B32, using their wifi service which costs $7.95 for the day. " created="Tue, 31 May 2005 16:52:18 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Reuters: &lt;a href=&quot;http://today.reuters.co.uk/news/newsArticle.aspx?type=worldNews&amp;storyID=2005-05-31T155626Z_01_SPI157357_RTRUKOC_0_LIFE-DEEPTHROAT.xml&quot;&gt;Ex-FBI man claims to be Deep Throat&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 31 May 2005 18:16:22 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Today's a travel day, so light posting. See you in Florida. " created="Tue, 31 May 2005 15:31:47 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.radioopensource.org/2005/05/27/web-20/&quot;&gt;The discussion&lt;/a&gt; for last night's radio show." created="Tue, 31 May 2005 15:33:39 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Just got a call from my insurance agent in Florida. No need to tell him I'm in Boston. Then the phone rings from someone in Boston. On my morning walk through Cambridge (temp 51F) I had the Billboard Top 100 from 1967, and let me say these are the songs that meant the most to me, programmed my brain about culture and love at the tender age of 12. Best song so far, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.songfacts.com/detail.lasso?id=1623&quot;&gt;Ode to Billie Joe&lt;/a&gt; by Bobbie Gentry." created="Tue, 31 May 2005 13:23:15 GMT"/>
				<outline text="It's hard to explain this &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.podbat.com/2005/05/30.html#a86&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; from Kosso, so please, just read it. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Tue, 31 May 2005 12:03:53 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Charlie Nesson is the guy who talked about Socrates, and by coincidence, John Palfrey sent a link to his &lt;a href=&quot;http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/nesson/blog/&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; shortly after I posted the link to Kosso's post, about Betsy Devine, The Balloon Man, and some guy who said I was like Socrates." created="Tue, 31 May 2005 12:12:41 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 30" created="Mon, 30 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wgbh.org/program-info?program_id=2271985&quot;&gt;WGBH at 7PM Eastern&lt;/a&gt; -- the inaugural airing of Chris Lydon's Open Source. 89.7 FM. Guests are David Weinberger, Doc Searls and yours truly. If you're not in the Boston area, please &lt;a href=&quot;http://streams.wgbh.org/wgbh/&quot;&gt;tune in&lt;/a&gt; to the webcast. " created="Mon, 30 May 2005 21:46:02 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/misc/radioOpenSource1.mp3&quot;&gt;Kosso recorded&lt;/a&gt; tonight's show. Best line: &quot;Revenge of the sources.&quot;" created="Tue, 31 May 2005 02:49:34 GMT" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/misc/radioOpenSource1.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay30.mp3&quot;&gt;A breakfast podcast&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;http://betsydevine.weblogger.com/&quot;&gt;Betsy Devine&lt;/a&gt; in Cambridge, we sing, and she enjoys being Mr Jennifer Lopez. " created="Mon, 30 May 2005 14:12:02 GMT" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay30.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/movies/betsyDevine.mov&quot;&gt;Betsy explains&lt;/a&gt;, in a movie. why people at Google, now that they're a huge company, do things that are not consistent with the values of early Google. Same is true at every other big tech company, maybe all big companies in every industry." created="Mon, 30 May 2005 14:14:07 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay30a.mp3&quot;&gt;A brief conversation&lt;/a&gt; with John Palfrey and Jim Moore who are starting an investment fund for RSS-related ventures. " created="Mon, 30 May 2005 18:33:52 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/movies/charlesRiverTaxiRide.mov&quot;&gt;A movie taken&lt;/a&gt; out the window of a speeding cab of the Charles River from Memorial Drive." created="Mon, 30 May 2005 18:22:35 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/05/30#a300&quot;&gt;I wonder if Netflix&lt;/a&gt; has ever thought of partnering with Match.com to connect people who like the same kind of movies? I suppose Barnes &amp; Noble could do something similar. Maybe therein lies a business model for podcasting. " created="Mon, 30 May 2005 10:41:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/20/ohYeahhhh.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/30/ohYeahhhhSmall.gif&quot; width=&quot;85&quot; height=&quot;91&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named ohYeahhhhSmall.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.zdnet.com/Gillmor/&quot;&gt;To Steve Gillmor&lt;/a&gt;, the constant evangelist for &quot;attention&quot; -- Netflix is in your corner, they actually publish attention data, today, not at some time in the future. If Match.com wanted to provide a service such as the one I described &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/05/30#When:6:41:31AM&quot;&gt;above&lt;/a&gt;, they wouldn't need to actually do a deal with Netflix, they already publish the data on a per-user basis, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.netflix.com/RSSFeeds&quot;&gt;they do it in XML&lt;/a&gt; (your favorite &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/&quot;&gt;format&lt;/a&gt; by the way). So Match could provide a place for you to enter your Netflix user id, and they could go get the data and use it in their matching algorithm. How about that!  BTW, so much for Dave Sifry's plan to invent a new format here. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Mon, 30 May 2005 11:42:01 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2001/05/30&quot;&gt;Four years ago&lt;/a&gt;: &quot; I thought my father was a weird guy, but it turns out he was just European.&quot;" created="Mon, 30 May 2005 10:43:06 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I've been playing around with Blogger on and and off, and was surprised to find out after all this time that they don't have an easy way to edit a blogroll. They &lt;a href=&quot;http://help.blogger.com/bin/answer.py?answer=110&quot;&gt;recommend&lt;/a&gt; by-hand editing of HTML lists. " created="Mon, 30 May 2005 04:03:51 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Two years ago: &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/whatMakesAWeblogAWeblog&quot;&gt;What makes a weblog a weblog?&lt;/a&gt;" created="Mon, 30 May 2005 10:45:15 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/30/NY2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/30/richie.jpg&quot; width=&quot;45&quot; height=&quot;70&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named richie.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I was flipping channels last night and caught a profile of R&amp;B star &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lionelrichie.com/biography1.html&quot;&gt;Lionel Richie&lt;/a&gt;, talking about what it's like to write a song. He says sometimes he's searching for the line that ties all the elements of a song together, he could be searching for weeks, and then it hits him like a thunderbolt -- &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/30/whatIsAMindBomb.gif&quot;&gt;boom&lt;/a&gt; -- mind bomb, that's &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/lyrics/allNightLong.txt&quot;&gt;it&lt;/a&gt;, and he can move on to the next project. Then I wondered if he actually wrote the songs, was he describing what it's like to have an idea, or what he &lt;i&gt;thought&lt;/i&gt; it would be like if he ever actually had one. I have no idea if Richie is a creative guy or if he pays people to be creative, or if he rips people off and says their creativity is his without paying. " created="Mon, 30 May 2005 11:06:33 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 29" created="Sun, 29 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/05/29#a1142&quot;&gt;Two buildings&lt;/a&gt;, one old and one new, are just a couple of blocks apart in Cambridge, MA." created="Mon, 30 May 2005 00:22:40 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/movies/walkingMovieCambridge.mov&quot;&gt;I took this movie&lt;/a&gt; holding the camera by my side while walking. Maybe it would be more colorful if there wasn't so much brick wall, more natural scenery? Hmmm." created="Mon, 30 May 2005 00:34:17 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/entry/2005/05/29#2613&quot;&gt;Rogers Cadenhead&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Mark Pursey has become the sixth member of the Creative Commons Choir, the asynchronous podcasting singing group that's now one-sixtieth as large as the Mormon Tabernacle Choir.&quot;" created="Sun, 29 May 2005 19:38:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="CBC does &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cbc.ca/podcasting/&quot;&gt;podcasts&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 29 May 2005 12:44:53 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/05/29#a292&quot;&gt;Central Florida&lt;/a&gt; podcast meetup in Gainesville?" created="Sun, 29 May 2005 13:47:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.time.com/time/magazine/article/0,9171,1066904,00.html?promoid=rss_top&quot;&gt;Time&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The wiki genie is out of the bottle.&quot;" created="Sun, 29 May 2005 23:12:49 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mrgutman.blogspot.com/2005/05/dating-terminology.html&quot;&gt;Mr. Gutman&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Once again a post on Halley Suitt's blog provides an opportunity for insightful social comment by Mr. Gutman.&quot;" created="Sun, 29 May 2005 22:21:17 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/amyGreenAcres.mp3&quot;&gt;Amy Bellinger&lt;/a&gt; joins me in a Green Acres duet. You &lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/greenAcres.mp3&quot;&gt;can do it&lt;/a&gt; too, you don't even have to be a woman. I have a &lt;s&gt;nightmare&lt;/s&gt; dream that Madge Weinstein will do one. What about Dawn? Lisa Williams? Sylvia Paull? Halley Suitt? Burning Bird? The hits keep coming. Heh." created="Sun, 29 May 2005 12:16:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Ted Turner to Dan Schorr, as recalled by Dan Schorr: &quot;I forget, are you mad at me, or am I mad at you?&quot;" created="Sun, 29 May 2005 12:23:42 GMT"/>
				<outline text="A BitTorrent &lt;a href=&quot;http://w1.isohunt.com/&quot;&gt;search engine&lt;/a&gt; that supports RSS. Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://w3.isohunt.com/js/rss.php?ihq=billboard&amp;op=and&amp;iht=-1&amp;nr&quot;&gt;feed&lt;/a&gt; that shows new downloads that have the word &lt;i&gt;Billboard&lt;/i&gt; in their descriptions." created="Sun, 29 May 2005 12:06:55 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I'm listening to Weekend Edition on WBUR. The soundbites don't change, and the memories come back. I had a good time here in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rssweather.com/hw3.php?pands=cambridge%2Cma&quot;&gt;Cambridge&lt;/a&gt;. The memories are good." created="Sun, 29 May 2005 13:40:00 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 28" created="Sat, 28 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Good evening (7PM Eastern) from Cambridge, MA. " created="Sat, 28 May 2005 22:56:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0100368/2005/05/28.html&quot;&gt;Harold Gilchrist asks&lt;/a&gt; a good question. I wonder what the iPodder devs think?" created="Sat, 28 May 2005 23:21:21 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/28/bigbozo.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/28/bozo.jpg&quot; width=&quot;45&quot; height=&quot;61&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named bozo.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I just checked my email and then caught my  breath and guess what, there's a thunderstorm brewing. Do I have the energy to do a podcast? Hmmm. Speaking of podcasts, I caught the first &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.gillmorgang.podshow.com/GillmorGang-2005.05.28.mp3&quot;&gt;new Gillmor Gang&lt;/a&gt; in three months. Doc was great, so was Jon Udell and all the other gangsters were just perfect. Best line came at the end, Doc talking about ri ding up the roller coaster. Yeah. Looking forward to tuning in every week. BTW, the length was perfect for a flight from Pittsburgh to Boston. It finished shortly before they told us to turn off all electronics. " created="Sat, 28 May 2005 23:01:17 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Good afternoon (1PM Eastern) from Pittsburgh International Airport, where they also have very strong, free wifi. Yowowowowo." created="Sat, 28 May 2005 17:12:28 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mrgutman.blogspot.com/2005/05/halley-suitts-politically-incorrect.html&quot;&gt;Mr Gutman&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Maybe there's a silver lining to this cloud.&quot;" created="Sat, 28 May 2005 18:08:40 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Good morning from Gate 54 in Terminal B at Orlando International Airport where they have a very strong, free, wifi signal. Most surprising, and most excellent!" created="Sat, 28 May 2005 12:50:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/28/ohRudyIsntThisAFunPlace.jpg&quot; width=&quot;107&quot; height=&quot;79&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named ohRudyIsntThisAFunPlace.jpg&quot;&gt;More thoughts on the Boston Globe &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boston.com/business/technology/articles/2005/05/26/bickering_among_thepod_squad/?rss_id=Boston+Globe+--+Business+News&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; that came out on Thursday. When you look at the amount of space he had, how could he justify wasting any of it on being snarky? Does he imagine his readers have any interest in the subject? If not, why is he writing about it. If so, imagine how frustrated the reader is. The subject isn't exactly a household coversation, like the suspected &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnn.com/rssclick/2005/US/05/28/crane.man/index.html?section=cnn_topstories&quot;&gt;murderer&lt;/a&gt; who was camped out atop a crane in Atlanta (a subject MSM holds in great reverence, apparently, based on the number of Very Serious reports and hourly status updates). Thinking about it, I came &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.gillmorgang.podshow.com/GillmorGang-2005.05.28.mp3&quot;&gt;to&lt;/a&gt; the conclusion that the reporter has no passion for news, no respect for his readers, and certainly no respect for the subjects of his reportage. If I worked for the Boston Globe, I'd be embarassed, and would want to explain that most Globe reporters aren't like this. But then this is the second time I've been honked on by a Globe report. Another observation, even the snarkiest of bloggers would have more regard for his or her readers, yet this is totally typical for the pros who so hypocrtically claim that only they know how to report the news, that we bloggers can't possibly compete. Well, I hope I never am so space-constrained as they, and I hope I never develop the level of cynicism they've reached." created="Sat, 28 May 2005 12:54:26 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/28/toyotaSienna.jpg&quot; width=&quot;125&quot; height=&quot;62&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named toyotaSienna.jpg&quot;&gt;Field test report on the new Sienna. It has great acceleration power for passing, and handles really smoothly on curves. The navigation system is a bit quirky, the route it chose for me to the Orlando Airport, through back roads and suburbania was surely slower than the freeway route, even if it was more direct. And it was bad for the driver's nerves, it was hard to tell if they were sending me to the correct airport (maybe Orlando has more than one). But I decided to trust it, I had loads of time to spare, and eased out a sigh of relief when I pulled onto a main drag, and saw signs for Terminal A and Terminal B. Whew." created="Sat, 28 May 2005 13:01:20 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/28/ipod.jpg&quot; width=&quot;125&quot; height=&quot;134&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named ipod.jpg&quot;&gt;Toyota clearly has never heard of an iPod or an Archos. There's no damned way to play one that I've found. And I thought I was getting a satellite radio with the thing, but nope, apparently you don't get satellite if you get a navigation system. Now what kind of sense does that make! Geez Louise. Now I love my new car, but even an ideal lover has warts. I'll have to get my own satellite radio and dammit I keep wishing they put a mini-jack on the car. Maybe they want to hire me as a consultant for the next version of the car. Please, let's have some wifi support or how about Bluetooth? And btw, to Archos, you should really have a mini FM transmitter. Every high-end MP3 device should have a good one built in. Do the Belkin ones work worth a damn? I bought an El Cheapo brand transmitter at Target (it was all they had) and it didn't work. The signal was too weak." created="Sat, 28 May 2005 13:03:45 GMT"/>
				<outline text="But like I said at the top of the report, Orlando Airport wifi rocks. Every airport should have free wifi. I'd choose Orlando over Jacksonville for this reason alone, and I do have a choice. One more thing, if you want to be sure to stay ahead in the power user race, be sure to have some electric outlets to recharge the batteries. You could even charge for that. (Honestly you could charge for the wifi too, but I really like that it's free.)" created="Sat, 28 May 2005 13:10:56 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 27" created="Fri, 27 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="A get-out-of-town pre-Memorial Day rambly Coffee Notes &lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cnMay27.mp3&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt;. Music, massage, happiness, BloggerCon, Grateful Dead, Bruce Springsteen, and a way of decentralizing the podcast community to find the good stuff." created="Fri, 27 May 2005 15:17:49 GMT" name="aGetoutoftownPrememorialDayRamblyCoffeeNotesAHrefhttpstatic2podcatchcomblogsgemssneditcnmay27mp3podcastaMusicMassageHappinessBloggerconGratefulDeadBruceSpringsteenAndAWayOfDecentralizingThePodcastCommunityToFindTheGoodStuff" type="link" url="http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cnMay27.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://abcnews.go.com/technology/podcasting/&quot;&gt;ABC News podcast page&lt;/a&gt;. Great to see these new casts, but we could really use a description saying what's covered in each installment. " created="Sat, 28 May 2005 01:54:51 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/05/28/arts/design/28podc.html?ex=1274932800&amp;en=db1ced6873dcc4b6&amp;ei=5090&amp;partner=rssuserland&amp;emc=rss&quot;&gt;NY Times&lt;/a&gt; on 21st century museum tours, with the people as curators, via podcasting. &lt;i&gt;Bing! Bing! Bing!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Sat, 28 May 2005 03:02:42 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=http://www.cnn.com/2005/SHOWBIZ/TV/05/27/obit.eddie.albert.ap/index.html?section=cnn_topstories&quot;&gt;Sadly&lt;/a&gt;, Eddie Albert, the star of one of the most &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/27/greenacres.jpg&quot;&gt;surreal&lt;/a&gt; TV shows ever, Green Acres, died today. In celebration of his life, I recorded &lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/greenAcres.mp3&quot;&gt;his part&lt;/a&gt; of the show's theme song. Don't worry, you'll know what to do. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Sat, 28 May 2005 01:39:52 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sonystyle.ca/commerce/servlet/ProductDetailDisplay?storeId=10001&amp;catalogId=10001&amp;langId=-1&amp;productId=174228&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/27/laptop.jpg&quot; width=&quot;85&quot; height=&quot;69&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named laptop.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.blogware.com/blog/_archives/2005/5/27/890485.html&quot;&gt;Tod Maffin&lt;/a&gt; switched to the Mac, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rexblog.com/2005/05/27#a6963&quot;&gt;Rex Hammock&lt;/a&gt; continues to break his vow of silence on the Mac, and I had a long interesting phone talk today with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.byte.org/blog/cmd=view_user/username=raysl&quot;&gt;Ray Slakinski&lt;/a&gt;, lead developer of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ipodderx.com/&quot;&gt;iPodderX&lt;/a&gt;, a podcast client for the Mac OS. Meanwhile both my PCs are suffering heavily, one from &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2004/05/27#servesMeRight&quot;&gt;spyware&lt;/a&gt; (installed exactly one year ago today), and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sonystyle.ca/commerce/servlet/ProductDetailDisplay?storeId=10001&amp;catalogId=10001&amp;langId=-1&amp;productId=174228&quot;&gt;other&lt;/a&gt;, well I'm not really sure &lt;i&gt;what&lt;/i&gt; it's suffering from. " created="Fri, 27 May 2005 21:04:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.seattlepi.nwsource.com/buzz/archives/004918.html&quot;&gt;Seattle P-I&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Producing a podcast is still far from a one-click operation.&quot;" created="Fri, 27 May 2005 13:44:40 GMT"/>
				<outline text="SEW: &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.searchenginewatch.com/blog/050527-070112&quot;&gt;Last Week, Google Had A Strategy. This Week, It Doesn't&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 27 May 2005 11:25:32 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.makeyougohmm.com/20050519/1883/#comment-7245&quot;&gt;Dutch Uncle&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Daily Source Code gets less interesting the more it starts to resemble an IPO road show.&quot;" created="Fri, 27 May 2005 23:28:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="A Seattle coffee shop &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.engadget.com/entry/1234000297044773/&quot;&gt;turns off wifi&lt;/a&gt; on the weekend and sales go &lt;i&gt;up.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 27 May 2005 10:44:15 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/entry/2005/05/26#2607&quot;&gt;Rogers Cadenhead&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;FeedBurner has begun adding web bugs to syndicated feeds that enable the service to track use of individual items.&quot;" created="Fri, 27 May 2005 07:41:30 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.google.com/images?q=pinata&amp;hl=en&amp;lr=&amp;safe=off&amp;start=20&amp;sa=N&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/27/pinata.jpg&quot; width=&quot;61&quot; height=&quot;96&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named pinata.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bayosphere.com/node/441&quot;&gt;Dan Gillmor&lt;/a&gt; has been calling the Bay Area housing market a &quot;bubble&quot; for as long as I've been reading him (and that's a long time), but if it is one, it refuses to pop. Meanwhile Dan's older brother Steve has coined a new term with sure lasting value. &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.zdnet.com/Gillmor/?p=103&quot;&gt;The Scobleizer Bunny&lt;/a&gt;. What an image! I'm sure Scoble will &lt;i&gt;love&lt;/i&gt; that. Not many people know that Steve worked with Scoble at Fawcette, and believe it or not was my editor when I wrote a column for &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.scripting.com/2000/07/10/whyILikeXml#xmlCanBeOpen&quot;&gt;XML Magazine&lt;/a&gt;. Me, I'm looking forward to a Scobleizer &lt;a href=&quot;http://dictionary.reference.com/search?q=pinata&quot;&gt;pinata&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe at Gnomedex? &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Fri, 27 May 2005 07:55:52 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/05/27/opinion/27krugman.html?ex=1274846400&amp;en=ee73a0d5d3c35710&amp;ei=5088&amp;partner=rssnyt&amp;emc=rss&quot;&gt;Paul Krugman&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Although the housing boom has lasted longer than anyone could have imagined, the economy would still be in big trouble if it came to an end.&quot;" created="Fri, 27 May 2005 11:52:17 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 26" created="Thu, 26 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Hey the Washington Post is &lt;a href=&quot;http://media.washingtonpost.com/media/download/rss.xml&quot;&gt;podcasting&lt;/a&gt;. Yow. " created="Fri, 27 May 2005 00:06:52 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cnMay26.mp3&quot;&gt;A 17-minute podcast&lt;/a&gt; with the missing bits on Trade Secrets and Adam Curry. We started a technology, business and artisitic partnership in public, and never explained why it fell apart. This is my story. " created="Thu, 26 May 2005 10:16:01 GMT" type="link" url="http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cnMay26.mp3"/>
				<outline text="Nick Bradbury of FeedDemon has started a &lt;a href=&quot;http://nick.typepad.com/blog/2005/05/river_of_news_1.html&quot;&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/riverOfNews&quot;&gt;River of News&lt;/a&gt; style of aggregators, and I join in. " created="Thu, 26 May 2005 17:09:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The PBS show NewsHour with Jim Lehrer &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pbs.org/newshour/rss/&quot;&gt;supports RSS&lt;/a&gt;." created="Thu, 26 May 2005 15:28:59 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The Make You Go Hmm &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.makeyougohmm.com/20050519/1883/#comment-7218&quot;&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt; got pretty interesting today." created="Fri, 27 May 2005 00:52:57 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/26/loveRss.gif&quot; width=&quot;80&quot; height=&quot;27&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named loveRss.gif&quot;&gt;Jeff Veen: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.veen.com/jeff/archives/000733.html&quot;&gt;The Usability of Subscribing to Feeds&lt;/a&gt;. I'm glad that Jeff is writing about this. Now that Safari has made subscribing easier, it would be great if the other browser vendors followed suit, and then carefully upped the ante. There's an evolution that could take place here over the next year that would make subscribing really easy. I'll write more about this soon." created="Thu, 26 May 2005 22:34:49 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/26/armadillo.jpg&quot; width=&quot;95&quot; height=&quot;39&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named armadillo.jpg&quot;&gt;At the beginning of today's &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/05/26#When:6:16:01AM&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; I said I'd talk about how I'd like to go on from here, but I finished before explaining. I really do think the air is clear now. I want to be able to talk about podcasting business models, where it was difficult before because I had undisclosed conflicts, now they're out in the open, so you know how to judge my opinion." created="Thu, 26 May 2005 11:03:04 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.weblogs.com/2005/05/24#justAThought&quot;&gt;Doc Searls&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The podosphere is the new conferencesphere.&quot;" created="Thu, 26 May 2005 12:01:39 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rexblog.com/2005/05/26#a6954&quot;&gt;Rex Hammock begins&lt;/a&gt; a series of blog posts he has entitled &quot;How Apple Will Change Everything About Podcasting.&quot;" created="Thu, 26 May 2005 15:40:01 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/26/ohRudyIsntThisAFunPlace.jpg&quot; width=&quot;107&quot; height=&quot;79&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;25&quot; vspace=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named ohRudyIsntThisAFunPlace.jpg&quot;&gt;In the &lt;i&gt;very next aggregator run&lt;/i&gt; after posting today's podcast, an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boston.com/business/technology/articles/2005/05/26/bickering_among_thepod_squad/?rss_id=Boston+Globe+--+Business+News&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; in the Boston Globe about the rift. I'm glad I got my side out there. I knew the Globe article was in process, I was interviewed for it on Tuesday. I was pretty sure it would be about as superficial as it turned out to be. Also on Tuesday I &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/05/24#When:2:22:36AM&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; podcasting can go deep, and today here's the proof. It's a new medium and a new world, I don't care how much they sniff in pro-jo land. You can't slime someone like the old days, nowadays we talk back. So there's a silver &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.gillmordaily.podshow.com/gillmordaily3.mp3&quot;&gt;lining&lt;/a&gt; to all the &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.scripting.com/2000/08/27/michegas&quot;&gt;michegas&lt;/a&gt;, we get to use the tools in new ways. " created="Thu, 26 May 2005 10:45:15 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Finally the &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/26/blogCartoon.jpg&quot;&gt;cartoonists&lt;/a&gt; are starting to figure out blogs. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Thu, 26 May 2005 08:35:21 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/26/pisa.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/26/drWiner.jpg&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;156&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named drWiner.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;" created="Fri, 27 May 2005 01:46:46 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 25" created="Wed, 25 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="This week's developments in podcasting by Apple, turning iTunes into a podcatcher, is enough for an &lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cnMay25.mp3&quot;&gt;entire&lt;/a&gt; 17-minute Morning Coffee Notes." created="Wed, 25 May 2005 13:40:54 GMT" name="thisWeeksDevelopmentsInPodcastingByAppleTurningItunesIntoAPodcatcherIsEnoughForAnAHrefhttpstatic2podcatchcomblogsgemssneditcnmay25mp3entirea17minuteMorningCoffeeNotes" type="link" url="http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cnMay25.mp3"/>
				<outline text="I booked a three-day trip to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rssweather.com/hw3.php?pands=cambridge%2Cma&amp;config=&amp;forecast=zandh&quot;&gt;Cambridge&lt;/a&gt; for the weekend. I'll be a guest on Chris Lydon's first &lt;a href=&quot;http://radioopensource.org/&quot;&gt;broadcast&lt;/a&gt; on WGBH on Monday. Had an itch to go north. Looks like I'll be in Chapel Hill, NC the first weekend in June. " created="Wed, 25 May 2005 14:57:08 GMT"/>
				<outline text="August 2003: &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2003/08/02#howToNameAProduct&quot;&gt;How to name a product&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 25 May 2005 23:21:25 GMT"/>
				<outline text="News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.com.com/ABC%2C+NBC+News+launch+news+podcasts/2100-1025_3-5720500.html?part=rss&amp;tag=5720500&amp;subj=news&quot;&gt;ABC, NBC News launch news podcasts&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 25 May 2005 23:15:16 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.blogware.com/blog/_archives/2005/5/25/884912.html&quot;&gt;Tod Maffin&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Canada’s major cellular providers have just joined forces to create a single Wi-Fi network across the country.&quot;" created="Wed, 25 May 2005 20:39:08 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.makeyougohmm.com/20050519/1883/&quot;&gt;Interesting outside perspective&lt;/a&gt; on the fallout between myself and Adam Curry. I haven't read it in detail, but I will, before commenting." created="Wed, 25 May 2005 22:02:13 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kraftfoods.com/coolwhip/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/25/topping.gif&quot; width=&quot;95&quot; height=&quot;72&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named topping.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/05/23#a253&quot;&gt;The announcement&lt;/a&gt;, earlier this week, that Apple will support podcasting in iTunes will give them a commanding position to determine the (defacto) standard subscription mechanism for RSS because they will have control of the two key pieces of software on a single platform. They have already invested in a simple subscription &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/04/30#morningCoffeeNotes&quot;&gt;mechanism&lt;/a&gt; in Safari, but with iTunes in the mix, they'll have huge market power that they didn't have before. And of course with podcasting, the centralized aggregator doesn't matter, so their coup is complete. I imagine they realize all this in Cupertino. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Wed, 25 May 2005 11:56:53 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Apple's position is so powerful because they will have content people are interested in, the podcasts people have been hearing so much about. They are rushing to fill the gap left by the weak iPodder software. Tim Jarrett's &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.jarretthousenorth.com/2005/05/24#a5162&quot;&gt;critique&lt;/a&gt; of Microsoft applies. In years past, they would have jumped on the opportunity. Now that role is left to Apple. A few weeks ago a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newsgator.com/news/archive.aspx?post=56&quot;&gt;venture capitalist&lt;/a&gt; said we're in the first inning of RSS. I said that's wishful thinking, the first inning was six years ago. He asked what inning are we in? I said it's the inning when the big guys swoop in and take markets from the little guys, with lightning speed. The VCs invested too late in this market. They could learn the lesson, you have to risk to earn the reward. The time to build is &lt;i&gt;before&lt;/i&gt; the big dudes see it. Way before." created="Wed, 25 May 2005 12:29:32 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radar.oreilly.com/archives/2005/05/atom_has_a_bran.html&quot;&gt;Marc Hedlund says&lt;/a&gt; it's time to throw in the towel in the fight among techies over the perfect syndication format. " created="Wed, 25 May 2005 05:28:10 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://weblog.infoworld.com/dickerson/001422.html&quot;&gt;Chad Dickerson&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Maybe the beauty of podcasts is that we are forced to step away from our hyper-efficient RSS news aggregator world and actually listen for once.&quot;" created="Wed, 25 May 2005 13:55:13 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0100165/2002/04/04.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/25/jesus.gif&quot; width=&quot;109&quot; height=&quot;56&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named jesus.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;On a lark, I thought about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.supernova2005.com/registration/register.php&quot;&gt;registering&lt;/a&gt; for the Supernova conference (I'll be on the west coast that week for Gnomedex) but gulped &lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/gulp.mp3&quot;&gt;audibly&lt;/a&gt; when I saw the &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/25/price.gif&quot;&gt;price&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alwayson-network.com/events/index.php&quot;&gt;AlwaysOn&lt;/a&gt;, with a stellar speaker lineup, is a tiny bit cheaper, with a 25 percent discount until June 1. Gnomedex is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mollyguard.com/event/16437164#ordernow&quot;&gt;better deal&lt;/a&gt; than both, by a lot. What do all three conferences have in common? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newmediamusings.com/blog/images/kim_polese_thumb.jpg&quot;&gt;Marc Canter&lt;/a&gt; is speaking. Maybe he can tell us what they talk about. BTW, AlwaysOn offered to let me in for free, as a blogger. I don't think so. I have no time for conferences where I have to sit in the audience and keep my hands folded and my mouth shut until it's time to ask a question. That's why I like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloggercon.org/iii/newbies&quot;&gt;unconferences&lt;/a&gt; where no one is less important and the interesting stuff happens in the sessions as opposed to the hallway." created="Wed, 25 May 2005 07:23:11 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Talk of the Nation: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=4664476&quot;&gt;Blogging Poses New Workplace Issues&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 25 May 2005 05:26:34 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/25/love.gif&quot; width=&quot;80&quot; height=&quot;27&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named love.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;" created="Wed, 25 May 2005 11:35:39 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 24" created="Tue, 24 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/05/24#a275&quot;&gt;An essay&lt;/a&gt; on the economics of the developing podcast industry. " created="Tue, 24 May 2005 15:44:30 GMT"/>
				<outline text="WSJ: &lt;a href=&quot;http://online.wsj.com/public/article/0,,SB111698169211742466-WwNhZxmt32qi6OJmCCRcOkbdRcs_20060524,00.html?mod=free&quot;&gt;Gates Casts Cold Eye on Google&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 25 May 2005 03:31:29 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lemonde.fr/web/rss/0,48-0,1-0,0.html&quot;&gt;Le Monde supports&lt;/a&gt; RSS. Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://jy.typepad.com/jy/2005/05/rss_lemondefr.html&quot;&gt;JY&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 24 May 2005 15:05:12 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://gigaom.com/2005/05/24/bit-torrent-resistance-is-futile/&quot;&gt;Om Malik&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Like a man in love, I just cannot get enough of Bit Torrent.&quot;" created="Tue, 24 May 2005 11:54:41 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://paolo.evectors.it/2005/05/24.html#a2532&quot;&gt;Paolo&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I must admit I am still not completely sold on tags.&quot;" created="Tue, 24 May 2005 11:48:13 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://ricksegal.typepad.com/pmv/2005/05/one_talk_two_pe.html&quot;&gt;Rick Segal&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;One talk -- two perspectives.&quot;" created="Tue, 24 May 2005 11:47:11 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://channel9.msdn.com/ShowPost.aspx?PostID=71140&quot;&gt;Scoble&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I spent some time today interviewing the Virtual Earth team. This is MSN's answer to Google Maps, coming in July 2005. As you see in the video MSN Virtual Earth goes noticeably further than Google Maps or other mapping services.&quot;" created="Tue, 24 May 2005 11:35:54 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.jarretthousenorth.com/2005/05/24#a5162&quot;&gt;Tim Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The good news in this scenario is that customers are getting a choice, as Microsoft feels the sting of competition. The bad news -- for customers and for its investors -- is that the most highly capitalized software company in the world isn’t capable of turning all its resources into bringing products like this to the market faster.&quot;" created="Tue, 24 May 2005 14:52:45 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessweek.com/technology/content/may2005/tc20050524_9688_tc_211.htm&quot;&gt;Business Week&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Yes, the pace is slow, much more suited to a long stretch of highway than a morning commute. At one point in the show I listened to, Winer got up, walked across the room, and poured himself a cup of coffee. You could hear his voice in the distance. His point: This is a relaxed conversation, not traditional radio.&quot;" created="Tue, 24 May 2005 05:54:11 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/24/cluetrainArmadilloThumb.gif&quot; width=&quot;50&quot; height=&quot;69&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named cluetrainArmadilloThumb.gif&quot;&gt;It's nice to see a review of podcast styles. Why not slow down and take a look at what makes this medium different from others. Maybe there's more to it than radio; maybe, like blogs, it has something to do with the telephone? Small scale instead of huge. Maybe it's silly to ask how many people listen to your podcast, as it would be silly to ask how many listen to your phone conversations? (Hopefully only one!) Also, podcasting is clearly &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; a conversation, even more than a blog, it's one-way. I've never bought into the idea that a blog is a conversation. I think that came from the always-more-influential Doc Searls's observation that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cluetrain.com/book/markets.html&quot;&gt;markets&lt;/a&gt; are conversations. That doesn't mean &lt;i&gt;everything&lt;/i&gt; is a conversation. Hehe. Okay, imho a podcast is less a conversation than a blog is because one listens to a podcast away from the computer, and you have to remember to respond. That doesn't mean I didn't hear what was said, quite the opposite. When I'm walking or driving, there's less to interfere, I hear better than I do when reading a blog or an email, where there is so much competing for my attention that I skim for comprehension. Podcasts can go deep." created="Tue, 24 May 2005 06:22:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://english.ohmynews.com/articleview/article_view.asp?no=227556&amp;rel_no=1&quot;&gt;OhMyNews&lt;/a&gt; covers BlogNashville." created="Tue, 24 May 2005 05:57:12 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.blogware.com/blog/_archives/2005/5/23/881386.html&quot;&gt;Tod Maffin&lt;/a&gt; is looking for Canadian podcasters." created="Tue, 24 May 2005 06:46:42 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/24/dogCowFarting.gif&quot; width=&quot;84&quot; height=&quot;32&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named dogCowFarting.gif&quot;&gt;News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.com.com/Your+chance+to+meet+Bill+Gates/2110-1042_3-5717606.html?part=rss&amp;tag=5717606&amp;subj=news&quot;&gt;Your chance to meet Bill Gates&lt;/a&gt;. Doc Searls &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thetwowayweb.com/discuss/msgReader$667?mode=day&quot;&gt;would&lt;/a&gt; love this. Microsoft has no taste, they love the junk created by users. Meanwhile &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/05/23#When:4:23:05PM&quot;&gt;Uncle Steve&lt;/a&gt; is &quot;trying to help in some small way&quot; by sending bloggers to jail. Doc called it, in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/davenet/stories/DocSearlsonSteveJobs.html&quot;&gt;1997&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;The influence of developers, even influential developers like you, will be minimal. The influence of customers and users will be held in even higher contempt.&quot;" created="Tue, 24 May 2005 06:04:07 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 23" created="Mon, 23 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Analysis: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thetwowayweb.com/2005/05/23#a654&quot;&gt;Why Apple and Google should blog&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Mon, 23 May 2005 10:45:56 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/05/23#a253&quot;&gt;Apparently&lt;/a&gt; the next version of iTunes will come with a podcatcher built in. I'm accumulating data and links in a post on my podcasting blog. If you have more info, please post a comment or trackback to it. &lt;i&gt;Thanks!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 23 May 2005 09:00:43 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/23/microBBanimes.gif&quot; width=&quot;62&quot; height=&quot;53&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;Look at these guys wiggle their butts. In amazing defiance of the laws of physics, they'll be wiggling for years, if the archive survives. How about that.&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.zdnet.com/Gillmor/?p=101&quot;&gt;Steve Gillmor&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;On Thursday, Google laid down a 60-day window for offering RSS support in their Fusion operating system/office suite hybrid. On Sunday night Steve Jobs laid down a 60-day window for RSS enclosure support inside iTunes. Today, as the smoke clears from these two cannon blasts across Microsoft’s bow, Bill Gates must surely realize he’s just been upgraded to the RSS revolution. Hoisted on his own petard.&quot;" created="Tue, 24 May 2005 00:20:32 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wonkette.com/politics/media/steve-jobs-makes-us-work-104568.php&quot;&gt;Via Wonkette&lt;/a&gt;: Kara Swisher asks Steve Jobs last night: &quot;Would you have sued if the Wall Street Journal had done this?&quot; Jobs: &quot;We might have. But the WSJ has serious thought behind it. The thing is today is that everyone can be a journalist. We are in a gray area and we are trying to help in some small way.&quot;" created="Mon, 23 May 2005 20:23:05 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/23/ipod.jpg&quot; width=&quot;125&quot; height=&quot;134&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;8&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named ipod.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://battellemedia.com/archives/001560.php&quot;&gt;Okay John Battelle&lt;/a&gt;, get ready -- I'm going to ask you an interesting question, I hope. You say Steve Jobs sucks because he's shutting down three bloggers who are publishing his secrets on the Internet. He feels justified because the courts have backed him up (so far). Okay, fast forward two to three years, when Google is even bigger (they're &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/05/23#When:3:56:50PM&quot;&gt;already&lt;/a&gt; worth twice Apple, today). Imagine they have a browser in their quiver now, and it's getting pretty popular. That's a reasonable assumption, right, I mean it &lt;i&gt;could&lt;/i&gt; happen? Okay, so Google doesn't like us sharing their secrets, and they're kind of touchy, some of the things they object to don't even seem to us like they're secrets. Well lucky for them, they own the throttle. They can just cut off our air supply. How could they do that. How how how? Well, remember we decided it was okay for them to modify our content way back in 2005. They didn't even have to ask our permission. Not only that, if we said no, they could ignore us. They're just giving the users what they want, and we believed them. But why John is it bad when Steve Jobs goes to court to get permission to modify three bloggers' content, but it's really coooool when Eric Schmidt calls it a feature? I guess the users wanted it, that's the difference. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Godwin's_law&quot;&gt;Yeah&lt;/a&gt;, they made the trains run on time too. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Mon, 23 May 2005 19:41:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://finance.yahoo.com/q?s=goog&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; is at $255 a share, with a market cap of $71 billion. &lt;a href=&quot;http://finance.yahoo.com/q?s=aapl&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; is at $40 per share, with a market cap of $33 billion. One has to adjust one's thinking doesn't one? Jobs looms so large, but his company is relatively small compared to Google. " created="Mon, 23 May 2005 19:56:50 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/23/coke.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/23/cokeTilted.gif&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;106&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named cokeTilted.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Oy I had a &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/23/grilledCheeseAndCoke.gif&quot;&gt;meltdown&lt;/a&gt; on one of my servers today, all of a sudden Frontier started consuming massive amounts of memory on startup. I mean huge amounts. The system had run out of disk space earlier, so I figured a restart would cure it, but nope -- still the same nasty behavior. I tried reconfiguring virtual memory, no change. So I made a fresh pot of coffee, and started moving sites one by one until things settled down. Luckily things &lt;i&gt;seem&lt;/i&gt; to have settled down after moving the first one! Hey that's kind of lucky. (Praise Murphy, I'm not worthy, I am not a lawyer, My mother loves me, etc etc.) This kind of crappy behavior by a server reminds me how nice it is when everything behaves well. " created="Mon, 23 May 2005 19:36:57 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tmcnet.com/usubmit/2005/May/1146821.htm&quot;&gt;Press Release&lt;/a&gt; for GarageBand Podcast Studio." created="Mon, 23 May 2005 15:35:20 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://online.wsj.com/public/article/0,,SB111679774079740049-1huOURq5XtF79GUaLgMFR6N5Hs4_20060523,00.html?mod=&quot;&gt;WSJ&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;It's far too early to write Apple's digital-music epitaph.&quot;" created="Mon, 23 May 2005 08:46:20 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Rex Hammock &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/entry/2005/05/22.html#2599&quot;&gt;joins&lt;/a&gt; the Dixie choir, making it a &lt;a href=&quot;http://idisk.mac.com/rexhammock/Public/dixie-with-rex.mp3&quot;&gt;quintet&lt;/a&gt;. It's included as an enclosure in my RSS feed. " created="Mon, 23 May 2005 08:44:28 GMT" type="link" url="http://idisk.mac.com/rexhammock/Public/dixie-with-rex.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newyorkmetro.com/nymetro/news/features/12061/index.html&quot;&gt;New York Metro&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Lessig has cast aside his caution about a secret that haunts him still. And while his passion about his client’s cause is real and visceral, Hardwicke isn’t the only plaintiff here. Lessig is also litigating on behalf of the child he once was.&quot;" created="Mon, 23 May 2005 08:28:41 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Just curious, were there any bloggers at last week's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boston.com/business/technology/articles/2005/05/23/market_leader_uses_fusion_to_stay_on_top?rss_id=Boston+Globe+--+Business+News&quot;&gt;Google Factory Tour&lt;/a&gt;, or did they just invite professionals?" created="Mon, 23 May 2005 08:22:33 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2005/05/22/AFF&quot;&gt;Tim Bray&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I guess they don’t need that kind of listening post.&quot;" created="Mon, 23 May 2005 08:39:04 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 22" created="Sun, 22 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Dramatic pre-storm &lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/05/22#a1124&quot;&gt;beach pictures&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 22 May 2005 19:07:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/movies/womanDogBeachBeforeStorm.mov&quot;&gt;Movie&lt;/a&gt; of a woman playing on beach with dog pre-storm. " created="Sun, 22 May 2005 19:12:57 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.zdnet.com/Gillmor/?p=100&quot;&gt;Steve Gillmor&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Schmidt says the battle is over and RSS has won.&quot;" created="Sun, 22 May 2005 21:32:14 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Rex Hammock &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rexblog.com/2005/05/22#a6898&quot;&gt;discovered&lt;/a&gt; the truth about my new Sienna. " created="Sun, 22 May 2005 21:46:39 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Wow Frank Paynter &lt;a href=&quot;http://sandhill.typepad.com/sandhill_trek/2005/05/little_deuce_mi.html&quot;&gt;sings&lt;/a&gt; like the Beach Boys! &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Sun, 22 May 2005 19:18:07 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.backupbrain.com/2005_05_15_archive.html#a004540&quot;&gt;Dori Smith&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;He won't read this, but it's kind of fun to needle someone when you know it's completely behind someone's back.&quot;" created="Mon, 23 May 2005 02:11:40 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0106327/2005/05/22.html#a409&quot;&gt;Today's song&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;On Deadman's Curve, I used to shut 'em down...&quot;" created="Sun, 22 May 2005 17:49:05 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.themediadrop.com/archives/003699.php&quot;&gt;The Media Drop&lt;/a&gt; lists newspapers with RSS feeds." created="Sun, 22 May 2005 11:16:58 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.potkast.com/search.php&quot;&gt;Potkast&lt;/a&gt; calls itself &quot;The Google Of Podcasts.&quot;" created="Sun, 22 May 2005 12:01:51 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Interesting &lt;a href=&quot;http://wroxblog.typepad.com/minatel/2005/05/wiley_and_wrox_.html&quot;&gt;application&lt;/a&gt; of OPML by &lt;a href=&quot;http://wroxblog.typepad.com/wileyauthors.opml&quot;&gt;Wiley&lt;/a&gt; &amp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://wroxblog.typepad.com/wroxauthors.opml&quot;&gt;Wrox&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 22 May 2005 11:10:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I plugged the OPML into my directory displayer, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.worldoutline.com/2005/May/22/&quot;&gt;it worked&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sun, 22 May 2005 14:58:16 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Adding spice to Joi's online life" created="Sun, 22 May 2005 14:22:11 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://joi.ito.com/archives/2005/05/21/becoming_boring.html&quot;&gt;Joi Ito is in a rut&lt;/a&gt; and is asking for... well I'm not sure what he's asking for. But I have some advice anyway. Heh. Here it is. " created="Sun, 22 May 2005 14:22:27 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Try podcasting! It's fun and new, and people are happy when they're doing new things and growing. I'm having a great time, almost a year into it, still discovering new stuff every day." created="Sun, 22 May 2005 14:33:16 GMT"/>
					<outline text="And the flamers, well, they're part of the package. They're the web equivalent of people shooting at you. And if people are shooting at you, as some wise person once said, you must be doing something right. Really, I'm not kidding. I actually talked about this in &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay21.mp3&quot;&gt;yesterday's podcast&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sun, 22 May 2005 14:23:40 GMT"/>
					<outline text="You should listen to the flamers, up to a point. They are an indicator that lots of people are listening. Yes, they drown out the good people. It takes some time to get used to that. But the good guys figure out how to get through to you anyway. " created="Sun, 22 May 2005 14:24:38 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I've been down the road you're going down, it's actually a &lt;a href=&quot;http://c2.com/cgi/wiki?OneInfiniteLoop&quot;&gt;loop&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Sun, 22 May 2005 14:25:16 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="New car" created="Sun, 22 May 2005 11:24:27 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/22/toyotaSienna.jpg&quot; width=&quot;125&quot; height=&quot;62&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named toyotaSienna.jpg&quot;&gt;I did the deed. I bought a new car yesterday. I spent more time shopping for this one than I ever had before. I shopped while driving cross-country, looking at cars parked in rest stops, reading reviews on Edmunds, Yahoo, MSN and others. Perhaps the best review I read was written by &lt;a href=&quot;http://philip.greenspun.com/materialism/cars/sienna&quot;&gt;Philip Greenspun&lt;/a&gt;. When I had narrowed it down to &lt;a href=&quot;http://autos.msn.com/research/vip/overview.aspx?modelid=11476&amp;src=LeftNav&quot;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://autos.msn.com/research/vip/overview.aspx?modelid=11478&amp;src=LeftNav&quot;&gt;models&lt;/a&gt;, I used the excellent resources on the web to find out what others had paid for the same car in the last few months, and to find out what my trade-in was worth. " created="Sun, 22 May 2005 11:24:29 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I got the car for two reasons: My old trusty &lt;a href=&quot;http://autos.msn.com/research/vip/overview.aspx?modelid=3189&amp;src=GBT&quot;&gt;Lexus RX-300&lt;/a&gt; was six years old, and there's a lot of new technology in cars in the last six years; and I needed more space. Since I live without a permanent home, at least for now, my car has to be able to carry all I need to live. I couldn't get a bicycle, for example, because I had no way to move one. This new car, while not much bigger than the old one, is configured for cargo, I can get a bike now. That's an important innovation because I've been walking so much and losing weight that walking now no longer is very much exercise at all. If I want to get to the next level I have to upgrade. " created="Sun, 22 May 2005 11:27:07 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I went with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.toyota.com/sienna/index.html&quot;&gt;Toyota Sienna&lt;/a&gt; over the Honda Odyssey largely on price and availablility. The local Toyota dealer had several cars that fit the bill, the Honda dealer had only one. So I was able to work out a better arrangement with Toyota. As both vendors say, both are excellent autos, full of features, fun to drive, really groomed for the market. I looked at Dodge and Chevy too, but the American cars just aren't in the same class as the Japanese. " created="Sun, 22 May 2005 11:45:00 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I'll probably be reporting on the technology of the car as the weeks go by. I'm going back on the road in July, heading west, of course, because there is no more east (I'm looking out the window at the Atlantic Ocean as I write this). I also plan to spend much of August in Europe -- London, Switzerland, Italy and on trains. " created="Sun, 22 May 2005 11:30:42 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Anyway, it's so exciting to have a new car! I really like this one. I think I'll take a couple of trips today. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Sun, 22 May 2005 11:32:03 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 21" created="Sat, 21 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Today's Morning Coffee Notes &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay21.mp3&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; is about my outliner, Windows, why flames aren't really such a problem, word processing, editing in the browser, how to do format and protocol work." created="Sat, 21 May 2005 14:51:04 GMT" name="todaysMorningCoffeeNotesAHrefhttpmp3morningcoffeenotescomcnmay21mp3podcastaIsAboutMyOutlinerWindowsWhyFlamesArentReallySuchAProblemWordProcessingEditingInTheBrowserHowToDoFormatAndProtocolWork" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay21.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2001/03/04&quot;&gt;3/4/01&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Text on rails.&quot;" created="Sat, 21 May 2005 14:49:54 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.evespeeves.com/2005/05/21#a140&quot;&gt;My mother&lt;/a&gt; is a Natural Born Blogger, in a league with Scoble and Doc Searls. On her blog today she says: &quot;In the final analysis I'm talking to myself.&quot; Exactly right. It's good to know who one's audience is. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Sat, 21 May 2005 16:36:56 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.com.com/Do+you+Google/2100-1038_3-5715707.html?part=rss&amp;tag=5715707&amp;subj=news&quot;&gt;News.Com&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Is Google following its rivals too closely?&quot;" created="Sat, 21 May 2005 14:20:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I heard about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lhotka.net/WeBlog/PermaLink.aspx?guid=7849bd66-21b9-4731-9a22-1d617f0f9455&quot;&gt;Indigo&lt;/a&gt; today. Some at Microsoft think this is what Ballmer was referring to in the comments that came public yesterday. " created="Sat, 21 May 2005 14:48:16 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/05/21/technology/21nocera.html?ex=1274328000&amp;en=873e03abc641e6ef&amp;ei=5090&amp;partner=rssuserland&amp;emc=rss&quot;&gt;NY Times&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Can the kinder, gentler, tempered-by-the-trial Microsoft do to Google what it did to Netscape lo these many years ago?&quot;" created="Sat, 21 May 2005 08:25:40 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radar.oreilly.com/archives/2005/05/new_products_fr.html&quot;&gt;According to O'Reilly&lt;/a&gt;, Google moved the announce date for their portal up from June 30 and promised &quot;universal RSS support will follow.&quot;" created="Sat, 21 May 2005 08:14:55 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://ricksegal.typepad.com/pmv/2005/05/the_anatomy_of_.html&quot;&gt;Rick Segal&lt;/a&gt;, a former Microsofter, says that &lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2005/05/21.html#a10174&quot;&gt;Scoble&lt;/a&gt; and I over-reacted to the Ballmer quotes yesterday. " created="Sat, 21 May 2005 08:16:07 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I'm getting some beautiful responses to yesterday's &lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cnMay20.mp3&quot;&gt;thunderstorm podcast&lt;/a&gt;, and have asked for permission to run some of them. And &lt;a href=&quot;http://ryantate.com/Updates/May202005.html&quot;&gt;Ryan Tate&lt;/a&gt; has a lengthy very interesting response to Thursday's &lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cnMay19b.mp3&quot;&gt;beach podcast&lt;/a&gt;, where I recount asking &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kpcb.com/news/article.php?frm_id=53&quot;&gt;Kleiner&lt;/a&gt; partner &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stanford.edu/class/e145/bios/randy_bio.htm&quot;&gt;Randy Komisar&lt;/a&gt; to sponsor intellectually enriching podcasts about what's going on in Silicon Valley. Ryan says that in its early days Red Herring magazine did just that. Tate is a former reporter at Upside. " created="Sat, 21 May 2005 08:17:32 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 20" created="Fri, 20 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="There was a honkin thunderstorm brewing off the coast, and even though I was late for dinner, you know I had to do a &lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cnMay20.mp3&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Fri, 20 May 2005 22:13:24 GMT" name="thereWasAHonkinThunderstormBrewingOffTheCoastAndEvenThoughIWasLateForDinnerYouKnowIHadToDoAAHrefhttpstatic2podcatchcomblogsgemssneditcnmay20mp3podcasta" type="link" url="http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cnMay20.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zaadz.com/quotes/topics/newspapers/&quot;&gt;Joseph Pulitzer&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Newspapers should have no friends.&quot;" created="Fri, 20 May 2005 21:14:28 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buzzmachine.com/archives/2005_05_20.html#009701&quot;&gt;Jeff Jarvis&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I just quit my job at Advance.net.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Congrats!!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 20 May 2005 20:55:16 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Discuss: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/05/20#a608&quot;&gt;Is Microsoft of two minds on RSS?&lt;/a&gt;" created="Fri, 20 May 2005 14:34:21 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldoflongmire.com/features/romance_novels/index.htm&quot;&gt;Dan Conover&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Romance novel covers are pretty silly.&quot;" created="Fri, 20 May 2005 15:07:21 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Gary Turner: &lt;a href=&quot;http://weblog.garyturner.net/archives/001739.html&quot;&gt;Long Time Lapse Folkography&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Neat-o!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 20 May 2005 14:30:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Here's a nice &lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/DSCN3122.MOV&quot;&gt;movie&lt;/a&gt; taken during this morning's sunrise." created="Fri, 20 May 2005 13:13:21 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Yeah, what &lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0107946/2005/05/20.html#a4201&quot;&gt;Ed Cone said&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Fri, 20 May 2005 15:48:05 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.livejournal.com/users/libertango/133265.html&quot;&gt;Hal O'Brien&lt;/a&gt;, on the new NY Times web pricing model: &quot;Fewer readers, less revenues, less prestige. Not often one sees a trifecta like that.&quot;" created="Fri, 20 May 2005 11:04:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.podbat.com/2005/05/20.html#a81&quot;&gt;Podbat Man&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;This year's Gnomedex promises to be the one they'll talk about for years to come I think.&quot;" created="Fri, 20 May 2005 10:50:48 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.steffanie.net/english/archives/2005/05/swedish_public.html&quot;&gt;Steffanie Muller reports&lt;/a&gt; that Swedish Public Radio is podcasting. " created="Fri, 20 May 2005 10:44:28 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oracle.com/technology/syndication/techcasts/index.html&quot;&gt;OTN TechCasts&lt;/a&gt; are online audio interviews with Oracle technology experts, delivered via podcasting." created="Fri, 20 May 2005 10:47:51 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/20/berkmanLand.jpg&quot; width=&quot;55&quot; height=&quot;52&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named berkmanLand.jpg&quot;&gt;Wow, I love what the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/thursdaymeetings/&quot;&gt;Berkman Thursday group&lt;/a&gt; has done. They've got mini-BloggerCon type meetups planned through mid-June every Thursday. Very nice work. Now I know why I want to stop in Cambridge sometime this summer. This could get huuuuuge. What an excellent group of people. I knew they'd figure it out (even though I didn't forsee what &quot;it&quot; is)." created="Fri, 20 May 2005 10:56:49 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The debacle that was Apple" created="Fri, 20 May 2005 11:27:23 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.scripting.com/1997/07/08/TheSureRoadtoBankruptcy&quot;&gt;7/8/97&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The key mistake Apple made was betting exclusively on its own people for new technology directions. Huge money was spent on researchers who were so inwardly directed they couldn't even see the worldwide web when it happened.&quot;" created="Fri, 20 May 2005 11:27:28 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I had a longer piece here about Microsoft of 2005, but then I re-read this piece about Apple in 1997 and realized it was a much better description of this year's Microsoft. So inwardly focused that they missed RSS, &lt;i&gt;for six years,&lt;/i&gt; they denied it existed. And now that it's grown so large that even they can't miss it, they reject it. Similarly, Apple management tried to reject the web. A total act of hubris and one that cost the people who made that call their jobs. (But don't worry they got new ones.)" created="Fri, 20 May 2005 11:31:14 GMT"/>
					<outline text="History repeats itself in the software business. Watch it happen as Microsoft apparently tries to re-invent RSS." created="Fri, 20 May 2005 11:33:02 GMT"/>
					<outline text="And you can watch Google do it too. I suppose this has something to do with the fact that they hired so many people from Apple and Microsoft? Who knows. It's a losing strategy, for sure, for both of them. RSS is too strong, as HTML was too strong in 1997 for Apple to overcome it." created="Fri, 20 May 2005 11:33:56 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 19" created="Thu, 19 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="A podcast &lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cnMay19b.mp3&quot;&gt;from the beach&lt;/a&gt; with thoughts on what makes a good platform, an intellectual life for Silicon Valley, beach philosophy; a &lt;a href=&quot;http://pics.scripting.com/0094/0003.jpg&quot;&gt;picture&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/DSCN3104.MOV&quot;&gt;movie&lt;/a&gt; where today's cast was empodded. " created="Thu, 19 May 2005 20:44:39 GMT" name="aPodcastAHrefhttpstatic2podcatchcomblogsgemssneditcnmay19bmp3fromTheBeachaWithThoughtsOnWhatMakesAGoodPlatformAnIntellectualLifeForSiliconValleyBeachPhilosophyAAHrefhttppicsscriptingcom00940003jpgpictureaAndAAHrefhttpstatic2podcatchcomblogsgemssneditdscn3104movmovieaWhereTodaysCastWasEmpodded" type="link" url="http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cnMay19b.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://pics.scripting.com/0094/0001.jpg&quot;&gt;Sunrise&lt;/a&gt; over the &lt;a href=&quot;http://pics.scripting.com/0094/0002.jpg&quot;&gt;Atlantic&lt;/a&gt; this morning.  " created="Thu, 19 May 2005 20:54:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pandemia.info/archives/2005/05/google_personal.html&quot;&gt;An Italian blog&lt;/a&gt; gets the scoop on today's announcement by Google that they're becoming another boring portal just like all the others. Follow-on report by &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.searchenginewatch.com/blog/050519-141359&quot;&gt;Search Engine Watch&lt;/a&gt;. Now, the big question, when will a new aggressive startup with a laser-like focus on search come along to do to Google what they did to everyone else? That's obvious now, isn't it?" created="Thu, 19 May 2005 18:45:43 GMT"/>
				<outline text="If Santorum didn't just &lt;a href=&quot;http://politicalwire.com/archives/2005/05/19/quote_of_the_day.html&quot;&gt;commit political suicide&lt;/a&gt; this country is a political disaster area. " created="Fri, 20 May 2005 02:00:15 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremy.zawodny.com/blog/archives/004684.html&quot;&gt;Zawodny is right&lt;/a&gt;, Google should embrace RSS already, it's getting late. " created="Fri, 20 May 2005 01:57:05 GMT"/>
				<outline text="eWeek: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,,1817683,00.asp&quot;&gt;MSN Gets Ready for RSS Push&lt;/a&gt;." created="Thu, 19 May 2005 17:34:28 GMT"/>
				<outline text="News.com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.com.com/2061-10789_3-5714383.html?part=rss&amp;tag=5714383&amp;subj=news&quot;&gt;VeriSign sees business in blogs&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 20 May 2005 01:31:01 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://weblog.infoworld.com/techwatch/archives/001402.html&quot;&gt;Infoworld reports&lt;/a&gt; that Yahoo is getting into VOIP. " created="Thu, 19 May 2005 16:30:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://audio.weblogs.com/&quot;&gt;audio.weblogs.com&lt;/a&gt; got a brain transplant today. Please let me know if there are any problems." created="Thu, 19 May 2005 16:00:11 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/19/meter.gif&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;160&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named meter.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.blogware.com/blog/_archives/2005/5/19/872204.html&quot;&gt;Tod Maffin is a fantastic source&lt;/a&gt; for new podcasts. We ought to organize this better. Somehow we built a centralized system, and we already know that centralized systems suck the life out of communities. How can I ask this question. Tod, I have an hour to spare. What should I listen to? Or alternatively, let's say I want to give Tod my Tuesday walk-time. Every Tuesday he's got something good fo\r me to hear. He had to make a gut-wrenching decision because there are really 18 things he knows I should hear, but I'm only giving him one hour per week. I have six other days. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/05/19#a250&quot;&gt;Who else&lt;/a&gt; should I give a day to?" created="Thu, 19 May 2005 15:55:49 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Apparently I am &lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.blogware.com/blog/_archives/2005/5/19/872422.html&quot;&gt;psychic&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe just intuitive?" created="Thu, 19 May 2005 17:28:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/19/fishing.pg.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/19/river.jpg&quot; width=&quot;85&quot; height=&quot;51&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;18&quot; vspace=&quot;8&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named river.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.25hoursaday.com/weblog/PermaLink.aspx?guid=caa63ed7-eedd-442e-a767-e6d6f2b2416d&quot;&gt;Dare is a nice guy&lt;/a&gt;, but I'm going to criticize the way he develops software anyway. (Ditto for Mike Torres.) Go study the competition guys. A few days of using software and thinking will save you &lt;i&gt;years&lt;/i&gt; of figuring it out on your own. We did this investigation years ago, and you can skip all the way to the end of this exploration, and do the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/riverOfNews&quot;&gt;River of News&lt;/a&gt;, and be done with it. It's so painful watching you &lt;s&gt;learn&lt;/s&gt; re-invent this stuff. &quot;Only steal from the best,&quot; boys!" created="Thu, 19 May 2005 13:40:18 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techspot.com/download685.html&quot;&gt;Bram Cohen&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;We've created a 'trackerless' method of publication.&quot;" created="Thu, 19 May 2005 11:03:58 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://gigaom.com/2005/05/19/bittorrent-now-trackerless/&quot;&gt;Om Malik&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;BitTorrent’s new version is easier, better and well simpler.&quot;" created="Thu, 19 May 2005 10:29:44 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/GillmorDaily1.mp3&quot;&gt;Steve Gillmor&lt;/a&gt; is back podcasting again. Yowza. " created="Thu, 19 May 2005 09:18:31 GMT" type="link" url="http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/GillmorDaily1.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/DSCN2838.MOV&quot;&gt;A good movie&lt;/a&gt; is often worth seeing twice." created="Thu, 19 May 2005 09:02:16 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://accordionguy.blogware.com/blog/_archives/2005/5/19/871434.html&quot;&gt;Accordion Guy&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;If you check the right-wing pundits, you'll see that a number of them have commented negatively about the unsubtle jabs that &lt;i&gt;Revenge of the Sith&lt;/i&gt; takes at the Bush administration.&quot;" created="Thu, 19 May 2005 09:10:58 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Jason on Om" created="Thu, 19 May 2005 11:04:18 GMT">
					<outline text="Jason Calacanis is on a &lt;a href=&quot;http://calacanis.weblogsinc.com/entry/1234000343043702/&quot;&gt;rampage&lt;/a&gt;, and I'm sure he means well, but he's wrong." created="Thu, 19 May 2005 11:04:23 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Please read on. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Thu, 19 May 2005 11:04:40 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Om Malik possibly had the first word on the net about the deal between FeedDemon and Newsgator. But he surely wasn't the first to know. Many, including yours truly, were respecting an embargo, and waiting for the companies to announce. Well, once Chris Pirillo published his &lt;a href=&quot;http://chris.pirillo.com/blog/_archives/2005/5/16/864924.html&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with Nick Bradbury, I felt safe in publishing &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/05/16#When:10:33:19PM&quot;&gt;my own thoughts&lt;/a&gt;, because I knew that Chris was also under embargo." created="Thu, 19 May 2005 11:04:46 GMT"/>
					<outline text="This embargo stuff is tricky business, but I agreed to it because I've come to respect Nick, and think he's a fair-minded person, and wouldn't give me a lot of grief in a situation like this, where I didn't particularly care about being first, but didn't want to be last, if you know what I mean." created="Thu, 19 May 2005 11:06:25 GMT"/>
					<outline text="So of course I &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/05/16#When:10:11:36PM&quot;&gt;pointed&lt;/a&gt; to Om's bit, when he was the only one out there with the news, but I didn't get the news from him, so I'm not under any obligation to credit him in my own writing, and neither is News.Com, assuming they had more than one source which seems reasonable since the Newsgator guys were being so free with the embargoed information." created="Thu, 19 May 2005 11:07:13 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Also, it gets ridiculous sometimes to link to the full chain that a story came to you through, and I often don't get that kind of credit, and while it pains me, I accept it, because really, most readers couldn't care less, and the readers are important, of course. Now, when I get something from someone I try to reciprocate. Again, back to Om, I subscribe to his feed and he gets great stuff, and I point to him regularly. I think I point to him more than vice versa and a link from me delivers more traffic, but who cares. I feel that once in a while I can take a link I got from him and point to it without attribution, because in balance I feel I've delievered more flow his way. Maybe it's like peering arrangements among backbones on the Internet. Who knows, but it's not so black and white, and basically I think News.Com didn't hurt anyone in this case." created="Thu, 19 May 2005 11:08:14 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="More Adam" created="Thu, 19 May 2005 09:40:32 GMT">
					<outline text="For now, I'm not going to go deeper into the rift between myself and Adam Curry, only to acknowledge that now he's saying more things that are untrue in press interviews, punishing me for thinking he was ever a friend. My generosity with him is, in an ironic and unfair way, a gift that keeps on giving. " created="Thu, 19 May 2005 09:40:35 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I guess it's not surprising that the mainstream press only talks with him, even when they acknowledge that there's another side to his story (as News.Com did). It's not surprising because if there was ever any doubt that he is one of them, there's no doubt anymore. He's a salary-man, working for a major broadcasting company, presumably trying to climb their ladder. They're paying Howard Stern $100 million a year. Presumably Adam would like that kind of compensation, or something &lt;i&gt;approaching&lt;/i&gt; that kind of compensation. Lying about someone he probably once actually did think of as a friend (just guessing here) seems a small price, to Adam. " created="Thu, 19 May 2005 09:42:31 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/19/redPill.gif&quot; width=&quot;73&quot; height=&quot;54&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named redPill.gif&quot;&gt;I believe the ladder is gone, it's like the Road Runner character in Warner Brothers cartoons, when he runs off a cliff, he keeps running for a while, until he looks down. Then, beep-beep, he goes into a nosedive. I think Elmer Fudd does this from time to time too. When there is a podcaster on every block, then one on every blog, who will have time to listen to Howard or Adam or Elmer Fudd? Hollywood's characters can't compete with the real characters in our lives. That's why Adam's trading us, the early podcasters, for the love of a big corp seems so utterly dumb. He had it, I was working for him for free, so were all of us, dammit. But this is what he wanted? Talk about snatching defeat from the mouth of victory. " created="Thu, 19 May 2005 09:44:54 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/19/bluePill.gif&quot; width=&quot;73&quot; height=&quot;54&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named bluePill.gif&quot;&gt;Xeni Jardin is every bit as much a short-term mainstream animal as Adam and the reporter at News.Com. They've taken the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.arrod.co.uk/essays/matrix.php&quot;&gt;blue pill&lt;/a&gt;, they're in the matrix, dumbing it down for job security and a chance for a career path, or at least another freelance job. We're on different sides. She calls me a dinosaur. I think that's a bit of wishful thinking. I'm one of the people, pretty defenseless against attacks from the press, but there are millions of me, eventually, if they trash us one by one, they'll run out of ink, and run out of advertisers to pay their salaries. We can't &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; be the flawed human beings they make me out to be. " created="Thu, 19 May 2005 09:46:29 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I guess Adam will keep accelerating the lies, and the pro journos will keep reporting them. At some point it will be easy for me to say what Adam is afraid I might say. I tried recording a MCN about it yesterday, but decided not to run it. It didn't sound right, I was too angry. I have to wait for that to abate before telling the story. " created="Thu, 19 May 2005 09:47:44 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Of course I could end up forgetting the story, but as long as he continues to say really nasty shit about me personally I don't think I will. " created="Thu, 19 May 2005 09:49:00 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 18" created="Wed, 18 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Don't forget there's a new &lt;a href=&quot;http://pda.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;PDA version&lt;/a&gt; of Scripting News." created="Thu, 19 May 2005 01:36:33 GMT"/>
				<outline text="When accepting an offer to lead a discussion at a BloggerCon-style conference in the Deep South (Greensboro, NC; October 8), I responded, with tongue in cheek: &quot;That's almost like asking the Boy Named Sue if he'd want to be reincarnated as a Boy Named Sue.&quot;" created="Wed, 18 May 2005 22:02:19 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.banned-width.com/shel/works/boysue.html&quot;&gt;Today's song&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I made me a vow to the moon and stars, that I'd search the honky-tonks and bars, and kill that man that give me that awful name.&quot;" created="Wed, 18 May 2005 22:05:47 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.jarretthousenorth.com/2005/05/18#a5143&quot;&gt;Tim Jarrett took&lt;/a&gt; notes at a recent speech by Google CEO Eric Schmidt." created="Wed, 18 May 2005 20:11:22 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2005/05/18.html#a10147&quot;&gt;Scoble&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;When I subscribe to an RSS feed that means I want a long-term relationship.&quot;" created="Wed, 18 May 2005 20:13:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://a.wholelottanothing.org/2005/05/dave_winer_1_ny.html&quot;&gt;Matt Haughey&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The first thought that came into my head after hearing The New York Times will be adding paid subscription walls to their content was that Dave Winer just totally sealed the win on his bet.&quot;" created="Wed, 18 May 2005 16:13:16 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessweek.com/technology/content/may2005/tc20050513_3634_tc024.htm&quot;&gt;Steve Ballmer&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The hottest company right now -- the one nobody thinks can do any wrong -- may just be a one-hit wonder.&quot;" created="Wed, 18 May 2005 16:08:55 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://iranscan.net/&quot;&gt;Iran Scan&lt;/a&gt; is an English-language blog covering the election in Iran. " created="Wed, 18 May 2005 09:45:08 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.blogware.com/blog/_archives/2005/5/18/869969.html&quot;&gt;Tod Maffin&lt;/a&gt; is looking for someone who can write a script to turn an OPML file into HTML. Piece of cake for someone who knows how to write an outline &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontier.userland.com/stories/storyReader$3122&quot;&gt;renderer&lt;/a&gt; in Frontier (or Radio). Which reminds me, I should do a generic release of &lt;a href=&quot;http://kernel.scripting.com/2004/09/28&quot;&gt;Frontier&lt;/a&gt; so people can download something for free to run random scripts. The current minimal install is pretty frightening." created="Wed, 18 May 2005 20:00:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/05/18#a602&quot;&gt;Thoughts&lt;/a&gt; on special feeds for bloggers, feed hosting services, podcast hosting services." created="Wed, 18 May 2005 10:05:42 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://pics.scripting.com/0093/0002.jpg&quot;&gt;Picture&lt;/a&gt; taken from my desk while skyping with Kosso." created="Wed, 18 May 2005 14:56:47 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/18/gosling.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/18/goslingsmall.jpg&quot; width=&quot;45&quot; height=&quot;61&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named goslingsmall.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.devx.com/Java/Article/28125&quot;&gt;Okay, James Gosling isn't really this ignorant&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;We hear very strongly that if this thing turned into an open source project -- where just any old person could check in stuff -- they’d all freak.&quot; Okay James, you don't want to open source Java, so just say it. I could respect that. But this is totally wrong, and I can't believe you don't know it. No open source project exists that way. It &lt;i&gt;would&lt;/i&gt; be chaos. How do you think Apache and Linux work? There's a priesthood and a cathedral, just like any commercial project, just like Java. What's different is that it could fork, so if the priesthood isn't productive a new priesthood can form. Often this is enough to keep the main thread moving along. " created="Wed, 18 May 2005 13:14:10 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I'm playing around today with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://casting.opml.org/Directory%20of%20podcasting%20directories/&quot;&gt;directory&lt;/a&gt; of podcasting directories. Nothing earth-shaking, just a couple of experiments. " created="Wed, 18 May 2005 13:09:05 GMT"/>
				<outline text="It's official. &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Scripting News&lt;/a&gt; is now part of Blogger. (Just kidding. Hehe.)" created="Wed, 18 May 2005 14:02:37 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://joi.typepad.com/photos/sf0307/kimlarry.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/18/lessig.jpg&quot; width=&quot;55&quot; height=&quot;68&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named lessig.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Yesterday I took a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.itconversations.com/shows/detail332.html&quot;&gt;Larry Lessig speech&lt;/a&gt; with me on my daily walk, but a funny thing happened when he played a very short track from the gray album, which is a mix of the black album which is a mix of the Beatles' white album -- I stopped and switched to listening to the white album which I also had on my Archos. Many thanks to Larry for making the suggestion. And a reminder that it wasn't that long ago that you couldn't take your entire music collection with you where ever you go. Someday I'm going to meet someone who won't understand how we could live that way, but we did, didn't we?" created="Wed, 18 May 2005 10:26:11 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.weblogs.com/2005/05/17#foundStupidestDamnElevatorsOnEarth&quot;&gt;Doc Searls&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The Marriott Marquis has a central cylinder of new elevators that rise and fall like bubbles on the surface of a reactor core.&quot;" created="Wed, 18 May 2005 11:15:15 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Cory Doctorow found a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boingboing.net/2005/05/17/trailer_suspended_50.html&quot;&gt;picture&lt;/a&gt; of a trailer suspended on a tower that looks like it was separated at birth from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/18/Windmill.jpg&quot;&gt;windmill&lt;/a&gt; on my uncle's hippie commune here in Florida." created="Wed, 18 May 2005 10:33:01 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/news/culture/0,1284,67545,00.html&quot;&gt;Wired&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Traditionally, bands toured cities and played dive bars to create buzz about their music. But with MySpace, bands can host demos of their songs, announce shows and connect with fans without spending weeks on the road.&quot;" created="Wed, 18 May 2005 10:14:44 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcastoutlaws.com/&quot;&gt;The Podcast Outlaws Network&lt;/a&gt; is &quot;a central place to find some of the brightest, funniest and most underrated Podcasts on the internet!&quot;" created="Wed, 18 May 2005 09:33:37 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Jupiter Research is now &lt;a href=&quot;http://podcasts.jupiterresearch.com/&quot;&gt;podcasting&lt;/a&gt;. You may have trouble getting to the site, but if you persist you will eventually get through." created="Wed, 18 May 2005 09:38:07 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 17" created="Tue, 17 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.zdnet.com/Gillmor/&quot;&gt;Steve Gillmor&lt;/a&gt; may be back on the air as soon as &lt;i&gt;tonight.&lt;/i&gt; Yehi! The Gang can't be far behind. Happy days are here again." created="Tue, 17 May 2005 22:07:39 GMT"/>
				<outline text="A late afternoon Morning Coffee Notes &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay17.mp3&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; (better late than never) about advertising in RSS, a vignette about the twisty world of 21st century radio, and an apology for the delay of the conversation-starters. " created="Tue, 17 May 2005 23:54:15 GMT" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay17.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/17/smallbrain.gif&quot; width=&quot;53&quot; height=&quot;43&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named smallbrain.gif&quot;&gt;We guessed that the talks at the Syndicate conference would be filled with ads, and based on reports on the web, we weren't wrong. They didn't like being talked about on my blog, but all I was doing is what I always do, think out loud and involve everyone in my drama. That, by the way, is how you build interest in an event and keep people thinking. This afternoon I told myself I need to get my head examined for trying to help big companies get their ideas exposure in the weblog world. In the end, they just freak out and try to extert control and you end up at the beach while everyone else is at the conference. Maybe I made out okay, but I do miss my friends -- this is a conference I should have been at. Oh well, life goes on. " created="Tue, 17 May 2005 22:09:20 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://todmaffin.com/publicradiofeeds/&quot;&gt;PublicRadioFeeds.com&lt;/a&gt; is &quot;the most comprehensive list of public radio podcasts on the Internet.&quot;" created="Tue, 17 May 2005 20:32:11 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Billboard: &lt;a href=&quot;http://billboardradiomonitor.com/radiomonitor/news/format/talk/article_display.jsp?vnu_content_id=1000921309&quot;&gt;Limbaugh Joins Podcasting Crowd&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 17 May 2005 22:07:11 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/2005/05/17/BUGRVCQ45G1.DTL&quot;&gt;SF Chronicle&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Podcasters took over a San Francisco radio station Monday, replacing traditional radio personalities like Don Imus with a homespun potpourri of shows featuring independent musicians, martini-making and mortality.&quot;" created="Tue, 17 May 2005 23:48:43 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2005/05/feed-me.html&quot;&gt;Google announces&lt;/a&gt; the beta of &quot;AdSense for Feeds.&quot;" created="Tue, 17 May 2005 20:27:12 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Sorry we're going to have to wait 24 hours for the conversation-starters to start the conversations. There's a bit more coordinating here than I would like, but I guess a few more hours won't hurt. " created="Tue, 17 May 2005 17:18:08 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kraftfoods.com/coolwhip/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/17/topping.gif&quot; width=&quot;95&quot; height=&quot;72&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named topping.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Two conversation-starters for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.teamrss.com/&quot;&gt;Team RSS&lt;/a&gt; today. The first is a suggestion for browser-makers: Microsoft, Firefox, Safari, Opera, et al, on how to simplify the subscription process in a powerful way. It's an answer to the hodgepodge of different one-offs that have emerged that don't really work. This one does work, and is complete, imho. The second is a design for turning outlines into feeds, or is it feeds into outlines? It's both &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; a dessert topping and a floor wax! Stay tuned folks, I'll have a podcast and a couple of docs, it should be an exciting day. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Tue, 17 May 2005 09:12:21 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Peter Day: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4508329.stm&quot;&gt;In Pod We Trust&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 17 May 2005 09:12:02 GMT"/>
				<outline text="About Newsweek" created="Tue, 17 May 2005 13:37:41 GMT">
					<outline text="I'm vaguely aware that Newsweek stepped in something as &lt;a href=&quot;http://journalism.nyu.edu/pubzone/weblogs/pressthink/2005/05/17/nwsk_err.html&quot;&gt;nasty&lt;/a&gt; as the stuff CBS stepped in last year. I'm catching it out of the corner of my eye as I scroll through my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/riverOfNews&quot;&gt;River of News&lt;/a&gt; aggregator on a day when I'm busy creating news instead of reading news." created="Tue, 17 May 2005 13:37:44 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/17/lemon.jpg&quot; width=&quot;70&quot; height=&quot;63&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named lemon.jpg&quot;&gt;I have a suggestion. Why don't we immediately assume that all press reports are at least as thinly sourced as the Newsweek story, and not make a big deal of it when we discover that one is. Instead, let's applaud the pros when they show evidence of diligence, multiple sourcing, and respect for what actually happened instead of what they think their editors will buy and what their readers will understand." created="Tue, 17 May 2005 13:38:22 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It's a new regime. Set expectations super-low. That way we can only be surprised by good news instead of bad. Make lemonade!" created="Tue, 17 May 2005 13:45:21 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PS: Here's some synchronicity. I went looking for a picture of a lemon, and tripped over a picture of Cynsa Bonorris, who I worked with on the SF strike paper website in 1994, which I discuss below. She's part of a singing duet called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lemonjuju.com/&quot;&gt;Lemon Ju Ju&lt;/a&gt;. More godcasting for y'all. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Tue, 17 May 2005 13:55:32 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="It worked!" created="Tue, 17 May 2005 09:41:10 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/17/accordianGuy.gif&quot; width=&quot;81&quot; height=&quot;194&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named accordianGuy.gif&quot;&gt;I got a call yesterday from a San Francisco reporter doing a story on KYOU on their debut day. It was a very interesting and lively talk, reminding me a lot of the talks we'd have in the Bay Area at the end of 1994, when the web was taking root in so many communities, including the newspaper writers, who went on strike and needed a way to get their words out to their readers. It turns out that was how SFGate was started, the website of the Chronicle. Anyway, my first experience with the web was working on the strike paper website, alongside Chris Gulker who was working on the management website, both of us competing to bootstrap something new. I was learning from the news writers who &quot;got&quot; the web better than any of us, the same way a radio guy today is excited by podcasting. Of course the really good ones are excited, because podcasting is the realization of the reason so many of them got into broadcasting in the first place. Radio people are an idealistic bunch, just as newspaper writers are, in general. What happened to the idealistic newspaper writers? I wish I knew. Did they all die in the last eleven years? Have they all become web people? Did they wake up one day and realize this idealism was interfering with their career path? It'd be interesting to hear people's theories." created="Tue, 17 May 2005 09:41:17 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Anyway, it turns out someone at KYOU has a sense of humor, or a sense of what's appropriate, because yesterday, during the drive time commute, they ran a podcaster who records his casts during his commute! Think about it. What a turnabout. Instead of being stuck in traffic listening to a predictable formulaic format, or at best Morning Edition on NPR, now the bored listeners are doing the programming. This struck me as amazing. The podcasting revolution has completed its mission in some sense, in a remarkably short period of time. " created="Tue, 17 May 2005 09:46:33 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Let me tell you a story that explains why I feel this way. A couple of years ago stuck in Boston traffic listening to a yet another WBUR pledge drive and thinking about technology that could turn this crap off for people like me who pay their NPR bill like a utility bill, I finally figured something out when the station manager, Jane Cristo, came on and said something that would be often repeated in the days ahead (my guess is that their marketing people decided it would be the theme of the pledge drive). This is your station, she said. You're the owners. We depend on your to pay the bills, that way we are only responsible to you, and blah blah blah and on and on, in the usual repetitive pledge drive way of doing things. " created="Tue, 17 May 2005 09:48:25 GMT"/>
					<outline text="This got me thinking. If I own this place, what can I do with it? So when I got into work I called the offices of WBUR and asked to speak with Ms Cristo. When asked who's calling, I gave my name, Dave Winer, and my role -- owner of the station. No one got the joke." created="Tue, 17 May 2005 09:50:36 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I did get to speak with a vice-president, and I asked the question, what can I do with my ownership, and seriously don't you think you should stop saying that since it's total bullshit? He sent me a station prospectus, kind of an annual report, with some nice pictures, glossy and puffy, and numbers that meant nothing to me. " created="Tue, 17 May 2005 09:51:22 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Thinking more about it I realized that the role of an owner of a public radio station is twofold. You listen and you pay. Occasionally, if you don't mind waiting and getting totally nervous, you can call in and ask a question of an expert -- someone who is probably just saying politically correct bullshit, but you never get to speak, what you think isn't important, your job is to pay, and if you like, listen, while they lull you to sleep with their relaxing talk that's only intelligent when compared to the other crap that's on the radio. " created="Tue, 17 May 2005 09:51:59 GMT"/>
					<outline text="So yesterday when I heard about the commuter musing about his mortality during drivetime while other San Franciscans were caught in the horrible traffic in the Bay Area, I let out a satisfied chuckle. I had lived long enough. I could now die a happy man. As they say in Apache Land when an install is successfully completed: It worked!" created="Tue, 17 May 2005 09:53:58 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 16" created="Mon, 16 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/16/toast.jpg&quot; width=&quot;52&quot; height=&quot;117&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;18&quot; vspace=&quot;8&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named toast.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://chris.pirillo.com/blog/_archives/2005/5/16/864924.html&quot;&gt;Chris Pirillo&lt;/a&gt; has an interview with Nick Bradbury about the deal with Newsgator. I guess it's official now. I was briefed on the deal by Nick Bradbury a couple of days ago. I understand that the motivation was to allow FeedDemon to tie into the subscription-sharing network Newsgator is building. It seems inevitable that they'll buy a Mac news reader product, they would probably like to buy NetNewsWire, and it would be hard to imagine Brent wouldn't take a reasonable offer (I have no inside knowledge). This is venture capital at work, not sales revenue. I  imagine that Newsgator will roll up with Feedburner (they share an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feld.com/blog/index.php&quot;&gt;investor&lt;/a&gt;), and Technorati may become part of this deal too. The goal? Get large enough to go public or merge with something going public (SixApart) or get bought by Microsoft." created="Tue, 17 May 2005 02:33:19 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://gigaom.com/2005/05/16/is-newsgator-buying-feed-demon/&quot;&gt;Om Malik&lt;/a&gt; first has a rumor then confirmation that Newsgator is buying FeedDemon. &quot;It's a cash-and-stock deal, and Nick will join Newsgator.&quot;" created="Tue, 17 May 2005 02:11:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/05/16#a1103&quot;&gt;For ten points&lt;/a&gt;, where was the &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/16/park.jpg&quot;&gt;picture&lt;/a&gt; taken?" created="Mon, 16 May 2005 21:25:55 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/16/boringBoring.gif&quot; width=&quot;39&quot; height=&quot;72&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named boringBoring.gif&quot;&gt;I get a yet another &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boingboing.net/2005/05/16/an_audience_with_the.html&quot;&gt;lecture&lt;/a&gt; from Boing Boing. I think they're even calling me names (kind of hard to tell). They say respect is not a loaf of bread, cool, but how long has it been since Boing Boing pointed to Scripting News with anything remotely approaching respect? I would absolutely plotz if they ever took a balanced view toward anything here. We share mostly the same politics, and many of the same friends, but boy the resentment is so damned thick. Anyway, Adam &lt;i&gt;does&lt;/i&gt;  take credit for work he didn't do. You might want to check on that Xeni, it might be more interesting than the cookie-cutter bullshit puff piece you just wrote. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Tue, 17 May 2005 02:53:26 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I've been hearing from &lt;a href=&quot;http://homepage.mac.com/seanwstewart/EOC/iMovieTheater42.html&quot;&gt;people&lt;/a&gt; who love their Elements. " created="Mon, 16 May 2005 20:06:29 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.corporate-ir.net/ireye/ir_site.zhtml?ticker=NYT&amp;script=411&amp;layout=-6&amp;item_id=710365&quot;&gt;The NY Times announces&lt;/a&gt; that they'll charge $49 a year for access to certain op-ed pieces and other stuff, including the archives. I don't get it. The op-ed stuff is well-competed with by blogs, which are free of course, and frankly there aren't any columnists that the Times has that I want to read, for pay or otherwise. I suppose others feel otherwise. Let's hope this doesn't affect their policy re the links in their RSS feeds. " created="Mon, 16 May 2005 19:04:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2005/05/16.html#a10131&quot;&gt;Scoble&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Will I start my own religion?&quot; Personally, I think that's a little premature. But I have suggested that Scoble start the Scoble School of Scoble, where Scoble teaches people who come how to be a scoble." created="Mon, 16 May 2005 19:00:01 GMT"/>
				<outline text="sco-ble, n, A person who blogs about an organization from the point of view of someone who works for the organization. Related verb: scobleize, to be influenced by a blog written by a scoble. Named after early 21st century blogger, Robert Scoble, whose disciples founded a religion, The Church of The Martyr Scoble, after he was violently murdered by Steven Ballmer, a destitute homeless person who was ruined by Scoble." created="Mon, 16 May 2005 19:17:11 GMT"/>
				<outline text="CBS Marketwatch: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marketwatch.com/news/story.asp?guid=%7B1CA684B9%2D0FE9%2D44F8%2DA857%2DDB203138A6ED%7D&amp;dist=rss&amp;siteid=mktw&quot;&gt;Podcasts go broadcast&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 16 May 2005 18:57:08 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://eve.scripting.com/2005/05/16#a134&quot;&gt;My mother thought&lt;/a&gt; buses in her neighborhood should turn off their engines while they're waiting at the depot, and she got what she wished for!" created="Mon, 16 May 2005 13:19:52 GMT"/>
				<outline text="A couple of notes. Some bloggers complain that we don't point to women often enough. First, we don't hesitate for a nanosecond to point to worthy posts by women. And second, how many bloggers, male or female, can boast that they've pointed to their mother! Fact is, my parents are extraordinary people. I hear that every day about my dad and his &lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cnMar29.mp3&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; about outliners and President Bush (who he calls a snake, people really seem to like that). Well, I have a mother too, and she kicks butt. " created="Mon, 16 May 2005 19:11:22 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://pg.photos.yahoo.com/ph/evespix/detail?.dir=/4d90&amp;.dnm=9246.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/16/noEngineIdle.jpg&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;68&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named noEngineIdle.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Another disclaimer about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kyouradio.com/&quot;&gt;KYOU&lt;/a&gt;, I did not &quot;submit&quot; my podcast through their form, and I never would, and I wouldn't recommend that others do. The legal agreement is too one-sided, it gives them all the protection, and gives you none. In the defense of the station, however, they are part of a media conglomerate, with very corporate lawyers, who need a serious education about how to relate to creative people with their own distribution system. In the past they could push us around because we had no voice, that's why we created this medium, so we could route around the lawyers and their bosses. The people running KYOU are the good guys, but they work for some people who seriously &lt;i&gt;need&lt;/i&gt; a kick in the butt (with love)." created="Mon, 16 May 2005 16:19:18 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I guess they did &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/16/firstpodcastbroadcast.gif&quot;&gt;play mine first&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for the honor." created="Mon, 16 May 2005 16:30:48 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Two signs that the world is either going crazy or getting saner, not sure which. There's blogging at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.jarretthousenorth.com/2005/05/16#a5126&quot;&gt;Gartner conference&lt;/a&gt;, by participants and by Gartner; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.com.com/2061-10809_3-5708645.html?part=rss&amp;tag=5708645&amp;subj=news&quot;&gt;IBM is encouraging&lt;/a&gt; its employees to blog. " created="Mon, 16 May 2005 15:55:25 GMT"/>
				<outline text="A sure sign of sanity, a German blogger has &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.searchenginewatch.com/blog/050516-095803&quot;&gt;banned Google&lt;/a&gt; from indexing his site in protest over their web accelerator. I'd love to ban Google from modifying the content on my site, however Google has not offered us a way to turn that off. " created="Mon, 16 May 2005 16:01:01 GMT"/>
				<outline text="It gets better. KYOU has an awful signup process, whether you want to &lt;i&gt;submit&lt;/i&gt; (awful word) a podcast for broadcast, or just want to listen. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paidcontent.org/pc/arch/2005_05_16.shtml#013761&quot;&gt;Staci Kramer called it&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;a process that almost dares people to listen.&quot; Also, to be clear, I am not being paid, and if they screw up, you'll hear about it here first." created="Mon, 16 May 2005 16:03:46 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://politicalwire.com/archives/2005/05/16/journalists_favored_kerry.html&quot;&gt;Political Wire&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;8 in 10 journalists said they read blogs.&quot;" created="Mon, 16 May 2005 16:42:03 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/16/apple.jpg&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;65&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named apple.jpg&quot;&gt;I just figured something out. My view of podcasting really isn't that radical, it's just an application of the same philosophy that led to the Apple II, IBM PC and Macintosh. Computers are tools used by people to think, organize and communicate. Podcasting just follows naturally. Sure, the tools are also used by professionals, but our real market, the one that pays the bills, are the people. It seems the &lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.userland.com/archive/stories/appleSparkedRevolution&quot;&gt;Young Steve Jobs&lt;/a&gt; would understand podcasting. " created="Mon, 16 May 2005 14:04:22 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/05/16#a243&quot;&gt;Gnomedex is right around the corner&lt;/a&gt;. It seems everyone is going this year, me too. I'm giving one of the keynotes, it's going to be BloggerCon-style, so I'll talk for 10 minutes, maybe do a demo, then lead a discussion. Are you going? What should we talk about? " created="Mon, 16 May 2005 10:19:42 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.active8.nl/index_news.srf?pkn=file_id&amp;pkv=2032&amp;lang_id=129&amp;skv=1167&quot;&gt;PodNova&lt;/a&gt; is an interesting podcasting &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podnova.com/&quot;&gt;directory&lt;/a&gt; built on OPML and RSS." created="Mon, 16 May 2005 11:47:02 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I'm playing around with some ideas this morning, and I needed to have an enclosure on an  item in my RSS feed for an experiment. It won't be very long, so if your iPodder downloaded it automatically, please excuse the intrusion. &lt;i&gt;Still diggin!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 16 May 2005 11:17:46 GMT" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/misc/dixieDuet.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/news/culture/0,1284,67514,00.html&quot;&gt;Wired&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Inventive web developers are taking Google's online map service to a new level, layering in house sales and apartment rentals, real-time traffic stats and Flickr photo tags.&quot;" created="Mon, 16 May 2005 10:33:55 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.msdn.com/ie/archive/2005/05/16/417732.aspx&quot;&gt;IE blog&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;IE7 has tabs.&quot;" created="Mon, 16 May 2005 10:34:42 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 15" created="Sun, 15 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Here's the Morning Coffee Notes &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay15.mp3&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; for May 15, the one that will be broadcast on KYOU at &lt;s&gt;midnight&lt;/s&gt; 6AM Pacific and again at noon tomorrow. It's 46 minutes long, and it's a rambler, but I think it's a pretty good podcasting manifesto, as applied to the Bay Area and the mission of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kyouradio.com/&quot;&gt;KYOU&lt;/a&gt;. I feel pretty good about this podcast. I was nervous, and it took me five tries to get started, which is very unusual for me. (Update: We're going to run the &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/05/12#When:10:36:38AM&quot;&gt;Pisa Podcast&lt;/a&gt; instead.)" created="Sun, 15 May 2005 14:30:03 GMT" name="heresTheMorningCoffeeNotesAHrefhttpmp3morningcoffeenotescomcnmay15mp3podcastaForMay15TheOneThatWillBeBroadcastOnKyouAtSmidnights6amPacificAndAgainAtNoonTomorrowIts46MinutesLongAndItsARamblerButIThinkItsAPrettyGoodPodcastingManifestoAsAppliedToTheBayAreaAndTheMissionOfAHrefhttpwwwkyouradiocomkyouaIFeelPrettyGoodAboutThisPodcastIWasNervousAndItTookMeFiveTriesToGetStartedWhichIsVeryUnusualForMeUpdateWereGoingToRunTheAHrefhttparchivescriptingcom20050512when103638ampisaPodcastaInstead" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay15.mp3"/>
				<outline text="WFMU &lt;a href=&quot;http://podcast.wfmu.org/&quot;&gt;podcasts&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 15 May 2005 22:55:18 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0100191/2005/05/15.html#a4215&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/15/marlboroLights.gif&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;93&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named marlboroLights.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Back in Mac scripting days, at WWDC or MacWorld Expo or after sushi dinner, I'd often go out for a smoke with Steve Michel. We were buddies, I remember once raising a toast to Steve and saying I was a Steve Michel fan. Well ten years ago today Steve quit smoking, an event he notes on his &lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0100191/2005/05/15.html#a4215&quot;&gt;weblog&lt;/a&gt;. I haven't seen Steve in a while, but I'm glad he's still out there kicking butt. On June 14 it'll be three years since I quit. &lt;i&gt;Notato fumare!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Sun, 15 May 2005 23:26:13 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://homepage.mac.com/adam210/.Music/Dixie_Sing-a-long.mp3&quot;&gt;Adam Hansen&lt;/a&gt; was inspired to a Duet with me too. Wow! It's viral." created="Sun, 15 May 2005 17:04:30 GMT" type="link" url="http://homepage.mac.com/adam210/.Music/Dixie_Sing-a-long.mp3"/>
				<outline text="Okay, now here's the &lt;a href=&quot;http://cadenhead.org/workbench/gems/dixie-quartet-with-amy-bellinger.mp3&quot;&gt;Dixie Quartet&lt;/a&gt; with Amy Bellinger. &lt;i&gt;Amen y'all!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Sun, 15 May 2005 19:19:10 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The Philadelphia Inquirer now has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.philly.com/blinq/&quot;&gt;staff blogger&lt;/a&gt;, Dan Rubin, who also was part of the first &lt;a href=&quot;http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/blogs/gems/dave/bostonJuly25.mp3&quot;&gt;soundseeing tour&lt;/a&gt;, at the DNC in Boston in July. " created="Sun, 15 May 2005 17:20:20 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Kosso the Podbat &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.podbat.com/2005/05/15.html#a72&quot;&gt;joins&lt;/a&gt; the Dixie Duet turning it into a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.podbat.com/gems/diccsie/diccxie.mp3&quot;&gt;trio&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 15 May 2005 14:43:14 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/52614599@N00/13962836/&quot;&gt;guy on the left&lt;/a&gt; is an arse-ole. (Practicing my Bwitish accent.)" created="Sun, 15 May 2005 23:19:52 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.scripting.com/1995/08/22/whatisaplatform&quot;&gt;8/22/95&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The author of an API is offering a challenge, saying 'blow my mind,' to everyone who might take a stab at implementing something on top of the API.&quot;" created="Sun, 15 May 2005 23:43:22 GMT"/>
				<outline text="NPR's Science Friday is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencefriday.com/audio/&quot;&gt;podcasting&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Bing!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Sun, 15 May 2005 07:47:15 GMT"/>
				<outline text="You can sing too" created="Sun, 15 May 2005 07:09:53 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/15/element.jpg&quot; width=&quot;93&quot; height=&quot;88&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named element.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/entry/2005/05/14#2590&quot;&gt;Rogers Cadenhead did&lt;/a&gt; something creative with the part of my last podcast where I sing the old &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niehs.nih.gov/kids/lyrics/dixie.htm&quot;&gt;song&lt;/a&gt; of the South -- Dixie. He turned it into a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/gems/dixie-dave-rogers-duet.mp3&quot;&gt;duet&lt;/a&gt;, and then sent an email asking if he could license the result under the Creative Commons. Of course I said yes. Now you can turn it into a trio or quartet. It's a perfect demo of the CC, and we can have some fun while we're at it, and demo the principle I outlined in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/05/12#When:10:36:38AM&quot;&gt;Pisa Podcast&lt;/a&gt; last week. Everyone gets to be creative, everyone gets to sing, you don't have to be Frank Sinatra or Madonna to hit the airwaves with your creation. God knows I'm no Frank Sinatra and Rogers ain't no... never mind. &quot;;-&gt;&quot; " created="Sun, 15 May 2005 06:46:53 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Honda" created="Sun, 15 May 2005 07:07:32 GMT">
					<outline text="BTW, I've included the picture of the Honda Element above because I test drove one yesterday and was absolutely charmed by it. What a neat car. You can almost extrapolate that next year's model will support wifi, so my Archos can connect up to the car over HTTP to play music over the sound system. You can see the path Honda is on. It's too bad they haven't quite got the car-as-platform thing ready to go yet." created="Sun, 15 May 2005 06:54:20 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Platforms" created="Sun, 15 May 2005 07:03:14 GMT">
					<outline text="Speaking of platforms, yesterday, on my daily walk, I took the IT Conversations podcast of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.itconversations.com/shows/detail329.html&quot;&gt;platform panel&lt;/a&gt; at Web 2.0. " created="Sun, 15 May 2005 06:56:14 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It was a pretty interesting discussion, centering around SOAP, XML-RPC and REST (although they didn't name XML-RPC, I think it's more widely deployed than the other two). " created="Sun, 15 May 2005 11:12:34 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It was both encouraging and discouraging. It was encouraging because now O'Reilly is including this vital topic in its conferences. I was pitching them on it for years, in the mid-late 90s. It should have been on the agenda of their open source convention, at least. It was discouraging, because with all due respect, they had the wrong people on stage. This is a technical topic, and I seriously doubt if any of the panelists were actually working on this stuff at their companies. We should be hearing from people who are actually coding, because only they know what the real problems are. " created="Sun, 15 May 2005 11:13:49 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Still, it was an interesting listen. There's something relaxing about the idea of &quot;attending&quot; a conference while walking with your bare feet in the Atlantic Ocean on a beautiful sunny day. " created="Sun, 15 May 2005 11:16:21 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PS: Tim O'Reilly asked Adam Bosworth to say what a platform is. I wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.scripting.com/1995/08/22/whatisaplatform&quot;&gt;piece&lt;/a&gt; in 1995 that attempted to define it. " created="Sun, 15 May 2005 11:46:46 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PPS: This is a continuation of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.docuverse.com/blog/donpark/EntryViewPage.aspx?guid=08b60742-8123-42d1-a58d-84cb2b632e97&quot;&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt;, started by Don Park, on conference-jacking. There's no reason we can't hijack a conference long after it happened. In fact, it's &lt;i&gt;easier&lt;/i&gt; to do it then!" created="Sun, 15 May 2005 11:48:14 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 14" created="Sat, 14 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="More ideas for the first broadcast podcast. Maybe we should &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niehs.nih.gov/kids/lyrics/spangle.htm&quot;&gt;sing&lt;/a&gt; The Star Spangled Banner? Or run the podcast with my &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay2.mp3&quot;&gt;parents&lt;/a&gt; on my birthday. Huey Lewis's &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/lyrics/hipToBeSquare.txt&quot;&gt;Hip To Be Square&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niehs.nih.gov/kids/lyrics/happytogether.htm&quot;&gt;Happy Together&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sat, 14 May 2005 23:09:03 GMT"/>
				<outline text="On today's &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay14.mp3&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; I ponder the possibilities for tomorrow's broadcast podcast for KYOU-AM in San Francisco. More singing this time with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niehs.nih.gov/kids/lyrics/dixie.htm&quot;&gt;MIDI&lt;/a&gt; of Dixie. You'll have to wade through it to get to the talk. Also includes philosophy from Ed Cone and Rogers Cadenhead. " created="Sat, 14 May 2005 15:55:33 GMT" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay14.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/14/radioMugOnGrey.gif&quot; width=&quot;89&quot; height=&quot;107&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named radioMugOnGrey.gif&quot;&gt;I winced a half-dozen times reading this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/news/culture/0,1284,67525,00.html&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with Adam Curry. He didn't invent podcasting, he didn't figure out that RSS would be a good transport. And he didn't write the first iPodder. Here's what Adam actually did do. He figured out the last yard was important and worked tirelessly to get people to listen to him. I was the only one who did, and I turned that idea into &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thetwowayweb.com/payloadsforrss&quot;&gt;RSS with enclosures&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thetwowayweb.com/payloadsforrss#software&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2004/10/30/enclosurePrefs.gif&quot;&gt;first&lt;/a&gt; iPodder, in 2001, &lt;i&gt;three years before&lt;/i&gt; Adam claims to have done all this stuff. I never denied him credit for his role in this work, quite the opposite, I praised him every way I could for his insight. I also did regular podcasts for a couple of months before he started. He was listening to them, calling me all the time, ecstatic at how I was reinventing radio. There are a couple of ideas in Daily Source Code that didn't come from me, and for that Adam deserves full credit and our thanks. But these lies have gone on and on, he just doesn't stop. " created="Sat, 14 May 2005 12:02:28 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://autos.yahoo.com/newcars/model/overview.html;_ylt=Ai1LA1sq2rbUfSiMA4ZpxeoEc78F?modelId=4306&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/14/element.jpg&quot; width=&quot;105&quot; height=&quot;61&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; vspace=&quot;3&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named element.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Also, as has been pointed out elsewhere, Chris Lydon's interviews with bloggers were &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/lydon/specialRssFeed&quot;&gt;available&lt;/a&gt; as an RSS feed with enclosures, starting in August 2003. I'd love to hear Adam's explanation of why that's not a podcast. That was followed very shortly by Doug Kaye's IT Conversations. My first podcasts were inspired by The Gillmor Gang, which I openly credit in those podcasts. I'm totally fed up with Adam taking credit for our hard risk-taking work. In other words, it's time for Adam to sit down and do his stinkin broadcast with his stinkin transmitter. " created="Sat, 14 May 2005 12:19:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Thing is -- Adam's star is fading, again. At some point he's going to need some &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/14/Adios_Amigo.jpg&quot;&gt;friends&lt;/a&gt;, and then I'm going to kick him in the ass, and then look him in the eye and say &quot;Shouldn't have lied so much, dickhead.&quot;" created="Sat, 14 May 2005 12:48:17 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 13" created="Fri, 13 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/12/bigpisa.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/13/tower.jpg&quot; width=&quot;45&quot; height=&quot;112&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named tower.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.julieleung.com/archives/001879.html&quot;&gt;Julie Leung transcribed&lt;/a&gt; bits of yesterday's &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/05/12#When:10:36:38AM&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;It's an instant classic. It's a tune I'd be happy to play over and over until the ears ring. As all great hits do, it ends with the best part of the song, something to hum long after the music has ended.&quot; She's right. If you've never listened to a podcast of mine, this is the one. It explains it all. If you miss DaveNet, this podcast gets to a place no DaveNet ever did. If you want to know how it all ties together, how this story we're writing together ends, this is the one to listen to. You won't be sorry. Even my mother likes it. &quot;I loved your podcast from Pisa,&quot; she wrote via email. It's only 25 minutes. Really, you &lt;i&gt;can&lt;/i&gt; afford the time. Go &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay12.mp3&quot;&gt;listen&lt;/a&gt; now." created="Fri, 13 May 2005 14:33:35 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay13.mp3&quot;&gt;A brief response&lt;/a&gt; to Chris Lydon's &lt;a href=&quot;http://radioopensource.org/wp-content/open_source_pilot_1.mp3&quot;&gt;pilot&lt;/a&gt; for his &lt;i&gt;Open Source&lt;/i&gt; radio program on Public Radio International." created="Fri, 13 May 2005 23:03:39 GMT" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay13.mp3"/>
				<outline text="Best wishes and good luck to Adam Curry on his new Sirius satellite &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sirius.com/servlet/ContentServer?pagename=Sirius/Page&amp;c=FlexContent&amp;cid=1115038974898&amp;source=218&amp;occ=curry21801&amp;flash=flash&quot;&gt;radio show&lt;/a&gt;, which debuts this evening at 6PM Eastern. Adam, please be sure people know they're tuned to a &lt;i&gt;broad&lt;/i&gt;cast, not a &lt;i&gt;pod&lt;/i&gt;cast. Thanks." created="Fri, 13 May 2005 21:27:30 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2005/05/13.html#a10087&quot;&gt;Scoble&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Bing, bing, bing! You win $10 million.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Coooooooool.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 13 May 2005 17:48:02 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The WSJ has an &lt;a href=&quot;http://online.wsj.com/xml/rss/0,,3_7077,00.xml&quot;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; for its free articles, which is how I found this &lt;a href=&quot;http://online.wsj.com/public/article/0,,SB111582547907330498-BJz4wNLNc8pxJ1Pf4hjMKB7mVTk_20060513,00.html?mod=&quot;&gt;piece&lt;/a&gt; in today's paper about podcasting and big-city newspapers. " created="Fri, 13 May 2005 17:37:27 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Speaking of things I just found, there's what appears to be an excellent &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.personaldemocracy.com/conference&quot;&gt;conference&lt;/a&gt; in NYC on Monday about politics and blogging. It's so &lt;i&gt;weird&lt;/i&gt; I'm just finding out about this. Sigh." created="Fri, 13 May 2005 17:39:44 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Ed Foster: &lt;a href=&quot;http://weblog.infoworld.com/foster/2005/05/13.html#a254&quot;&gt;It's Hard to Say Goodbye to AOL&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 13 May 2005 09:43:27 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.syndic8.com/~jeff/blog/index.php?p=214&quot;&gt;Jeff Barr's apology&lt;/a&gt; for spamming Google for money. Jeff says he's never been the target of &quot;a public attack&quot; before, but he wasn't attacked, he did something that hurt the web, and that was made public, making it possible for him to fix it, which he did, apparently. " created="Fri, 13 May 2005 10:12:53 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/13/grapefruitSmall.gif&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;64&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named grapefruitSmall.gif&quot;&gt;In the meantime, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1815479,00.asp&quot;&gt;yesterday&lt;/a&gt; Google took the Toolbar out of beta, and along with it released the &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/search/default?q=autolink&quot;&gt;AutoLink&lt;/a&gt; feature we were discussing in February and March. They made some minor mods, but still haven't allowed authors a way to opt-out on a feature that &lt;i&gt;should&lt;/i&gt; be opt-in only. So, imho, Google is doing its own part to destroy the value of the searchable web, cashing our work out for a short-term benefit for their shareholders. That was my last attempt to try to coax Google back onto our side. We're now on their slippery slope, I fully expect that they will release more content-modifying technology soon. AutoLink was merely a precedent-setter for them, and for their competitors. I'm not going to do interviews on this, I've already said so much about it. It's time to move on." created="Fri, 13 May 2005 10:17:59 GMT"/>
				<outline text="On the other hand, perhaps this is a good time for Google's competitors in toolbars, search and advertising to take a pledge to help build the integrity of the web instead of foreclosing on it. Yahoo? Microsoft? Anyone?" created="Fri, 13 May 2005 12:25:00 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 12" created="Thu, 12 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/12/bigpisa.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/12/tower.jpg&quot; width=&quot;45&quot; height=&quot;112&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;20&quot; vspace=&quot;8&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named tower.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay12.mp3&quot;&gt;The podcast of today's talk&lt;/a&gt; in Pisa, Italy; unconferences, blogging, RSS, podcasting, making money on the Internet, and an end to monoculture. This is probably the podcast I'll give to KYOU for their inaugural broadcast, and it's the speech I would have given at the Syndicate conference. It's a pretty good explanation of the ideas that are making a difference in the blog, pod, syndo-spheres. Web services are in there too, but aren't really part of the user story. If you want to understand where I think we're going, please listen to this cast. It's only 25 minutes, and it's packed with ideas." created="Thu, 12 May 2005 14:36:38 GMT" name="aHrefhttpimagesscriptingcomarchivescriptingcom20050512bigpisajpgimgSrchttpimagesscriptingcomarchivescriptingcom20050512towerjpgWidth45Height112Border0AlignrightHspace20Vspace8AltaPictureNamedTowerjpgaaHrefhttpmp3morningcoffeenotescomcnmay12mp3thePodcastOfTodaysTalkaInPisaItalyUnconferencesBloggingRssPodcastingMakingMoneyOnTheInternetAndAnEndToMonocultureThisIsProbablyThePodcastIllGiveToKyouForTheirInauguralBroadcastAndItsTheSpeechIWouldHaveGivenAtTheSyndicateConferenceItsAPrettyGoodExplanationOfTheIdeasThatAreMakingADifferenceInTheBlogPodSyndospheresWebServicesAreInThereTooButArentReallyPartOfTheUserStoryIfYouWantToUnderstandWhereIThinkWereGoingPleaseListenToThisCastItsOnly25MinutesAndItsPackedWithIdeas" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay12.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/05/12#a231&quot;&gt;Does&lt;/a&gt; podcasting make you a better writer?" created="Thu, 12 May 2005 22:57:42 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/002719.php&quot;&gt;ReadWriteWeb&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Is there a Web-based RSS aggregator out there that will be a Bloglines killer?&quot;" created="Thu, 12 May 2005 19:49:46 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Here's what the Pisa conference &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/12/conference.gif&quot;&gt;looked like&lt;/a&gt; from my point of view." created="Thu, 12 May 2005 12:28:10 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thenationaldebate.com/blog/archives/2005/05/thoughts_on_a_r.html&quot;&gt;Robert Cox&lt;/a&gt;, the host and organizer of BlogNashville, on the Respectful Disagreement discussion." created="Thu, 12 May 2005 15:08:26 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gizmodo.com/gadgets/smartphones/first-windows-mobile-50-phones-htc-universal-and-samsung-sghi300-103272.php&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/12/billg.jpg&quot; width=&quot;45&quot; height=&quot;66&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;8&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named billg.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Some people who were critical of BlogNashville probably weren't familiar with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloggercon.org/III/newbies&quot;&gt;unconference format&lt;/a&gt;, which was borrowed from BloggerCon. &quot;The discussion leader is the editor, so if he or she feels that a point has been made they must move on to the next point quickly. No droning, no filibusters, no repeating an idea over and over.&quot; Notice the word &quot;must&quot; in that sentence. The obligation of the discussion leader is to the discussion, not to people who repeat themselves, or take the discussion off-topic. The leader is a reporter, the session is a weblog. For better or worse, the judgment of the discussion leader is what forms the session, as the judgment of the reporter forms the story. &quot;The leader's job is to keep it moving. Sometimes this means cutting people off.&quot;" created="Thu, 12 May 2005 11:34:10 GMT"/>
				<outline text="New header graphic: &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/dir/davesWorld/history/previousHeaderGraphics/stormBuildingOutsideSacramento&quot;&gt;Storm building outside Sacramento&lt;/a&gt;." created="Thu, 12 May 2005 23:30:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Let's see, Jason Calacanis &lt;a href=&quot;http://calacanis.weblogsinc.com/entry/1234000250043163/&quot;&gt;calling&lt;/a&gt; you a jerk, is that like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ctv.ca/servlet/ArticleNews/story/CTVNews/1115894078967_20/?hub=World&quot;&gt;Pope&lt;/a&gt; saying you're pious? &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Thu, 12 May 2005 21:48:10 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mod.blogs.com/art_mobs/&quot;&gt;Art Mobs&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;If a painting could speak, what would it say?&quot;" created="Thu, 12 May 2005 11:17:06 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Broadcasting a podcast" created="Thu, 12 May 2005 09:12:42 GMT">
					<outline text="This week, while deflecting flames from Tennessee, I've also been talking with people about the podcast I'm going to do this weekend, the one that will be broadcast on KYOU-AM in San Francisco early on Monday morning (midnight) and again at noon on Monday. If you don't live in the Bay Area, the program will also be webcast." created="Thu, 12 May 2005 09:12:53 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I've gotten a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/05/09#a189&quot;&gt;feedback&lt;/a&gt; already, and that's cool. Now I have to figure out what I want to do with the time. It's a bit tricky -- should I assume that most of the people listening will have heard about it on the web? I remember how hard people were on us when we blogged the DNC, they expected, somehow, that we would turn into amateur Wolf Blitzers or Dan Rathers, maybe Ted Koppel or Judy Woodruff. " created="Thu, 12 May 2005 09:14:38 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Nahhh, we're still bloggers, and the style guide for blogging, imho, is &quot;Come as you are, we're just folks.&quot; There's no James Earl Jones voiceover saying &quot;This is CNN.&quot; " created="Thu, 12 May 2005 09:18:33 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The reason you send bloggers to a place like the DNC is so they can tell you what they see. If you read the blog regularly, you now have some data you didn't have before. That's all we can do. But if you get enough known views of an event, you can figure out what happened. The problem with the mainstream media approach is that they strive for an inhuman sameness, after all, they're pleasing the same commercial sponsors, fighting for the same ad dollar, so how different &lt;i&gt;could&lt;/i&gt; their programming be? But human reporters are different, we bring color, we make mistakes, we wear glasses, all different tints. That's why we want lots of bloggers and lots of podcasters. What we lack in polish we make up in numbers. " created="Thu, 12 May 2005 09:18:35 GMT"/>
					<outline text="So what should a broadcast of a podcast be? How does the broadcasting shape the podcasting? I have some thoughts about that." created="Thu, 12 May 2005 09:21:35 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The broadcast nails the podcast down in two dimensions: 1. Time and 2. Geography. So it seems that the broadcasted podcast should reflect the specifics of the time and geography. This says that the KYOU broadcasted podcasts should somehow reflect the culture of the Bay Area, something I know about, luckily, having lived there for 22 years. Even better, I &lt;i&gt;like&lt;/i&gt; the culture of the Bay Area, when compared to that of say, Nashville, which I am coming to detest. With a passion." created="Thu, 12 May 2005 09:22:09 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It seems the first Bay Area podcasts should include the figureheads of the Bay Area, those with large personalities who, for better or worse, shape the area's personality, make it seem an approachable place, defying its &lt;i&gt;un&lt;/i&gt;approachableness, the traffic, the cost of living, the inevitable &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/7832219/&quot;&gt;Big One&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 12 May 2005 09:29:33 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Scoop Nisker, Carlos Santana, George Coates, Huey Lewis, &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/12/willie.jpg&quot;&gt;Willie Brown&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/12/jerry.jpg&quot;&gt;Jerry Brown&lt;/a&gt;, George Lucas, Diane Feinstein, Louis Rosetto, Marc Canter, John Doerr, Phil Lesh, Steve Jobs, Jonathan Schwartz, Barry Bonds. " created="Thu, 12 May 2005 09:59:16 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It seems The Gillmor Gang and IT Coversations were made for Bay Area broadcast. Give KQED a run for its money? Yes, a good Bay Area podcast broadcaster would put some heat on public radio, in a good way of course. " created="Thu, 12 May 2005 09:59:21 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Sylvia Paull says it's time for me to head west. She might be right. Maybe Nashville is the clue. Or maybe, as Steve Gillmor says I could do the Bay Area scene from Florida or New York. Or maybe Nashville is really saying &quot;Come home Dave.&quot; Maybe that would be the punishment they are asking for, the penalty they deserve? Heh. " created="Thu, 12 May 2005 09:31:16 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 11" created="Wed, 11 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/technology/4536417.stm&quot;&gt;BBC&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Like sushi restaurant conveyor belts, RSS delivers content to people so they can easily pick what they want to read.&quot;" created="Thu, 12 May 2005 01:02:24 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://friends.macjournals.com/mattd/2005/05/11#a1205&quot;&gt;Matt Deatherage&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Programmers from the early days like Dave are used to being told they can't do things, and then they sat down and did them anyway.&quot;" created="Wed, 11 May 2005 20:13:47 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Don Park: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.docuverse.com/blog/donpark/EntryViewPage.aspx?guid=08b60742-8123-42d1-a58d-84cb2b632e97&quot;&gt;Conference-jacking&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 11 May 2005 20:06:02 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/11/blackHelicopter..jpg&quot; width=&quot;125&quot; height=&quot;62&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named blackHelicopter..jpg&quot;&gt;Dear Google. You're doing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/searchhistory/help.html#what&quot;&gt;personalization&lt;/a&gt; now. Good idea. I'm signed in, and you've been recording my searches for the better part of a month now. Next, let me tell you where my weblog is. That should let you do even more personalization. Think of all the info you have about me because of that. (And by the way that goes a long way toward clueing in the people who want to put ads in RSS feeds. Maybe if I have a certain amount of flow you don't want to distract me with ads, just think how many hits I can deliver if I link to your story.)" created="Wed, 11 May 2005 18:49:30 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoworld.com/article/05/05/11/HNgooglebloggergmail_1.html?source=rss&amp;url=http://www.infoworld.com/article/05/05/11/HNgooglebloggergmail_1.html&quot;&gt;Infoworld&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Google is contemplating various improvements to its popular Blogger Web logging service, including native image uploading and deeper integration with the company's Gmail Web-mail service.&quot;" created="Wed, 11 May 2005 20:04:37 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/11/italy.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/11/italia.jpg&quot; width=&quot;85&quot; height=&quot;117&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named italia.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Afternoon coffee notes: Tomorrow I'm giving a talk at an academic conference in Pisa, Italy; from the beach in Florida. We did a dry-run of the video conferencing tools on Monday, they work great. It's also been suggested that I do a podcast of the talk I would have done at the Syndicate conference next week, and I think that's exactly the right way to route around an outage, in this case the lack of trust of a conference promoter. There's still important business to be done among the leading users of RSS. So I've had two jarring experiences with conferences this month. Maybe it has something to do with turning 50. Trying to make lemonade best I can. And looking forward to tomorrow's talk. Ironically the politics of the coastal United States are closer to that of Italy than they are of the deep south. Go figure. BTW, in an email from Glenn Reynolds he says the aftermath of the Respectful Disagreement discussion is not political. I'm going to give him the benefit of the doubt and assume he's only been listening to himself not the people he's been defending. If it's not political, Glenn I got a nice &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.electriceggplant.com/davidmccullough/bridge.htm&quot;&gt;bridge&lt;/a&gt; you'd be interested in. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Wed, 11 May 2005 18:33:54 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Mark Glaser's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ojr.org/ojr/stories/050510glaser/&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; from BlogNashville." created="Wed, 11 May 2005 18:26:57 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.com.com/2061-10787_3-5703278.html?part=rss&amp;tag=5703278&amp;subj=news&quot;&gt;Pssst Charles&lt;/a&gt;, try &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.itconversations.com/&quot;&gt;IT Conversations&lt;/a&gt;. It's exactly what you're looking for. " created="Wed, 11 May 2005 18:14:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="And Charles, here's some &lt;a href=&quot;http://rc3.org/cgi-bin/less.pl?arg=6962&quot;&gt;good advice&lt;/a&gt;. Pandering for links that way is un-cool." created="Wed, 11 May 2005 22:06:18 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geeknewscentral.com/archives/004284.html&quot;&gt;Geek News notes&lt;/a&gt; that we're talking more about Yahoo these days." created="Wed, 11 May 2005 18:11:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.librarystuff.net/2005/05/rss-feeds-from-us-copyright-office.html&quot;&gt;Library Stuff reports&lt;/a&gt; on four new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.copyright.gov/help/rss.html&quot;&gt;feeds&lt;/a&gt; from the US Copyright Office." created="Wed, 11 May 2005 16:15:20 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://backstage.bbc.co.uk/&quot;&gt;backstage.bbc.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; is the BBC's new developer network." created="Wed, 11 May 2005 14:55:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Thank you Instapundit" created="Wed, 11 May 2005 09:36:28 GMT">
					<outline text="Glenn Reynolds's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.instapundit.com/&quot;&gt;Instapundit&lt;/a&gt; weblog is quite a flow machine. In the last few days since BlogNashville, he's been sending his readers over here, always with a scolding message. My behavior isn't up to his standards, I am too rude for him, so he's now telling everyone who reads his blog that I'm not a nice person. " created="Wed, 11 May 2005 09:36:36 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Okay, I'll survive. I'm not your typical shirking liberal, scared of a few nasty words from the Limbaugh crowd. Only it's a surprise to see Reynolds defending their right to control the conversation, especially since he didn't have anything to say at the session on Saturday. It's like the citizen who doesn't vote yet has the gall to complain about the outcome. " created="Wed, 11 May 2005 09:37:49 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Over the objections of those who Reynolds defends, the mission actually was accomplished, we came up with a great &lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/05/08#a1051&quot;&gt;list of shared values&lt;/a&gt; -- imho &lt;i&gt;that's&lt;/i&gt; what we should be discussing. Right and Left did get together on Saturday, between the slurs and attacks, we managed to draft a pretty good list. It's not ratified by anyone, but at least it's the beginning of an important discussion. " created="Wed, 11 May 2005 09:39:24 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/11/america.gif&quot; width=&quot;125&quot; height=&quot;81&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named america.gif&quot;&gt;Instead Reynolds wants the focus on my personality. I don't know why, but I can imagine. It's his worst nightmare that his conservative colleagues would work with my liberal friends to help &lt;i&gt;our&lt;/i&gt; country. That's right Glenn, it's our country, and don't you forget it. People from Boston, New York, Philadelphia, Detroit, Chicago, Seattle, Atlanta, Miami, San Francisco and Los Angeles go to war and die for America when our country needs us. Patriotism isn't exclusive to conservatives or Christians. The strength of our country is its diversity, intelligence, ambition, idealism, resources and our love of country. " created="Wed, 11 May 2005 09:40:51 GMT"/>
					<outline text="At the beginning of the conference we sang &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niehs.nih.gov/kids/lyrics/america.htm&quot;&gt;America The Beautiful&lt;/a&gt;. At the time I wasn't sure if that was the right song, but after the fact I feel it was the perfect song." created="Wed, 11 May 2005 10:09:17 GMT"/>
					<outline text="So to Glenn Reynolds, you pointed to me when I was sarcastic and angry. How about pointing to me now? Sure I don't agree with your focus, but I will fight to the death for your right to speak, for your dignity as an American, for your right to disagree with me. Let's get back on the road to success in America. And to do that, we need everyone's help." created="Wed, 11 May 2005 09:43:56 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 10" created="Tue, 10 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://ntl.matrix.com.br/pfilho/html/lyrics/m/me_and_bobby_mcgee.txt&quot;&gt;Today's song&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Freedom's just another word for nothin left to lose.&quot;" created="Wed, 11 May 2005 00:28:30 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay10.mp3&quot;&gt;Today's podcast&lt;/a&gt; includes lots of singing, one idea, not much more. A Windows reboot. A bunch of philosophy. Thirty minutes. Amazing." created="Tue, 10 May 2005 17:30:20 GMT" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay10.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/05/09#a189&quot;&gt;Yesterday I was invited&lt;/a&gt; to be the first &lt;i&gt;pod&lt;/i&gt;caster to be &lt;i&gt;broad&lt;/i&gt;cast on KYOU-AM. This raised some very interesting questions" created="Tue, 10 May 2005 13:51:37 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ajaxian.com/&quot;&gt;Gotta love O'Reilly&lt;/a&gt;, they always let everyone know about their open technology &quot;summits,&quot; &lt;i&gt;after&lt;/i&gt; they happen. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Wed, 11 May 2005 00:55:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/comment/2581#discuss&quot;&gt;Rogers&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;At this point, he has enough Southern in him to order 'unsweet tea' by its proper name and is getting closer all the time to a convincing pronunciation of 'y'all.&quot;&quot;" created="Wed, 11 May 2005 01:35:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Some more clues on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fortune.com/fortune/breakout/snapshot/0,23871,12,00.html&quot;&gt;Odeo in Fortune&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;When Odeo goes live in early May, podcasters will log on and employ Odeo-crafted, simple-to-use tools to record anything from found sounds to near-professional shows.&quot;" created="Wed, 11 May 2005 01:17:08 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.researchbuzz.org/google_news_to_rss_scraper.shtml&quot;&gt;ResearchBuzz&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;TimYang.com has a Google News scraper available called ScrappyGoo.&quot;" created="Tue, 10 May 2005 19:37:53 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Here's their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.timyang.com/scrappygoo/?q=dave+winer&quot;&gt;feed for me&lt;/a&gt;, and one for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.timyang.com/scrappygoo/?q=podcast&quot;&gt;podcasting&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 10 May 2005 19:46:39 GMT"/>
				<outline text="What is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gather.com/about.html&quot;&gt;gather.com&lt;/a&gt;?" created="Tue, 10 May 2005 14:32:50 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/05/10#a576&quot;&gt;Update&lt;/a&gt;: The people running the Syndicate conference say I am welcome to speak, but I can't have a sponsor." created="Tue, 10 May 2005 13:55:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The fundamental theorem of calculus" created="Tue, 10 May 2005 09:16:24 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/news/local/la-me-leithold8may08,0,4688756.story?coll=la-home-headlines&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/10/leithold.jpg&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named leithold.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Yesterday on All Things Considered they had a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=4645383&quot;&gt;segment&lt;/a&gt; on a famous professor and book author, Louis Leithold, who died on April 29. They explained how he taught high school calculus in his final years. On the big day, his favorite day of the course, when he unveiled the Fundamental Theorem of Calculus to his students, he'd wear two shirts, an outer shirt and a t-shirt that had the theorem printed on it. At the big moment, when he was ready to reveal the secret, he'd ask &quot;Is it hot in here?&quot; and then rip off the shirt, like a mathematical Superman, and the students would laugh, and there it was, a truth for all to see, discovered by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.maths.tcd.ie/pub/HistMath/People/Newton/RouseBall/RB_Newton.html&quot;&gt;Newton&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mally.stanford.edu/leibniz.html&quot;&gt;Leibniz&lt;/a&gt;, but written by God Almighty, the most advanced mathematics produced by man in their time. " created="Tue, 10 May 2005 09:16:33 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I was a math major, but I had forgotten that there was a Fundamental Theorem of Calculus, and once I remembered that there was one, I couldn't remember what it said (they didn't say on NPR). So I made a note to look it up when I got back to my computer, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathworld.wolfram.com/FundamentalTheoremsofCalculus.html&quot;&gt;so here it is&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 10 May 2005 09:19:59 GMT"/>
					<outline text="And here is the LA Times &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/news/local/la-me-leithold8may08,0,4688756.story?coll=la-home-headlines&quot;&gt;obituary&lt;/a&gt; for Dr Leithold." created="Tue, 10 May 2005 09:35:25 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="More Nashville post-trip notes" created="Tue, 10 May 2005 08:51:33 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/movies/drinksNachosMovie.mov&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/10/rmac.jpg&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;66&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named rmac.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sure, the Nashville blog conference had its share of Limbaugh-like dittoheads, but most of the people were very nice, and the part of Nashville the conference was held in, where the universities are, could be the college section of any city, but more stately and &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; pretty. I thought their university section was nicer than that of New Orleans, Madison or &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/dowbrigade/2005/05/08&quot;&gt;Cambridge&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe it looked so pretty because of the time of year, almost everywhere, early May is a nice time. I bet &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.madison.com/&quot;&gt;Mad-town&lt;/a&gt; looks pretty good this week too. And of course Palo Alto, where I lived for so long, is picture-post-card beautiful 365 days a year. " created="Tue, 10 May 2005 08:45:12 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Three people stand out among my new Nashville aquaintances, two whose name I know; the other, I don't remember. The man without a name spoke with me after the Respectful Disagreement session to say he is politically a Christian conservative, but found my point of view interesting, and said that after the bashing I took in the session he felt he could spend two weeks talking with me and learn something through the whole time. I looked at him, a bit in disbelief, he was dressed very nicely, in the style of an artist. I told him if he were in San Francisco, I'd think he was a left-leaning Democrat. He told me he &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; an artist, but also is a conservative. " created="Tue, 10 May 2005 08:47:40 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I said I felt the same way he does. Given the incongruence of his appearance and his politics, and the fact that he had the self and mutual respect to be generous with a stranger in his hometown, told me there's a grace to conservatives that you would never see if you let the louts speak for all of them. If I were in his shoes, I would have done the same. Make sure that the guest knows that the loudmouths don't speak for everyone. Maybe then that would appear in the stranger's blog a few days after the conference." created="Tue, 10 May 2005 08:55:23 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I also met &lt;a href=&quot;http://nick.typepad.com/&quot;&gt;Nick Bradbury&lt;/a&gt;, a Nashville native, and developer of the FeedDemon feed reader. He's a soft-spoken, gentle, thoughtful man. Can't tell what his politics are, and I didn't ask, possibly because we come from such a politically charged technologic place, the world of RSS.  It's always good to have a face to put with a name. " created="Tue, 10 May 2005 08:54:24 GMT"/>
					<outline text="My host for the trip was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rexblog.com/&quot;&gt;Rex Hammock&lt;/a&gt;, who is a very nice guy, and probably a Republican, something I teased him about endlessly (don't worry he found something to tease me with too). He's an interesting guy, one of the few people with a blog who I seem to always agree with. Even so, he's the blogger who met with President Bush a couple of years ago. How could it be that I always agree with someone who would be invited to such a meeting? (To be clear, I would have accepted the invite myself, had it been offered, but the Republicans don't even allow people like myself to cover their national convention.) I think friendships like this, that are in themselves conundrums, are more important in some ways that friendships between people whose politics are identical. Between Rex and myself there's a clue, some value, a fundamental theorum, that's more important than whether you vote Democratic or Republican. " created="Tue, 10 May 2005 09:10:59 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Anyway, Rex was a fantastic, generous host. I hope someday to be able to return the favor. (But first I have to decide where I'm going to live!)" created="Tue, 10 May 2005 09:14:37 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 9" created="Mon, 09 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay9.mp3&quot;&gt;A podcast&lt;/a&gt; about the difference between &lt;i&gt;broad&lt;/i&gt;casting and &lt;i&gt;pod&lt;/i&gt;casting, and a request for ideas about the first podcasts that will be broadcast." created="Tue, 10 May 2005 00:40:54 GMT" name="aHrefhttpmp3morningcoffeenotescomcnmay9mp3aPodcastaAboutTheDifferenceBetweenIbroadicastingAndIpodicastingAndARequestForIdeasAboutTheFirstPodcastsThatWillBeBroadcast" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay9.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/05/09#a189&quot;&gt;A place&lt;/a&gt; for comments on tonight's podcast." created="Tue, 10 May 2005 01:21:07 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/05/09#a1083&quot;&gt;Pictures&lt;/a&gt; taken over drinks and nachos after BlogNashville." created="Mon, 09 May 2005 23:26:40 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The same scene in a very &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/movies/drinksNachosMovie.mov&quot;&gt;funny movie&lt;/a&gt;. Don't miss the last frame! &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Mon, 09 May 2005 23:37:46 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Some of Kosso's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/camoby/12680848/in/photostream/&quot;&gt;gadgets&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 09 May 2005 23:46:16 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www3.clearlight.com/~acsa/introjs.htm?/~acsa/songfile/TENNESSE.HTM&quot;&gt;Today's song&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Tennessee, Tennessee, there ain't no place I'd rather be. Baby won't you carry me, back to Tennessee.&quot;" created="Mon, 09 May 2005 22:43:50 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Press release: &lt;a href=&quot;http://home.businesswire.com/portal/site/google/index.jsp?ndmViewId=news_view&amp;newsId=20050509005769&amp;newsLang=en&quot;&gt;BMI Launches New Songwriter/Artist Podcast&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 09 May 2005 18:05:37 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/09/wayDownSouthInTheLandOfCott.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/09/theLandThatTimeForgotten.gif&quot; width=&quot;85&quot; height=&quot;54&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;17&quot; vspace=&quot;8&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named theLandThatTimeForgotten.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;We should return the favor and host an open blogging conference in a blue state, and import some of the south's most famous bloggers. Before the conference we should make sure that the most flamey left-wing bloggers are present, the people who posted in the comments on Dean For America, for example; and urge them to hurl insults at our southern brothers and sisters, while we sit back and enjoy the scene (and leave early because we have better things to do). Then, when they return to their red state homes, in Tennessee perhaps, they will feel properly chastised as we continue to slam them on our blogs, and they'll hate the north even more than they did before. Think how much better we'd feel about ourselves! (Sorry for the sarcasm.)" created="Mon, 09 May 2005 15:47:46 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/&quot;&gt;The Huffington Post&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Delivering news and opinion since May 9, 2005.&quot;" created="Mon, 09 May 2005 12:48:22 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Oy you can tell Arianna has a political system designer. Their site only supports RSS 1.0 and Atom, and while many cool sites are included in her blogroll, this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; isn't. This level of route-around can't be an accident. I sent her a note of congratulation and a heads up on the problem. And since I linked to the site before noticing these things, I left the link in place. I think her publication is a good thing, so let's help with the launch, and hope we can be part of her view of the blogosphere. When I met her last fall she certainly seemed pretty inclusive. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Mon, 09 May 2005 13:02:15 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.podbat.com/2005/05/09.html#a65&quot;&gt;I'm on the Blugg and Doctoe&lt;/a&gt; show again this week, calling in from the airport in Nashville, y'all. I wonder if the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.podbat.com/h2g2/HHIKERS_1of6_Archos.avi&quot;&gt;bits&lt;/a&gt; from Amsterdam's Schipol &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.podbat.com/h2g2/HHIKERS_2of6_Archos.avi&quot;&gt;made&lt;/a&gt; it into the podcast? Attenzie austerleaf." created="Mon, 09 May 2005 12:19:44 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://conference.digitalidworld.com/2005/&quot;&gt;Digital ID World&lt;/a&gt; starts today in San Francisco." created="Mon, 09 May 2005 12:10:19 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Remember last week when I was seeking a sponsor for my trip to NY to speak at the Syndicate conference? Several volunteered to do partial sponsorships, but I was looking for one sponsor for the whole trip, and now have one, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.perseus.com/index.html&quot;&gt;Perseus Development&lt;/a&gt;. I've gotten to know &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeffrey.henning.com/cv.htm&quot;&gt;Jeffrey Henning&lt;/a&gt;, over the years, and I'm very happy to thelp build awareness for his company, and their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.perseus.com/survey/news/reviews.html&quot;&gt;products&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Mon, 09 May 2005 12:10:34 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/05/06#a566&quot;&gt;Last week&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;You can have a good format without the other guy being incompetent.&quot;" created="Mon, 09 May 2005 11:35:58 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 8" created="Sun, 08 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="The Gallup Poll &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gallup.com/poll/rss/&quot;&gt;supports RSS&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;News the moment we publish it.&quot;" created="Mon, 09 May 2005 00:50:19 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/05/08#a1059&quot;&gt;My own comments&lt;/a&gt; on the Respectful Disagreement discussion." created="Mon, 09 May 2005 00:31:12 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Listening to a new podcast, &lt;a href=&quot;http://candacecorrigan.com/v-web/b2/index.php&quot;&gt;The Nashville Nobody Knows&lt;/a&gt;. Good stuff. " created="Sun, 08 May 2005 18:22:08 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/05/08#a1051&quot;&gt;Kevin Howarth's notes&lt;/a&gt; from yesterday's Respectful Disagreement session at BlogNashville." created="Sun, 08 May 2005 15:37:57 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 7" created="Sat, 07 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/07/tennessee.gif&quot; width=&quot;125&quot; height=&quot;81&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named tennessee.gif&quot;&gt;The answer we sought at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/05/05#When:12:45:45PM&quot;&gt;Respectful Disagreement&lt;/a&gt; session was yes and no. Most red state and blue state people can get along, even like each other, were it not for a very small number of people who won't let the conversation take place. Five people dominated, if they hadn't, I think we would have found lots of shared values. As it was, we found a few. But it was a hostile exchange, lots of the usual mindless crap you get on political TV shows. A lot was learned. We're going to have to work hard if we want to work together." created="Sat, 07 May 2005 23:43:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay7.mp3&quot;&gt;Today's podcast&lt;/a&gt; discussion at a Nashville restaurant with Hoder and Brendan Greeley about podcasting, context, making money, including a run-in with a Channel 2 camera crew. An interesting discussion." created="Sat, 07 May 2005 18:40:38 GMT" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay7.mp3"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/movies/staciKramer.mov&quot;&gt;Staci Kramer gave&lt;/a&gt; a speech at the Global Voices session." created="Sat, 07 May 2005 16:46:13 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/07/airplane.gif&quot; width=&quot;104&quot; height=&quot;64&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named airplane.gif&quot;&gt;Rebecca just asked me if I &quot;blogged that fact.&quot; No I haven't. I wll now. Aaron Brown was the last bastion of news on CNN. Last week he dedicated a whole show to The Runaway Bride story. That was the last straw. I don't watch CNN anymore. There is no more news on TV. That's the fact that RMac wanted me to blog. Check. " created="Sat, 07 May 2005 15:59:56 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/07/rmac.jpg&quot;&gt;Rebecca MacKinnon&lt;/a&gt; is leading the Global Voices session." created="Sat, 07 May 2005 15:43:52 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/movies/rMacDisussLeader.mov&quot;&gt;Three-D walkthrough&lt;/a&gt; movie of RMac introducing the GV discussion." created="Sat, 07 May 2005 15:48:24 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/05/07#a1049&quot;&gt;Photos&lt;/a&gt; from the Journalism session at BlogNashville." created="Sat, 07 May 2005 15:19:42 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://janus.mtsu.edu/hooker/hooker.html&quot;&gt;John Jay Hooker&lt;/a&gt; gave a brief talk during the Journalism session." created="Sat, 07 May 2005 15:25:20 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.engadget.com/entry/1234000130042399&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/07/billg.jpg&quot; width=&quot;45&quot; height=&quot;64&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named billg.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;My morning walk took me through &lt;a href=&quot;http://history.acusd.edu/gen/recording/music-row.html&quot;&gt;Nashville's Music Row&lt;/a&gt;, which is (I guess) the headquarters of the country music industry. They're mostly small, nicely remodeled houses. The weather couldn't have been better. A little chill, bright blue sky and since it was early on a weekend morning, I had the streets to myself. Of course I brought the Archos with me and listened to the recent Engadget &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.engadget.com/entry/1234000130042399&quot;&gt;interview with Bill Gates&lt;/a&gt;. Highly recommended. Gates should do a regular podcast, he's good. I'd love to interview him about Scoble and blogging, and a bit of RSS, and talk about the media industry and technology. The Engadget interview was good for the hardware and how they're marketing it. Also caught the beginning of the TechNation &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.itconversations.com/shows/detail515.html&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; of John Markoff. More on that later." created="Sat, 07 May 2005 12:05:42 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Human Rights Watch &lt;a href=&quot;http://hrw.org/rss/&quot;&gt;feeds&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sat, 07 May 2005 11:02:03 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://hrw.org/blogs.htm&quot;&gt;Also&lt;/a&gt;: You can become a blogger for human rights." created="Sat, 07 May 2005 14:08:48 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.blogware.com/blog/_archives/2005/5/6/659332.html&quot;&gt;According to I Love Radio&lt;/a&gt;, Chris Lydon's new &quot;Open Source&quot; show on WGBH-FM in Boston (syndicated by PRI) will air on May 30 for an hour at 7PM and every Monday through Thursday thereafter. Congrats to Chris and Mary. I am honored to be a guest on the inaugural show. " created="Sat, 07 May 2005 10:56:37 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/05/07/technology/07tele.html?ex=1273118400&amp;en=0ad186931c756dd5&amp;ei=5090&amp;partner=rssuserland&amp;emc=rss&quot;&gt;NY Times&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;A federal appeals court handed a major setback to Hollywood and the television networks on Friday when it struck down an antipiracy regulation requiring computer and television makers to use new technology that would make it difficult for consumers to copy and distribute digital programs.&quot;" created="Sat, 07 May 2005 04:53:13 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 6" created="Fri, 06 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2005/05/06.html#a10008&quot;&gt;Scoble reports&lt;/a&gt; that Microsoft has reversed its position on the anti-discrimination bill. " created="Sat, 07 May 2005 01:09:59 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/06/airplane.gif&quot; width=&quot;98&quot; height=&quot;36&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named airplane.gif&quot;&gt;I took my first trip on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.southwest.com/&quot;&gt;Southwest Airlines&lt;/a&gt; today, a direct flight from Jax to Nashville. All SW flights are open seating. I got to the airport late, so I got in the third group. The flight was full. I groaned, assuming that meant a middle seat for Uncle Davey. Well, as it turns out, not. As I'm walking on the plane, only four people after me, I spy a middle seat open between two skinny people, a man and a woman, with lots of stuff on the seat inbetween. They look like a husband and wife. I point to the middle seat and ask if it's open. They look at me unpleasantly (I'm big) the man slides over, takes the middle seat and I get the aisle. Lots of leg room, plenty of space for my shoulders. Happy. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Fri, 06 May 2005 22:30:33 GMT"/>
				<outline text="5PM Central: Arrived safely in Nashville, TN." created="Fri, 06 May 2005 22:11:58 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I may have missed &lt;a href=&quot;http://battellemedia.com/archives/001493.php&quot;&gt;some&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchenginejournal.com/index.php?p=1676&quot;&gt;the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.poynter.org/column.asp?id=31&amp;aid=82028&quot;&gt;punditry&lt;/a&gt; on the new Google Web Accelerator offering, but the paranoia seems to have a blind spot. People are justifiably worried about Sergey and Larry knowing where they've been. But what about the other side -- content modification. What if Google decides to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thetwowayweb.com/2005/02/22#a272&quot;&gt;change the content&lt;/a&gt; as it's accelerating it? " created="Fri, 06 May 2005 12:24:34 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/06/hope.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;253&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named hope.jpg&quot;&gt;I cancelled my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.audible.com/&quot;&gt;Audible&lt;/a&gt; subscription this morning. I hadn't used it in a few months yet was still paying the monthly fee. I stopped using it because both the computer I used to download books and the iPod I used to listen to them developed difficulties. I've replaced both the computer and the iPod but the Audible service doesn't transfer because of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_rights_management&quot;&gt;DRM&lt;/a&gt; limits. I think they assume that I'm &quot;stealing&quot; the books. This has always been the problem with copy protection and nothing has changed. The same thing happened with the app I used to digitize CDs, and to record my podcasts. I had to buy new licenses just because I had a hard disk crash. I don't know who to blame, but I'm tired of footting the bill. No point continuing to pay Audible because I can't use their service. They won't let me. However I'll give them credit for making it obvious and easy to opt out. " created="Fri, 06 May 2005 11:05:14 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The University of Calgary has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.ucalgary.ca/index.php/Podcasting&quot;&gt;What is Podcasting page&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 06 May 2005 10:52:52 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/05/06#a566&quot;&gt;A brief essay&lt;/a&gt; about advocacy of XML formats." created="Fri, 06 May 2005 11:38:27 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/05/06/national/06time.html?ex=1273032000&amp;en=cade63cb7f6e26cf&amp;ei=5090&amp;partner=rssuserland&amp;emc=rss&quot;&gt;NY Times&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;If you can just give up a Saturday night, there's a very small chance at it being the biggest event in human history.&quot;" created="Fri, 06 May 2005 08:36:13 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 5" created="Thu, 05 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Apparently Google's new web accelerator is doing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.benjaminadam.com/archives/2005/05/05/bad-google-web-accelerator-bad&quot;&gt;something evil&lt;/a&gt;. But I had the same thing happen with the toolbar, and the same evil behavior persisted after I uninstalled the toolbar. I even wrote about it &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/03/18#When:10:01:48AM&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; on this weblog. I'm still getting taken to Google every time I get a server failure." created="Fri, 06 May 2005 02:10:12 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Mr Warren can &lt;a href=&quot;http://bw.watchtan.com/index.php?id=119&quot;&gt;block Google's irritating ads&lt;/a&gt; in NetNewsWire with CSS. " created="Fri, 06 May 2005 02:15:02 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I missed Dan Gillmor's &lt;a href=&quot;http://dangillmor.typepad.com/dan_gillmor_on_grassroots/2005/05/dave_winer_a_to.html&quot;&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt; on my 50th. Very nice. Thanks Dan!!" created="Thu, 05 May 2005 21:04:30 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I'm getting a bunch of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rexblog.com/2005/05/05#a6662&quot;&gt;good&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.livejournal.com/users/libertango/131694.html&quot;&gt;feedback&lt;/a&gt; on this line: &quot;Basically it's bad economics to spoil a good thing for a couple of incremental bucks today, for zero total bucks later.&quot;" created="Thu, 05 May 2005 21:01:03 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/05/moneymoneymoney.gif&quot; width=&quot;85&quot; height=&quot;60&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named moneymoneymoney.gif&quot;&gt;Progress report on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/05/05#a553&quot;&gt;offer for sponsorship&lt;/a&gt; of my trip to the Syndicate conference on May 17. So far I've only got a few partial offers. I'm still hoping some company goes for the whole trip. Should cost about $1500 when all is said and done. The conference organizers were a little surprised, but I think that's my job, to be surprising. I have to get people to see me more as a whore and less as utopian. And I want to jar them with an ad or two in a place they're not happy about having an ad, so they can empathize with their readers and users a little more than they might otherwise. RSS isn't going to be business as usual, but it certainly can be about business. So if your company wants to participate in a bit of social theater and help out the emerging RSS industry, consider sponsoring my trip to NYC. Thanks. " created="Thu, 05 May 2005 20:45:04 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gigaom.com/2005/05/05/quadruple-5555s/&quot;&gt;Om Malik points&lt;/a&gt; out that today is 05-05-05. Glad I didn't miss that!" created="Thu, 05 May 2005 20:37:15 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Reminder to self: I still have to write the session description for Saturday's discussion at BlogNashville. I finally figured it out at dinner the other night. We need to find a way to discuss our disagreements without burning the bridges. It's not just a red-state blue-state thing, it happens in technology too. It's why some people &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/04/13#mrPickyAndMrCoward&quot;&gt;aren't welcome&lt;/a&gt; at some conferences. Is it racism, sexism, or greed that causes some people to want to exclude others? But first I'm going to treat myself to a rainy day movie. The big debate is whether it should be the Interpreter or the Hitchhiker. Nice problem to have of course. (Postscript: Went to see the Interpreter. I really liked it. I think Nicole Kidman is hot.)" created="Thu, 05 May 2005 16:45:45 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/05/ads.gif&quot;&gt;An example&lt;/a&gt; of an ad in a feed. " created="Thu, 05 May 2005 16:34:01 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/05/05#a553&quot;&gt;Notes on my talk&lt;/a&gt; later this month at the Syndicate conference, with a special limited time offer. Act now!" created="Thu, 05 May 2005 14:31:32 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://weblogs.jupiterresearch.com/analysts/gartenberg/archives/008092.html&quot;&gt;To Michael Gartenberg's point&lt;/a&gt;, his feed and those of his colleagues at Jupiter Research are also ads, even though they include the full content of the posts in the feeds. Having a blog is a smart move for a consultancy like Jupiter. The blog itself is an ad that says &quot;Here we are, we are Jupiter, and this is how we think.&quot; Implicit is &quot;Maybe you'd like to buy our services?&quot; It's an ad the same way Scripting News is an ad, for anything I happen to be selling at the moment, whether it's the software I've been developing, or will develop, or some format or protocol I'd like to see gain adoption. The other day I was asked how I make money from my blog, for the 18 millionth time. I turned it around and asked &quot;How do you make money from your office?&quot; You have an office, of course, as part of your livelihood, but how it makes money depends on what you do. I explained that my weblog is my place of business. If you want to find out what I'm selling, on any given day, the place to look is scripting.com." created="Thu, 05 May 2005 14:00:37 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/05/RSSGreenOnWhite.gif&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;59&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named RSSGreenOnWhite.gif&quot;&gt;Here's some food for thought for &quot;marketers&quot; who say they need to put ads in RSS feeds to make them pay. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleywatcher.com/mt/archives/2005/04/rss_may_generat.php&quot;&gt;By some calculations&lt;/a&gt;, in three years, 27 percent of the NY Times hits will originate from their RSS feeds. The BBC is &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/04/30#When:10:47:06AM&quot;&gt;aiming&lt;/a&gt; for 10 percent by the end of the year. Neither company puts ads in their feeds because: The feeds themselves are ads for the stories they link to, which are revenue-generators. Anything that keeps people from clicking, that confuses them, takes them off course, is going to drop the click-through rate. And it's a good deal for the users, because they get the headlines and summaries for articles they only have a superficial interest in, and can easily access the full stories for articles that they want more information on. The rare win-win. Of course for the marketers win-win isn't good enough, they aren't happy until everyone but them loses. I speak as a fan of the Times and BBC approach, which happens to be the approach of CSM, WSJ, MSNBC, AP, Reuters, and every other mainstream media supporter of RSS, by the way. I am making an issue of this because I don't want to see them swept up in this lunatic frenzy to spoil a really good thing by a few people who have no idea what they would be spoiling. Basically it's bad economics to spoil a good thing for a couple of incremental bucks today, for zero total bucks later. I get branded a &quot;utopian&quot; for this, which is the way it goes. " created="Thu, 05 May 2005 10:07:44 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcastercon.org/blog/?p=15&quot;&gt;Brian Russell&lt;/a&gt; needs $2695 to make PodcasterCon happen. " created="Thu, 05 May 2005 04:07:24 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w2idigitalcitiesconvention.com/overview.html&quot;&gt;I just heard about&lt;/a&gt; a wireless digital cities conference that took place this week in Philadelphia. It was a meeting for cities that are planning wifi infrastructure. There were some Scripting News readers at the conf." created="Thu, 05 May 2005 04:14:27 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 4" created="Wed, 04 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoimagination.org/ps/iraq/credibility.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/04/blair.jpg&quot; width=&quot;45&quot; height=&quot;65&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named blair.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Mini-editorial. I was going to go to the UK for the election, which is tomorrow, until I found out that Blair was a &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.telegraph.co.uk/news/main.jhtml?xml=/news/2005/05/05/nelec05.xml&quot;&gt;shoo-in&lt;/a&gt; for re-election. I didn't want to go then, because I found that so disheartening, especially after all the bullshit we got from Europeans about our election last November (which was second only to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swiftvets.com/&quot;&gt;our&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://politicalhumor.about.com/library/images/blpic-kerryreporting.htm&quot;&gt;bullshit&lt;/a&gt; about the election). Sure we led the war effort in Iraq, but Blair was right there providing political cover for Bush, the whole way. If he hadn't maybe Bush wouldn't have gotten re-elected. So why wasn't there (or was there?) an effective campaign to deny Blair re-election for what he did in the war, the lies he told? Or do the British think somehow that Bush was lying and Blair wasn't, because if you do, I got a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phrases.org.uk/bulletin_board/39/messages/638.html&quot;&gt;bridge&lt;/a&gt; I want to tell you about. " created="Thu, 05 May 2005 00:38:57 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.micropersuasion.com/2005/05/forbes_starts_a.html&quot;&gt;Steve Rubel&lt;/a&gt; sends word that Forbes is starting to podcast." created="Wed, 04 May 2005 20:36:34 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Hats off to the Internet for bringing us the &lt;a href=&quot;http://rconversation.blogs.com/rconversation/2005/05/burka_band.html&quot;&gt;girl band from Afghanistan&lt;/a&gt;, they're hip, they're girls, and they wear Burkas! Wow." created="Thu, 05 May 2005 00:20:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="A guy named &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.livejournal.com/users/mcdordad/6848.html&quot;&gt;McDorDad thinks&lt;/a&gt; I'm a lously marketer. " created="Thu, 05 May 2005 00:01:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://hyku.com/blog/archives/000498.html&quot;&gt;They're starting&lt;/a&gt; to cast Blog -- The Movie!" created="Wed, 04 May 2005 20:50:01 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dawnanddrew.com/dnds_bb/viewtopic.php?t=639&quot;&gt;Dawn &amp; Drew&lt;/a&gt; and family have a very sweet birthday thread. Nice! I love the comment about my tech-savvy parents. The other day I described my mother as an &quot;eBay hacker.&quot; It's true!" created="Wed, 04 May 2005 09:02:59 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Could Scoble's ego stand any more inflation? " created="Wed, 04 May 2005 08:45:04 GMT">
					<outline text="We'll find out, now that Bill Gates Himself &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.seattlepi.nwsource.com/microsoft/archives/004772.html&quot;&gt;wants&lt;/a&gt; to be interviewed on his Channel 9 video feed. " created="Wed, 04 May 2005 08:50:14 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://pbcliberal.users.blogmatrix.com/podcasts/2005/05.02/0000/&quot;&gt;PBC Liberal&lt;/a&gt; posits that video blogging may displace podcasting in about (big radio pause) 5 seconds. I always dismiss that when asked, saying that podcasting is great because you can listen on a subway, while you're driving, or walking. But maybe he has a point. " created="Wed, 04 May 2005 08:50:34 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Video is big with today's kids. I have gotten a whole new appreciation for it, carrying around the Archos. It's a kid magnet. They want to know what it is. I say it plays videos and music, and can run my own software. They think that part is really interesting. How do you get stuff on it, a seven year old asks. I connect it to my laptop. He nods knowingly. What interface? USB 2.0. Uh huh. " created="Wed, 04 May 2005 08:57:19 GMT"/>
					<outline text="This is a new world ladies and gentlemen." created="Wed, 04 May 2005 08:51:23 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/04/news-banana.gif&quot; width=&quot;33&quot; height=&quot;35&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named news-banana.gif&quot;&gt;"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 3" created="Tue, 03 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Folks, listen to what &lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.weblogs.com/2005/05/03#takingTheFork&quot;&gt;Papa Doc says&lt;/a&gt; about podcasting and radio. " created="Wed, 04 May 2005 01:24:47 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcastingnews.com/archives/2005/05/podfather_dave.html&quot;&gt;Podcasting News&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;In a surprise move only tangentially related to podcasting, iconoclast and developer Dave Winer turned 50 today.&quot; " created="Wed, 04 May 2005 01:18:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chumfm.com/podcast/CHUMFMPodcasting.asp&quot;&gt;Broadcast to podcast&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Every weekday you can download highlights from CHUM FM’s Morning Show with Roger Rick and Marilyn to your MP3 player.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Bing!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Wed, 04 May 2005 01:14:44 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnet.com/4520-6033_1-6214591-1.html?tag=cnetfd.sd&quot;&gt;CNET&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;We media types need to quit kowtowing to manufacturers who are trying in vain to hold on to the last shred of control they think they have. Those manufacturers need to wake up and smell the RSS feeds--the information's already out there.&quot;" created="Wed, 04 May 2005 01:03:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Kosso sent an email suggesting I do an image search on Google for &quot;xml inventors.&quot; Please don't go there if you are easily frightened or are under a certain age, or prone to nightmares." created="Wed, 04 May 2005 00:50:39 GMT"/>
				<outline text="WSJ: &lt;a href=&quot;http://online.wsj.com/public/article/0,,SB111507332363322596-fh27AEoX3_U3IT_7XFntAZ2mw6k_20050602,00.html?mod=public_home_us&quot;&gt;Corporate Marketers Try Out Blogs&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 04 May 2005 02:19:13 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/entry/2005/05/03#2575&quot;&gt;Rogers Cadenhead&lt;/a&gt; has lost his mind. He's giving away free Radio UserLand books." created="Tue, 03 May 2005 22:06:49 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I keep meaning to write an update of my Archos mini-computer. I take it everywhere with me and love it. It works really well. I keep discovering things it can do. The wifi hardly works at all. This isn't the review, btw, just the reminder that I owe you one." created="Tue, 03 May 2005 22:09:33 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Leon Winer, PhD: &quot;If you think fifty is nifty let me tell you that at seventy-five it's great to be alive.&quot;" created="Tue, 03 May 2005 22:12:46 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://podcatcher.rubyforge.org/&quot;&gt;Armangil's podcatcher&lt;/a&gt; is a &quot;podcast client for the command line.&quot;" created="Tue, 03 May 2005 22:11:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://whoisylvia.typepad.com/my_weblog/2005/05/birthday_for_bi.html&quot;&gt;Sylvia's love letter&lt;/a&gt; to two Daves, one of whom is me! &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Tue, 03 May 2005 15:02:59 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/03/chuckBerry.jpg&quot; width=&quot;95&quot; height=&quot;148&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named chuckBerry.jpg&quot;&gt;Now that the &quot;marketing&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;http://dictionary.reference.com/search?q=idiots&quot;&gt;folk&lt;/a&gt; have arrived in RSS-land, I've become a &lt;a href=&quot;http://dictionary.reference.com/search?q=utopian&quot;&gt;utopian&lt;/a&gt;. Isn't that funny. Hey remember, this an optional advertising place. Treat me with respect or your subscription goes into the bit-bucket. Marketing guys and their messages. I can think of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://dictionary.reference.com/search?q=sleazebag&quot;&gt;few&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://dictionary.reference.com/search?q=scumbag&quot;&gt;choice&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://dictionary.reference.com/search?q=Republican&quot;&gt;words&lt;/a&gt; for them. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Tue, 03 May 2005 13:13:19 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I thought I would do a lot of podcasts last night, but nope -- too busy schmoozing and the place was so loud. Lots of good gossip. I think we're becoming an industry. And I'm seeing people for the third and fourth times at NY dinner events, so there's some continuity developing. Of course we don't all agree, but that's part of the fun. Lots of good data exchanged. And then we do it again, starting Friday, at a Southern blog meetup on a huge scale, in Nashville, y'all!" created="Tue, 03 May 2005 12:59:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="What a birthday. My voice is gone. Good sign. Speaking with Jim Moore from a cab yesterday afternoon he thought I sounded like Bob Dylan. Heh. If he heard me now he'd think he was talking with &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Everett_Dirksen&quot;&gt;Everett Dirksen&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Tue, 03 May 2005 12:18:18 GMT"/>
				<outline text="More comments on the Curry-Sirius deal" created="Tue, 03 May 2005 09:38:52 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gigaom.com/2005/05/02/curry-casting/&quot;&gt;Om Malik posits&lt;/a&gt; that the deal is really about broadcasting not podcasting. " created="Tue, 03 May 2005 09:34:50 GMT"/>
					<outline text="When you combine yesterday's announcement with the weekend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.curry.com/2005/04/29#a7132&quot;&gt;strategy-cast&lt;/a&gt; that becomes obvious. Some talent is leaving the podcastosphere, and joining the broadcastosphere, where the issues are different. They don't have to worry about podsafe music up in satellite-land because they've made their deal with the RIAA. That means that there will be new content created for the 4-hour broadcast that &lt;i&gt;can't&lt;/i&gt; be played on the Internet. " created="Tue, 03 May 2005 09:39:17 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The scaling issues that confront a popular podcast like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dailysourcecode.com/&quot;&gt;DSC&lt;/a&gt; go away in the satellite system that already has its scaling worked out. But also gone is the breathless freedom, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cnJan22.mp3&quot;&gt;DIYness&lt;/a&gt; of podcasting. As one of Om's commenters points out, the satellite people will want some control, the kind of control that isn't present in podcasts." created="Tue, 03 May 2005 09:39:40 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The BitTorrent corner-turn is nowhere near as hard as some think, but it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a corner-turn, and will require careful work with developers. Now that the air has cleared, and we can see that there are two distinct approaches, one which is a revisit of an old medium (radio), and the other a continuation of the new (podcasting), it could be time for the podcast community to get moving again." created="Tue, 03 May 2005 09:41:15 GMT"/>
					<outline text="But there's still another shoe out there,which has yet to drop. Odeo. In the spirit of &quot;we do what we know how to do,&quot; it seems fair to assume that Ev and company will look at podcasting and see Blogger plus some of the community improvements of Flickr. I suspect that will further clear up what podcasting is, and isn't. " created="Tue, 03 May 2005 09:42:28 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/05/03#a174&quot;&gt;Comment here&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 03 May 2005 13:09:31 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 2" created="Mon, 02 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.micropersuasion.com/2005/04/scoble_rubel_ho.html&quot;&gt;See you&lt;/a&gt; at 6PM at Grand Central Station!" created="Mon, 02 May 2005 17:06:46 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Search Engine Watch has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.searchenginewatch.com/blog/050502-214904&quot;&gt;clue&lt;/a&gt; about some kind of feed reader from Google." created="Tue, 03 May 2005 03:25:44 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Thanks everyone from the bottom of my heart for all the grrrreat birthday wishes. Tonight's geek dinner was so warm, so friendly, there were 60 geeks there all singing happy birthday. I haven't had such a nice birthday since the big 3-0. I especially appreciate the kind words from Dan Bricklin and Wes Felter. So many great messages. It's been a great thoroughly exhausting day, and one to remember, forever. Thank you so much!!" created="Tue, 03 May 2005 02:15:18 GMT"/>
				<outline text="On this day in 1997, &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.scripting.com/1997/05/02/ProofthatyouExist&quot;&gt;Proof that You Exist&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 03 May 2005 02:19:15 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Much appreciated &lt;a href=&quot;http://photomatt.net/2005/05/02/dave-50/&quot;&gt;hat-tip&lt;/a&gt; from Matt Mullenweg. " created="Tue, 03 May 2005 02:10:10 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I just checked in at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://grandnewyork.hyatt.com/property/index.jhtml&quot;&gt;Grand Hyatt&lt;/a&gt; in NY, and this is the first hotel I've been to that has T-Mobile wireless. I was able to use my ordinary account, just sign on, and go. I'd prefer free Internet, but if they have to make it for-pay this is the way to go. " created="Mon, 02 May 2005 18:18:08 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Very active &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/podcasters/messages&quot;&gt;discussion&lt;/a&gt; on the Podcasters mail list. " created="Mon, 02 May 2005 16:51:03 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogdex.net/&quot;&gt;Wow all the birthday links&lt;/a&gt; are pushing Scripting News toward the top of Blogdex. That's cool!" created="Mon, 02 May 2005 16:46:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acidplanet.com/podcasts/&quot;&gt;Acid Planet&lt;/a&gt; is a podcasting community in Madison." created="Mon, 02 May 2005 16:44:15 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://disneyland.disney.go.com/disneyland/en_US/calendar/specialEvents/detail?name=PodcastingSpecialEventDetailPageGold&amp;CMP=ILC-vanurlpodcast&amp;bhcp=1&quot;&gt;DisneyLand turns 50 too&lt;/a&gt;, and has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://disneyland.disney.go.com/disneyland/en_US/rss/podcast/disneylandresort50th&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; to celebrate. " created="Mon, 02 May 2005 15:32:32 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.weblogs.com/2005/05/01#heresToTheNext50&quot;&gt;Highest praise&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;When they scroll the credits of my life, Dave's is going to be one of the first names on the list.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Wow.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 02 May 2005 15:26:26 GMT"/>
				<outline text="A birthday &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay2.mp3&quot;&gt;breakfast podcast&lt;/a&gt; at a noisy restaurant with my parents. We talk about idea processors, Macs, eBay, buying and selling online." created="Mon, 02 May 2005 14:47:44 GMT" type="link" url="http://mp3.morningcoffeenotes.com/cnMay2.mp3"/>
				<outline text="10:30AM Eastern: Arrived safely in NYC." created="Mon, 02 May 2005 14:37:14 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/dir/davesWorld/history/previousHeaderGraphics/sedonaArizona&quot;&gt;New header graphic&lt;/a&gt;. Sedona, Arizona." created="Mon, 02 May 2005 08:53:56 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Thanks for all the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.langmaker.com/db/log_0505.htm#NoFineWineBeforeItsTime&quot;&gt;great&lt;/a&gt; birthday wishes. &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/palfrey/2005/05/02#a847&quot;&gt;To John Palfrey&lt;/a&gt;, actually your link &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/05/01#aBirthdayRequest&quot;&gt;counts&lt;/a&gt; as much as any other link in the Technorati &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.technorati.com/live/top100.html&quot;&gt;list&lt;/a&gt;. They're not weighted (at least that's the way it looks). There are some other parables out there, some highly opinionated ones, in fact, but rather than point to them, I'll let you go digging for them. It seems that turning 50 (me? 50? no way) inspires parables. As Tim Bray &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2005/05/01/Winer_50&quot;&gt;pointed&lt;/a&gt; out there sure are lot of us old fuckers out there. Yeah I can sign up for the AARP now sonny, so listen up. It doesn't seem right that old people can do cool stuff, so I'll just stay young at heart. Hehe. Stop laughing. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Mon, 02 May 2005 07:52:29 GMT"/>
				<outline text="A parable from the West Wing" created="Mon, 02 May 2005 06:31:47 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://westwing.bewarne.com/pres.html&quot;&gt;President Bartlet&lt;/a&gt; is the president we all wish we could have but can't. He's a rich chocolate cake with ice cream and hot fudge topped with whipped cream and nuts and a cherry. A cookie on the side." created="Mon, 02 May 2005 06:32:04 GMT"/>
					<outline text="He sees a Republican consultant on a political show clean the clock of bright &lt;a href=&quot;http://westwing.bewarne.com/sam.html&quot;&gt;Sam Seaborn&lt;/a&gt;, one of the leading minds of his generation, and insists that Leo McGarry, the grizzled chief of staff with the big heart, hire her. Leo protests that he'll change his mind in the morning, but the President assures him he won't." created="Mon, 02 May 2005 06:33:17 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The Republican &lt;a href=&quot;http://westwing.bewarne.com/ainsley.html&quot;&gt;consultant&lt;/a&gt; gets the job, and becomes less snotty but not much. She's assigned to work on a case with her former nemesis Sam Seaborn, the bright guy who helps a hooker because he's got a big dumb streak in him (but we love him even more because of it). She's given the task of summarizing a memo that Sam wrote about helping small business people, but in doing so, changes Sam's opinion to something very Republican. At first Sam is pissed, but then he stops and says &quot;Wait a minute she's right.&quot; So he presents her idea to &lt;a href=&quot;http://westwing.bewarne.com/leo.html&quot;&gt;Leo McGarry&lt;/a&gt;, at the end of a long day with the lights turned down low, he's sipping a cup of coffee, with a stack of work waiting for him, but he has time for Sam and his Republican consultant assistant. " created="Mon, 02 May 2005 06:34:21 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&quot;I thought we were going the other way,&quot; Leo says to Sam, lowering his eyeglasses so we can tell he's surprised, but thoughtful,. &quot;Yes, we were but this spunky and sassy Republican consultant you hired convinced me to go the other way.&quot; Leo puts down his coffee, pauses for a moment, says Okay and signs the memo and moves it to his out box. Sam and his young consultant friend are whisked out of the room so Leo can resume dealing with other important affairs at the end of a long but satisfying day at the White House." created="Mon, 02 May 2005 06:37:42 GMT"/>
					<outline text="As they're walking away, the consultant is shrill. &quot;But but you weren't supposed to do what I told you to do!&quot; she shouts. You can tell she's panicked because she didn't think anything would come of her having a contrary opinion and being so sassy about it. Sam says &quot;But you were right,&quot; and walks off stage." created="Mon, 02 May 2005 06:39:40 GMT"/>
					<outline text="She's left standing in the middle of the White House offices, with people whirring by purposefully, all doing important things that change our lives, because they work in the best place in the world and can do powerful things." created="Mon, 02 May 2005 06:41:02 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The point of this story, I feel like the Republican consultant. You guys weren't supposed to &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; what I told you to do! I was just having an opinion. " created="Mon, 02 May 2005 06:41:48 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&quot;curly&quot;" created="Mon, 02 May 2005 06:47:18 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Adam's new gig" created="Mon, 02 May 2005 07:58:55 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/05/02/business/media/02SIRIUS.html?ex=1272686400&amp;en=742729572081f9b8&amp;ei=5090&amp;partner=rssuserland&amp;emc=rss&quot;&gt;NY Times&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Adam Curry will produce and be host of a four-hour program every weekday starting May 13 on Sirius Satellite Radio.&quot; " created="Mon, 02 May 2005 07:23:11 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I guess we all do what we know how to do. He always wanted to compete with Howard Stern, now he gets to." created="Mon, 02 May 2005 07:57:28 GMT"/>
					<outline text="He's got a good lineup with Dawn &amp; Drew, and the other podshow gods and goddesses. Hope they all got a good deal." created="Mon, 02 May 2005 07:59:25 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 1" created="Sun, 01 May 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.megnut.com/2005/05/when-a-party-of-one-isnt-alone&quot;&gt;A sweet story&lt;/a&gt; of France from Megnut. &quot;I settled into my seat and watched the families and couples enjoy their dinner while I slurped my last briny oysters of my visit. And the feeling of being alone was forgotten.&quot;" created="Mon, 02 May 2005 02:06:50 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2005/05/01/Winer_50&quot;&gt;An interesting post&lt;/a&gt; from Tim Bray about a club I didn't know I was a member of! " created="Mon, 02 May 2005 02:09:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I've been getting nice email on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/04/30#When:9:23:53PM&quot;&gt;thunderstorm podcast&lt;/a&gt;. I listened to it a second time, and realized I should let you in on a secret. I got the sense of how long after a lightning bolt the thunder clap would come. Because you couldn't see the lightning, you didn't know when the thunder was coming, but I did, and was able to use it to good effect in the podcast. Another example of &lt;b&gt;g&lt;/b&gt;odcasting, a collaborative effort, with your humble servant, Uncle Davey. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Sun, 01 May 2005 22:38:58 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/05/01#a168&quot;&gt;Raymond Poort sent&lt;/a&gt; me one of those nice emails about the thunderstorm podcast. It's great to hear from him." created="Mon, 02 May 2005 00:04:40 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podbat.com/login/&quot;&gt;Podbat&lt;/a&gt; would like you to log in. " created="Mon, 02 May 2005 02:04:28 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I just listened to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.itconversations.com/shows/detail502.html&quot;&gt;podcasting panel&lt;/a&gt; from SXSW and it was excellent. I loved the idea of an RSS-enabled alarm clock. You know someday you'll have one, maybe pretty soon. " created="Sun, 01 May 2005 22:37:08 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2005/05/01.html#a9967&quot;&gt;The New York Geek Dinner&lt;/a&gt; tomorrow night is shaping up as an extra-va-ganza. Mary Jo Foley. Joel Spolsky. Scoble. Rubel. " created="Sun, 01 May 2005 12:42:05 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://politicalwire.com/archives/2005/05/01/laura_bush_desperate_housewife.html&quot;&gt;Laura Bush&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I was a librarian that spent 12 hours a day in the library. Yet somehow I met George.&quot;" created="Sun, 01 May 2005 14:40:28 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/dowbrigade/2005/05/01#a4965&quot;&gt;Dowbrigade&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;...a white limousine, which had apparently exploded just as it was entering Johnson Gate, the main entrance to Harvard Yard off of Massachusetts Avenue, a mere 50 feet from the office of Harvard President Lawrence Summers.&quot;" created="Sun, 01 May 2005 17:08:42 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blaserco.com/blogs/2005/05/01.html#a345&quot;&gt;Britt Blaser&lt;/a&gt; has an imporant announcement to make. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Sun, 01 May 2005 12:00:04 GMT"/>
				<outline text="People sometimes ask why the header graphic on Scripting News doesn't usually reflect the place I'm at. As far as I know the only time that it did was &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2004/07/26/demCon.jpg&quot;&gt;when&lt;/a&gt; I was at the Democratic National Convention in Boston last summer. Anyway, the reason it's different is that I like the change of scenery. Where ever you are, after a while, seems less exotic than some other place. Nothing more than that." created="Sun, 01 May 2005 19:47:16 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Morning coffee notes" created="Sun, 01 May 2005 11:45:32 GMT">
					<outline text="Good morning everybody!" created="Sun, 01 May 2005 11:37:44 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Don't miss the thunderstorm &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/04/30#When:9:23:53PM&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt;, I think it came out pretty good." created="Sun, 01 May 2005 11:37:50 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Today's the last day of my forties. I'm ready to make the transition. What does turning 50 mean? Well, if I make it, I lived longer than Douglas Adams. When he died at the tender age of 49 (which happens to be how old I am right now, but you knew that) it made me feel some very mortal feelings. That's how deaths of other people always are. You can try all you want to &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; make it about you, but that's all you know about. " created="Sun, 01 May 2005 11:38:09 GMT"/>
					<outline text="What's it like to die? Some people believe they know, but that's just a belief. You won't know for sure until it happens to you. And that, my friends, is both the curse and the blessing of humanity. It's the curse because it haunts each of us from the age of seven or eight when it first hits us that &lt;i&gt;we're going to die too.&lt;/i&gt; I remember very well lying in bed as a small child totally freaked out about this. It becomes the backdrop of all we do, it's where our sense of urgency comes from, if it weren't for this, why would we ever actually do anything?" created="Sun, 01 May 2005 11:50:59 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It's also a blessing because we get rid of old ideas and old thinking. Every seventy or eighty years we do a complete refresh of the species. No idea gets to continue along without being examined by fresh minds, and this probably has led to a lot of the growth of our species. It's why the sense of &quot;things have always been this way and always will&quot; actually changes so often. If we didn't die, it probably wouldn't." created="Sun, 01 May 2005 11:41:33 GMT"/>
					<outline text="So one more birthday, one year closer to the end, whenever that will be. Ooops, ten years closer to the end. Maybe it will be a relief. Whew. Don't have to do this for another ten years. That was the feeling at 40, and it surprised me. I looked inside, after the fact, and wondered why I dreaded it so. Turns out it was because I thought at 40 I would turn into my father. I didn't, I was still me. Now as I turn 50, it seems it wouldn't be such a terrible thing to turn into my father. Not a small bit of progress for one man, in just ten years, wouldn't you say?" created="Sun, 01 May 2005 11:43:00 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="A birthday request" created="Sun, 01 May 2005 11:45:57 GMT">
					<outline text="If you want to wish me a happy birthday, first, let me say, thank you, mazel tov, a blessing back at ya, namaste and let's have fun. I have one request, which I get to make because it'll be my birthday tomorrow, and I'm getting in practice for one day of pure selfishness. Instead of sending an email, if you have a blog, how about posting your wishes on your blog with a link to mine? I could always use some more flow, and I'd love to climb a few notches on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.technorati.com/live/top100.html&quot;&gt;Technorati list&lt;/a&gt;, truth be told. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Sun, 01 May 2005 11:46:00 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			</outline>
		</body>
	</opml>
