<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- OPML generated by OPML Editor v10.1b19 on Wed, 22 Dec 2021 16:02:27 GMT -->
<opml version="2.0">
	<head>
		<title>Scripting News</title>
		<dateCreated>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 16:02:24 GMT</dateCreated>
		<dateModified>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 16:02:27 GMT</dateModified>
		<ownerName>Dave Winer</ownerName>
		<ownerId>http://davewiner.com/</ownerId>
		<expansionState>1</expansionState>
		<vertScrollState>1</vertScrollState>
		<windowTop>631</windowTop>
		<windowLeft>1087</windowLeft>
		<windowBottom>831</windowBottom>
		<windowRight>1472</windowRight>
		</head>
	<body>
		<outline text="September 2005" created="Thu, 01 Sep 2005 05:00:02 GMT">
			<outline text="September 30" created="Fri, 30 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niallkennedy.com/blog/archives/2005/09/opml_listing_of_my_weblog_entr.html&quot;&gt;On Niall Kennedy's blog&lt;/a&gt;, Jeremy Zawodny asked what OPML is for. I answered in terms that might make sense to a Yahoo. \&quot;Jeremy, you could think of OPML as a way for users to author structures that work like &lt;a href=&quot;http://dir.yahoo.com/Computers_and_Internet/Internet/World_Wide_Web/Weblogs/&quot;&gt;dir.yahoo.com&lt;/a&gt;. It's like blogging but for hierarchies of links. Another way of looking at it is that RSS is designed for time-based info, news; and OPML is for structures of information that change less frequently, where what matters is the relationship between ideas.\&quot;" created="Fri, 30 Sep 2005 23:46:05 GMT"/>
				<outline text="1/14/04: &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.scripting.com/powerOpmlGuidelines&quot;&gt;Guidelines for more powerful OPML&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sat, 01 Oct 2005 00:51:27 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Roger Benningfield has &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.worldoutline.com/2005/September/30/Roger%20Benningfield%27s%20JournURL%20blog/&quot;&gt;implemented&lt;/a&gt; category OPML for JournURL." created="Fri, 30 Sep 2005 21:28:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/30/puppy.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/30/labpupsmall.jpg&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;62&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named labpupsmall.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.opml.org/belaLabovitch/2005/09/30#checkOutTheNewVersionOfAHrefwwwopmlsearchcomaHrefhttpwwwopmlsearchcomopmlSearchaa&quot;&gt;RSS Labs has&lt;/a&gt; an OPML search engine that does it in the Googlish way I described so many years ago. When it finds what you're looking for in an OPML file, it offers to show it to you as a directory. Simple, brain-dead obvious, imho. Of course the other search engines only know about HTML. In an age when there are billions of feeds out there, it's getting pretty lame to only read HTML, don't you think!" created="Fri, 30 Sep 2005 21:33:28 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cn05Sep30.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast&lt;/a&gt;: The story of the TechCrunch Directory box on Scripting News, the OPML behind it, Robert Scoble, Niall Kennedy, Matt Mullenweg and Mike Arrington. &quot;Users and developers party together.&quot;" category="/Harvard/Berkman" created="Fri, 30 Sep 2005 15:04:26 GMT" type="link" url="http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cn05Sep30.mp3"/>
				<outline text="In the rush yesterday I mis-spelled Matt's last name (instead of &quot;weg&quot; I typed &quot;web&quot;), and in an email asked for a change in the URL for the by-category OPML for the WordPress blogs. Both changes &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.worldoutline.com/2005/September/30/&quot;&gt;evident here&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Fri, 30 Sep 2005 11:48:53 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2005/09/30.html#a11296&quot;&gt;Scoble sets&lt;/a&gt; a developer straight about the proper way to address users. Good work Scoble. The guy is just trying to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FUD&quot;&gt;FUD&lt;/a&gt; you. It's great to see a user stand up to that kind of crap. Judge technology by results, not arrogance. There's no shortage of idiots who want you to justify your wants to them. &lt;a href=&quot;http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2005/09/its-coders-world-we-just-live-in-it.html&quot;&gt;Google says&lt;/a&gt; &quot;It's a coder's world -- we just live in it.&quot; That's just plain wrong. Hubris. We live in god's world. " created="Fri, 30 Sep 2005 12:20:03 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I wonder if any of you remember the PFS products. There was PFS:File and PFS:Report. Then PFS:Write, they had a graphics program, and a spreadsheet called PFS:Plan. Then I tried to remember what PFS stood for, I'm sure it didn't mean what I &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/30/pfs.gif&quot;&gt;thought it meant&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Fri, 30 Sep 2005 12:36:33 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/30/nasa.gif&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;54&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named nasa.gif&quot;&gt;David Mercer, via email: &quot;I think that the Google/NASA deal stinks to high heaven of all sorts of unfair advantage to Google.  Everything NASA does should, as all non-classified things are in Federal Agencies, be public domain.  Sounds like Google are trying to get a super-cozy sweetheart deal on collaborations that sound to me a lot like they will help their core businesses, which have nothing whatsoever to do with NASA or their mission.  Which is unlike, say, Boeing working with NASA, as things Boeing develops have to do with what NASA is up to, not merely in the other direction.&quot;" created="Fri, 30 Sep 2005 11:53:14 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nasa.gov/centers/ames/news/releases/2005/05_50AR.html&quot;&gt;NASA press release&lt;/a&gt; announcing deal with Google." created="Fri, 30 Sep 2005 11:55:33 GMT"/>
				<outline text="David has a point. As a US taxpayer, I wonder why my government is doing deals to help one technology company and not &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; technology companies. Who bribed who to make that happen. Further, I don't understand why Google's search engine doesn't understand RSS. Shouldn't they take care of that before they worry about space travel, if that's what they're doing? And why don't their competitors' search engines take advantage of the billions of feeds out there? Come on MSN, Yahoo, Jeeves, let's go, there's some butt to kick here. And they say this industry is driven by innovation. Feh. It's driven by press releases." created="Fri, 30 Sep 2005 11:57:40 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 29" created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/29/screen1.gif&quot;&gt;See&lt;/a&gt; the TechCrunch Directory in the right margin? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thetwowayweb.com/2005/09/29#a2069&quot;&gt;It's new!&lt;/a&gt;" created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 11:36:29 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techcrunch.com/2005/09/29/opml-an-awesome-experiment/&quot;&gt;Mike Arrington&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;We’ve created a directory, in OPML format, of every TechCrunch company profile.&quot;" created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 23:05:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2005/09/29.html#a11295&quot;&gt;Scoble&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I will switch to the blogging tool that outputs OPML automatically like what Michael Arrington did by hand.&quot;" created="Fri, 30 Sep 2005 01:43:45 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/29/puppy.jpg&quot; width=&quot;125&quot; height=&quot;182&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named puppy.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niallkennedy.com/blog/archives/2005/09/opml_listing_of_my_weblog_entr.html&quot;&gt;Niall Kennedy&lt;/a&gt; created a template that teaches Movable Type how to produce &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niallkennedy.com/blog/index.opml&quot;&gt;categorized OPML&lt;/a&gt; per Scoble's request. And it &lt;i&gt;works.&lt;/i&gt; Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/29/niallOpml.gif&quot;&gt;screen shot&lt;/a&gt; of Niall's OPML in my outliner. And here's the same outline viewed through my directory &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.worldoutline.com/2005/September/29/&quot;&gt;browser&lt;/a&gt;. Ahhhhh. That's the sound of developers and users partying together. &quot;You can get anything you want...&quot;" created="Fri, 30 Sep 2005 02:59:02 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Next up, I got an email from Matt Mullenweg saying that he's got every blog on wordpress.com supporting categorized OPML. It works. I was able to &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.worldoutline.com/2005/September/29/Matt%20Mullenweb%27s%20WordPress%20blog/&quot;&gt;browse&lt;/a&gt; his OPML. &quot;Walk right in, it's around the back....&quot;" created="Fri, 30 Sep 2005 03:24:43 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://reactor-core.org/~djw/apex1500/restore/Arlo%20Guthrie%20-%20Alices%20Restaurant.mp3&quot;&gt;Today's song&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;You can get anything you want, at Alice's Restaurant. You can get anything you want. At Alice's Restaurant. Walk right in it's around the back, just a half a mile from the railroad track. And you can get anything you want at Alice's Restaurant.&quot;" created="Fri, 30 Sep 2005 01:55:17 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Glad to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.news.harvard.edu/gazette/2005/09.29/02-rss.html&quot;&gt;see&lt;/a&gt; Harvard &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hno.harvard.edu/rss/&quot;&gt;support&lt;/a&gt; RSS 2.0. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 21:14:52 GMT"/>
				<outline text="A year ago yesterday, &lt;a href=&quot;http://new.itgarage.com/node/462&quot;&gt;Doc Searls predicted&lt;/a&gt; there would be hundreds of thousands, &quot;maybe even millions&quot; of hits on Google for podcast. Doc was actually thinking small, it turns out. According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://reilly.typepad.com/cameronreilly/2005/09/doc_searls_blew.html&quot;&gt;Cameron Relly&lt;/a&gt;, there are over &lt;b&gt;61 million&lt;/b&gt; hits. How's that for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/26/hiddenMeme.gif&quot;&gt;meme&lt;/a&gt;. Yo &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.curry.com/&quot;&gt;Adam&lt;/a&gt;, we actually created something. &lt;i&gt;Feels good.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 23:27:03 GMT"/>
				<outline text="In February of this year, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rexblog.com/2005/02/20#a5901&quot;&gt;Rex Hammock explained&lt;/a&gt; how things like podcasting happen. " created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 23:40:19 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Is it just me, or does anyone else wonder about the propriety of a US government agency doing a deal with Google? Maybe there's nothing wrong with it, after all software companies sell stuff to the government all the time. But who's the customer here. Hard to tell. " created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 21:08:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buzzmachine.com/index.php/2005/09/29/recovery-20-help-may-need-meeting-space-in-sf/&quot;&gt;Jeff Jarvis&lt;/a&gt; may need meeting space in SF next week. " created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 21:10:40 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Went over to see Mike Arrington, we talked about the new directory and came to an interesting place. It all would have been easier if WordPress, the blogging software he uses, produced an OPML file listing all the articles in his blog, according to the category they appear in. Then Mike took it to the next place. Once in OPML, he could do a more robust categorization. Two-way. &lt;i&gt;Exactly!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 20:54:20 GMT"/>
				<outline text="From Scott Young comes news that a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.userland.com/2005/09/29#a72&quot;&gt;public beta of Manila 9.6&lt;/a&gt; is now available." created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 20:56:54 GMT"/>
				<outline text="With the new version of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macromedia.com/software/flash/flashpro/&quot;&gt;Flash&lt;/a&gt; out, it's time to renew the request for a weblog-viewer in Flash, with an integrated Edit This Page style editor. " created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 17:32:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Roberts was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/09/29/politics/politicsspecial1/29cnd-confirm.html?ex=1285646400&amp;en=d3fd144731d5789f&amp;ei=5090&amp;partner=rssuserland&amp;emc=rss&quot;&gt;confirmed&lt;/a&gt; as Chief Justice. To be sworn in today." created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 17:29:57 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Roberts is the name of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.robertsmarket.com/homepage.shtml&quot;&gt;fancy supermarket&lt;/a&gt; in Woodside, CA." created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 23:37:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.docnotes.net/002307.html&quot;&gt;Jacob Reider's history&lt;/a&gt; of medical weblogs going back to 1998." created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 11:34:06 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I had &quot;guilty until proven innocent&quot; below. A bunch of readers caught that. Hey it's good to know people are reading. " created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 17:25:18 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Had a doctor's appt today with my &lt;a href=&quot;http://dictionary.reference.com/search?q=general%20practitioner&quot;&gt;GP&lt;/a&gt; -- I've been seeing her for &lt;i&gt;18 years.&lt;/i&gt; It was good to get back in the loop. Her 12-year-old daughter has a blog. I apologized. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 17:26:26 GMT"/>
				<outline text="DeLay and guilt" created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 12:13:41 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/29/prosecutor.pg.jpg&quot; width=&quot;45&quot; height=&quot;57&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named prosecutor.pg.jpg&quot;&gt;On TV last night the Republicans were either swinging at the Texas &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/09/29/politics/29earle.html?ex=1285646400&amp;en=9d2218e4c2f0eae6&amp;ei=5090&amp;partner=rssuserland&amp;emc=rss&quot;&gt;prosecutor&lt;/a&gt; who indicted Tom DeLay, or calling Democrats names, or saying that Kay Bailey Hutchinson had similar charges leveled at her and they were dropped. I wondered if it occurred to them to shut up. Or maybe to talk about how important it is to have clean elections. &quot;Innocent until proven guilty&quot; is a rule juries must abide by, as long as I'm not on the jury, I can decide he's guilty whenever I want. That they yell, so loudly, saying nothing but dirt, responding only by trying to change the subject, says one thing to me. The trail leads to them. They talk about liberals as if they had a philosophy other than robbing us blind. We're fools for putting up with this, and the Republicans are the worst fools. It's long past time when a person with honor or integrity could support these people. " created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 12:08:33 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Where's Alda?" created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 23:12:27 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/29/wwcast.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;101&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named wwcast.jpg&quot;&gt;" created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 23:12:31 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I just noticed something weird about the picture of the cast on The West Wing on their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nbc.com/The_West_Wing/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. The Democrat candidate played by Jimmy Smits is included in the picture, but the Republican candidate played by Alan Alda is not. What the hell does &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; mean?" created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 23:12:45 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 28" created="Wed, 28 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.opml.org/cgerrish/2005/09/28#itsTheUserStupid&quot;&gt;Cliff Gerish says&lt;/a&gt; Web 2.0 is all about user interfaces." created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 03:53:41 GMT"/>
				<outline text="What if Web 2.0 is actually about sex? What if you could choose -- a bubble in which some VCs get rich, or a bubble in which we all get laid? Come on, seriously now. Given a choice would you rather hang around a party listening to some idiot talk about target markets and business models or have wild sex with the partner(s) of your dreams? &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 03:54:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="We solved this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rassoc.com/gregr/weblog/archive.aspx?post=779&quot;&gt;problem&lt;/a&gt; in Radio, four years ago. Here's what we did. We didn't export subscriptions that required passwords in the OPML. Our feeling was that the existence of these feeds shouldn't even be advertised, and certainly not the &quot;credentials.&quot; Never had a single user complain about this solution. The power of &lt;a href=&quot;http://essaysfromexodus.scripting.com/stories/storyReader$2070&quot;&gt;prior art&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 03:39:17 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/28/furrier.jpg&quot; width=&quot;45&quot; height=&quot;62&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named furrier.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podtech.net/&quot;&gt;John Furrier&lt;/a&gt;, in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gigaom.com/2005/09/28/what-is-web-20/&quot;&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt; on Om Malik's site, says something wise and fair: &quot;Come on this is so simple.. Web 2.0 is the next version of the Web 1.0 -- it’s simply a better version than the previous version.&quot; That cuts through the hype, and opens the door wide and inclusive. It works for me, sign me up, I'm on board for improving the web. I'm not so chauvinistic about it to think it couldn't be improved. I guess what I object to is the clubby-ness of it. If you're not cool enough to be invited into the club you can't be part of the new web. That's totally unweblike, imho." created="Thu, 29 Sep 2005 01:40:04 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://gigaom.com/2005/09/28/what-is-web-20/&quot;&gt;Om Malik's take&lt;/a&gt; on the existential question of our day. Great rewards await the guru who discovers the deep &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.scripting.com/2000/09/20/whatIsP2p&quot;&gt;beauty&lt;/a&gt; of two-point-oh." created="Wed, 28 Sep 2005 20:29:39 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.worldoutline.com/2005/September/28/DaveNet%20in%20an%20outline/&quot;&gt;Major progress&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.opml.org/2005/09/28#a289&quot;&gt;OPMLization&lt;/a&gt; of DaveNet. " created="Wed, 28 Sep 2005 17:40:45 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://support.opml.org/stories/storyReader$293&quot;&gt;Screen shot&lt;/a&gt; of the OPML Editor viewing the DaveNet outline." created="Wed, 28 Sep 2005 19:37:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="They're talking about a food museum for New Orleans. Now &lt;i&gt;that's&lt;/i&gt; a kickass idea. I bet that would be a huge tourist attraction. Reminds me of an idea I heard at breakfast last Thursday. A guy sitting next to me said he was dating through a site called &lt;a href=&quot;http://marriage.com/&quot;&gt;marriage.com&lt;/a&gt;. I thought to myself, now there's a place you could get some dates. Turns out I imagined that's what he said, it was some other site. " created="Wed, 28 Sep 2005 15:17:37 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I missed this week's West Wing, so I fired up my BitTorrent client and downloaded the latest episode, and 25 minutes later I was watching it, without commercials. While I love the West Wing, and didn't want to wait for the rerun (to be aired &lt;i&gt;months&lt;/i&gt; later) it's not right to get the show without commercials. So, why don't they offer a legal version of the show, for BitTorrent download, including commercials, maybe even special commercials for people who watch the stuff on their computers. Reading this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessweek.com/technology/content/sep2005/tc20050927_3006_tc024.htm&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; in BusinessWeek about the new company founded around BitTorrent, it seems like an obvious collaboration. BTW, I'd like to talk with the VCs who passed on this one, thinking that podcasting somehow obviates the need for BitTorrent. The two are very &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/bitTorrentRssModule&quot;&gt;complementary&lt;/a&gt;, even essential to each other. The BT guys get that and are adopting RSS, but I gather that the VC-backed podcasting startups are missing this one." created="Wed, 28 Sep 2005 14:53:42 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Eirikso: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eirikso.com/2005/06/06/how-bob-the-millionaire-became-a-pirate/&quot;&gt;How Bob the Millionaire became a pirate&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 28 Sep 2005 16:33:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/28/ball.jpg&quot; width=&quot;75&quot; height=&quot;74&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named ball.jpg&quot;&gt;Here's something wierd and kind of depressing. &lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.weblogs.com/2005/09/27#syndicatingYourBalls&quot;&gt;Doc Searls quotes me&lt;/a&gt;, at length, but my name isn't there, and he links to some site named &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joape.com/jolog/?p=718&quot;&gt;Joape&lt;/a&gt; which apparently is repurposing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/09/16#a962&quot;&gt;my writing&lt;/a&gt;. I'm sure Doc doesn't know this is my work, and I usually don't object to people republishing my stuff, but man, I really like to get proper credit for my writing and a proper link back to it. (My site is included in a list of &quot;Associates&quot; in the right margin, but the association is in their mind only, no one asked if I wanted to be associated with them.)" created="Wed, 28 Sep 2005 11:27:40 GMT"/>
				<outline text="BTW, Joape is almost certainly a spam blog. &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/28/associates.gif&quot;&gt;Look at all the links&lt;/a&gt; for gas and electricity pricing in the &quot;Associates&quot; column. They all go to the same place. This is becoming more common, using RSS-derived content to game search engines as they try to detect fake sites. Any defense against this kind of spam is going to have to keep a database of content in RSS and know which is the original and which is a game. " created="Wed, 28 Sep 2005 14:07:18 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Okay so &lt;a href=&quot;http://abc.go.com/primetime/commanderinchief/articles/&quot;&gt;Commander In Chief&lt;/a&gt; isn't the West Wing, but give it a chance. It's gotta be pretty good, with Geena and Donald as the stars. It's just getting started. A woman president. Of course. She kicks butt." created="Wed, 28 Sep 2005 05:31:41 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 27" created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/27/spam.gif&quot; width=&quot;125&quot; height=&quot;103&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named spam.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feedblog.org/2005/09/a_pending_ping_.html&quot;&gt;Kevin Burton considers&lt;/a&gt; a pending ping crisis. There &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a solution to ping spam, but he's right, it will require more resources than are currently available to services running on a Labor Of Love basis. It's surprising that they're just tuning into the crisis, it's existed for quite some time. Today, for example, I spent three hours shutting down idiot ping spammers on audio.weblogs.com. The sites had no hope of making it through to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://audio.weblogs.com/changes.xml&quot;&gt;output queue&lt;/a&gt;, they didn't have enclosures at all, but someone must have realized &quot;Hey there's another site that takes pings, let's flood them!&quot; The solution is to use collaborative filtering techniques to figure out what a pinger's site is about. If it's about nothing, then segregate the ping, don't ever not include it, but provide higher quality output feeds that only include sites known not to be about nothing, if you get my drift. Anyway, I'm happy to report that we're making progress on a deal to implement this, and hopefully will have something to announce fairly soon." created="Wed, 28 Sep 2005 00:27:24 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Jeff Jarvis: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buzzmachine.com/index.php/2005/09/27/seeing-the-forest-for-the-flood/&quot;&gt;Seeing the forest for the flood&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 28 Sep 2005 00:49:05 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rexblog.com/2005/09/27#a8325&quot;&gt;Rex Hammock observes&lt;/a&gt; a milestone in the evolution of podcasting." created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 23:00:56 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://marc.blogs.it/archives/2005/09/my_cell_phone_f.html&quot;&gt;Marc Canter's cell&lt;/a&gt; phone is sleeping with the fishes." created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 22:57:44 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dummies.com/WileyCDA/DummiesArticle/id-2677.html&quot;&gt;Dummies.com&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Both Dave Winer and Howard Dean are known for being, well, intense characters.&quot;" created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 22:32:45 GMT"/>
				<outline text="My blog has been nominated for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thebobs.com/thebobs05/bob.php&quot;&gt;BOB award&lt;/a&gt;. If I win then I can say Scripting News is an award-winning weblog. That would be nice." created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 22:29:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Elmer Masters is &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.opml.org/teknoids/&quot;&gt;live-blogging the Duke podcasting conference&lt;/a&gt;, in OPML. Outliners are especially good for meeting notes. " created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 22:07:13 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://ipodderx.com/download/win&quot;&gt;iPodderX for Windows&lt;/a&gt; is out." created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 20:44:58 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Wired: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/news/digiwood/0,1412,68950,00.html&quot;&gt;Podcasting Goldrush Is On&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 18:42:18 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2005/09/27.html#a11268&quot;&gt;Scoble&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Don't like our aggregator? Take your OPML somewhere else!&quot;" created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 17:07:24 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/1998/09/27&quot;&gt;7 years ago today&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;By this time tomorrow New Orleans may be under water as Hurricane Georges creeps toward the Gulf Coast.&quot;" created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 11:35:18 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Statesman-like technology company" created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 10:23:12 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1999/07/07/linuxDontBlink&quot;&gt;7/7/99&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Having witnessed the Internet turned into a battlefield, and assessing that at least half of the blame for that belongs to Microsoft, I am in no mood for another contentious, irrelevant do-or-die battle. This time around either Microsoft grows up and learns to be the statesman of the industry that it could be, or we'll do a Linus, and keep doing the work we love..&quot;" created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 10:39:07 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Starting many many years ago, I urged Microsoft and other technology companies, to adopt a different poise with respect to the community of developers and users. Microsoft had outgrown its self-image of &quot;scrappy upstart.&quot; In the mid-nineties, Microsoft was anything but that. Some phrases that might have made more sense: Lumbering Giant, Awkward Adolescent. Adjectives: self-absorbed, unfocused, off-topic, dangerous. Dangerous to it itself, and dangerous to everyone else." created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 10:23:19 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Then, humbled by the antitrust trial and conviction, Microsoft sulked. At no point did it ever occur to Microsoft to do the one positive thing left to upstarts that become monopolies -- LEAD. Now, perhaps, there are signs that Microsoft may be becoming a leader. They can lead not through technical innovation, that's the province of scrappy upstarts. Their job is to identify the positive trends that lead to growth in their markets, they don't even have to be early in recognizing these, and then just support them, and by all means, don't get in the way. As I said, there are signs that they are beginning to accept this role. " created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 10:25:53 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I called this &quot;statesman-like.&quot; A George Soroos of the software world. A Jimmy Carter, Henry Kissinger, a Ford Motor Company, or General Electric. Bill Gates helping technology the same way he's helping health care. " created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 10:28:57 GMT"/>
					<outline text="In the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/discuss/msgReader$971?mode=day&quot;&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt; of yesterday's post about my Yahoo visit, I &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/discuss/msgReader$976?mode=day&quot;&gt;noted&lt;/a&gt; that &quot;Yahoo is rapidly becoming the statesman-like technology company I've been hoping would emerge. Too many tech companies throw their weight around, and try to act like scrappy upstarts, when taking the long-term big-picture view would serve themselves and the community much better.&quot;" created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 10:30:33 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I observed that I should say something about this on Scripting News, to commend them for starting to lead our industry, and to hopefully help create room for more inspired leadership from Microsoft, Apple, and maybe someday, Google. Steve Gillmor &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.zdnet.com/Gillmor/?p=157&quot;&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; today that Eric Schmidt did an interview with News.Com. Good good good. There was no point trying to freeze them out. A mature statesman-like company can accept that not everyone agrees with everything they do, without lashing out like a spoiled powerless child, which often describes Google's posture, but certainly does not describe the company, with its $7 billion in cash, and a juggernaut of relevant products. Now we hope Google can approach the blogosphere with the same &lt;a href=&quot;http://dictionary.reference.com/search?q=equanimity&quot;&gt;equanimity&lt;/a&gt;, and wouldn't it be wonderful if Apple found a way of working with us, instead of in spite of us. In other words, once one technology giant becomes a statesman, it's likely that they all will have to. "/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Web 2.0 is Really Simple" created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 10:36:13 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/36521959321@N01/44349798&quot;&gt;Tim O'Reilly posted&lt;/a&gt; a &quot;meme map&quot; that was developed at Foo Camp for the thing he calls Web 2.0." created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 10:36:19 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techcrunch.com/2005/09/26/web-20-this-week-september-18-24/&quot;&gt;Mike Arrington says&lt;/a&gt; it's not simple, he feels what's needed is simplicity." created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 10:48:05 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I think we need honesty. Just as we need Microsoft, Yahoo, Google and Apple to recognize their truth, we must deal with our own. We have abused the economic system and channeled money away from the technology we say we love, and into the hands of hucksters and carpetbaggers who promote complicated self-serving memes. " created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 10:48:21 GMT"/>
					<outline text="That the memes are complicated is no big surprise. It's hard work to make things really simple. " created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 10:54:07 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Note that the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss&quot;&gt;thing&lt;/a&gt; that's &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; going, the juggernaut that's powering the growth of the new applications of the web, isn't on the O'Reilly map. " created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 10:59:05 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Web 2.0 &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; really simple, it's RSS 2.0. " created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 11:31:20 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 26" created="Mon, 26 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/09/26#a970&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/27/bss.gif&quot; width=&quot;48&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named bss.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/09/26#a970&quot;&gt;A report&lt;/a&gt; from my meeting at Yahoo last Thursday, where we discussed the user interface for subscribing and I was informed that Yahoo is making their user's subscription lists available in OPML. " created="Mon, 26 Sep 2005 16:36:06 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I may have missed the season premiere of The West Wing (good thing there's BitTorrent) but I won't miss tonight's opening of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/09/27/arts/television/27stan.html?ex=1285473600&amp;en=dc5acdac23ffcd40&amp;ei=5090&amp;partner=rssuserland&amp;emc=rss&quot;&gt;Commander In Chief&lt;/a&gt;, starring my favorite actress of all time, Geena Davis, as the President of the United States. What could possibly be better? " created="Mon, 26 Sep 2005 23:54:21 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The word &lt;a href=&quot;http://dictionary.reference.com/search?q=meme&quot;&gt;meme&lt;/a&gt; has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/26/hiddenMeme.gif&quot;&gt;hidden meaning&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Mon, 26 Sep 2005 21:20:15 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Kudos to &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.searchenginewatch.com/blog/050926-075429&quot;&gt;Danny Sullivan&lt;/a&gt; for straightening things out with David Berlind. Class act. " created="Mon, 26 Sep 2005 20:03:06 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloggercon.org/2005/09/26#a9346&quot;&gt;If you have any thoughts&lt;/a&gt; on the next generation of user-oriented blogging tools, please let's start talking about it now." created="Tue, 27 Sep 2005 01:45:04 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://weblog.infoworld.com/udell/2005/09/26.html#a1308&quot;&gt;Jon Udell explains&lt;/a&gt; how to approximate a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/riverOfNews&quot;&gt;River of News&lt;/a&gt; in Bloglines. At dinner the other night Scott Rosenberg told me that this could be done. But that doesn't solve the problem for the 98 percent of users who think three-pane is the only way and would not be able to figure how how to hack it up. And Udell points out the method is less than perfect. Someday one of the current vendors will just copy the method used by My.UserLand in 1999, and cloned by Radio in 2002. Maybe if we had patented the River of News more developers would have copied it? Probably so. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;:" created="Mon, 26 Sep 2005 15:52:07 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Jakob Nielsen: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.useit.com/alertbox/defaults.html&quot;&gt;The Power of Defaults&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 26 Sep 2005 16:30:39 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newshounds.us/2005/09/26/antitroll_resources_an_update.php&quot;&gt;editors of News Hounds&lt;/a&gt; are trying to train the trolls." created="Mon, 26 Sep 2005 13:26:16 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Let me be totally clear about this" created="Mon, 26 Sep 2005 15:05:05 GMT">
					<outline text="I'm getting tons of mail about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/09/26#broussardAndRussert&quot;&gt;bit&lt;/a&gt; below. Let me say something very clearly. I voted for Clinton, but when he lied repeatedly to cover up, I urged him to &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.scripting.com/1998/08/18/truthDecay&quot;&gt;resign&lt;/a&gt; so we could move beyond his failings. It's time for Republicans to have some self-respect and stop standing up for Bush. There's nothing to argue about here, no spin possible. Bush is very bad for us. Americans are dying because of his dishonesty and incompetence. If you can't see the problem, nothing I can say will help you see it. We need to solve this problem, &lt;i&gt;we&lt;/i&gt; need to solve it. " created="Mon, 26 Sep 2005 15:05:14 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I just re-read some of the stuff I wrote about Clinton and his crimes. What's striking about it is how far we've slid. In 1998 we were debating whether or not to &lt;i&gt;remove a President&lt;/i&gt; (he was impeached and tried, if you recall) for doing something that's so tame compared to the crimes of Bush. I can't believe we're not doing something about it. The Congress is Republican-controlled, but the press must be also, otherwise why aren't we talking about making major changes in government?" created="Mon, 26 Sep 2005 15:20:03 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://bayosphere.com/&quot;&gt;Dan Gillmor&lt;/a&gt; says that communities are the losers as journalists are laid off at local newspapers. I say good riddance. These guys are so far from doing their jobs. We need a total house-cleaning across the board. This system doesn't work. A few years ago I tried to engage Dan in a discussion of the conflict of interest the press has, it's so huge it's like an elephant in the middle of the room, but they'll never write about it. They need to start explaining the role of the owners of the media companies in governance. I have a funny feeling there's a lot of dirt there, because we &lt;i&gt;never&lt;/i&gt; look there." created="Mon, 26 Sep 2005 15:22:45 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Broussard and Russert" created="Mon, 26 Sep 2005 12:56:40 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.opml.org/amyloo/2005/09/25#bigbigisThereAnEchoInHerebigbig&quot;&gt;Amyloo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.weblogs.com/2005/09/24#readThisAndTryToSeeTvTheSameWayAgainOrEvenBlogging&quot;&gt;Doc Searls&lt;/a&gt; on Aaron Broussard's Meet the Press appearance, which I wrote up &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/09/25#When:10:03:08PM&quot;&gt;yesterday&lt;/a&gt;. Especially important is Amy's perspective. &quot;The MSM needs to say, &quot;Now wait a second. So what's the important thing here? Did Bush breeze through his mililtary service? Yes or no. Did the nursing home resident die because the rescue coordination was screwed up? Yes or no.&quot; " created="Mon, 26 Sep 2005 12:48:10 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Russert had a chance to put the Dean Scream in proper perspective, but went the other way. He had the chance to get to the core issue of the screwed-up CBS story about Bush's military service, to get the story back on track in time to teach us something important about our presiden, but he went the other way. And he had a chance to do the most real journalism of his career and keep the open dialog that came out of the Katrina disaster. He chose to go the other way." created="Mon, 26 Sep 2005 12:57:17 GMT"/>
					<outline text="But Broussard said as long as you keep giving me airtime I'm going to keep using it to expose your bullshit. And for that, Russert and NBC are in league with Brown and Bush. Part of the same team, determined to keep the discourse low and in Broussard's words, black-hearted." created="Mon, 26 Sep 2005 12:58:12 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/26/cheerios.gif&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;83&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named cheerios.gif&quot;&gt;I don't like what the conservatives do with blogging, they give what we do a bad name. We should be willing to go where ever the story leads. I called for Clinton's resignation, now it's time for conservative bloggers to do the same. We need a house-cleaning in the Bush administration, we need to get the cronies out and get competence in. Same goes for our journalists. They were culpable here. Had Russert and his colleagues pressed Bush on his military career, we might have avoided the disaster of Mike Brown by avoiding the larger disaster of George Bush. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.time.com/time/magazine/article/0,9171,1109345,00.html&quot;&gt;Time&lt;/a&gt; is right to ask how many other Browns are there? They're as dangerous as Osama bin Laden, and luckily we can root them out and get rid of them, we're not powerless. Russert should be our tool in this crusade, instead he's nitpicking and looking for an emotional joyride. " created="Mon, 26 Sep 2005 12:52:39 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 25" created="Sun, 25 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="I read &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.zdnet.com/Gillmor/?p=156&amp;part=rss&amp;tag=feed&amp;subj=zdblog&quot;&gt;Gillmor because&lt;/a&gt; I like the way he writes. &lt;i&gt;My&lt;/i&gt; detractors say they hate me because I link to things sometimes with vague inexplicable statements that refer to an idea deeply buried in the piece I'm linking to. You have to actually read the thing I link to if you want to understand what I'm saying, and then after all that reading, my idea wasn't all that clever anyway. I like Gillmor's advice in that case, and sorry, you have to read his piece to get the advice. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Mon, 26 Sep 2005 03:15:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/25/cheerios.gif&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;83&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named cheerios.gif&quot;&gt;I'm glad that Meet The Press is &lt;a href=&quot;http://podcast.msnbc.com/audio/podcast/MSNBC-MTP.xml&quot;&gt;podcasting&lt;/a&gt;. I listened to this week's &lt;a href=&quot;http://podcast.msnbc.com/audio/podcast/pd_mtp-09-25-2005-074233.mp3&quot;&gt;episode&lt;/a&gt; on today's walk. Absolutely wonderful moment when Jefferson Parish president Broussard said that Tim Russert had a black heart, and that they buried his friend's mother, not a box of Cheerios. He spoke for me when he told Russert that he was nit-picking, and yes he meant what he said, and you should try living down here for a while. It was wonderful wonderful wonderful. The best interview I've ever heard. " created="Mon, 26 Sep 2005 02:03:08 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.engadget.com/entry/1234000140060331/&quot;&gt;Engadget reports&lt;/a&gt; that record labels want a share of iPod revenues." created="Sun, 25 Sep 2005 23:26:28 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/25/reefer.jpg&quot; width=&quot;89&quot; height=&quot;51&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named reefer.jpg&quot;&gt;It's great that Adam has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://tikibase.com/tiki-index.php?page=Show+Notes+September+24%2C+2005&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt; for his shownotes, now you can keep up with what he's doing even if you don't have time to listen to the podcast. I also noticed that they've changed the name of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ipodder.org/&quot;&gt;ipodder.org&lt;/a&gt; to indiepodder.org. Anyway, who else thinks that the connection between Doerr and Podshow has something to do with all the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;q=dark+fiber+google&quot;&gt;dark fiber&lt;/a&gt; deals Google is rumored to be doing?" created="Sun, 25 Sep 2005 23:30:28 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.badscience.net/?p=172&quot;&gt;Ben Goldacre&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The media create a parody of science, for their own means. They then attack this parody as if they were critiquing science.&quot;" created="Sun, 25 Sep 2005 19:45:56 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://online.wsj.com/article/0,,SB112743680328349448,00.html&quot;&gt;A WSJ puff piece&lt;/a&gt; with Jim Allchin as the hero. It's the wrong story. Here's the right one. Allchin was the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pantheon.org/articles/l/little_dutch_boy.html&quot;&gt;little Dutch boy&lt;/a&gt; with his finger in the dyke. Anyone looking at the situation from above could see that the dyke was springing dozens then hundreds of leaks. But it took a long time for all those little leaks to become a flood so Jim could claim to his pals that his leak-plugging techniques were working. Now they're humoring him before they give up his strategy, putting off the day when they turn into a nation of boat-builders, like everyone else." created="Sun, 25 Sep 2005 19:28:53 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0107946/2005/09/25.html#a5076&quot;&gt;Ed Cone&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;People are requesting press passes for Converge.&quot;" created="Sun, 25 Sep 2005 15:57:25 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Time: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.time.com/time/magazine/article/0,9171,1109272,00.html?promoid=rss_top&quot;&gt;How Many More Mike Browns are out There?&lt;/a&gt;" created="Sun, 25 Sep 2005 15:32:19 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Saw &lt;a href=&quot;http://movies.yahoo.com/shop?d=hv&amp;cf=info&amp;id=1808625206&quot;&gt;The Corpse Bride&lt;/a&gt; yesterday. Loved it. They use a film technique called &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stop_motion_animation&quot;&gt;stop-motion animation&lt;/a&gt;, using dolls and a camera. They are moved by hand a little bit, then take a picture. Move them a bit, take a picture, etc. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/King_Kong&quot;&gt;King Kong&lt;/a&gt; was an early application of stop-motion. &lt;a href=&quot;http://chris.pirillo.com/blog/_archives/2005/9/24/1253744.html&quot;&gt;Chris Pirillo&lt;/a&gt; is a Burton fan too. Interesting &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lebonze.co.uk/v2/flash/planes.htm&quot;&gt;variant&lt;/a&gt; of stop motion." created="Sun, 25 Sep 2005 11:13:10 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 24" created="Sat, 24 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/24/new.jpg&quot; width=&quot;55&quot; height=&quot;31&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named new.jpg&quot;&gt;I love the new Yahoo mail. It's rapidly becoming my primary mail system. Good spam blocking, great user interface, really works on all my computers/browsers. Gmail doesn't. And the Gmail UI is looking pretty pale compared to Yahoo's. Now we're in a sweet spot, possibly a very sweet spot. Two great development companies competing for our attention, and neither of them is Microsoft. Come to think of it, neither is Apple. Yahoo!" created="Sat, 24 Sep 2005 14:59:48 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://support.opml.org/2005/09/24#a280&quot;&gt;I found a workaround&lt;/a&gt; for a display problem in the Mac version of the OPML Editor and wonder if it works for others. " created="Sat, 24 Sep 2005 06:08:53 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/24/DSCN0926.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/24/reservedParking.jpg&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named reservedParking.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Also, last night while watching the coverage of Hurricane Rita on CNN and MSNBC, I did my first real programming on the Mac. Since my development environment is cross-platform, and since I was a Mac user for many years, the learning curve was practically non-existent. I found the experience very empowering. My first project was converting all the back-issues of DaveNet into a static archive. Most of the pieces were written in an outliner, so most of them can be saved in OPML. Not only do I want to create a permanent downloadable archive so this stuff doesn't get lost, it also forms a very large base of OPML documents for people to play with. This may be useful for people working on OPML search tools." created="Sat, 24 Sep 2005 14:59:54 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 23" created="Fri, 23 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="News.com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.com.com/2100-1012_3-5877197.html&quot;&gt;Microsoft's nightmare inches closer to reality&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 23 Sep 2005 18:12:26 GMT"/>
				<outline text="BBC: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/technology/4267690.stm&quot;&gt;Radio has its eye on podcasters&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 23 Sep 2005 13:45:26 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/lydon/specialRssFeed&quot;&gt;9/23/03&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Only a tiny number of aggregators understand enclosures because there's never been a great source of enclosures like this one.&quot;" created="Fri, 23 Sep 2005 15:43:55 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.searchenginewatch.com/blog/050923-061942&quot;&gt;Danny Sullivan&lt;/a&gt; is unnecessarily personal in his criticism and &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.zdnet.com/BTL/?p=1898&quot;&gt;David Berlind&lt;/a&gt;, who he ridicules, is actually &lt;i&gt;right,&lt;/i&gt; which makes Sullivan's condescension even more unfair. Google doesn't include blogs in Google News, or at least that's what they claim. However, a lot of the supposed non-blogs they include are in every way blogs. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Fri, 23 Sep 2005 13:31:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnn.com/rssclick/2005/WEATHER/09/23/rita/index.html?section=cnn_topstories&quot;&gt;CNN&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;A bus carrying elderly Hurricane Rita evacuees caught fire and exploded early today on a crowded Texas interstate, killing as many as 20 people.&quot;" created="Fri, 23 Sep 2005 13:54:19 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;center&gt;&lt;table style='border:1px solid black'&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=center&gt;&lt;FONT size=3&gt;You are a   &lt;CENTER&gt;&lt;BR&gt;&lt;FONT size=4&gt;&lt;B&gt;Social Liberal&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; &lt;BR&gt;&lt;FONT shmolor=#a8a8a8 size=3&gt;(75% permissive)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/CENTER&gt;&lt;BR&gt;and an...   &lt;CENTER&gt;&lt;BR&gt;&lt;FONT size=4&gt;&lt;B&gt;Economic Liberal&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt; &lt;BR&gt;&lt;FONT shmolor=#a8a8a8 size=3&gt;(36% permissive)&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/CENTER&gt;&lt;BR&gt;You are best described as a:&lt;BR&gt;&lt;BR&gt;&lt;FONT size=+2&gt;&lt;U&gt;  &lt;CENTER&gt;&lt;B&gt;Democrat&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/CENTER&gt;&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;TABLE id=thetable height=375 cellSpacing=0 cellPadding=0 width=375 background=http://is1.okcupid.com/graphics/politics/chart_political.gif border=0 name=&quot;thetable&quot;&gt;  &lt;TBODY&gt;  &lt;TR height=218&gt;  &lt;TD width=262&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;  &lt;TD width=112&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;  &lt;TR height=156&gt;  &lt;TD width=262&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;  &lt;TD vAlign=top align=left width=112&gt;&lt;IMG src=&quot;http://is1.okcupid.com/graphics/politics_you.gif&quot; border=0&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;TABLE id=thetable height=375 cellSpacing=0 cellPadding=0 width=375 background=http://is1.okcupid.com/graphics/politics/chart_basic.jpg border=0 name=&quot;thetable&quot;&gt;  &lt;TBODY&gt;  &lt;TR height=218&gt;  &lt;TD width=262&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;  &lt;TD width=112&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;  &lt;TR height=156&gt;  &lt;TD width=262&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;  &lt;TD vAlign=top align=left width=112&gt;&lt;IMG src=&quot;http://is1.okcupid.com/graphics/politics_you.gif&quot; border=0&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;&lt;/TBODY&gt;&lt;/TABLE&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Link: &lt;a href='http://www.okcupid.com/politics'&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Politics Test&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  on &lt;a  href='http://www.okcupid.com'&gt;&lt;b&gt;OkCupid Free Online Dating&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/center&gt;" created="Sat, 24 Sep 2005 00:52:19 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 22" created="Thu, 22 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="I'm having dinner this evening with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stallman.org/&quot;&gt;Richard Stallman&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 23 Sep 2005 00:41:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://gsoblogcon.blogspot.com/2005/09/blogging-tools_22.html&quot;&gt;The discussion&lt;/a&gt; I will lead at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://2005.convergesouth.com/&quot;&gt;Greensboro bloggercon&lt;/a&gt;, Oct 8." created="Thu, 22 Sep 2005 23:52:50 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The more I &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/22/yahoomail.gif&quot;&gt;use&lt;/a&gt; Yahoo's new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thetwowayweb.com/2005/09/14#a2049&quot;&gt;mail client&lt;/a&gt;, the more I like it." created="Thu, 22 Sep 2005 22:15:52 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.davosnewbies.com/2005/09/22/its-definitive-rss-rules/&quot;&gt;Lance Knobel&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;My children's soccer league provides RSS feeds.&quot;" created="Thu, 22 Sep 2005 22:04:40 GMT"/>
				<outline text="David Berlind: &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.zdnet.com/BTL/?p=1898&quot;&gt;Shouldn't Google Alerts include blogs?&lt;/a&gt;" created="Thu, 22 Sep 2005 20:49:06 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Grace Cathedral in San Francisco is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gracecathedral.org/av/podcast.shtml&quot;&gt;podcasting&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 22 Sep 2005 20:47:13 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://grumet.net/weblog/archives/2005/09/22/001520.html&quot;&gt;Andrew Grumet&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;There are new 2.2 beta iPodders up on Sourceforge.&quot;" created="Thu, 22 Sep 2005 19:49:22 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Apparently there's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://isis.duke.edu/events/podcasting/schedule.html&quot;&gt;podcasting conference&lt;/a&gt; at Duke University next week. Just heard about it. Oy. " created="Thu, 22 Sep 2005 14:28:11 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.yahoo.com/&quot;&gt;Ed Cone&lt;/a&gt;, a leading blogger who lives down the road from Duke in Greensboro, is first hearing about their podcasting conference, less than a week before it happens and after registration is closed. What's going on over there, and in the blogosphere, that we're hearing about an important event like this at such a late date. " created="Thu, 22 Sep 2005 15:56:21 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Had a great visit at Yahoo yesterday. Can't say what I saw. Can't wait to talk about it publicly, but I have to. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Thu, 22 Sep 2005 14:28:43 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I got an email from someone I don't know asking how I rationalize getting a preview of a Yahoo product privately and confidentially, when I criticize Technorati for having an semi-secret totally private &quot;summit&quot; about issues of public importance. I guess I just explained what the difference is. I get private product briefings &lt;i&gt;all the time,&lt;/i&gt; and it's important to be able to learn what's coming, and to be able to provide feedback and guidance before new products and services are publicly availble. I agree it's a fine line, but life is filled with fine lines. Your mileage may vary, etc, etc." created="Thu, 22 Sep 2005 15:58:10 GMT"/>
				<outline text="For example, I'm learning all the time how we're all paying a high price for Apple's reluctance to trust leading podcasters prior to releasing iTunes with podcasting support. They reinvented so many things. It's possible they didn't know that we had already worked out ways to do the things they reinvented. I didn't even know they had a product on the way. Now we have to live with those mistakes, probably for &lt;i&gt;years. &lt;/i&gt;" created="Thu, 22 Sep 2005 16:00:51 GMT"/>
				<outline text="A Berkeley vignette" created="Thu, 22 Sep 2005 15:24:47 GMT">
					<outline text="On an elevator yesterday in Berkeley, a man with t-shirt that looked like a school shirt for a state university -- it said &quot;College Dropout.&quot; I asked if he was really a dropout and he said no, he goes to UC. Down a couple of floors and another young man gets on wearing a t-shirt saying, in large capital letters: &quot;I fuck on the first date.&quot; He gets off a couple of floors down. I turn to the other guy -- I was going to ask if it was true, but I wasn't sure I wanted to hear the answer. We both laughed. I said I'm going to blog this for sure." created="Thu, 22 Sep 2005 15:06:41 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 21" created="Wed, 21 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnn.com/2005/WEATHER/09/21/rita/index.html?section=cnn_topstories&quot;&gt;Rita is now&lt;/a&gt; a Category 4 hurricane, &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/21/map_tropprjpath18_fcst_5nhato_enus_600x405.jpg&quot;&gt;headed&lt;/a&gt; toward Texas or Louisiana. " created="Wed, 21 Sep 2005 16:40:29 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://gigaom.com/2005/09/21/google-wifi-more-than-bay-area/&quot;&gt;Om Malik says&lt;/a&gt; that Google's wifi service can be found in London. Is this how their rollout works, a global Easter Egg hunt?" created="Wed, 21 Sep 2005 16:39:15 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thetwowayweb.com/2005/09/21#a2061&quot;&gt;Michael Watkins&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;In crises ranging from the lax oversight of public companies that led to Enron, the systemic weaknesses in airline security and intelligence gathering that presaged 9/11, the dismal post-war planning in Iraq, and now the catastrophic damage wrought by Katrina on the Gulf Coast, our leaders have failed to mobilize to avoid well-recognized potential disasters.&quot;" created="Wed, 21 Sep 2005 16:23:58 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.donsblog.donmc.co.uk/?p=134&quot;&gt;Don McAllister&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;A collaboration tool with no RSS in this day and age -- come on Apple, you’ve dropped the ball on this one!&quot;" created="Wed, 21 Sep 2005 15:31:18 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/09/21/technology/21book.html?ex=1284955200&amp;en=0fac2a8661f7deba&amp;ei=5090&amp;partner=rssuserland&amp;emc=rss&quot;&gt;NY Times&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Three authors are contending that Google's program to create searchable digital copies of the contents of university libraries constitutes 'massive copyright infringement.'&quot;" created="Wed, 21 Sep 2005 05:02:35 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://minimsft.blogspot.com/2005/09/microsoft-reorg-reshuffle.html&quot;&gt;Mini-Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Microsoft certainly needed a reorg -- something like a good, vigorous shaking of one of those snow-globes.&quot;" created="Wed, 21 Sep 2005 04:16:40 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 20" created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="If Google really is doing a big nationwide wifi network then bless their souls for thinking so big. &lt;i&gt;Someone&lt;/i&gt; has to do that big network. I mean, all our laptops have wifi now. Someday we'll have wifi access everywhere, why wait? The money we're spending on the war in Iraq could have done it. The money we'll spend rebuilding the Gulf Coast could have done it. If Google can leverage their economic power to give us the network we deserve, now, then I gotta say thanks." created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 23:05:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&quot;Like Scoble says, I don't understand this industry,&quot; says Steve Gillmor, in a phone conversation today." created="Wed, 21 Sep 2005 00:46:01 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://matrix.scripting.com/blogs/gems/cd/gilliganAndPinky.wav&quot;&gt;Pinky&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Hmmm. Don't think I've seen that one.&quot;" created="Wed, 21 Sep 2005 00:55:06 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/20/floridaRoadside.jpg&quot;&gt;New header graphic&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.google.com/maps?q=st+augustine,fl&amp;ll=29.743960,-81.416931&amp;spn=0.559573,0.948463&amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;roadside&lt;/a&gt; in Florida. Looks pretty, doesn't it. I miss Florida, the walks on the beach, the easy flow of life. I even came to like the sand and the heat. " created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 23:04:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/05/19/fishing.pg.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/20/river.jpg&quot; width=&quot;85&quot; height=&quot;51&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named river.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rexblog.com/2005/09/20#a8238&quot;&gt;Sure sign&lt;/a&gt; that Rex uses a poorly designed RSS aggregator. It shouldn't make you feel guilty. You should have easy access to news, and stuff you missed while you were away is nothing more than stuff you missed. Let the news flow by you and relax like someone sitting on the bank of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/riverOfNews&quot;&gt;river&lt;/a&gt; looking for something interesting as you while away the time. That's how news works, and RSS is, emphatically, for news. " created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 21:42:44 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.microsoft.com/presspass/press/2005/sep05/09-20ExecChangesPR.mspx&quot;&gt;Microsoft reorganizes&lt;/a&gt;. Allchin will retire in 2006. Raikes stays. Ozzie gets new responsibilities. &lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2005/09/20.html#a11205&quot;&gt;Scoble&lt;/a&gt; likes it. What about MSN?" created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 21:27:57 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Microsoft public relations has &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.microsoft.com/presspass/rss/default.mspx&quot;&gt;RSS feeds&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Subscribed.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 21:40:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Motley Fool: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fool.com/News/mft/2005/mft05092015.htm&quot;&gt;Why I Fear Google WiFi&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 19:00:29 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nhc.noaa.gov/text/refresh/MIATCUAT3+shtml/201711.shtml&quot;&gt;Rita is now&lt;/a&gt; a Category 2 hurricane. " created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 18:18:56 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://wifi.google.com/faq.html&quot;&gt;From the FAQ&lt;/a&gt; of something called Google Secure Access: &quot;The program can currently be downloaded at certain Google WiFi locations in the San Francisco Bay Area.&quot; I guess this means that Google is going to compete with Wayport, T-Mobile and Boingo." created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 15:07:19 GMT"/>
				<outline text="NPR: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=4855620&amp;ft=1&amp;f=3&quot;&gt;Simon Wiesenthal Dies at Age 96&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 12:51:33 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The culpability of the press in Katrina" created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 15:09:03 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2004/09/20#a74&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/20/users.jpg&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;84&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named users.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Listening to Meet the Press this week was interesting, but this time not because the interview was so one-dimensional and horribly adversarial. The main interview was actually pretty good -- it was with former President Bill Clinton, who they call &quot;William Jefferson Clinton.&quot; They cut him a lot of slack, which is appropriate I guess, for an ex-president, and he cuts himself a lot of slack too. He's a master of these things, much better than the current crop of politicians from either party. " created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 15:09:12 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Meanwhile I have no sympathy for Bush who a NY Times columnist I &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.warandpiece.com/blogdirs/002640.html&quot;&gt;can't point to&lt;/a&gt; called Lucy to our Charlie Brown. Are we going to fall for it again? This is the guy who lied about WMD's yet never fessed up. He only took the blame for the screwup in the aftermath of Katrina because there was no way out, the story couldn't be spun, it was not just close to home, it was actually &lt;i&gt;at home. &lt;/i&gt;" created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 15:34:39 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Anyway, all that was interesting, but what was really interesting was the discussion between the reporters at the end of the show. They were so smart and relaxed and having a real discussion about real things, for a change. They were talking about who was going to catch the blame for screwing up this and that. One of them said there are a lot of rocks and hard places in Washington these days. Brilliant! Then I wondered who was going to ask about the culpability of the press. How many ways did they screw up in the lead up to and the aftermath of Katrina? Weren't we watching them figure out, in real-time, how horribly vulnerable New Orleans was? Why weren't they ringing the alarm bells as Katrina turned into a Category 5 storm in the Gulf and turned toward a major city with lots of people so poor they couldn't evacuate? Did any of them know that the levees were so vulnerable? (Even &lt;i&gt;after&lt;/i&gt; the levee broke.)" created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 15:12:22 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I was struck a few years ago when I found out that the major US networks all rent apartments permanently on &lt;a href=&quot;http://glasssteelandstone.com/VA/PiazzaSanPietro.html&quot;&gt;St Peter's Square&lt;/a&gt; in Rome so that when a Pope dies they can have live camera shots of the mourning and the deliberation about the new Pope. So when big news is inevitable, like the devastation of New Orleans was, they pre-position resources, and are ready to go when the event happens. I'm sure all the major papers had already written their obits of Simon Wiesenthal. Hey maybe one or two has a little blurb already written about me. Nahhh. Anyway, back to the question -- why didn't they know, and why didn't they make a stink about it while it was happening? How many lives could they have saved? Better question, how many lives &lt;i&gt;should&lt;/i&gt; they have saved?" created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 15:15:20 GMT"/>
					<outline text="No one will pay any attention to this question, it's just the old irascible gadfly again, that's how they rationalize it. But if bloggers don't ask the question -- who will?" created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 15:18:00 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="When RSS isn't very great">
					<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/20/hov.gif&quot; width=&quot;60&quot; height=&quot;468&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named hov.gif&quot;&gt;Boing Boing has run an ad for &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/20/iBag.gif&quot;&gt;A History of Violence&lt;/a&gt; in its feed 17 times in the last two days. That's as if a feed ran a post with a picture and repeated it 17 times. It was on the 17th time that I said enough, I've had enough of this." created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 12:25:06 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I'm tired of being a lab rat for Boing Boing, their feed just doesn't have enough value to compensate for the distraction. They should just pay me to watch the damned show (if that's what A History of Violence is), I might even subscribe to their feed (assuming they have one), but paying Boing Boing to interrupt my news-reading with a &quot;message&quot; is not going to get me to watch. It did get me to finally &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/20/unsubBoingBoing.gif&quot;&gt;unsub&lt;/a&gt; from BB." created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 12:29:19 GMT"/>
					<outline text="On my walk yesterday I realized something. You can use RSS in un-RSS-like ways, and when you do, it stops being like RSS (of course). I think so many people are using crappy readers, and reading feeds with these junky ads in them (even more coming soon), that net-net the user experience is almost as if they had a bookmark manager in a web browser. For them RSS really doesn't do anything all that useful. I'm surprised they even like it!" created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 12:27:41 GMT"/>
					<outline text="As I've said so many times, RSS is itself an advertising medium. Boing Boing isn't set up to advertise anything, I guess -- although I imagine that the blog has helped Xeni get her jobs at NPR and ABC News, and helped Cory get his job at EFF and lots of option shares in companies that have made or might make him rich. Come to think of it, running ads for TV shows couldn't possibly be so lucrative as to let it interfere with their much bigger business model. Hmmm." created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 12:32:01 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 19" created="Mon, 19 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nhc.noaa.gov/text/refresh/MIATCPAT3+shtml/192334.shtml&quot;&gt;&lt;font sixze=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;RITA&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Expected to reach hurricane strength later tonight.&quot;" created="Tue, 20 Sep 2005 00:17:40 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.warandpiece.com/blogdirs/002640.html&quot;&gt;Laura Rozen&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The NYT Select thing is a total catastrophe.&quot;" created="Mon, 19 Sep 2005 23:23:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Seattle P-I &lt;a href=&quot;http://seattlepi.nwsource.com/business/241192_software19.html&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; about RSS at the PDC. " created="Mon, 19 Sep 2005 21:16:45 GMT"/>
				<outline text="You might have to squint to &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/19/menuwithxml.jpg&quot;&gt;see&lt;/a&gt; the white-on-orange XML icon on Allegheny College's cafeteria &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.allegheny.edu/administration/dining/menu/&quot;&gt;menu page&lt;/a&gt;, but yes indeed, it has an &lt;a href=&quot;http://webtools.allegheny.edu/menus/rss.php?menu=0&quot;&gt;RSS 2.0 feed&lt;/a&gt;, so you can find out in advance what they'll be eating. I subscribed to the feed because it's so futuristic. Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://syndicateblog.petersons.com/wordpress/index.php/allegheny-college-launches-rss-feed-for-dining-hall-menu/&quot;&gt;Syndication for Higher Ed&lt;/a&gt;, via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.librarystuff.net/2005/09/get-rss-feed-eat-here.html&quot;&gt;Library Stuff&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Mon, 19 Sep 2005 20:55:56 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I've been on Doc's case for years about bloggers participating in closed, private and/or secret events where information is shared with some, but not all. Today he &lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.weblogs.com/2005/09/19#aDowner&quot;&gt;calls Google out&lt;/a&gt; for inviting some bloggers to some kind of meeting, with a rule that they can't blog. There's something wrong and dirty about this. They benefit enormously from the open generosity of others. They've made billions of dollars and have concentrated a huge amount of power. How nasty is it then to not share that value with the people who brought them there, the authors of the Internet. " created="Mon, 19 Sep 2005 20:13:34 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Best wishes to &lt;a href=&quot;http://halleyscomment.blogspot.com/2005/09/okay-im-in-hospital.html&quot;&gt;Halley Suitt who's&lt;/a&gt; in the hospital with chest pain. " created="Mon, 19 Sep 2005 17:35:11 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2004/09/27#When:7:38:04PM&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/19/hahaItsThePope.jpg&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;84&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named hahaItsThePope.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A note to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podshow.com/&quot;&gt;people&lt;/a&gt; who maintain the Gillmor Gang &lt;a href=&quot;http://gillmorgang.podshow.com/?feed=rss2&quot;&gt;podcast feed&lt;/a&gt; -- the channel-level title element is required. I suppose technically your feed is valid if it has an empty title, but it makes my aggregator unhappy. (Folders with empty names are frowned on by the operating system.) Could you please help me out and include a nice title, something like &lt;i&gt;The Gillmor Gang,&lt;/i&gt; for example. Thanks. (While you're at it, the channel-level description is required as well.)" created="Mon, 19 Sep 2005 17:41:22 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rexblog.com/2005/09/19#a8225&quot;&gt;Rex Hammock&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Maybe now's not the right time to be inviting all those folks back into New Orleans.&quot;" created="Mon, 19 Sep 2005 18:01:45 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/19/tuba.jpg&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;128&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named tuba.jpg&quot;&gt;There's hope for the free world. Here's proof. &lt;a href=&quot;http://philringnalda.com/blog/2005/09/cuddling_up_to_rssitemlink.php&quot;&gt;Phil Ringnalda caught&lt;/a&gt; a wiff of something amiss in an MS embrace of RSS, wrote it up, then &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.25hoursaday.com/weblog/PermaLink.aspx?guid=1c1e580a-681f-4bbb-b827-095b4ad8b25d&quot;&gt;Dare Obasanjo explains&lt;/a&gt; what happened, and stands up for RSS. He reports that Microsoft will now do the right thing (he works for Microsoft, at MSN). This is an example of something I've been writing about -- that while it's nice that Microsoft embraces RSS, and has opinions about its future, the opposite is also true. Further, the previously dysfunctional RSS &quot;community&quot; is now acting sanely, and protecting something that's good for everyone, the simplicity of RSS. Slowly, the weird trips are rolling back, people are starting to do the right thing." created="Mon, 19 Sep 2005 12:59:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.filmloop.com/&quot;&gt;FilmLoop&lt;/a&gt; is &quot;free software that gives you the power to create new loops or join existing ones. Loops are strings of images that move across your desktop.&quot;" created="Mon, 19 Sep 2005 05:30:26 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rssweather.com/hw3.php?config=&amp;forecast=warnings&amp;place=key+west&amp;state=fl&amp;zipcode=&amp;country=us&amp;county=12087&amp;zone=flz078&quot;&gt;A hurricane warning&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.google.com/maps?q=Key+West,FL&amp;ll=24.696934,-81.421051&amp;spn=0.580791,1.055443&amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;Key West&lt;/a&gt;. Tropical Storm &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kten.com/article.asp?id=10179&quot;&gt;Rita&lt;/a&gt; is building in the Bahamas, it will cross into the Gulf of Mexico, forecasters believe it will head toward Texas and coastal Mexico." created="Mon, 19 Sep 2005 04:17:18 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 18" created="Sun, 18 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.opml.org/amyloo/2005/09/17#bigbigackRawCodeRunSaveMebigbig&quot;&gt;Amyloo&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;For right now, until somebody comes up with a better scheme, I'm still with Dave on this: let users see the XML&quot;" created="Mon, 19 Sep 2005 03:39:05 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tinyscreenfuls.com/2005/09/vista-hearts-rss.html&quot;&gt;Josh Bancroft&lt;/a&gt; was at the Microsoft PDC session on RSS, and says Microsoft is doing right by RSS. " created="Mon, 19 Sep 2005 01:57:50 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://weblog.infoworld.com/udell/2005/09/15.html#a1302&quot;&gt;Transcript&lt;/a&gt; of Jon Udell's interview with Bill Gates about RSS and other topics." created="Sun, 18 Sep 2005 19:56:32 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://podcast.msnbc.com/audio/podcast/MSNBC-MTP.xml&quot;&gt;Meet the Press&lt;/a&gt; already has the &lt;a href=&quot;http://podcast.msnbc.com/audio/podcast/pd_mtp-09-18-2005-074609.mp3&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; of this week's show up.  (Pretty good show, the featured guest was Bill Clinton.)" created="Sun, 18 Sep 2005 17:16:49 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Face the Nation's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cbsnews.com/common/includes/podcast/podcast_nation_1.rss&quot;&gt;podcast feed&lt;/a&gt; hasn't updated since Sept 4." created="Sun, 18 Sep 2005 19:57:54 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Old Hype, New Hype" created="Sun, 18 Sep 2005 23:51:18 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oreillynet.com/pub/wlg/7823&quot;&gt;Kendall Clark&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;There is considerable overlap between the Web, Web 2.0, and the Semantic Web.&quot;" created="Sun, 18 Sep 2005 23:50:53 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The Web is real. The Semantic Web is an idea and Web 2.0 is a marketing concept used by venture capitalists and conference promoters to try to call another bubble into existence. " created="Mon, 19 Sep 2005 01:37:31 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The hype is treating &quot;Web 2.0&quot; as more and more real, and the hypesters are getting further and further out on a limb. " created="Mon, 19 Sep 2005 01:45:17 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Web 2.0 is P2P, only worse. P2P at least referred to &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2000/06/20#photosFromNapster&quot;&gt;something&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2000/06/29#whyWeLoveNapster&quot;&gt;identifiable&lt;/a&gt;, even if its P2P-ness wasn't the point. " created="Mon, 19 Sep 2005 01:45:54 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 17" created="Sat, 17 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Greetings from &lt;a href=&quot;http://sanfrancisco.giants.mlb.com/NASApp/mlb/sf/ballpark/index.jsp&quot;&gt;SBC Park&lt;/a&gt;, Club Level, Section 213, Row I, Seats 7 &amp; 8., where the wifi is free and &lt;i&gt;fast. &lt;/i&gt;" created="Sat, 17 Sep 2005 20:47:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/DSCN4006.MOV&quot;&gt;Here's a movie&lt;/a&gt; of the action from the park." created="Sat, 17 Sep 2005 20:57:18 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/news/2763/keep-eye-out-hurricane-philippe&quot;&gt;Rogers owns&lt;/a&gt; 804 shares of Hurricane Philippe." created="Sat, 17 Sep 2005 18:36:49 GMT"/>
				<outline text="George Ou: &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.zdnet.com/Ou/index.php?p=103&quot;&gt;Is the Firefox honeymoon over?&lt;/a&gt;" created="Sat, 17 Sep 2005 12:17:59 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessweek.com/technology/bestof/editorpicks.htm&quot;&gt;BusinessWeek chose&lt;/a&gt; Scripting News as one of their favorite work weblogs. &lt;i&gt;Thanks!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Sat, 17 Sep 2005 04:55:39 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Exclusive ways" created="Sat, 17 Sep 2005 12:30:08 GMT">
					<outline text="I can blog about &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.searchenginewatch.com/blog/050916-124622&quot;&gt;Google's unbloggable community conference&lt;/a&gt; because I wasn't invited. Great community building Google. Exclusive events suck. I guess News.com wasn't invited either. I probably wouldn't have gone anyway. I don't think bloggers should go to public events they can't blog about. What's going to be discussed there? You and I won't find out, and that's the way Google wants it. But what's puzzling is that their competitors &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; invited. So they don't want to keep the information from them, it's just the public they want kept in the dark. Geez Louise, isn't stuff like that illegal?" created="Sat, 17 Sep 2005 12:22:31 GMT"/>
					<outline text="While I'm at it, the &quot;summit&quot; next Wednesday, at Google, is still a bad idea. It should be open to anyone who wants to participate, and it should be bloggable, and it shouldn't be called a summit. How arrogant of Technorati to think they can decide who goes to a summit. Feh. And it shouldn't be at Google. It would be so easy to get a classroom, or a conference room at a library (they're free in Berkeley, probably in Mountain View too) or even at a local branch of the Bank of America. Doing it at Google will stifle the conversation, and help reinforce the very bad idea that the tech world revolves around them, one that I'm sure they don't mind pushing, but why should &lt;i&gt;we&lt;/i&gt; support it? " created="Sat, 17 Sep 2005 12:30:39 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Also a little advance planning would have made it possible for me to participate, but I have an all-afternoon meeting in the South Bay on Wednesday, so unless things can be rescheduled I'll probably keep my appointment, and skip the summit. I have a feeling I'll be able to read about it on the blogs even if it's not bloggable. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Sat, 17 Sep 2005 12:33:56 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Now that the PDC is over, I also gotta say it was disappointing to not have had a place there, after seeing so many people were invited, and to have my work featured so prominently. I even &lt;i&gt;asked&lt;/i&gt; for an invite. " created="Sat, 17 Sep 2005 12:36:10 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It seems the tech industry cares more about not being criticized than in building something that works. That certainly describes Google, and I was surprised to find out it also describes today's Microsoft. I would have been happy to work the hallways at PDC, maybe even speak. Maybe someone on their Team RSS can explain. Was it an oversight? Did anyone ask if I should be part of the RSS conversation at PDC? It left a really bad feeling, and not much of a basis for working together in the future. I'm behind the curve now, I don't know what they're doing with RSS, I find myself in the awkward position of having to tell reporters who ask what I think that they know more about what MS is doing in RSS than I do. I wonder if anyone in Redmond thought about that. Scoble had the presence to pick up the phone and call on Tuesday, but that was the extent of communication from Microsoft about the PDC. " created="Sat, 17 Sep 2005 13:11:14 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I've been back in the Bay Area for about a month now, I left because this is a company town, and the penalty for not being onboard is exclusion. It still is that way, only more so. I'm hoping I can exist here, outside of the context of this bad blood, enjoy the weather, and be picky about who I spend time with, and only work with people who aren't scared of a strong idea or two, or in knowing what someone really thinks. A bunch of scared people run this place, and you can't make love out of fear. " created="Sat, 17 Sep 2005 12:35:22 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 16" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mbatoolbox.org/stories/storyReader$26&quot;&gt;A new chapter&lt;/a&gt; in my dad's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mbatoolbox.org/&quot;&gt;MBA Toolbox&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Once you start looking for business opportunities, you are more likely to find them.&quot;" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2005 19:17:24 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/16/ball.jpg&quot; width=&quot;75&quot; height=&quot;74&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named ball.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://titleist.com/news/newsdetail.asp?id=233&amp;category=media_center&amp;subcategory=&amp;bhcp=1&quot;&gt;Titleist&lt;/a&gt;, a company that makes golf balls, clubs and accessories, now &lt;a href=&quot;http://titleist.com/news/news_overview.asp?bhcp=1&quot;&gt;has RSS feeds&lt;/a&gt;. Really smart. Golf is a conversation, and if you make golf balls, you want to be part of the golf conversation. The golf part of RSS is largely a void in 2005, so if you're Titleist, why not move to fill it? It's cheap. An example of RSS-as-advertising; much more powerful than advertising-in-RSS. Why pay someone else to hitch a ride in a conversation, when you can host it yourself? Much more cost-effective, and appreciated by customers. People don't like intrusive marketing as much as they like finding commercial information they're looking for. As Doc Searls says, there's no demand for messages. But there is demand for golf balls, says Titleist. Both are right. " created="Fri, 16 Sep 2005 19:40:22 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/09/16#a962&quot;&gt;I cross-posted&lt;/a&gt; on the Really Simple Syndication site, it'll be interesting to see if &lt;a href=&quot;http://tech.memeorandum.com/&quot;&gt;Memeorandum&lt;/a&gt; picks it up. Like Scoble, I find it's changed the way I think about blogging. Not many of these tech gadgets do that. " created="Fri, 16 Sep 2005 20:41:34 GMT"/>
				<outline text="PaidContent &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paidcontent.org/pc/arch/2005_09_15.shtml#015867&quot;&gt;interviews&lt;/a&gt; Martin Nisenholtz of the NY Times." created="Fri, 16 Sep 2005 16:56:29 GMT"/>
				<outline text="BusinessWeek &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessweek.com/magazine/content/05_39/b3952009.htm?chan=tc&quot;&gt;profiles&lt;/a&gt; anonymous blogger Mini-Microsoft." created="Fri, 16 Sep 2005 16:27:19 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Bret Fausett: &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.lextext.com/blog/_archives/2005/9/15/1230492.html&quot;&gt;ICANN Adopts RSS...and Podcasts!&lt;/a&gt;" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2005 12:43:59 GMT"/>
				<outline text="A parable of Postelia" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2005 12:44:59 GMT">
					<outline text="Once upon a time there was a fictitious continent named Postelia, and it had a wonderful network of trains. You could go anywhere you liked, every town had a station, and there were subways too, every neighborhood had a stop, and you could get from the main rail line to one of the sub-lines, and through a complicated set of &quot;peering arrangements&quot; your pass on one line would gain you entrance to the other. It was very convenient to get around in Postelia, and inexpensive too. While America, Europe and Asia were choking under clouds of gasoline exhaust, the skies of Postelia were clear. Birds sang, children played and life was good!" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2005 12:45:07 GMT"/>
					<outline text="To make the system even more terrific, there were conventions. If you went into a station you'd find that there was a pattern. The low numbered tracks were for inter-city express trains, the high-numbered ones were for tourists and students and went to resorts or places of historic interest. The odd-numbered tracks went north or east, the even-numbered ones went south or west. There were hot dog stands on tracks whose numbers were divisible by five, and news stands on tracks whose numbers were divisible by 12. " created="Fri, 16 Sep 2005 12:48:41 GMT"/>
					<outline text="And at every station, on Track 24, there was a Traveler's Aid station. That meant that if a Postelian lost his wallet while traveling, or got tired and needed a place to sit down, they could go to Track 24, where they would find someone with a helpful attitude and a hot cup of coffee. Some tourists knew about the Track 24 convention, and those that didn't could find the information in one of the many tour guides. Or they would learn about it if they asked someone on the train where to go for help, or if they stopped a friendly policeman, or asked a vendor at a hot dog stand. Most people didn't know about the Track 24 convention, but the people who helped people, did. The information wasn't known by many people, but it &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; widely available. A subtle difference." created="Fri, 16 Sep 2005 12:52:58 GMT"/>
					<outline text="And that concludes our story for today. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2005 12:56:55 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 15" created="Thu, 15 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/09/15#a956&quot;&gt;One day later&lt;/a&gt;, here's the net-net on Google's blog search." created="Thu, 15 Sep 2005 19:07:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.technorati.com/weblog/2005/09/47.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/16/spam.jpg&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;66&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named spam.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.technorati.com/weblog/2005/09/47.html&quot;&gt;Technorati&lt;/a&gt; is &quot;organizing the second Web Spam Summit taking place next week at Google's headquarters in Mountain View.&quot; You know it would be nice if this were done at a more neutral site, not sponsored by one vendor and hosted at another's headquarters. That's got to influence the way the discussion takes place. How about getting Stanford to host it, or UC-Berkeley. That's one of the things universities are good at. In any case I'm going to try to be at this discussion. " created="Fri, 16 Sep 2005 04:21:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://classcaster_news.classcaster.org/blog/announcements/2005/09/15/cclive&quot;&gt;Classcaster&lt;/a&gt; is a &quot;blogging system with podcasting built-in.&quot;" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2005 00:51:50 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Engadget: &lt;a href=&quot;http://engadget.com/entry/1234000917058865/&quot;&gt;Apple files for “iPodcast” trademark&lt;/a&gt;." created="Thu, 15 Sep 2005 11:23:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The Trademark Blog &lt;a href=&quot;http://trademark.blog.us/blog/2005/03/14.html#a1624&quot;&gt;found&lt;/a&gt; a registration of &quot;podcast&quot; in February. " created="Thu, 15 Sep 2005 13:42:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="AP: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/news/technology/0,1282,68853,00.html&quot;&gt;Yahoo Overhauling Free E-Mail&lt;/a&gt;." created="Thu, 15 Sep 2005 11:21:34 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 14" created="Wed, 14 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thetwowayweb.com/2005/09/14#a2049&quot;&gt;Exclusive preview&lt;/a&gt; of Yahoo's browser-based email based on Oddpost. " created="Wed, 14 Sep 2005 22:01:24 GMT"/>
				<outline text="PS: &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/14/pic2.gif&quot;&gt;Yahoo Mail works&lt;/a&gt; with Firefox/Mac, it &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/14/pic4.gif&quot;&gt;does not work&lt;/a&gt; with Safari." created="Thu, 15 Sep 2005 00:05:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Watching Google's blog search for a few hours, it doesn't seem to have a concept of page-rank. The order of the results seems pretty random. " created="Wed, 14 Sep 2005 17:49:30 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/rss/pod/roberts.xml&quot;&gt;NPR has a podcast&lt;/a&gt; about the Roberts hearings. I caught a bit of it yesterday and it was really interesting. Surprisingly so. " created="Wed, 14 Sep 2005 12:19:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/entrepreneurstechnology/2005/09/14/podcasting-blogging-internet-cx_tt_0914straightup.html?partner=rss&quot;&gt;Forbes is looking&lt;/a&gt; for, but hasn't found the profits in podcasting. " created="Wed, 14 Sep 2005 11:27:05 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://paolo.evectors.it/2005/09/14.html#a2621&quot;&gt;Paolo spots&lt;/a&gt; Googlebot reading his RSS feed." created="Wed, 14 Sep 2005 11:26:50 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Google adds blog search" created="Wed, 14 Sep 2005 10:54:42 GMT">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://search.blogger.com/&quot;&gt;search.blogger.com&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Search blogs from all over the web.&quot;" created="Wed, 14 Sep 2005 10:39:26 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It's also available at http://blogsearch.google.com/." created="Wed, 14 Sep 2005 10:55:03 GMT"/>
					<outline text="A FAQ &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/help/about_blogsearch.html&quot;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt; is also available. &lt;a href=&quot;http://tech.memeorandum.com/&quot;&gt;Memeorandum&lt;/a&gt; is tracking it. " created="Wed, 14 Sep 2005 11:06:03 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogsearch.google.com/blogsearch?hl=en&amp;q=%22google+blog+search%22&quot;&gt;Google Blog Search&lt;/a&gt; search query for &quot;google blog search.&quot;" created="Wed, 14 Sep 2005 11:34:04 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It appears to be searching the RSS feeds. Based on a little experimentation with recent content, it's not very useful as a search engine for this weblog. If a post doesn't have a title it doesn't seem to see it. It actually picks up posts on my ancillary sites better than those on this site. &lt;a href=&quot;http://search.blogger.com/blogsearch?ui=blg&amp;q=blogurl%3Ahttp://geeks.opml.org/&amp;scoring=d&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/a&gt;. It's good that they support RSS output (it was sure to be a frequent feature request) but once again they ask the user to make a choice of output formats, they really need to get this -- users don't care. And they're breaking &lt;a href=&quot;http://search.blogger.com/?q=postel%27s+law&amp;hl=en&amp;ui=blg&quot;&gt;Postel's Law&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Wed, 14 Sep 2005 10:45:07 GMT"/>
					<outline text="They might want to look at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/search/default&quot;&gt;weblog search&lt;/a&gt; engine for Scripting News, an &lt;a href=&quot;http://essaysfromexodus.scripting.com/aboutWeblogSearch&quot;&gt;application&lt;/a&gt; of the Google API. Really they shouldn't depend so heavily on blog posts having titles. Really need to give this some thought, I think you punted too early. " created="Wed, 14 Sep 2005 10:55:36 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/14/gbs.gif&quot; width=&quot;135&quot; height=&quot;83&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named gbs.gif&quot;&gt;It's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/help/about_blogsearch.html&quot;&gt;good&lt;/a&gt; that they're using weblogs.com output, and give it credit in their FAQ (something Technorati, for example, doesn't do, preferring to claim credit for our work). Speaking of Technorati, okay, Google's blog search isn't perfect, but now there's a benchmark to compare against. It sure performs well. Let's see if they can keep it running (my guess is that they can). Politically, Google is making the user pay for their religion, so that's a point in Technorati's favor. Neither company is much-loved in the community these days, but in balance I trust Google more, which is pretty amazing, considering how small Technorati is. We knew the day would come when Technorati would have to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sifry.com/alerts/archives/000340.html&quot;&gt;compete&lt;/a&gt; with Google. They could have prepared much better for this day, imho." created="Wed, 14 Sep 2005 10:55:43 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Scanning some of the Memeorandum-gleaned links, Google's should do a better job working with bloggers. We do more than publish &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/14/summersalad.gif&quot;&gt;summer salad recipes&lt;/a&gt; and Harry Potter reviews. If any bloggers were briefed in advance, none gave it a thorough look. Also, the timing is obviously designed to steal some of Microsoft's thunder. Maybe we could move beyond that. We want to look at what Google is doing, for sure, so please give us a chance to do that, even if we won't write puffball pieces about your work, and let Microsoft speak too. Maybe even let them have a week to communicate their product strategy." created="Wed, 14 Sep 2005 11:11:09 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 13" created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/13/jazz.jpg&quot;&gt;New header graphic&lt;/a&gt;, derived from a New Orleans &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/08/31/fullJazzFuneral.jpg&quot;&gt;jazz funeral pic&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 14 Sep 2005 02:38:44 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Jon Udell &lt;a href=&quot;http://weblog.infoworld.com/udell/2005/09/13.html#a1300&quot;&gt;interviews&lt;/a&gt; Bill Gates in a podcast. " created="Wed, 14 Sep 2005 01:09:05 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.com.com/Gates+on+Google/2008-1082_3-5863514.html?tag=alert&quot;&gt;News.com has&lt;/a&gt; a Gates interview too, not a podcast." created="Wed, 14 Sep 2005 01:13:42 GMT"/>
				<outline text="BBC: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/business/4243744.stm&quot;&gt;Google getting its Microsoft man&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 23:22:25 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Scoble called to say that RSS was all over the Windows Vista demos at the PDC today. It's nice to get a call like that. It's not like Apple called to say they liked RSS when they copied and pasted it all over their OS." created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 18:36:32 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://microsoftgadgets.com/&quot;&gt;Gadgets&lt;/a&gt; are a &quot;new category of mini-application designed to provide information, useful lookup, or enhance an application or service on your Windows PC or the Web.&quot;" created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 18:52:10 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://weblogs.jupiterresearch.com/analysts/gartenberg/archives/010450.html&quot;&gt;Gartenberg&lt;/a&gt; on the new Office 12 user interface, RSS support." created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 17:18:46 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.zdnet.com/BTL/?p=1845&quot;&gt;Dan Farber&lt;/a&gt; has some screen shots of the new UI." created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 17:36:34 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.germancarblog.com/2005/09/vw-get-connected.html&quot;&gt;German Car Blog&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;You can now connect your USB powered MP3 player filled with your personal choice of music to VW cars.&quot;" created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 16:07:56 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Richard MacManus &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/002824.php&quot;&gt;reviews&lt;/a&gt; the new Memeorandum. " created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 11:13:03 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blaserco.com/blogs/2005/09/13.html#a366&quot;&gt;Britt wants&lt;/a&gt; one for Katrina." created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 18:40:16 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://sdk.typepad.com/trust/2005/09/more_on_gabe_ri.html&quot;&gt;Staci Kramer&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I approached Gabe about doing just that nearly two weeks ago. We went back and forth about the idea; his chief concern was  whether a hurried effort would add enough to the conversation about Katrina.&quot;" created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 21:29:59 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Why blame is not the issue" created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 18:03:47 GMT">
					<outline text="I had to set up a bank account in Massachusetts because Scripting News, Inc is a Massachusetts corp. The bank made &lt;i&gt;many&lt;/i&gt; mistakes setting up the account, especially the Internet part of the account. " created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 17:59:10 GMT"/>
					<outline text="So here I am, 3000 miles away, and the people on the other end of the line are talking about who's at fault. Some say it's another guy at the bank, some suggest it might be my fault (hard to imagine, I just showed them the corporate documents and answered their questions truthfully). But blame &lt;i&gt;isn't&lt;/i&gt; what I care about. A bank is something you put trust in. I want to know my money is safe. " created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 18:06:38 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Now we put even more faith in our government. They run everything, including the banks. And the nukes. And the levees in New Orleans. And the war in Iraq. So when Bush &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/09/13/national/nationalspecial/13cnd-storm.html?ex=1284264000&amp;en=871cd60ee280dbd6&amp;ei=5090&amp;partner=rssuserland&amp;emc=rss&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; he'll take responsibility for what's his fault, that's not good enough. I want it to work. After I'm dead it doesn't matter who's to blame. " created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 18:06:08 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Easing into Firefox" created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 18:27:21 GMT">
					<outline text="Thanks to Apple for making such a shitty browser, and forcing me to learn to love Firefox, now I have a way out of the spyware quagmire on Windows, without very much discomfort at all. Read on..." created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 18:33:11 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Last week I found myself in a new apartment, a permanent address at last, and a laptop that's so riddled with spyware as to be unusable. While watching Katrina on CNN and MSNBC, I ran all the spyware removal tools I had, they're known to work, but then I couldn't bring myself to launch MSIE, because that's how the spyware comes back. Then I had an epiphany. I didn't use Firefox on this computer in the past because it was so strange, so different from MSIE as to be jarring. I put up with the spyware in order not to be forced to do the uncomfortable. So I installed Firefox, and I use it on two of my three computers, happily, and the spyware-infested laptop is now a spyware-free laptop! Happy days." created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 18:28:12 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Sometimes you have to sneak up on yourself to get something done. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 18:31:02 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Starbucks" created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 18:35:14 GMT">
					<outline text="It's a good place to edit your blog, on a cloudy Tuesday in Berkeley. Just enough activity to provide inspiration without being too distracting. And the coffee, even if it isn't the best in the world, is fresh and plentiful, and the Internet works. And across the street a &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/13/apeLikeSmoker.jpg&quot;&gt;man&lt;/a&gt; who looks like an ape with sunglasses smokes slowly, in the same place he was yesterday. Slowly smoking. Not going anywhere. Just standing there looking like an ape and a man at the same time, smoking, slowly." created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 18:35:16 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 12" created="Mon, 12 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2005/09/12.html#a11129&quot;&gt;Scoble has been raving&lt;/a&gt; privately about two new services from Memeorandum, for months, but hasn't been able to talk about it publicly, until now. The two services are &lt;a href=&quot;http://tech.memeorandum.com/&quot;&gt;Tech Memeorandum&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.memeorandum.com/&quot;&gt;Political Memeorandum&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Memeorandum chews through thousands of blogs in minutes and tells you what's important. It does this every few minutes. It is dramatically faster than I could ever be. It's all machine based. No humans involved,&quot; says Scoble. I'm looking forward to checking it out." created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 02:12:58 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/12/cuteDancingHamster.gif&quot; width=&quot;53&quot; height=&quot;74&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named cuteDancingHamster.gif&quot;&gt;Microsoft PDC &lt;a href=&quot;http://commnet1.microsoftpdc.com/content/sessionview.aspx?TopicID=524efeda-c77d-4358-8dd6-62e0be18a234&quot;&gt;session&lt;/a&gt; on the future of RSS. Maybe RSS has something to say about the future of Microsoft. Not a joke, not even slightly. If Microsoft wants to accomplish anything by using RSS, they have to let RSS use Microsoft. It's not enough for MS to embrace RSS, they must let RSS embrace MS. I don't think this has really sunk in over there at MS yet, but I have hope that it will. " created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 02:53:04 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I'm having coffee with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.donhopkins.com/&quot;&gt;Don Hopkins&lt;/a&gt; -- one of the programmers on The Sims. He says &quot;every object has a bit that says whether it's burning or not.&quot; Pretty coool!" created="Tue, 13 Sep 2005 00:44:13 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/news/2753/cspan-has-begun-podcasting&quot;&gt;Rogers reports&lt;/a&gt; that CSPAN has begun &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.c-span.org/podcast/&quot;&gt;podcasting&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 12 Sep 2005 18:30:14 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The Jerusalem Post is &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.userland.com/2005/09/12#a49&quot;&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt; blogs with Manila." created="Mon, 12 Sep 2005 18:13:21 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/discuss/msgReader$1458?mode=day&quot;&gt;John Roberts&lt;/a&gt; at CNET points out their &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.com.com/html/ne/podcasts/daily_podcast.xml&quot;&gt;daily tech podcast&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Mon, 12 Sep 2005 17:41:17 GMT"/>
				<outline text="On Friday I &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/09/09#a1431&quot;&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt; where are the mainstream news podcasts." created="Mon, 12 Sep 2005 17:43:19 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://gigaom.com/2005/09/11/skype-ebay-happening/&quot;&gt;Om Malik reports&lt;/a&gt; that eBay is buying Skype for $4.1 billion." created="Mon, 12 Sep 2005 15:05:30 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Jon Udell's departure &lt;a href=&quot;http://weblog.infoworld.com/udell/2005/09/12.html#a1299&quot;&gt;checklist&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Mon, 12 Sep 2005 14:50:05 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I just got news that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tyborg.com/2005/09/10/terry-teague/&quot;&gt;Terry Teague&lt;/a&gt;, one of the most &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontier.userland.com/credits#fromTheFrontier10Page&quot;&gt;senior members&lt;/a&gt; of the Frontier community, and longtime employee of Apple Computer, died over the weekend. He will totally be missed. " created="Mon, 12 Sep 2005 05:49:13 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 11" created="Sun, 11 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reallysimplesyndication.com/2005/09/11#a951&quot;&gt;BTW&lt;/a&gt;, when people ask what &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; is, I say it's &lt;i&gt;automated web surfing.&lt;/i&gt; We took something lots of people do, visiting sites looking for new stuff, and automated it. It's a very predictable thing, that's what computers do -- automate repetitive things. " created="Mon, 12 Sep 2005 01:18:48 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Continuing the discussion about technologies with weird names, consider &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/W/Wi_Fi.html&quot;&gt;Wifi&lt;/a&gt;. What does &quot;wireless fidelity&quot; mean? Who came up with that nonsense phrase and why? There are TV commercials that talk about wifi, so it's become pretty mainstream. While we're at it, what does TV mean? Vision over tele. Hellllo. Okay, one more, what will we call EVDO? Do you know what it is? Some &lt;a href=&quot;http://weblogs.jupiterresearch.com/analysts/gartenberg/archives/010342.html&quot;&gt;people&lt;/a&gt; who think RSS isn't a good enough name for RSS throw around the term EVDO as if everyone knows what it means. Remember that TV commercial about wifi? They &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.verizonwireless.com/b2c/mobileoptions/broadband/index.jsp&quot;&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt; about &quot;wireless broadband access.&quot; What do you suppose &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; means? Oy." created="Mon, 12 Sep 2005 00:13:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://stanleydaily.com/2005/08/07/Blogging_the_Roberts_Nomination.php&quot;&gt;Stan Krute&lt;/a&gt; on blogging of the Roberts hearings, which start tomorrow. " created="Sun, 11 Sep 2005 22:56:40 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnn.com/2005/POLITICS/09/11/katrina.politics.ap/&quot;&gt;A factoid&lt;/a&gt; gleaned from the Sunday talk shows -- most of the people who left Louisiana were Democrats, meaning that the future for a Democrat &lt;a href=&quot;http://gov.louisiana.gov/&quot;&gt;governor&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://landrieu.senate.gov/hurricanes/index.cfm&quot;&gt;senator&lt;/a&gt; are in doubt. " created="Sun, 11 Sep 2005 23:04:08 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The Times-Picayune &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nola.com/newslogs/breakingtp/index.ssf?/mtlogs/nola_Times-Picayune/archives/2005_09_11.html#078871&quot;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; that 5.2 million gallons of water are being pumped out of New Orleans every minute, and that the airport will &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nola.com/newslogs/breakingtp/index.ssf?/mtlogs/nola_Times-Picayune/archives/2005_09_11.html#078870&quot;&gt;re-open&lt;/a&gt; for commercial flights on Tuesday." created="Sun, 11 Sep 2005 21:18:45 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/11/russert.jpg&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;121&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named russert.jpg&quot;&gt;I could only watch two minutes of Meet the Press before the &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2004/02/01#When:11:59:31AM&quot;&gt;disgust&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2004/01/25#When:3:56:41PM&quot;&gt;came&lt;/a&gt; back. Russert is doing what he always does, tries to twist the soundbite into an admission of hypocrisy. New Orleans mayor Ray Nagin doesn't have the lawyer's gift that former prosecutor Rudy Giuliani does. &quot;Is it really racism?&quot; Russert expresses doubt, asking over and over for proof that decisions were made on a racist basis. The answer is in another question. If the dying tax-paying grandmas were white do you think they would have been left to die? I don't care if a Republican actually said out loud that he or she hates blacks, the actions speak for themselves. We live in a sick country with a sick governing process, and that sickness &lt;i&gt;definitely&lt;/i&gt; includes the press. " created="Sun, 11 Sep 2005 15:37:01 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.salon.com/0000014/2005/09/11.html#a918&quot;&gt;Scott Rosenberg&lt;/a&gt; has a talk with his past self. " created="Sun, 11 Sep 2005 15:14:59 GMT"/>
				<outline text="ABC News Nightline, a daily news broadcast, is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://abcnews.go.com/xmldata/xmlPodcast?id=868748&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sun, 11 Sep 2005 15:10:34 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.zdnet.com/Gillmor/?p=150&amp;part=rss&amp;tag=feed&amp;subj=zdblog&quot;&gt;Steve Gillmor&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;There's nothing up Bill's sleeve.&quot;" created="Sun, 11 Sep 2005 05:26:24 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Four years ago, &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2001/09/11&quot;&gt;you know what&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sun, 11 Sep 2005 15:17:32 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.weblogs.com/2001/09/11#loverolling&quot;&gt;Doc Searls on 9/11/01&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I need to pick up the kid from school soon. This morning he wanted to know why his parents were crying. We couldn't begin to explain.&quot;" created="Sun, 11 Sep 2005 23:12:39 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 10" created="Sat, 10 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/03/27#When:10:38:00AM&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/11/beda.jpg&quot; width=&quot;45&quot; height=&quot;56&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named beda.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eightypercent.net/&quot;&gt;Joe Beda&lt;/a&gt; from Google &lt;a href=&quot;http://geeks.opml.org/comments?u=geeks&amp;p=276&amp;link=http%3A%2F%2Fgeeks.opml.org%2F2005%2F09%2F10%23a276&quot;&gt;checks in&lt;/a&gt; on connecting to Google Talk from Radio, but I don't think we have SSL running in there, if not we're out of luck, for now at least. Maybe this is one of those times when being GPL will help us muster the developer resources we need. " created="Sun, 11 Sep 2005 04:48:29 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.salon.com/0000014/2005/09/10.html#a917&quot;&gt;Scott Rosenberg&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;...a juggernaut of dysfunction, headed for the ditch.&quot;" created="Sun, 11 Sep 2005 04:35:13 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/10/dietPepsi.jpg&quot; width=&quot;61&quot; height=&quot;86&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;I drink Diet Coke, not Diet Pepsi, I prefer the taste of Diet Coke, and no one paid me to run this picture of a Diet Pepsi can, so it's not a commercial.&quot;&gt;Two nightly news shows available via podcast: &lt;a href=&quot;http://podcast.msnbc.com/audio/podcast/MSNBC-Nightly.xml&quot;&gt;NBC Nightly News&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pbs.org/newshour/rss/media/index.html&quot;&gt;PBS NewsHour&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/discuss/msgReader$1446?mode=day&quot;&gt;Bob Stepno&lt;/a&gt; for links to both. Here's a guess why these shows are available via podcast and the NPR news shows are not. NPR is protecting their affiliate stations, giving them an exclusive on distribution. The two TV shows are only distributing audio, so they aren't undermining their current distribution network. I think it's short-sighted. It seems to me that NPR is in the news business not the radio business. Long-term they gain nothing by protecting the radio form, they just encourage competition in podcast-space from television-based news organizations. " created="Sun, 11 Sep 2005 02:33:03 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Podcasting Couch has &lt;a href=&quot;http://podcastingcouch.com/air_america/podcast_feeds/&quot;&gt;feeds&lt;/a&gt; for Air America radio shows. " created="Sat, 10 Sep 2005 21:47:20 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://geeks.opml.org/2005/09/10#a276&quot;&gt;Has anyone&lt;/a&gt; tried using Radio's built-in instant messaging verbs to talk through Google's Jabber server?" created="Sat, 10 Sep 2005 21:24:07 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The Contra Costa Times has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.contracostatimes.com/mld/cctimes/news/local/states/california/counties/alameda_county/cities_neighborhoods/berkeley/rss.xml&quot;&gt;feed&lt;/a&gt; for Berkeley news. " created="Sat, 10 Sep 2005 15:37:13 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/10/dance34.gif&quot; width=&quot;164&quot; height=&quot;126&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;They'll be dancing here as long as this website exists.&quot;&gt;" created="Sun, 11 Sep 2005 02:45:05 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 9" created="Fri, 09 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podcatch.com/2005/09/09#a1431&quot;&gt;Where&lt;/a&gt; are the mainstream news podcasts?" created="Sat, 10 Sep 2005 00:20:26 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.msdn.com/ie/archive/2005/09/09/463204.aspx&quot;&gt;Tariq Sharif&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I want to tell you about the Phishing Filter in IE7.&quot;" created="Sat, 10 Sep 2005 00:01:53 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Rogers: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/news/2749/technoratis-fing-ping-thing&quot;&gt;Technorati's F'ing Ping Thing&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 09 Sep 2005 23:39:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.com.com/2061-11199_3-5857123.html?part=rss&amp;tag=5857123&amp;subj=news&quot;&gt;Some guy who lost his home&lt;/a&gt; in Katrina told Dick Cheney to go fuck himself. Cheney thought he was talking about someone named John." created="Fri, 09 Sep 2005 21:06:59 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://booknote.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;A blog&lt;/a&gt; from a Katrina survivior in the Houston Astrodome. " created="Fri, 09 Sep 2005 21:00:17 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Bob Doyle: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.econtentmag.com/Articles/ArticleReader.aspx?ArticleID=13515&quot;&gt;The First Podcast&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 09 Sep 2005 20:20:57 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Time: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.time.com/time/nation/article/0,8599,1103003,00.html&quot;&gt;How Reliable Is Brown's Resume?&lt;/a&gt;" created="Fri, 09 Sep 2005 19:28:51 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2001/09/09&quot;&gt;Four years ago&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Ballmer isn't on the first page of Steves.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Still true.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 09 Sep 2005 18:48:33 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/news/2748/police-trapped-thousands-new-orleans&quot;&gt;Rogers Cadenhead&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The Louisiana Superdome is less than two miles from a bridge that leads over the Mississippi River out of the city.&quot;" created="Fri, 09 Sep 2005 16:17:47 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Another piece of data has now come to light. Parts of metro New Orleans were hit by the storm surge. Water levels in most of the area rose more gradually, but in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedaily.com/upi/?feed=TopNews&amp;article=UPI-1-20050908-11541200-bc-us-katrina-stbernard-.xml&quot;&gt;St Bernard Parish&lt;/a&gt;, the water rose &lt;i&gt;eight feet in one hour.&lt;/i&gt; Had the whole of New Orleans been hit the way &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.google.com/maps?q=Chalmette,+LA&amp;ll=29.958207,-89.969101&amp;spn=0.069232,0.131930&amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;Chalmette&lt;/a&gt; was, many more people would have died, hard as that may be to believe. " created="Fri, 09 Sep 2005 16:18:04 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessweek.com/the_thread/blogspotting/archives/2005/09/is_technorati_m.html&quot;&gt;Stephen Baker asks&lt;/a&gt; if Technorati is making deals to get ping data first. " created="Fri, 09 Sep 2005 14:57:14 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/cgi/content/full/309/5741/1656&quot;&gt;Science&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;There are times when scientists would prefer to be wrong.&quot;" created="Fri, 09 Sep 2005 14:34:55 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 8" created="Thu, 08 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/08/corporalBushBigger.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/08/bushy.jpg&quot; width=&quot;65&quot; height=&quot;79&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named bushy.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.frc.org/get.cfm?i=WU05I05&amp;f=PG03I03&quot;&gt;Tony Perkins&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;There was a television show in the 1960's called F-Troop about an incompetent band of post-Civil War troops stationed at Fort Courage, somewhere west of the Missouri. Having been forced to deal with &lt;font size=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;FEMA&lt;/font&gt; and other government bureaus these last few days, I am reminded of this sitcom, except this is no comedy.&quot;" created="Fri, 09 Sep 2005 00:20:28 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blaserco.com/blogs/2005/09/08.html#a364&quot;&gt;Pfizer is offering&lt;/a&gt; free drugs to Katerina survivors. " created="Thu, 08 Sep 2005 21:46:21 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://inessential.com/?comments=1&amp;postid=3169&quot;&gt;Brent Simmons reviews&lt;/a&gt; user interface trends on the Mac." created="Thu, 08 Sep 2005 22:08:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.google.com/images?q=channel%209%20guy&amp;hl=en&amp;lr=&amp;safe=off&amp;sa=N&amp;tab=wi&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/08/nineguy.gif&quot; width=&quot;78&quot; height=&quot;112&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named nineguy.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://channel9.msdn.com/showpost.aspx?postid=111598&quot;&gt;Scoble interviews&lt;/a&gt; Microsoft founder Bill Gates. If I were him I'd ask if he reads Scobleizer. And of course I'd like to know if he reads Scripting News. And it would be cool if he asked him some hard questions, like this: If you had a choice would you be running Microsoft of 1976 or Microsoft of 2005? What advantages do Google and Yahoo have over Microsoft? Does the largeness of Microsoft ever get you down? Now, of course it's hard to interview a guy of Gates's stature, especially when he signs the paycheck of your boss's boss's boss's boss's boss's boss's boss. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Thu, 08 Sep 2005 21:00:40 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.veen.com/jeff/archives/000782.html&quot;&gt;Jeff Veen wants&lt;/a&gt; to know who will build Web 2.0. " created="Thu, 08 Sep 2005 20:19:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Berkeley is home to &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/08/politicalBandwidth.gif&quot;&gt;political wireless&lt;/a&gt; networks. " created="Thu, 08 Sep 2005 17:39:44 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Vint Cerf &lt;a href=&quot;http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2005/09/cerfs-up-at-google.html&quot;&gt;joins Google&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;See you on the ‘Net!&quot;" created="Thu, 08 Sep 2005 17:26:50 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Maybe Vint will convince Eric, Sergey and Larry to talk with &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.com.com/Google+hires+Net+pioneer+Vint+Cerf/2100-1032_3-5854806.html?part=rss&amp;tag=5854806&amp;subj=news&quot;&gt;News.com&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 08 Sep 2005 17:48:03 GMT"/>
				<outline text="It's cool that there are so many &lt;a href=&quot;http://movies.yahoo.com/showtimes/showtimes?z=Berkeley%2C+CA&amp;date=20050908&quot;&gt;movie theaters&lt;/a&gt; in Berkeley. " created="Thu, 08 Sep 2005 13:06:01 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Ask a fish to describe water. It can't because it doesn't know that water exists. But try changing the water, its temperature, or add a pollutant, and all of a sudden the fish gets it. " created="Thu, 08 Sep 2005 13:06:36 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2001/09/08&quot;&gt;On this day four years ago&lt;/a&gt; we had no idea what was in store for us three days hence." created="Thu, 08 Sep 2005 13:11:08 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 7" created="Wed, 07 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/07/maynardGKrebs.gif&quot; width=&quot;95&quot; height=&quot;263&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named maynardGKrebs.gif&quot;&gt;An amazing Netflix experience. Yesterday at 4PM, I dropped two movies in a mailbox in Berkeley. They were addressed to Netflix in Daytona Beach. This morning I got an email  saying they had been received and this evening they mailed my next two movies, claiming they'd be here &lt;i&gt;tomorrow.&lt;/i&gt; Wow." created="Thu, 08 Sep 2005 01:33:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Boing Boing now has &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/07/boingads.gif&quot;&gt;distracting graphic ads&lt;/a&gt; in its RSS feed. So far it's just making it hard to scan their blog posts, but if it starts interfering as I scan others, I'll unsub. It'll be the second feed I said goodbye to because of annoying item-level ads. It's Feedburner again. Why they don't give users a way to opt out of these ads is beyond me. " created="Wed, 07 Sep 2005 22:56:43 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0107946/2005/09/07.html#a4946&quot;&gt;Ed Cone points&lt;/a&gt; to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thinkprogress.org/katrina-timeline&quot;&gt;timeline&lt;/a&gt; of Katrina events." created="Wed, 07 Sep 2005 21:07:28 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.com.com/Apples+Rokr+iTunes+phone+ready+to+roll/2100-1041_3-5851608.html?tag=nefd.lede&quot;&gt;News.com&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Apple Computer on Wednesday rolled out a cell phone capable of playing music and accessing iTunes.&quot;" created="Wed, 07 Sep 2005 18:18:19 GMT"/>
				<outline text="They also announced a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/ipodnano/&quot;&gt;new iPod&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 07 Sep 2005 18:25:49 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ernietheattorney.net/ernie_the_attorney/2005/09/report_from_ste.html&quot;&gt;Steve Domas&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I just couldn't take it and went down to N.O. today. And I'm very heartened. Uptown, Warehouse District, and CBD are dry.&quot;" created="Wed, 07 Sep 2005 17:47:41 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2005/09/07.html#a11049&quot;&gt;Scoble&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Steve Gillmor has this whole industry wrong.&quot;" created="Wed, 07 Sep 2005 16:24:57 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/07/nagin.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/07/naginhead.jpg&quot; width=&quot;55&quot; height=&quot;97&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named naginhead.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The problem with authority these days is that they love themselves more than those they serve. George Bush praises the bureaucrats, you're doing a great job Bob, so are you Mike. Keep up the good work Pete. But wait a minute. People are dying. Are they doing a great job too? I guess if we interviewed them they might not say that they're too busy right now to talk about who or what killed them. Maybe they wouldn't be so happy with the president, maybe they wouldn't find his excuses very convincing. Mayor Ray Nagin of New Orleans is an exception, maybe he wasn't always so, but he is now. Same with the Times-Picayune. Times of major need can shake foundations and change things and wake people up. Too bad these things don't change before the levees break." created="Wed, 07 Sep 2005 15:57:27 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Hurricane Ophelia &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nhc.noaa.gov/text/refresh/MIATCPAT1+shtml/071738.shtml&quot;&gt;public advisory&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nhc.noaa.gov/index-at.xml&quot;&gt;feed&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Wed, 07 Sep 2005 15:55:41 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cadenhead.org/workbench/news/2742/i-awoke-morning-40&quot;&gt;Rogers Cadenhead&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I awoke this morning to 40 mph winds from an outer band of Tropical Storm Ophelia.&quot;" created="Wed, 07 Sep 2005 15:54:06 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/07/podphone.jpg&quot; width=&quot;73&quot; height=&quot;147&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named podphone.jpg&quot;&gt;All day yesterday I wondered if the world had finally come to its senses and denied Apple the huge unfair public relations advantage it has garnered by turning every secretive announcement into a rumor festival. I thought their announcement was yesterday. Maybe they're getting the same treatment of other technology companies, I wondered. I even went into an Apple store. And a Cingular store. No sign of anything new. Hmmm. Foolish me, I was off by one day. Hurricane or no, the rumor mill is churning. I refuse to get caught up in the foolishness. I refuse, I say. Then why am I &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/go/rss/-/2/hi/technology/4222394.stm&quot;&gt;pointing&lt;/a&gt; to a BBC article with speculation on what Apple's announcement might be? &lt;i&gt;Arrrrrgh.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Wed, 07 Sep 2005 12:06:42 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.zdnet.com/Gillmor/?p=149&amp;part=rss&amp;tag=feed&amp;subj=zdblog&quot;&gt;Steve Gillmor&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;What, you say, no word processor?&quot;" created="Wed, 07 Sep 2005 11:34:04 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/09/07/arts/television/07opra.html?ex=1283745600&amp;en=d1766a1b423fc0e9&amp;ei=5088&amp;partner=rssnyt&amp;emc=rss&quot;&gt;Oprah Winfrey&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;This should not have happened.&quot;" created="Wed, 07 Sep 2005 05:45:23 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 6" created="Tue, 06 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Mark Bernstein: &lt;a href=&quot;http://markbernstein.org/Sep0501/WhatEnded.html&quot;&gt;What Ended&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 07 Sep 2005 05:11:29 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Today's purchases include a new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/mightymouse/&quot;&gt;Apple mouse&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.overstock.com/cgi-bin/d2.cgi?PAGE=PRODUCT&amp;PROD_ID=1570208&amp;cid=48717&amp;fp=F&quot;&gt;Sims 2 for the Mac&lt;/a&gt;. Don Hopkins, one of the Sims authors, says that the Sims for the PC requires special graphics hardware that apparently my machines (a Sony and a ThinkPad) don't have. Hopefully &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.apple.com/1-800-MY-APPLE/WebObjects/AppleStore.woa/wo/StoreReentry.wo?family=iBook&quot;&gt;my Mac&lt;/a&gt; is capable. I also bought a new Linksys router to go with my cable modem." created="Wed, 07 Sep 2005 00:26:33 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nola.com/newslogs/breakingtp/&quot;&gt;The New Orleans Times-Picayune&lt;/a&gt; has been a total inspiration. Their coverage of Katrina has been a milestone in journalism. Great stuff. Proof that necessity is the mother of invention. " created="Tue, 06 Sep 2005 21:41:25 GMT"/>
				<outline text="A Morning Coffee Notes &lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cn05Sep06.mp3&quot;&gt;podcast begins with a song&lt;/a&gt;, and then gets around to a rambling discussion of New Orleans and what has changed not just for the people of the Crescent City, but for all of us. " created="Tue, 06 Sep 2005 20:02:16 GMT" type="link" url="http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cn05Sep06.mp3"/>
				<outline text="10/21/02: &lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.userland.com/stories/storyReader$19964&quot;&gt;How to redirect an RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 06 Sep 2005 16:47:53 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Audioblog.com &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.audioblog.com/blog/_archives/2005/9/3/1195399.html&quot;&gt;finds&lt;/a&gt; investors in Japan, Korea and China. " created="Tue, 06 Sep 2005 15:58:08 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/06/california.gif&quot; width=&quot;125&quot; height=&quot;81&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named california.gif&quot;&gt;The cable company got my Internet working this morning, so now I have my own line to the outside world. Today marks the first day in a long time that I begin the day with a live net connection and nowhere to go. No four hundred miles to drive. Only one meeting, and it's on the phone. I have time for a walk, and healthy eating, an afternoon nap, and back to work on software. I have a great view of the Berkeley hills from my office window, every bit as stunning as the view out my window in Florida. Look forward to some pictures of life around Berkeley. " created="Tue, 06 Sep 2005 15:28:12 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opinionjournal.com/columnists/bminiter/?id=110007212&quot;&gt;WSJ&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;New Orleans's kids now have a better shot at getting a decent education.&quot;" created="Tue, 06 Sep 2005 15:04:47 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chron.com/cs/CDA/rssstory.mpl/special/05/katrina/3340927&quot;&gt;Houston Chronicle&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The 70,000-unit apartment glut is disappearing.&quot;" created="Tue, 06 Sep 2005 11:40:55 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mikewatkins.net/categories/technical/hurricanetech.html&quot;&gt;Mike Watkins&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Don’t write one line of code, not one XML spec, until you’ve worked a week in a Red Cross call center on family reunification tasks.&quot;" created="Tue, 06 Sep 2005 11:32:45 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.salon.com/0000014/2005/09/05.html#a915&quot;&gt;Scott Rosenberg&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Let there be some accountability.&quot;" created="Tue, 06 Sep 2005 11:12:42 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/3036677/&quot;&gt;Keith Oberman&lt;/a&gt; was awesome &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/8514671/#050905a&quot;&gt;tonight&lt;/a&gt;. Just awesome. " created="Tue, 06 Sep 2005 04:50:34 GMT"/>
				<outline text="I was checking my email at &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.google.com/maps?q=1600+Shattuck+Avenue,berkeley,ca&amp;ll=37.878647,-122.269335&amp;spn=0.007884,0.016491&amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;Starbucks&lt;/a&gt; on Shattuck today and who was sitting across from me but &lt;a href=&quot;http://chinadigitaltimes.net/xiao_qiang/&quot;&gt;Xiao Qiang&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Small world!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Tue, 06 Sep 2005 04:48:50 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 5" created="Mon, 05 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/09/05#a5555&quot;&gt;Editorial&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Today's New Orleans may be the first virtual city.&quot;" created="Mon, 05 Sep 2005 11:09:03 GMT"/>
				<outline text="My Internet coverage will suck for the next X days. Looking forward to getting it all together sometime soon. I'll let you know when it happens. " created="Tue, 06 Sep 2005 02:12:39 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Postscript: I was able to connect through one of my neighbors' wifi. Berkeley is wonderful. Hehehe. " created="Tue, 06 Sep 2005 03:53:30 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/americas/4214516.stm&quot;&gt;Interesting BBC editorial&lt;/a&gt; asks if Katrina has saved US media. " created="Tue, 06 Sep 2005 02:07:33 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Jeff Jarvis: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buzzmachine.com/index.php/2005/09/05/recovery-20-a-call-to-convene/&quot;&gt;Recovery 2.0: A call to convene&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 06 Sep 2005 02:12:04 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rexblog.com/2005/09/05#a7981&quot;&gt;Rex Hammock&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Political persuasions, like the earth, can be round.&quot;" created="Mon, 05 Sep 2005 13:58:42 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2005/09/05.html#a11047&quot;&gt;Scoble reviews&lt;/a&gt; my car's navigation system. (The toll-road avoidance feature is an option that can be turned off, but it defaults on, which is probably wrong. It was wrong for me, since my first trip was from St Augustine to the Orlando Airport, which involves a toll road, if you go the most direct way.)" created="Mon, 05 Sep 2005 20:42:37 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/06/11#When:7:56:28PM&quot;&gt;A podcast duet&lt;/a&gt; with my navigation system, 6/11/05." created="Mon, 05 Sep 2005 20:49:46 GMT"/>
				<outline text="This is really puzzling. &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/09/04#When:10:06:40PM&quot;&gt;Yesterday&lt;/a&gt; the Charlotte Observer OPML file worked with my software, but today it's &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/05/brokenOpml.gif&quot;&gt;broken&lt;/a&gt;. If anyone from the Observer has a clue, I'd love to &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/dave/profiles/sendMail?usernum=1&amp;referer=http://www.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;hear&lt;/a&gt; what happened. Thanks!" created="Mon, 05 Sep 2005 20:29:28 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.salon.com/0000014/2005/09/04.html#a914&quot;&gt;Scott Rosenberg&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;No one knows how many thousands are dead. A minimum of hundreds of thousands are homeless. And Bush and his men are passing the buck. It doesn't get much lower than this.&quot;" created="Mon, 05 Sep 2005 10:37:45 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://zesty.ca/pfif/pfif-draft.html&quot;&gt;This document&lt;/a&gt; &quot;defines the People Finder Interchange Format, which encompasses both a data model and an XML-based exchange format for sharing data about people who are missing or displaced by natural or human-made disasters.&quot;" created="Mon, 05 Sep 2005 14:06:04 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boston.com/business/technology/articles/2005/09/05/investors_get_behind_podcasting_but_will_the_listeners/?page=2&quot;&gt;Boston Globe&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;What's special about podcasting, though, is how it makes it simple for individuals or companies to express themselves and, if what they have to say is interesting, enlightening, or clever, to earn attention. You can point someone to a worthy podcast through a link on your blog, or an e-mail to a friend, in a way you could never point them to a snippet of radio. That's powerful.&quot;" created="Mon, 05 Sep 2005 10:30:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cn05Sep05.mp3&quot;&gt;Patrick and I sing&lt;/a&gt; a few verses of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.whitetreeaz.com/plastic_jesus/plasticj.htm&quot;&gt;Plastic Jesus&lt;/a&gt;, and we leave a voicemail for Dawn &amp; Drew." created="Mon, 05 Sep 2005 04:56:02 GMT" type="link" url="http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/cn05Sep05.mp3"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 4" created="Sun, 04 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chron.com/cs/CDA/rssstory.mpl/special/05/katrina/3339323&quot;&gt;Houston Chronicle&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;New Orleans police killed four looters who had opened fire on them today.&quot;" created="Mon, 05 Sep 2005 02:54:24 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rexblog.com/2005/09/04#a7975&quot;&gt;Rex Hammock links&lt;/a&gt; to various Katrina people-finder databases." created="Mon, 05 Sep 2005 02:52:50 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The Charlotte Observer &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.charlotte.com/mld/charlotte/rss/&quot;&gt;has RSS&lt;/a&gt;, and an &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.worldoutline.com/2005/September/4/Charlotte%20Observer%20RSS%20feeds/Site%3A%20Charlotte.com/&quot;&gt;OPML file&lt;/a&gt; organizing them. " created="Mon, 05 Sep 2005 02:06:40 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/04/think.gif&quot; width=&quot;69&quot; height=&quot;59&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named think.gif&quot;&gt;Watching Larry King, seeing how helpless people are at finding out the fate of family members, it's pitiful that we information technologists have not marshalled the systems to distribute information about survivors of the aftermath of Katrina. Following up on Doc Searls's &lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.weblogs.com/2005/09/04#warOnError&quot;&gt;War On Error&lt;/a&gt; concept, below, we ought to solve this problem as quickly as we can for Katrina and then deploy systems that make this work much better for future disasters. It's 2005, we have mastered the technology, now let's deploy it, with the intent of competence and success. " created="Mon, 05 Sep 2005 01:42:56 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.weblogs.com/2005/09/04#warOnError&quot;&gt;Doc Searls&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;In the War on Error, people will need to take the lead. Governments will need to follow or get out of the way.&quot;" created="Mon, 05 Sep 2005 01:37:35 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theday.com/eng/web/news/re.aspx?re=916E4C65-4234-4197-BB4C-2F837D6A90FA&quot;&gt;The Day&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The hurricane that struck Louisiana was nicknamed Katrina by the National Weather Service. Its real name is global warming.&quot;" created="Mon, 05 Sep 2005 00:59:50 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nola.com/newslogs/breakingtp/index.ssf?/mtlogs/nola_Times-Picayune/archives/2005_09.html#076939&quot;&gt;Times-Picayune&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The breach in the 17th Street Canal levee that had put the city of New Orleans underwater was essentially closed early Sunday evening.&quot;" created="Mon, 05 Sep 2005 00:57:09 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://ngs.woc.noaa.gov/katrina/090E29M_KATRINA.HTM&quot;&gt;Hi-rez satellite pics&lt;/a&gt; of post-Katrina New Orleans." created="Mon, 05 Sep 2005 00:50:01 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Pics: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/09/04#a5548&quot;&gt;Monterey, Pebble Beach, Carmel&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 04 Sep 2005 22:23:34 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Army Times: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.armytimes.com/story.php?f=1-292925-1077495.php&quot;&gt;Troops begin combat operations in New Orleans&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 04 Sep 2005 17:59:46 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/09/04#a5547&quot;&gt;Patrick wonders&lt;/a&gt; how he'd spend $1 billion if he had that much money." created="Sun, 04 Sep 2005 17:51:50 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/09/04#a5545&quot;&gt;Scoble models&lt;/a&gt; modern blogging attire." created="Sun, 04 Sep 2005 16:55:53 GMT"/>
				<outline text="According to Technorati, this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; is #1 for: &lt;a href=&quot;http://technorati.com/blogs/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://technorati.com/blogs/podcasting&quot;&gt;podcasting&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://technorati.com/blogs/opml&quot;&gt;OPML&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 04 Sep 2005 15:48:15 GMT"/>
				<outline text="But it isn't in the top 20 for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.technorati.com/blogs/Syndication&quot;&gt;Syndication&lt;/a&gt;. Huh?" created="Sun, 04 Sep 2005 16:28:57 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/09/04/national/nationalspecial/04quarter.html?ex=1283486400&amp;en=790763bd3a93a7c8&amp;ei=5088&amp;partner=rssnyt&amp;emc=rss&quot;&gt;NY Times&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The French Quarter has been spared the worst of Hurricane Katrina's winds and sitting high enough to have avoided the flooding.&quot;" created="Sun, 04 Sep 2005 15:38:31 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nola.com/weblogs/nola/&quot;&gt;Nola.com&lt;/a&gt;, the site run by the Times-Picayune, has messages about hundreds of people still trapped and dying in New Orleans. " created="Sun, 04 Sep 2005 10:53:52 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 3" created="Sat, 03 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="This is what &lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/09/03#a5538&quot;&gt;Scoble looks like&lt;/a&gt; when he blogs." created="Sun, 04 Sep 2005 03:51:48 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/03/renquistdies.gif&quot;&gt;On CNN&lt;/a&gt; -- US Supreme Court Chief Justice William Renquist has died." created="Sun, 04 Sep 2005 03:11:49 GMT"/>
				<outline text="And here's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/ohYouShattup.mp3&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; we did. It's got a very simple theme." created="Sun, 04 Sep 2005 00:35:40 GMT" type="link" url="http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/ohYouShattup.mp3"/>
				<outline text="Patrick Scoble's favorite podcast is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apeboymonkeygirl.com/&quot;&gt;The Daily Download.&lt;/a&gt; He's almost 12 years old. He also likes &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dawnanddrew.com/&quot;&gt;Dawn and Drew&lt;/a&gt;, but don't tell his &lt;a href=&quot;http://scoble.weblogs.com/&quot;&gt;dad&lt;/a&gt;! &quot;;-&gt;&quot;" created="Sat, 03 Sep 2005 23:49:57 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Check this out. The Podfeed podcasting &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podfeed.net/&quot;&gt;directory&lt;/a&gt; is now &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podfeed.net/opml/directory.opml&quot;&gt;available in OPML&lt;/a&gt;. Awesome. Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/03/podfeedDirectory.gif&quot;&gt;screen shot&lt;/a&gt; of the outline being viewed in the OPML Editor. And here's an &lt;a href=&quot;http://casting.opml.org/Directory%20of%20podcasting%20directories/Podfeed%20directory%20in%20OPML/The%20Podfeed.net%20Podcast%20Directory/&quot;&gt;HTML rendering&lt;/a&gt; of their OPML. I bet the folks at the OPML &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opmlsearch.com/&quot;&gt;search engine&lt;/a&gt; will be indexing it shortly. &lt;i&gt;Hot damn!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Sat, 03 Sep 2005 23:39:34 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nhc.noaa.gov/text/refresh/MIATCPAT4+shtml/032037.shtml&quot;&gt;NOAA&lt;/a&gt;: \&quot;&lt;font size=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;MARIA NEARING HURRICANE STRENGTH.&lt;/font&gt;\&quot;" created="Sat, 03 Sep 2005 22:18:53 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chron.com/cs/CDA/rssstory.mpl/special/05/katrina/3338327&quot;&gt;According to the Houston Chronicle&lt;/a&gt;, the French Quarter has not been damaged by flooding, the Garden District and St Charles Avenue were heavily damaged by wind, and also has not flooded. From Google's satellite &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.google.com/maps?q=New+Orleans&amp;t=e&quot;&gt;shots&lt;/a&gt;, much of Uptown, where Tulane and Loyola universites and Audubon Park are located, is not shown. . " created="Sat, 03 Sep 2005 22:05:37 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.minnesota.publicradio.org/features/2005/09/03_ap_katrina6/?rsssource=1&quot;&gt;MPR&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Thousands more bedraggled refugees were bused to salvation Saturday, leaving the city of New Orleans to the dead and dying, the elderly and frail stranded too many days without food, water or medical care.&quot;" created="Sat, 03 Sep 2005 21:55:58 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0001011/2005/09/03.html#a11032&quot;&gt;Scoble has links&lt;/a&gt; to Google Maps with satellite imagery of post-Katrina New Orleans." created="Sat, 03 Sep 2005 21:50:44 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.scripting.com/2005/08/01#When:4:33:03AM&quot;&gt;Earlier&lt;/a&gt; this summer I read McCullough's history of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.johnstownpa.com/History/hist30.html&quot;&gt;Johnstown Flood&lt;/a&gt; of 1889. Like New Orleans, fires played a role in the destruction and loss of life. Johnstown was rebuilt. " created="Sat, 03 Sep 2005 21:51:15 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Houston Chronicle: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chron.com/cs/CDA/rssstory.mpl/special/05/katrina/3338396&quot;&gt;Some evacuees say they won't return&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sat, 03 Sep 2005 21:57:59 GMT"/>
				<outline text="2:30PM Pacific: Greetings from Monterey, CA." created="Sat, 03 Sep 2005 21:31:29 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 2" created="Fri, 02 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nola.com/newslogs/breakingtp/index.ssf?/mtlogs/nola_Times-Picayune/archives/2005_09.html#076316&quot;&gt;Times-Picayune&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The Lake Pontchartrain Causeway sustained no major damage from Katrina’s storm surge, the bridge’s general manager said in the first official report of its condition.&quot;" created="Fri, 02 Sep 2005 22:39:12 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chron.com/cs/CDA/rssstory.mpl/special/05/katrina/3336345&quot;&gt;Houston Chronicle&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Four days after Hurricane Katrina struck, the National Guard arrived in force today with food, water and weapons.&quot;" created="Fri, 02 Sep 2005 18:45:22 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://static2.podcatch.com/blogs/gems/snedit/WWLAMInterviewNagin.mp3&quot;&gt;Audio&lt;/a&gt; of WWL-AM interview with New Orleans mayor Ray Nagin. " created="Fri, 02 Sep 2005 15:43:48 GMT"/>
				<outline text="That's a must-listen-to interview. Stunning. People are breaking into hospitals because they're addicts who have run out of drugs. " created="Fri, 02 Sep 2005 16:05:26 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.time.com/time/archive/preview/0,10987,997384,00.html&quot;&gt;Time Magazine in 2000&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;If a flood of Biblical proportions were to lay waste to New Orleans, Joe Suhayda has a good idea how it would happen.&quot;" created="Fri, 02 Sep 2005 18:40:12 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Forbes: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/9174372/&quot;&gt;Will Katrina ground airlines for good?&lt;/a&gt;" created="Fri, 02 Sep 2005 16:28:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usatoday.com/weather/news/2000/wnoflood.htm&quot;&gt;USA Today, in 2000&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;New Orleans, a city of nearly 1.4 million people, sits below sea level, as much as 8 feet lower than water in nearby Lake Pontchartrain and the Mississippi River and its delta, where it empties into the Gulf of Mexico.&quot;" created="Fri, 02 Sep 2005 15:39:35 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.weblogs.com/2005/09/01#prophesies&quot;&gt;Doc Searls&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;When the dead are counted, most of them will have been poor.&quot;" created="Fri, 02 Sep 2005 14:56:06 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Jason Lefkowitz, via email: \&quot;Bill Moyers' PBS show &lt;font size=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;NOW&lt;/font&gt; did an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pbs.org/now/transcript/transcript_neworleans.html&quot;&gt;entire program&lt;/a&gt; on the subject of 'what happens if New Orleans gets hit by a category 5 hurricane' in 2002:\&quot;" created="Fri, 02 Sep 2005 14:27:06 GMT"/>
				<outline text="John Pedersen via email: &quot;Why are the flags still flying at full staff?&quot;" created="Fri, 02 Sep 2005 11:04:22 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciam.com/article.cfm?chanID=sa006&amp;articleID=00060286-CB58-1315-8B5883414B7F0000&amp;pageNumber=1&amp;catID=2&quot;&gt;Scientific American article in 2001&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;A major hurricane could swamp New Orleans under 20 feet of water, killing thousands. Human activities along the Mississippi River have dramatically increased the risk, and now only massive reengineering of southeastern Louisiana can save the city.&quot;" created="Fri, 02 Sep 2005 11:10:14 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cbsnews.com/stories/2003/02/24/tech/main541807.shtml?cmp=EM8705?CMP=ILC-SearchStories&quot;&gt;AP story in 2003&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The levees built to keep the Mississippi within its banks all but stopped the floods that used to lay down new layers of soil over the land.&quot;" created="Fri, 02 Sep 2005 11:07:38 GMT"/>
				<outline text="MoveOn's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hurricanehousing.org/&quot;&gt;hurricane housing&lt;/a&gt; matchup site. " created="Fri, 02 Sep 2005 10:05:43 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/02/60Minutes.gif&quot; width=&quot;85&quot; height=&quot;105&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named 60Minutes.gif&quot;&gt;On last &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnn.com/CNN/Programs/aaron.brown/&quot;&gt;NewsNight&lt;/a&gt; yesterday, Aaron Brown corrected President Bush who claimed that no one could have foreseen the collapse of the levees in New Orleans. Brown said that two reporters at the New Orleans Times-Picayune &lt;i&gt;had&lt;/i&gt; foreseen it. I'm sure that's true, but it didn't stop there. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cbsnews.com/sections/60minutes/main3415.shtml&quot;&gt;CBS 60 Minutes&lt;/a&gt; had a segment on the issue, not sure when it aired, but it was some time back. It featured a federal bureaucrat in New Orleans, a very colorful guy, who explained eloquently how precarious the situation was. I saw the show and it made a very clear impression. That's why I was covering Katrina from the New Orleans perspective long before it was a national story. It looked like the scenario that 60 Minutes warned of, and in the end what happened was exactly what they predicted would. I've tried to find the piece, but haven't found it yet. If you can, please send me a pointer. We need to find this guy. " created="Fri, 02 Sep 2005 08:23:55 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/02/train.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/02/carfront.pg.jpg&quot; width=&quot;85&quot; height=&quot;81&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named carfront.pg.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In the background are all the other preventable disasters that have been predicted. Recently, I think again on 60 Minutes, I saw a story about a key vulnerability in New York's infrastructure -- the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nycsubway.org/&quot;&gt;subway system&lt;/a&gt; and the rivers it passes under. If there were a breach in one of the tunnels, say a bomb exploded, not ncessarily a big one, and caused one of the tunnels to fail, letting in water from the East River, for example. The entire &lt;a href=&quot;http://essaysfromexodus.scripting.com/pictures/viewer$998&quot;&gt;system&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://essaysfromexodus.scripting.com/pictures/viewer$999&quot;&gt;would&lt;/a&gt; flood, quickly, possibly killing thousands, and turning the city back to the time before the subways. Like New Orleans's levees, this technical innovation allowed the city to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.subwaywebnews.com/history.htm&quot;&gt;grow&lt;/a&gt;, from a relatively small concentration of homes and businesses in lower Manhattan, populating the rest of Manhattan and the boroughs -- the Bronx, Brooklyn, Queens. Staten Island, which is still relatively unpopulated, has no subway connecting it with the rest of the city. People who &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/worldlatest/story/0,1280,-5249797,00.html&quot;&gt;argue&lt;/a&gt; that we shouldn't rebuild New Orleans would probably say we shouldn't rebuild New York either. Now, the city &lt;i&gt;could&lt;/i&gt; be protected against this disaster, with walls that close automatically when there's a breach, and stay closed until it can be repaired. As far as I know, nothing is being done about this vulnerability." created="Fri, 02 Sep 2005 08:37:07 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 1" created="Thu, 01 Sep 2005 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pbs.org/newshour/rss/redir/http://www.pbs.org/newshour/bb/weather/july-dec05/levees_8-31.html&quot;&gt;NewsHour&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The editor of Scientific American magazine explains how the levees broke and what crews can do to plug the holes.&quot;" created="Fri, 02 Sep 2005 02:14:13 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.docuverse.com/blog/donpark/EntryViewPage.aspx?guid=02bf1b61-5b8d-4ad1-a6a5-5ceb35ea7ec2&quot;&gt;Don Park&lt;/a&gt; has before-and-after sattelite pictures of New Orleans." created="Thu, 01 Sep 2005 23:52:10 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Here's my &lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/discuss/msgReader$5507?mode=day&quot;&gt;answer&lt;/a&gt; to Dan Conover's &lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/09/01#a5495&quot;&gt;question&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 01 Sep 2005 21:31:35 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/world/americas/4206620.stm&quot;&gt;BBC&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;New Orleans Mayor Ray Nagin has issued a 'desperate SOS' for thousands of people stranded with no food or water at the city's convention centre.&quot;" created="Thu, 01 Sep 2005 21:27:00 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lakeprovidencehelp.com/&quot;&gt;Brendan Greely&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Since Sunday, hundreds of evacuees from New Orleans have arrived in Lake Providence and the surrounding area.&quot;" created="Thu, 01 Sep 2005 21:14:18 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/rss/podcast/podcast_directory.php&quot;&gt;NPR's podcast directory&lt;/a&gt;. Looking for the OPML..." created="Fri, 02 Sep 2005 03:24:24 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/01/worldTradeCenterDemise.gif&quot; width=&quot;182&quot; height=&quot;248&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named worldTradeCenterDemise.gif&quot;&gt;I've had a chance to think about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usopen.org/en_US/index.html&quot;&gt;US Open&lt;/a&gt; tennis tournament going on in NYC, and I am very angry about it. How dare the citizens of NY, who received so much help from the rest of the country, host a sporting event, while this tragedy is unfolding. September 11 was an instant event, it destroyed a large complex of buildings and killed thousands of Americans, but it was over quickly, and except for emotional damage, the city went on exactly as it did before. This is so much bigger, it effects so many more people, and its effect will be felt for the indefinite future. New York must stop right now, and reflect on exactly how it can now come to the aid of the rest of the country. It is completely inappropriate for a sport tournament to be going on now, while so many are suffering, &lt;i&gt;while so many are dying. &lt;/i&gt;" created="Thu, 01 Sep 2005 19:27:47 GMT"/>
				<outline text="It's not as if &lt;a href=&quot;http://pubs.usgs.gov/dds/dds-29/&quot;&gt;California&lt;/a&gt; can afford to look the other way, either. " created="Thu, 01 Sep 2005 19:39:45 GMT"/>
				<outline text="The president is going to the &lt;i&gt;wrong place&lt;/i&gt; tomorrow. New Orleans is where the problem started. Yes, there are still people there who need help, desperately, but the help they need is to be removed from New Orleans. Now Mr President, where will they be moved to? After they move, they won't be going back to New Orleans anytime soon. No planning is possible there. Touring New Orleans is looking in the wrong direction, back in time. That's just plain dumb. Go to Houston, go to Atlanta, Jackson, go to places that are habitable, and start working on getting these Americans, most of whom voted for you (how different from NYC) into homes befitting Americans. We need to figure out how we're going to house over a million homeless US citizens. I think now you have to very seriously consider removing our troops from Iraq, and bringing them home to the US, where they can build housing for the people of the United States. I don't think the dwindling support for the war will last through the next few weeks, as the dire state of our country sinks in with the populace. " created="Thu, 01 Sep 2005 19:14:50 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Dan Conover asks a &lt;a href=&quot;http://davetravel.scripting.com/2005/09/01#a5495&quot;&gt;question&lt;/a&gt; that's much on my mind too." created="Thu, 01 Sep 2005 18:20:24 GMT"/>
				<outline text="CNN: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnn.com/2005/WEATHER/09/01/Katrina.SpareRooms.ap/index.html&quot;&gt;Americans opening spare rooms to evacuees&lt;/a&gt;." created="Thu, 01 Sep 2005 18:23:47 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Today is move-in day for me in Berkeley. I have a bright shiny new place to live, with a great view and great plentiful food nearby. I feel very lucky. " created="Thu, 01 Sep 2005 14:37:23 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rexblog.com/2005/09/01#a7892&quot;&gt;Rex Hammock&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Nashville is becoming a destination for people leaving those areas. There are lots of folks here opening their homes to friends and relatives.&quot;" created="Thu, 01 Sep 2005 14:34:33 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/images/2001/09/15/usFlag.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/01/think.gif&quot; width=&quot;69&quot; height=&quot;59&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named think.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Good morning. I'm watching the continuing television coverage of the Katrina aftermath (which needs a new name, some have suggested &lt;a href=&quot;http://dictionary.reference.com/search?q=diaspora&quot;&gt;diaspora&lt;/a&gt;). Already nearby cities are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nola.com/newslogs/breakingtp/index.ssf?/mtlogs/nola_Times-Picayune/archives/2005_09.html#075628&quot;&gt;turning away&lt;/a&gt; refugees. You have to wonder how far the refugees will travel. Will the problem spread throughout the South? Beyond? And what about mercy for the people, where are they going to go? How would you feel if you were a refugee? A woman on the I-10 says angrily that she's a taxpayer, but no one is trying to save her life. These are Americans! Meanwhile, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startribune.com/stories/503/5590744.html&quot;&gt;sports&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mlb.mlb.com/NASApp/mlb/news/wrap.jsp?ymd=20050831&amp;content_id=1191810&amp;vkey=wrapup2005&amp;fext=.jsp&amp;c_id=mlb&quot;&gt;events&lt;/a&gt; continue. The Director of Homeland Security preaches preparedness. Ads on TV urge us to buy huge recreation vehicles and to attend home decoration shows. Buy a new deodorant, switch to a new cola. Americans are dying, right now. Nothing like this happened in the aftermath of 9/11 and that disaster was &lt;i&gt;much smaller&lt;/i&gt; than this one. A small part of a big city was destroyed. In this event a large US city is being &lt;a href=&quot;http://dictionary.reference.com/search?q=ravaged&quot;&gt;ravaged&lt;/a&gt;. The disaster is continuing. The national response is wholly inappropriate. I think we have to get ready to welcome the refugees into our homes, to absorb the population of New Orleans and the surrounding area into the rest of the country. It's clear that's where we're headed." created="Thu, 01 Sep 2005 14:07:04 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/09/01/opinion/01thu1.html?ex=1283227200&amp;en=abe5e2ccb6821298&amp;ei=5090&amp;partner=rssuserland&amp;emc=rss&quot;&gt;NY Times&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The president appeared a day later than he was needed.&quot;" created="Thu, 01 Sep 2005 05:36:17 GMT"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gumbopages.com/Tuba/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2005/09/01/ribbon_blk.gif&quot; width=&quot;34&quot; height=&quot;48&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named ribbon_blk.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;" created="Thu, 01 Sep 2005 23:56:57 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			</outline>
		</body>
	</opml>
