<?xml version="1.0"?>
<opml version="2.0">
	<head>
		<title>Scripting News</title>
		<dateCreated>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 15:51:38 GMT</dateCreated>
		<urlPublic>http://scripting.com/publicfolder/scripting/blog.opml</urlPublic>
		<flPublic>true</flPublic>
		<ownerEmail>dave.winer@gmail.com</ownerEmail>
		<ownerId>dave.winer@gmail.com</ownerId>
		<urlUpdateSocket>wss://drummer.land/</urlUpdateSocket>
		<dateModified>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 13:50:29 GMT</dateModified>
		<expansionState></expansionState>
		<lastCursor>0</lastCursor>
		</head>
	<body>
		<outline text="September 2025" created="Mon, 01 Sep 2025 13:09:14 GMT" name="september2025" type="calendarMonth">
			<outline text="September 30" created="Tue, 30 Sep 2025 15:17:00 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="30">
				<outline text="&quot;WordLand&quot; is not a blogging platform, it builds on a blogging platform. " created="Tue, 30 Sep 2025 16:32:07 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The &lt;a href=&quot;https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/%5EGSPC/?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAN5lwHEXSbu3MdQqpmURpinbGpH440mO7t1lOolTGdgOvaxp4Ik1eryviEO4dcS_9J2bS9TCWSwgeHBE1ceQXCjNmHXsS4LttOtD0WNVeqjo8wLper1K7ez_j9xi8YZwYd1IMivOrEWOzoaeMw9mvt0hkhrap2nIN42yMSJrStix&quot;&gt;stock market&lt;/a&gt; is doing really well, &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/30/sandp500.png&quot;&gt;still&lt;/a&gt;. But a really important part of our workforce is being attacked by the government. I have no idea what's going on among the immigrant workers in the US. Maybe this is something one of the news orgs could look at. But it seems we must already be short on labor to do the things that keep our lives and businesses functioning. If so, why isn't that showing up in the market? " created="Tue, 30 Sep 2025 16:25:57 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="One thing journalism could do for us is sponsor polls to find out how many people are scared about what's coming next and how scared are they? " created="Tue, 30 Sep 2025 16:35:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="People are not symbols." created="Tue, 30 Sep 2025 15:17:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 29" created="Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:41:48 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="29">
				<outline text="Please read Stephanie Booth's three-part &lt;a href=&quot;https://climbtothestars.org/archives/2025/09/28/rebooting-the-blogosphere-part-3-integration/&quot;&gt;Rebooting the Blogosphere&lt;/a&gt;. She's doing great work organizing the ideas around what can we do better in the new blogosphere. " created="Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:52:37 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&quot;It happened so slowly that we didn't notice but Twitter wiped out the idea of the web developer. The platforms we were trying to make work together were programmed so they couldn't work together.&quot; I didn't want to let that pass without notice. As the early blogosphere is coming back into focus, and given what we know about the before and after of Twitter, I'd say this was hard to see, I was too close to it, but now having gained some distance, and rebuilding the basics of the blogging with the tools of 2025, it has become clear. The age of the blog ended sometime after 2006 because people moved what they were doing in blogs to Twitter. It wasn't Twitter's fault, if the independent developers had been willing to pool resources to make certain things easy that were hard with blogs, we could have offered a good alternative that didn't make all the compromises on writing that Twitter did. That was unnecessary damage to the web. I'm now referring to that time as &quot;the rude interruption&quot; as in &quot;before we were so rudely interrupted.&quot; I am energized by the blogging energy that's come out of the two podcasts I did last week to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2025/09/23.html#a133652&quot;&gt;ActivityPub world&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2025/09/25.html#a130421&quot;&gt;WordPress community&lt;/a&gt;. They may or many not remember blogging before Twitter, but they do viscerally feel that the web has unrealized potential. " created="Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:41:49 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/17/reallySimpleCola.png"/>
				<outline text="I watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metacritic.com/tv/alien-earth/&quot;&gt;Alien: Earth&lt;/a&gt; to the end, didn't like it, it was &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noah_Hawley&quot;&gt;Noah Hawley&lt;/a&gt;, got great ratings. But I was wary going in. I don't like horror. I don't like seeing human bodies opened up, esp brains and guts. For those reasons I have never been a fan of the original Alien movie, I was bored and disgusted at the same time, and shocked once. As far as I can remember the movie had no plot and that one big scene. Anyway, Alien: Earth is another one of those &quot;universe&quot; thing, like the Marvel or DC universe, or Petticoat Junction and Green Acres. Aliens Earth had to fit into a pre-determined timeline. Good versus evil. Kids good. I hoped it would be great because Noah Hawley is the showrunner of the Fargo series on Hulu. It also defines a universe, but it's okay because they're cool or depraved or really stupid or cute in a Wisconsin way or from Europe, or twins. And there are aliens floating around there too, and Ronald Reagan even. And it was a completely different story from multiple different angles every time, and it had the same outrageous and dark and mostly intelligent tone that goes back to the original movie, which was the best movie ever of its kind, and gave us the Coen Brothers who haven't given us a dud so far. Noah Hawley disappoints." created="Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:09:04 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/29/alienEarth.png"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 28" created="Sun, 28 Sep 2025 13:19:11 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="28">
				<outline text="There should be a Hall of Fame for open software, formats and protocols that have stood the test of time, esp those that have taken a beating from commercializers. Not for the people who did it, that could be a separate thing, so there are no fights about who gets credit for what, but for the thing itself. It would be a way for the industry to say &quot;Hey sorry we didn't accept you at first, and we just want to acknowledge that, after X years of doing something hard, it worked, we're all using it now.&quot; To which the open format would say, &quot;Hey thanks for the call out, and let us know if you did something cool with it.&quot; " created="Sun, 28 Sep 2025 16:01:55 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I now have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.social/?feedurl=https%3A%2F%2Fdaveverse.org%2Fcategory%2Fwordpress%2Ffeed%2F&quot;&gt;feed&lt;/a&gt; in the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.feedland.org/&quot;&gt;WordPress News&lt;/a&gt; site. " created="Sun, 28 Sep 2025 14:42:35 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/index.opml&quot;&gt;OPML version&lt;/a&gt; of this blog, &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20041229084558/http://scripting.com/index.opml&quot;&gt;according to archive.org&lt;/a&gt;, goes back to &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2005/12/28.html&quot;&gt;Dec 28, 2005&lt;/a&gt;. It &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20041229084558/http://scripting.com/index.opml&quot;&gt;appears&lt;/a&gt; that it hasn't updated since &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2010/06/08.html&quot;&gt;June 8, 2010&lt;/a&gt;. On further investigation, we do maintain an &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/index.json&quot;&gt;JSON file&lt;/a&gt; for the site, it's just JSONified OPML. That works too. I'm looking for a way to direct posts to the WordPress news river I started last week. You can already easily use WordLand to do that, we have excellent category support, you're one click away from a dialog where you can choose from your categories while writing. You don't have to go anywhere to do that. The JSON file &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20170718223834/http://scripting.com/index.json&quot;&gt;starts&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2017/07/18.html&quot;&gt;July 18, 2017&lt;/a&gt; and it's rebuilt every time I post an update to the blog along with the RSS feed. And 2017 was when I did my 180 degree turn back to blogging as I was doing it before we were so rudely interrupted by Twitter. " created="Sun, 28 Sep 2025 13:19:12 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2017/07/18/leinenkugel.png"/>
				<outline text="The stuff I'm posting on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://daveverse.org/&quot;&gt;Daveverse&lt;/a&gt; site isn't getting into my &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=daytona&quot;&gt;Daytona search engine&lt;/a&gt;. I'm writing some real stuff there that should be included. I write on Daveverse using WordLand, it's proof that it's working as a comfortable writing tool and helps me think of features. I do most of my Daveverse writing on my iPad. Test posts are done on my desktop while I'm working on it, but sometimes they contain stuff that could be indexed as well. With enough time I could easily do this, but that's the problem, not enough time. " created="Sun, 28 Sep 2025 13:25:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 27" created="Sat, 27 Sep 2025 14:29:42 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="27">
				<outline text="I'm writing &lt;a href=&quot;https://daveverse.org/2025/09/27/wordland-synchronization-issue/&quot;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; about problems with WordLand using WordLand and I'm liking it. That's a good sign btw. And also I think it looks pretty great viewed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://daveverse.org/2025/09/27/wordland-synchronization-issue/&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; and in &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@scripting@daveverse.org/115277099316805872&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sat, 27 Sep 2025 16:02:28 GMT" type="outline" category="wordpress, wordland"/>
				<outline text="Automattic shipped a new product called &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com/blog/2025/09/23/telex-turns-everyone-into-a-wordpress-block-developer/&quot;&gt;Telex&lt;/a&gt; that's a ChatGPT for designing blocks in WordPress designs. Blocks are a simple result of design and programming that define the behavior of a part of a WordPress page. Having seen a demo, it looks really useful and is a nice small programming space, where a lot of users could actually control the process, and get something useful quickly. I've gotten pretty adept at teasing images out of ChatGPT, and at some point I'm probably going to need a commerce site, to allocate subdomains for people's feeds in WordLand. Still have to figure out how that works. " created="Sat, 27 Sep 2025 14:52:00 GMT" type="outline" category="wordpress"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 26" created="Fri, 26 Sep 2025 20:59:06 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="26">
				<outline text="I put out a request for WordPress-related blogs on &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@davew/115270627531848336&quot;&gt;Masto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/scripting.com/post/3lzqi6vzvtc2n&quot;&gt;Bluesky&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/davewiner/status/1971553589031248069&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; this morning. Got enough feeds to start &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.feedland.org/&quot;&gt;wordpress.feedland.org&lt;/a&gt;. If you have a site that should be included, please post the URL in one of those places and I'll add it to the subscription list for the site. " created="Fri, 26 Sep 2025 20:59:07 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Really Simple potato chips" created="Fri, 26 Sep 2025 21:12:19 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="&quot;The #1 chips for dips!&quot;" created="Fri, 26 Sep 2025 21:12:27 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/26/reallySimplePotatoChips.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 25" created="Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:04:14 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="25">
				<outline text="Good morning sports fans!" created="Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:04:15 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Today there is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://wptavern.com/podcast/186-dave-winer-on-decentralisation-wordpress-and-open-publishing&quot;&gt;new podcast&lt;/a&gt;, this one for members of the WordPress community. I was interviewed by the very capable Nathan Wrigley of WP Tavern. I thought it was a great conversation, we talked about the remarkable position WordPress is in to serve as the OS for a rebooted web. I love the introduction they wrote, I also figured out how to make content management work in the browser, which was the foundation for blogging and eventually WordPress, though it seems that legacy is a bit lost in all the other stuff I've had my fingers in over the years. I hope you listen to this podcast, and if you have &lt;a href=&quot;https://wptavern.com/podcast/186-dave-winer-on-decentralisation-wordpress-and-open-publishing&quot;&gt;questions or comments&lt;/a&gt;, here's a good place to post them. " created="Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:04:21 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/17/reallySimpleCola.png"/>
				<outline text="This came up in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@darius@friend.camp/115266052576766302&quot;&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt; on Mastodon about &quot;social network&quot; vs &quot;social media.&quot; I also think &quot;social web&quot; should be used sparingly.  Because imho there is such a thing as the social web but we haven't developed very much of it, i think because we were intimidated by the silos. I'm not intimidated any more, I'm fed up and going ahead without them.   " created="Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:13:27 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I just heard about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.health.harvard.edu/blog/how-to-recognize-and-tame-your-cognitive-distortions-202205042738&quot;&gt;thinking errors&lt;/a&gt;, via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apa.org/ptsd-guideline/patients-and-families/cognitive-behavioral&quot;&gt;Cognitive Behavioral Therapy&lt;/a&gt;.  " created="Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:54:26 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 24" created="Wed, 24 Sep 2025 13:36:46 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="24">
				<outline text="There are a lot of developers who think they understand WordPress but they don't. It has a REST api that you can build on. Everything WordPress does. It's the API the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dashboard.wordpress.com/wp-admin/index.php?page=my-blogs&quot;&gt;browser client&lt;/a&gt; is built on. I didn't know it was there until I added WordPress login to FeedLand a couple of years ago. I couldn't believe what I was seeing. What can I do with it? It snuck up on me that it's an API for the web, and it's also the easiest API for ActivityPub. The programming model for the fediverse might be a lot simpler than you think. WordLand is as exciting as any web product I did before, because now, after being &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rip_Van_Winkle&quot;&gt;asleep&lt;/a&gt; for 19 years, the web can now wake up. It really feels that way. " created="Wed, 24 Sep 2025 13:48:03 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/24/ripVanWinkle.png" imageLink="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rip_Van_Winkle"/>
				<outline text="The web has been asleep for 19 years, which is almost as long as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rip_Van_Winkle&quot;&gt;Rip Van Winkle&lt;/a&gt; was asleep, according the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Washington_Irving&quot;&gt;Washington Irving&lt;/a&gt; story." created="Wed, 24 Sep 2025 15:56:39 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="In the future &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; will be able to chain social networks together." created="Wed, 24 Sep 2025 15:59:28 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Yesterday's &lt;a href=&quot;https://openchannels.fm/exploring-wordpress-textcasting-and-open-web-standards/&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; was with Matthias Pfefferle, who is developing Automattic's ActivityPub functionality. I talk about the totality of the app I'm building and the role WordPress and RSS play in the network. It's an all-web approach to social media. Another big podcast came out today, this one for the WordPress community. I'll write it up tomorrow. I'm on a press tour folks and having a great time. I think I finally found my tribe? And if you're in Canada, come to &lt;a href=&quot;https://canada.wordcamp.org/2025/&quot;&gt;WordCamp in Ottawa&lt;/a&gt;, October 15-17. I haven't given a public in person talk since April 2019. I'm realllly looking forward to this. " created="Wed, 24 Sep 2025 14:32:50 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="So far the WordPress API hasn't been promoted much, I only found out about it by accident. Judge my success by how many other editors show up for WordPress and how they are all automatically plugged into networks defined by ActivityPub and RSS. People will be totally surprised by what you can do with tools that can be plugged into each other in all the ways you can think of. In other words, goodbye &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22Tiny%20Little%20Text%20Boxes%22&quot;&gt;Tiny Little Text Boxes&lt;/a&gt;! " created="Wed, 24 Sep 2025 13:36:47 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/24/ripVanWinkle.png" isComment="true"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 23" created="Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:36:51 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="23">
				<outline text="I did a &lt;a href=&quot;https://openchannels.fm/exploring-wordpress-textcasting-and-open-web-standards/&quot;&gt;podcast interview&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;https://pfefferle.dev/&quot;&gt;Matthias Pfefferle&lt;/a&gt; last week. I wanted to introduce my ideas to the Fediverse world. I haven't listened to it yet, but I remember it being a good discussion on basically all the things I am working on and with these days. It's all a continuation of what we were doing when we were so rudely interrupted by the silos, Twitter, Facebook, Bluesky and to a lesser extent Mastodon. I want to reform social media, go back to the beginning and let's ask the question -- what kind of social media does the web want? Start with the basics, and build a stack that performs like Twitter or Bluesky, but never veer from the standards of the web. Every component must be replaceable. Writers must have all the writing power of the web. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evan_Prodromou&quot;&gt;Evan Prodromou&lt;/a&gt; will be glad to hear that I am a huge fan of the role &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/plugins/activitypub/&quot;&gt;ActivityPub&lt;/a&gt; is playing in bringing the power of &lt;a href=&quot;https://textcasting.org/&quot;&gt;textcasting&lt;/a&gt; to Mastodon. Matthias, my partner in this podcast episode has been working on this since 2008, and now we are reaping the benefit all the way up the stack in &quot;WordLand&quot;. See, that's what the web is about. Building and including. Without walls that keep competitors out and keep users in.  " created="Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:36:52 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2019/09/11/tide.png"/>
				<outline text="Why &lt;a href=&quot;https://textcasting.org/&quot;&gt;textcasting&lt;/a&gt;? When Twitter came out in 2006 they left out most of the writing features of the web. Their competitors copied the limits. Textcasting says writers don't want the limits. Add &lt;a href=&quot;https://textcasting.org/&quot;&gt;these features&lt;/a&gt; to your twitter-like social network and we are happy and will sing your praise. That's it. It's no more complicated than that. People ask questions about what it means. This is what it means." created="Tue, 23 Sep 2025 14:00:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="It happened so slowly that we didn't notice but Twitter wiped out the idea of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22web%20developer%22&quot;&gt;web developer&lt;/a&gt;. The platforms we were trying to make work together were programmed so they &lt;i&gt;couldn't&lt;/i&gt; work together. As well-intentioned we may have been, it wasn't the web we were developing for. I know the term web developer has come to mean more than it means to me. But it's like saying someone is a Mac developer. A web developer creates apps for the web. Not for a specific service. For any service that supports the open formats that everyone else uses. " created="Tue, 23 Sep 2025 15:13:48 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="McLuhan in header image" created="Tue, 23 Sep 2025 15:44:48 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="&lt;hr style=&quot;margin: 0; margin-bottom: 5px;&quot;&gt;The new header image on &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/&quot;&gt;scripting.com&lt;/a&gt; may be the best ever. " created="Tue, 23 Sep 2025 15:42:37 GMT" type="outline" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/23/headerImageMcLuhan.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 22" created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 13:32:46 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="22">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedlandSocket/blob/main/worknotes.md#92225-100532-am-by-dw&quot;&gt;Updates&lt;/a&gt; to the feedlandSocket &lt;a href=&quot;https://socketdemo.feedland.org/&quot;&gt;demo app&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 18:48:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/wordlandDev/issues/3&quot;&gt;A new doc for RSS nerds&lt;/a&gt;. WordLand implements a &lt;i&gt;shadow&lt;/i&gt; feed, in addition to the feed that WordPress maintains, with a few additions and differences. The two main things we do in a site's shadow feed is support linkblogs and markdown. " created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 13:32:47 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I’ve been writing about the rebirth of WordPress in &lt;a href=&quot;https://iconick.io/cool-kids/&quot;&gt;similar terms&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=wordpress&quot;&gt;on my blog&lt;/a&gt;, in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ashownotes.scripting.com+wordpress&amp;rlz=1C5CHFA_enUS743US747&amp;oq=site%3Ashownotes.scripting.com+wordpress&quot;&gt;podcasts&lt;/a&gt;, hoping people would listen. WordPress is a lot more than people think. We can have &lt;a href=&quot;https://iconick.io/cool-kids/&quot;&gt;all this&lt;/a&gt;, a lot sooner than you think. " created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 18:56:59 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="My new blog home page?" created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 21:42:00 GMT" metaImage="http://scripting.com/images/2025/09/22/mcluhan.png" type="outline">
					<outline text="I have a plan for how to bootstrap WordLand 0.8." created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 21:42:06 GMT"/>
					<outline text="First I will introduce you to a new way to read my blog. " created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 21:43:19 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It will be a timeline of items posted to many of my feeds. " created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 21:44:02 GMT" flBulletedSubs="true">
						<outline text="daveverse -- lives on WordPress and Mastodon." created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 21:44:27 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Great art on Bluesky -- daily version." created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 21:44:57 GMT"/>
						<outline text="links.daveverse.org -- my linkblog." created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 21:45:08 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Scripting News -- my main blog." created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 21:45:16 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Scripting News podcast -- a new podcast stream. " created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 21:45:19 GMT"/>
						<outline text="WordCamp Canada 2025 -- I'm keynoting in October." created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 21:45:24 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="What each of these have in common is that each has an RSS feed that supports rssCloud. So updates flow instantaneously." created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 21:45:34 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Anyway... so instead of going to scripting.com, you'll go to this other place, on an experimental basis. It's got color and nice icons, and looks a bit like a timeline in twitter-like systems. " created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 21:48:49 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Now here's the fun part. You may read something that you want to comment on. Or quote what I've said. The kinds of things you do on twitter-like systems. " created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 21:50:54 GMT"/>
					<outline text="You will be able to do that. The editor is right there. One click away while you're reading. I didn't invent this flow, Twitter did, it's comfortable, we understand it. " created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 21:51:30 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The difference is here you edit in your space and pass around links via &lt;i&gt;your&lt;/i&gt; feeds. " created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 22:04:21 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I will see what you wrote, but it's up to me if it is attached to my posts. I did a &lt;a href=&quot;https://shownotes.scripting.com/scripting/2025/09/10/aNewModelForBlogDiscourse.html&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; about this earlier this month. " created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 23:14:34 GMT"/>
					<outline text="This, imho, is the social network the web always wanted. " created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 21:53:03 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PS: My timeline as a FeedLand-compatible &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.social/opml?screenname=davewiner&amp;catname=daveverse&quot;&gt;reading list&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 22 Sep 2025 21:57:24 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 21" created="Sun, 21 Sep 2025 13:06:12 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="21" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/21/socketScreenShot.png">
				<outline text="New release of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedlandSocket?tab=readme-ov-file#watch-it-run&quot;&gt;feedlandSockets code&lt;/a&gt;. Still more work to do." created="Sun, 21 Sep 2025 15:42:37 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Last night I learned about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.com/docs/glossary/headless-wordpress/&quot;&gt;headless WordPress&lt;/a&gt; installations from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/photomatt/status/1969510572853993587&quot;&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt; by Matt Mullenweg. It got me going on various explorations. Wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://daveverse.org/2025/09/21/dave-learns-of-headless-wordpress/&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; on my WP site. It's actually easier for me to write posts on that site when all I have is my iPad. I do all my writing on Scripting News in &lt;a href=&quot;https://docserver.scripting.com/drummer/electricDrummer.opml&quot;&gt;Electric Drummer&lt;/a&gt;, which is a desktop-only app. I'm going to start engaging in discussions about WordPress where the people are. Also starting to think about my keynote in Ottawa in October which is now less than a month away. A note to the people running the show, I would be open to having it be an interview instead of a speech. I have trouble staying anchored to the audience with slides, I don't really like that way of communicating. I prefer interview style, with an interviewer who is interested in the subject matter. I want to do at least a bit of a demo, talk about how we got here, the early blogosphere, all the things that led to WordPress, and the connection WordPress has now to social media systems like Mastodon. We must focus on that connection because so much has been accomplished there in the last year, and it hasn't imho gotten enough attention. I want to talk more about the big picture, how WordPress has a role to play that goes beyond serving ecommerce sites, which is, I understand where the money is. Money is good but right now imho our world wide public communication system desperately needs an upgrade. It's been crippled by decisions made by Twitter almost 20 years ago. I want to turn that around, put back &lt;a href=&quot;https://textcasting.org/&quot;&gt;the features they took out&lt;/a&gt;, and to do that I need to start a network that's built on the web, not in silos that can't connect to each other. That is not the web I know, where everything can connect to anything. I don't think at this time any of the social media apps should be considered part of the web. I remember the magic of the web, we built the blogosphere around the web, and thus WordPress is also built around the web. For more perspective, see the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2025/08/28/140604.html&quot;&gt;piece&lt;/a&gt; I wrote in August about thinking differently about WordPress. That's what I am the evangelist for, thinking about WordPress in a different, wider role, bringing the web to the people in a very usable way. " created="Sun, 21 Sep 2025 13:06:13 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/08/28/thinkDifferentBillboard.png"/>
				<outline text="Here's a thought for WordPress users and developers. WordPress is huge, but it's just part of the web. That's what it means to be on the web, my friends. Everything connects to anything on the web. Once we build out a social network from WordPress, all the other systems will have no choice but to hook up too. All this talk of AT Proto and ActivityPub being the connecting glue is nonsense. &lt;i&gt;The web is the connecting glue. &lt;/i&gt; " created="Sun, 21 Sep 2025 13:33:39 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 20" created="Sat, 20 Sep 2025 14:13:16 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="20">
				<outline text="They should make a ChatGPT that two or more people can chat in. I guess that's what Twitter is doing.  " created="Sat, 20 Sep 2025 15:19:04 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="In ways older people handle change better than younger ones, because we know change is here, every freaking day, and we know in a few years, at most, really big change is coming. So the attitude of the older person is often what the fuck, let's go. I'm not kidding. Maybe later in life I will get more conservative, it could happen." created="Sat, 20 Sep 2025 15:17:33 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I'd like to see a mutual defense pact among the open source projects who depend on the stability each others' work. Not with the people, but the projects. Sort of like a NATO of open source. " created="Sat, 20 Sep 2025 14:29:54 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I've never been very interested in what Kimmel says &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Streisand_effect&quot;&gt;but I am now&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sat, 20 Sep 2025 14:13:17 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 19" created="Fri, 19 Sep 2025 13:07:17 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="19">
				<outline text="The challenge we face in the social web is enticing people off the silos with fun toys to play with that from the start don't rely on a bigco to run it. The back-end is a server you could run for $20 a month on Digital Ocean for example. But the logical network isn't tied to the physical server. We use URLs or DNS to find other nodes. They can be hosted anywhere. The reason to run lots of servers is to demonstrate that it's only as centralized as the web itself, from day 1. You can browse other people's subscription lists as you can in twitter-like networks. But it's made of feeds. The really simple ones. " created="Fri, 19 Sep 2025 15:06:03 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2022/08/08/bootstrappingByEngelbart.png"/>
				<outline text="I'm going to call it &quot;social web&quot; not &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22open%20social%20web%22&quot;&gt;open social web&lt;/a&gt;. You don't need the &quot;open&quot; part. The web is open. It's like saying &quot;wet water.&quot;" created="Fri, 19 Sep 2025 21:01:03 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="There should be a ChatGPT &quot;personality&quot; for the chatbot. I'd like to start with a black lab. When I say &quot;good work&quot; that reinforces that what it did should be a priority. If I say that and give it a treat (by typing &quot;treat&quot;) that should get double emphasis. I might like it better if I could train it. I don't mind a little enthusiasm, but I want it to respond to me with respect. " created="Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:55:51 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Highly recommend today's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theringer.com/podcasts/the-bill-simmons-podcast/2025/09/18/the-kimmel-situation-plus-can-the-chiefs-really-go-0-3-and-more-week-3-gambling-questions-with-joe-house&quot;&gt;Bill Simmons podcast&lt;/a&gt; where he talks about the Jimmy Kimmel situation. His perspective is very good, he says Kimmel doesn't need ABC. And I believe him.  " created="Fri, 19 Sep 2025 21:04:59 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The penalty for ABC and Disney should be we stop watching their stuff." created="Fri, 19 Sep 2025 13:07:18 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Can we finally put the past behind us?" created="Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:17:05 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="&lt;i&gt;Cross-posted from my &lt;a href=&quot;https://daveverse.org/2025/09/16/can-we-finally-put-the-past-behind-us/&quot;&gt;daveverse site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:19:19 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I hadn’t considered the point of view of people who worked at Netscape when it disappeared just as RSS 0.9.1 was being adopted by the blogosphere in 1999. We tried to get in touch, even when they didn’t work there, but no one responded. So we kept going. " created="Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:19:44 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Then we were surprised when a group of people we didn’t know announced, publicly, that they were the new authority on RSS and at the same time introduced a version 1.0 that was incompatible with the format Netscape left behind. Most developers didn’t switch, very few used their format. " created="Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:21:54 GMT"/>
					<outline text="There were discussions and arguments and lots of hurt feelings on the mail list, but the status quo remained for a couple of years. There was RSS 0.91 and RSS 1.0. Most sites used 0.91. "/>
					<outline text="After a couple of years, we got lucky and found the people at the NYT who could license their proprietary feeds to us to use in our Radio UserLand product. We did a deal with them, and we were allowed to bundle their feeds with Radio. At first we stayed with their proprietary format, wanting to avoid dragging them into the arguments. But then we heard from other pubs that wanted to follow the NYT, and they wanted to know what they should do. We had a new version in the works, 0.92, that had a few new features, but as this was in development, we realized were doing all the work, and 1.0 was just sitting there as an obstacle, it would always appear as what we were doing was less than what they did, when the two really had nothing to do with each other. Since they never consulted us about superceeding the format we were using, we changed 0.92 to 2.0, waited for the flames, but they never came. People were tired of the arguing and there was too much potential in a publishing surface that was shared by bloggers and professional news. So guess what -- RSS 2.0 became the standard. " created="Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:23:19 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The ex-Netscapers never talked with us, even though their big company no longer existed. We might have worked out something if they had talked with us as equals. But I guess we weren't good enough for them? Hard to say."/>
					<outline text="I don’t care if they claim they created RSS, I've never claimed to be the inventor, and I don't there's much value in that -- and frankly I think The NY Times had more to do with its success than any of us. If they hadn’t decided to jump in simply because they liked my little company, RSS would be nothing but a bunch of geeks arguing about who did what about something no one cared about. We might be reminiscing about what might have happened if we could only work with each other and considered each others’ perspective. "/>
					<outline text="To this day, decades later, they still won't talk to us. But I guess from their point of view we had no right to use the supposedly open format their defunct company had left behind."/>
					<outline text="I have a different view of the web. It is not made of companies, it’s made of people. Companies can use the web, but they can’t own it. And I suggest that the people here no matter where they work now or in the past understand that there are other points of view. No matter how big your company is or was, you are still just people. "/>
					<outline text="I have worked for big prestigious companies and organizations too. So what. "/>
					<outline text="Okay so you all sent me a message by taking something I created and was proud of and called it your own without saying where you got it. You can do that, and hopefully this is the end of the vendetta. You can feel you got the win you are entitled to. You caused the pain you were hoping to. So now can we finally put the past behind us? Imho we have much bigger problems to solve and that can only happen if people work together. " created="Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:25:37 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Maybe we can agree that RSS has done a lot of good for a lot of people. It isn't perfect. But it deserves a little peace and quiet, that I actually thought it had achieved. From here-on, let's try to make it better, not take things out of it for our own benefit." created="Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:48:49 GMT"/>
					<outline text="How about a virtual handshake and finally put the past behind us?" created="Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:48:44 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Really Simple beer" created="Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:46:36 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Most beers are too complicated." created="Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:47:01 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/19/bigBeerPackage.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 18" created="Thu, 18 Sep 2025 13:02:57 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="18">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/18/disneystock.png&quot;&gt;Disney stock&lt;/a&gt; down 1.1% at 11:30AM Eastern, indicating that in the opinion of shareholders, the first amendment isn't that big a deal for a media company. " created="Thu, 18 Sep 2025 15:37:29 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I got a few good &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/wordlandSupport/issues/107&quot;&gt;error reports&lt;/a&gt; and that led to an easy fix. So if &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2025/09/17.html#a191912&quot;&gt;you had a problem&lt;/a&gt; creating a new post on &quot;WordLand&quot; could you please try again and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/wordlandSupport/issues/107&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; any problems, or success. &lt;i&gt;Thanks!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Thu, 18 Sep 2025 14:50:17 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/18/gorilla.png"/>
				<outline text="When Paramount said firing Colbert was financial, I think they were telling the truth. Unless they dumped Colbert the $8 billion &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Merger_of_Skydance_Media_and_Paramount_Global&quot;&gt;deal&lt;/a&gt; with the Ellisons wouldn't happen. So it was Colbert or $8 billion. They went for the money. Pretty sure it's the same thing with ABC and Kimmel. " created="Thu, 18 Sep 2025 13:02:58 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Test post test post test post test post test post test post, my kingdom for a test post!" created="Thu, 18 Sep 2025 14:55:11 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Really simple book and beans" created="Thu, 18 Sep 2025 14:58:08 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I've been getting ChatGPT to draw me product shots of all kinds of &quot;really simple&quot; things like ketchup, cola, cheese,The penalty for ABC and Disney should be we stop watching their stuff. beans (see below). " created="Thu, 18 Sep 2025 15:07:29 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Then I thought it might work pretty well as a line of books? " created="Thu, 18 Sep 2025 14:59:07 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I'll have my Python simple. &lt;i&gt;Really&lt;/i&gt; simple." created="Thu, 18 Sep 2025 15:01:21 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/18/pythonInAShoeboxBookCover.png"/>
					<outline text="Who would want complicated baked beans?" created="Thu, 18 Sep 2025 15:04:19 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/18/reallySimpleBakedBeans.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 17" created="Wed, 17 Sep 2025 13:12:50 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="17">
				<outline text="I had a great talk/podcast interview yesterday with &lt;a href=&quot;https://pfefferle.dev/&quot;&gt;Matthias Pfefferle&lt;/a&gt; about everything I'm interested in re WordPress and networking, and our interests overlap a lot. I was explaining how I wanted to see a whole market of editors. You could see them as &quot;For WordPress&quot; but there's another way to look at them. They're plug-in replacements for the dreaded &quot;tiny little textboxes&quot; we see in twitter-like systems. Those awful little things. We know so many ways to make better editors. Now imagine that we store your Mastodon posts in WordPress documents (we do). And you see how the pieces start to fit together. Think of WordPress as the command line of the social web. And it really will be the web, not a promise of someday maybe being the web. It's like a Wordle puzzle. You have to move the parts around until you see a picture develop. Another fun thing, WordPress has a great simple REST api that's been around since 2017, and it covers most of the product functionality and is debugged, scaled and stable. It probably is the simplest API for ActivityPub. Now does that blow your mind? This is how you know this is the web, because your mind keeps exploding once you realize the things you could do just by connecting two things together and it works because they interop. Matthias has been working on this stuff since 2008. Our paths didn't cross until earlier this year. " created="Wed, 17 Sep 2025 21:11:33 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/17/reallySimpleCola.png"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/17/realestate/real-estate-guide-amenia-new-york.html?unlocked_article_code=1.mk8.pyS5.EYIaVe05LN5h&amp;smid=url-share&quot;&gt;This town&lt;/a&gt;, at the end of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mta.info/agency/metro-north-railroad&quot;&gt;Metro North&lt;/a&gt; line, looks like an ideal place to park yourself for easy access to the city, yet a fairly country experience. " created="Wed, 17 Sep 2025 21:02:41 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="There have been reports of people having trouble using &quot;WordLand&quot;. I was just able to do a &lt;a href=&quot;https://techfightclub.wpcomstaging.com/2025/09/17/one-of-a-million-test-posts/&quot;&gt;test post&lt;/a&gt;, and I can see from the logs that other people are successfully posting. It would be helpful if people with accounts could do a short test post. And if you have something to report, here's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/wordlandSupport/issues/107&quot;&gt;good place&lt;/a&gt; to do it.  " created="Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:19:12 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="In a piece I wrote yesterday &lt;a href=&quot;https://daveverse.org/2025/09/16/can-we-finally-put-the-past-behind-us/&quot;&gt;on my WordPress blog&lt;/a&gt;, I offered to do a virtual handshake with the people who worked at Netscape when it disappeared just as RSS 0.9.1 was being adopted by the blogosphere in 1999. I never considered their point of view, but in fairness, they never would talk to us except to dictate and dominate. In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://daveverse.org/2025/09/16/can-we-finally-put-the-past-behind-us/&quot;&gt;piece&lt;/a&gt; I try to explain how it all looked from my point of view, that of a developer who had adopted RSS 0.91 in favor of my own earlier format. Most of the stories miss the real innovator, and when you find out &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2011/11/07/martinLeavesTheTimes.html&quot;&gt;who&lt;/a&gt; it is you will be surprised. (It's not me, most of my job re RSS has been fairly thankless and not creative, and definitely not profitable, but still worth doing because the web is the only place independent developers can work without the interference of big tech companies.)" created="Wed, 17 Sep 2025 13:12:51 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/17/reallySimpleKetchup.png" imageLink="https://ketchup.reallysimple.org/"/>
				<outline text="A bunch of new people are trying out FeedLand news products. I haven't looked at them in a long time. I'm glad they're looking, but most of my demo news products were broken. Oy. It was hard to untangle. It should be a lot easier, and next time I can dig in and do it over I think it will be. Anyway as I convert my demos, I'll list them here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://mlbriver.com/&quot;&gt;mblriver.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://politics.newsriver.org/&quot;&gt;politics.newsriver.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bloggers.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;bloggers.scripting.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dave.podcatch.com/&quot;&gt;dave.podcatch.com&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 17 Sep 2025 16:48:00 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 16" created="Tue, 16 Sep 2025 14:21:11 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="16">
				<outline text="It's &lt;a href=&quot;https://really.reallysimple.org/&quot;&gt;really&lt;/a&gt; simpler than really simple." created="Tue, 16 Sep 2025 20:18:51 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Here's an idea. Why doesn't Apple make a laptop with a light shining out to highlight the user's face so they look better when they're on a Zoom call. I bet someone makes a device like this to clip on a laptop. Right?? " created="Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:18:55 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Until we start working together it’s going to keep getting worse." created="Tue, 16 Sep 2025 16:45:07 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I've started calling ChatGPT boss as in &lt;i&gt;OK boss.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Tue, 16 Sep 2025 15:30:34 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="ChatGPT is great at &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SVG&quot;&gt;SVG&lt;/a&gt;. Describe the icon you want and in a few iterations you have it, even if it's not in &lt;a href=&quot;https://fontawesome.com/&quot;&gt;Font Awesome&lt;/a&gt;. I would have killed to have this a few years ago, before FA came out. This is the best of both -- use FA if they have the right icon, design your own if they don't. It also makes me think that now perhaps SVG-based user interfaces are within the realm of possibility. CSS is no way to design UIs. I have a podcast in the pipe about this. If you want to know what I mean, look at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/publicfolder/scripting/misc/quickdrawApiSummary.pdf&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2025/06/19/152802.html&quot;&gt;QuickDraw&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 16 Sep 2025 14:54:48 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Now would be a good time for everyone to watch &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metacritic.com/movie/the-lives-of-others/&quot;&gt;this movie&lt;/a&gt;. This is where we are now. It's not in the future. Getting this info will help. Spread the word. Download a copy too. It's a great movie.  " created="Tue, 16 Sep 2025 14:43:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="To people who read my blog. If you have a quick thought about something you read here, it's ok if you send me an email. It should be short and not personal, if it adds some info or perspective that might be interesting, or if you just agree feverishly (not so much if you disagree, please) drop me a line. My return address on the nightly emails is my real email address. And you can find the address on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/?tab=about&quot;&gt;About page&lt;/a&gt; on my blog. Also sometime soon I think there will be a way to read my blog inside WordLand, so you can post a response to something I wrote, on your own blog, and I can get a link to it. I think this is the best of both worlds. You maintain the integrity of your blog, all your comments are in the same place, and if I think my readers would benefit, I can link it into my blog. I don't think we need comments, in other words. I think our blogs are powerful enough with some new code.  " created="Tue, 16 Sep 2025 14:21:12 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 15" created="Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:07:02 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="15">
				<outline text="Podcast: &lt;a href=&quot;https://shownotes.scripting.com/scripting/2025/09/15/wordlandTheTimelineAndCheckboxes.html&quot;&gt;WordLand, the timeline and checkboxes&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 15 Sep 2025 21:38:10 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I've gotten a lovely response to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/davenet/1996/10/24/QueSeraSera.html&quot;&gt;Que Sera Sera&lt;/a&gt; post I linked to &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2025/09/13/001819.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It's from 1996, I was reporting from a tech conference I was at where there were all angry men on stage threatening everyone else. They may not have known they were doing that, but it was awful. And so different from the web we were just beginning to understand at that time. I'm going to start going through the posts that I remember making a difference at the time. No better way for me to remember what the web is, going back to these memories when it was all fresh and new, before the leaders of tech realized what was going on. Google didn't ship for another two years. It probably wasn't even in development at the time. Yet I think the last section is a good anthem for the web, for those of us who think it's time to cut pop all the bullshit off the stack and get back to our roots." created="Mon, 15 Sep 2025 15:07:23 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/05/13/modernTimes.png"/>
				<outline text="I had a flash last night during the Emmys. &lt;a href=&quot;https://daveverse.org/2025/09/14/the-bloggers-of-mastodon/&quot;&gt;The Bloggers of Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;. I loved the concept right off the bat, so I wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://daveverse.org/2025/09/14/the-bloggers-of-mastodon/&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; using in WordLand that went through WordPress and landed &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@scripting@daveverse.org/115205341809959164&quot;&gt;on Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;. It all works. Where are the other Bloggers of Mastodon? Let's start a club!" created="Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:36:19 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="feedland.org or feedland.com?" created="Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:07:03 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="This question has come up quite a bit lately. " created="Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:07:10 GMT"/>
					<outline text="People don't know that there are two places you can use FeedLand, feedland.org and feedland.com." created="Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:09:48 GMT"/>
					<outline text="There's a lot of history here, and some uncertainty about the future, so there's not much I can do other than explain the situation." created="Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:10:16 GMT"/>
					<outline text="First you're welcome to use either of them. " created="Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:10:40 GMT"/>
					<outline text="feedland.org is running on a simple small server on Digital Ocean, and feedland.com is on Automattic's VIP network. " created="Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:10:49 GMT"/>
					<outline text="If feedland.org gets overloaded, it gets slow. " created="Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:11:25 GMT"/>
					<outline text="if feedland.com gets overloaded, it adds more servers and should stay about the same at all times. " created="Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:17:24 GMT"/>
					<outline text="You should pick one and use it and not have two accounts, but people accidentally create them, because in some places we point to .com and in others we the default is .org. It's because we haven't gotten it together yet. " created="Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:12:35 GMT"/>
					<outline text="There are also performance issues on .com -- ones that we still need to address. " created="Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:13:40 GMT"/>
					<outline text="That's about all I can say at this point. At the same time I'm working on a whole other product while all this is happening, and I'm not that young, and really can only work so many hours a day before I have to stop. A fact. " created="Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:08:34 GMT"/>
					<outline text="And I'm really glad so many new people are trying FeedLand. I use it myself in so many ways. And it will be deeply integrated with WordLand in the next release. I'm not kidding. " created="Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:15:00 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 14" created="Sun, 14 Sep 2025 14:12:55 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="14">
				<outline text="The Bloggers &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@scripting@daveverse.org/115205341809959164&quot;&gt;of Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 15 Sep 2025 01:33:24 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="A very smart application of AI. Google could add it to the debugger. When my program crashes deep in jQuery code, with no stack crawl, it could suggest what the problem might be without me have to try to describe it for ChatGPT. The Google AI debugger would be able to look everywhere any anywhere in the virtual machine. Much faster than I can. As a programmer I hope they're working on this. Or maybe it's already out in testing form?" created="Sun, 14 Sep 2025 22:55:36 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="A couple of days ago I saw a &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@evan@cosocial.ca/115180872933751939&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; from Evan Prodromou asking if I had seen a product announcement, and was wondering what I thought of the name. The name of the product was Really Simple Something. I said it was the first I heard of it. I did a little digging using ChatGPT and found they can do this, it’s not illegal or unethical. But it’s also true that you could invent a new format and call it HTML even if it isn’t what we think of as HTML today . The W3C would have no recourse. If you wanted to make a new CSS to compete with the existing CSS, no one can stop you, and you can call it CSS. Not a good way to run the internet imho. But that appears that's how it works. So as much as I didn't like what they did, esp the fact that the first I heard of it was a public announcement, and had no time to prepare or maybe even help them do something better, I guess we have to accept it. RSS has been through this before and came out okay. I just wish it would stop at some point. It's a useful thing, deserves &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2025/09/11/123936.html#a124132&quot;&gt;love&lt;/a&gt; and support, not just from me, but from everyone, esp people who run companies that depend on it. You benefit as much as I do. End of sermon." created="Sun, 14 Sep 2025 16:36:16 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/14/cheezWhiz.png"/>
				<outline text="Last night's email didn't go out. I found and fixed the bug, and the mails went out about 10.5 hours late. " created="Sun, 14 Sep 2025 14:12:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 13" created="Sat, 13 Sep 2025 14:13:00 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="13">
				<outline text="I've found &lt;a href=&quot;https://daveverse.org/2025/09/13/where-is-this-on-mastodon/&quot;&gt;new freedom&lt;/a&gt; on my WordPress blog that's also on Masto. " created="Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:45:25 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="How did a healthy well-fed and educated 22 year old man from a good family throw his life away and for what? To kill a 31 year old family man who dedicated his life to making massive numbers of people miserable? What’s more tragic? And how many other Americans are on this track?" created="Sat, 13 Sep 2025 14:13:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Embrace the creativity of others" created="Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:18:19 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/davenet/1996/10/24/QueSeraSera.html&quot;&gt;piece&lt;/a&gt; in October 1996 after attending a conference of the tech industry that as it turns out was in its final stages. This was one of the last times it met. I was coming from the web, and wanted to see if anyone else was ready to change how we work with each other. " created="Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:33:58 GMT">
						<outline text="Here's an invitation to truly embrace the creativity of others. Instead of beating your breast about how great you are, try saying how great someone else is. Look for win-wins, make that your new religion. Establish a policy that nothing will be announced unless it can be shown that someone else will win because of what you're doing. How much happier we would be if instead of crippling each other with fear, we competed to empower each others' creativity." created="Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:15:58 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="I've been following that ideal ever since, people seem to misinterpret it for subservience or weakness, or a pretense to cover another kind of greed, when it's really sincere, and all about strength. Sometimes people say yes, and when that happens magical things happen. I swear to god. I've been there. I've done it, it's not something you can do on your own, by definition. It's rare when people actually help each other and thereby create something. It's why the Beatles are such a great story. Someday I still hope to be part of a group like that. Right now, it's still &lt;i&gt;totally&lt;/i&gt; everyone for themself.  That is breaking. Read the news. But I believe if we did start really collaborating and not just talking about it, things would change very very quickly. Things would happen that can't happen until we work together. " created="Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:19:51 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I had it figured out in 1996, but still haven't figured out how to make it happen, and time &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; running out." created="Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:30:07 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 12" created="Fri, 12 Sep 2025 14:47:31 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="12">
				<outline text="I did a podcast interview yesterday with &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@nathanwrigley&quot;&gt;Nathan Wrigley&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wptavern.com/&quot;&gt;WP Tavern&lt;/a&gt;. I had a great time, and learned a lot. It's interesting that while I am not a member of the WordPress community, there is a big intersection between that community and one I &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; belong to -- the web. WordPress was founded on the principles and idealism of the web. It's baked in. So it might be the largest community of users, not exclusively developers, who have the same values as the web, which are very very powerful values. I'm rediscovering them and it's wonderful. It means I can plug your app into my server and they work first time. It's the &lt;i&gt;just works&lt;/i&gt; part that makes it the web. It makes you suck in your breath and go, I'm there now. One interesting thing that came up was the subject of altruism, which is something I reject re myself. It doesn't work if what I do is altruism, because we all must be somewhat committed to the success of our competitors, because if we don't we are locking people in. It's so important that users have freedom of movement. If they don't things stagnate like our 19 years of Twitter. I'm going to be Nathan's show again, and again if he'll have me, to check in on the progress of my humble project to create a new layer, combining WordPress and all the other good stuff that isn't hooked up to it yet. I could not have hoped for a better introduction to The Land of WordPress. " created="Fri, 12 Sep 2025 14:47:32 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2022/08/08/bootstrappingByEngelbart.png"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 11" created="Thu, 11 Sep 2025 12:29:23 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="11">
				<outline text="It's really simple" created="Thu, 11 Sep 2025 12:39:36 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Reminder: &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2022/09/18.html&quot;&gt;Sept 18&lt;/a&gt;, one week from today, is the 3rd anniversary of the 20th anniversary of the release of RSS 2.0. I often forget to mark that day. It's not an event that's marked by others very often, but in my humble opinion, it deserves more respect than it gets. " created="Thu, 11 Sep 2025 12:29:24 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="Around the time of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2022/09/18.html&quot;&gt;20th anniversary&lt;/a&gt; I decided to swing back and see what more we could do with RSS. It had been sitting there basically going nowhere for most of those 20 years. I want to be clear, there were good and useful products created and supported, but there was none of the innovation that would have happened if it hadn't been so severely injured by Google and the many VC-backed startups hacking away at it." created="Thu, 11 Sep 2025 12:53:18 GMT"/>
					<outline text="A format like &quot;RSS&quot; has to be loved. And if you make it too complicated or vague, with too much political shuffling of the deck what you get is ActivityPub. That's what RSS would have become if it went down the path the tech industry wanted to take it down. We have a perfect artifact to look at. An A-B comparison. Couldn't be more stark. And, after almost 23 years, RSS is still simple." created="Thu, 11 Sep 2025 12:41:32 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Anyway, around the 20th anniversary, in the leadup to it, I decided if no one else was going to invest in RSS, I would, and let's see what comes of it." created="Thu, 11 Sep 2025 12:42:42 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The result was &quot;FeedLand&quot; which is fundamentally different from all the other feed readers in that its subscription model is patterned after the twitter-like social media apps. Everyone's subscription list is public. I can look at your list and you can look at mine. You can also put categories on the feeds you subscribe to and route them to other servers doing other things, through the magic of the web. And get this -- you can even subscribe to a category of my subscriptions. Lots of power there, but still it's simple." created="Thu, 11 Sep 2025 12:43:17 GMT"/>
					<outline text="FeedLand is the perfect back-end for a twitter-like system, for the feeds part. And for the words, the perfect back-end is &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2025/08/28/140604.html&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;. I only discovered that about 1.5 years ago. And I had to see what it looks like. No more &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/01/14/031201.html&quot;&gt;tiny little text boxes&lt;/a&gt;, WordLand is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://this.how/wordland/&quot;&gt;real editor&lt;/a&gt; that supports the basic writing features of the web. How do I know? Because it saves its data in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.markdownguide.org/cheat-sheet/&quot;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;. That has come to be the defining format for the text-based web. One which has been totally ignored by the twitter-like systems. Markdown is like MP3. If you're mixing &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2025/08/20/141957.html&quot;&gt;sound into feeds&lt;/a&gt; you use MP3 of course. It's there for you to use. As was Markdown. If you're mixing text you're mixing Markdown. " created="Thu, 11 Sep 2025 12:45:40 GMT"/>
					<outline text="So while everyone was dancing on Twitter's &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dumpster_fire&quot;&gt;dumpster fire&lt;/a&gt; of a social network I decided to build on something much bigger. The web. RSS and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.markdownguide.org/cheat-sheet/&quot;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;. WordPress and FeedLand. " created="Thu, 11 Sep 2025 12:47:46 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The name &lt;i&gt;Really Simple Syndication&lt;/i&gt; is supposed to make you smile, while most techie formats make you want to pull your hair out. RSS reads pretty well even if you know nothing about feeds and XML. I wish the browser people hadn't insisted on masking it with ugly CSS style sheets. I like lifting the hood of a car to see what's there even though I don't know what many of the things in there do. I learn by doing it. " created="Thu, 11 Sep 2025 12:48:41 GMT"/>
					<outline text="RSS isn't ugly, it's brilliant, and shouldn't be fear-inducing, hence the promise: it's really simple." created="Thu, 11 Sep 2025 13:55:02 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&quot;curly&quot;" created="Thu, 11 Sep 2025 13:55:27 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 10" created="Wed, 10 Sep 2025 14:00:15 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="10">
				<outline text="Today's song: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G0bvKJaTB2s&quot;&gt;When you awake&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 10 Sep 2025 16:10:58 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Podcast: &lt;a href=&quot;https://shownotes.scripting.com/scripting/2025/09/10/aNewModelForBlogDiscourse.html&quot;&gt;A new model for blog discourse&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Wed, 10 Sep 2025 14:00:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://climbtothestars.org/&quot;&gt;Stephanie Booth&lt;/a&gt;, an OG blogger of great renown, now has a FeedLand &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/a8cteam51/feedland-blogroll&quot;&gt;blogroll&lt;/a&gt; on her WordPress blog. It is I believe going to make her blog feel less &lt;a href=&quot;https://manuelmoreale.com/blogs-don-t-need-to-be-so-lonely&quot;&gt;lonely&lt;/a&gt;. If anyone else wants to get one going, I have more confidence that it's pretty do-able. &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/10/stephanieBlogroll.png&quot;&gt;Screen shot&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 10 Sep 2025 14:08:55 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Heh. Yesterday I started writing a post about something Brent wrote on his blog, and then I must've gotten distracted and didn't finish it. I will now proceed to explain. " created="Wed, 10 Sep 2025 14:02:45 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Brent &lt;a href=&quot;https://inessential.com/2025/08/28/easy-app-writing.html&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; he cares about desktop software but not about phone and tablet versions of same. I found that liberating. It's always been a pain in the ass to do something beautiful on the desktop only to have to destroy its utility by squeezing it into a space with no keyboard or pointing device that's more accurate than my finger (I have huge fingers, and a normal size phone). I found it liberating, but -- I'm working on the design of an app that should work well on either a phone or a laptop, and I've had that in mind the whole life of the product. But now I realize in a new way that it's a choice. It always was, but it didn't &lt;i&gt;feel&lt;/i&gt; that way. " created="Wed, 10 Sep 2025 14:03:21 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 9" created="Tue, 09 Sep 2025 11:44:45 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="09">
				<outline text="I read something on Brent's blog the other day that changed my thinking. He said " created="Tue, 09 Sep 2025 17:38:54 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="WWND. What Would Navalny Do? Think about it." created="Tue, 09 Sep 2025 13:05:34 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The Dems are terrible at politics. They should be running ads on TV saying that no workers in the fields means food prices soaring as we'll have to import food because all the American crops are dead because there was no one to harvest them. It's true. Why didn't anyone see this coming? Well we &lt;i&gt;did&lt;/i&gt; see it coming, but the Dems were too dumb to do anything about it. They're supposed to be the &quot;woke&quot; party, isn't it funny that they're so un-woke about something like keeping Americans fed!" created="Tue, 09 Sep 2025 12:26:14 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2020/11/26/uncleSam.png"/>
				<outline text="Bullet points from yesterday's podcast" created="Tue, 09 Sep 2025 11:44:46 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I asked ChatGPT to provide bullet points for &lt;a href=&quot;https://shownotes.scripting.com/scripting/2025/09/08/whyBloggingLostToTwitterAndOtherFolkSongs.html&quot;&gt;yesterday's podcast&lt;/a&gt;. I thought this time it did a really good job. It did misunderstand some things I said, I just deleted those, below." created="Tue, 09 Sep 2025 11:44:49 GMT" flBulletedSubs="true">
						<outline text="Blogging lost to Twitter because Twitter had one-click subscribe." created="Tue, 09 Sep 2025 11:45:15 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Subscribing in feed readers required too many steps: copying URLs, menus, pasting, confirming."/>
						<outline text="This friction discouraged adoption compared to Twitter's simplicity." created="Tue, 09 Sep 2025 11:45:58 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Feed reader developers (2002-2006) competed instead of cooperating, creating cluttered subscription buttons." created="Tue, 09 Sep 2025 11:46:03 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Twitter succeeded because it eliminated that friction."/>
						<outline text="FeedLand solves this with one-click subscribe and checkboxes next to feeds."/>
						<outline text="Users can see others' subscriptions, similar to Twitter, Bluesky, Mastodon, Threads, Facebook." created="Tue, 09 Sep 2025 11:46:12 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Private feeds are possible but niche; public following is standard and expected."/>
						<outline text="Emphasis on factoring UI: reduce steps, as with &quot;Edit This Page&quot; in 1999." created="Tue, 09 Sep 2025 11:46:24 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Rebooting the blogosphere requires cooperation and a universal &quot;follow&quot; button." created="Tue, 09 Sep 2025 11:46:49 GMT"/>
						<outline text="FeedLand's checkboxes make subscribing or filtering feeds simple." created="Tue, 09 Sep 2025 11:47:02 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Introduces &quot;Radio WordLand&quot; release with advanced checkbox features." created="Tue, 09 Sep 2025 11:47:07 GMT"/>
						<outline text="FeedLand timelines can be filtered live using checkboxes tied to feeds."/>
						<outline text="Example feeds: Daves WordPress blog, Great Art feed from Bluesky, linkblog, Scripting News, podcast, WordCamp Canada 2025 feed." created="Tue, 09 Sep 2025 11:48:03 GMT"/>
						<outline text="WordCamp Canada keynote in Ottawa, Oct 16-17, 2025." created="Tue, 09 Sep 2025 11:48:15 GMT"/>
						<outline text="WordLand integrates categories for organizing feeds."/>
						<outline text="Commitment to &quot;Edit This Page&quot; feature: too valuable to abandon." created="Tue, 09 Sep 2025 11:48:31 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Broader goal: restore writer-friendly features Twitter removed (links, styling, no character limits)."/>
						<outline text="Criticism of Bluesky/Twitter/Threads for perpetuating character limits and stripped-down writing."/>
						<outline text="Aim: build software that forces platforms to support the web by user demand."/>
						<outline text="Automatic/WordPress bringing ActivityPub to blogs is &quot;heroic&quot; bridging web and Mastodon." created="Tue, 09 Sep 2025 11:48:58 GMT"/>
						<outline text="WordPress posts in Mastodon retain titles, styling, links, and images -- better than Twitter/Bluesky." created="Tue, 09 Sep 2025 11:49:22 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Believes competition will pressure other networks to drop artificial limits."/>
						<outline text="Concludes with confidence: momentum is building, new features will roll out soon."/>
						</outline>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 8" created="Mon, 08 Sep 2025 14:01:15 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="08">
				<outline text="Podcast: &lt;a href=&quot;https://shownotes.scripting.com/scripting/2025/09/08/whyBloggingLostToTwitterAndOtherFolkSongs.html&quot;&gt;Why blogging lost to Twitter and other folk songs&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Mon, 08 Sep 2025 21:24:20 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I've been calling the next release &lt;a href=&quot;https://daveverse.org/2025/09/08/radio-wordland-coming-along-nicely/&quot;&gt;Radio WordLand&lt;/a&gt;. If you know the &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22Radio%20UserLand%22&quot;&gt;history&lt;/a&gt; you'll understand why. I'll start posting screen shots soon. " created="Mon, 08 Sep 2025 16:37:31 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/08/evanPostMasto.png&quot;&gt;Screen shot&lt;/a&gt; of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@evan@cosocial.ca/115164400820285035&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; by Evan Prodromou on Masto yesterday. &quot;You publish where you want to publish, Dave. We'll find a way to connect to you. That's the whole point.&quot; Indeed that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the whole point. I say it &lt;a href=&quot;https://this.how/standards/#1497798753000&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Interop is all that matters.&quot; If our products interop that's pure love. The rest of it is baloney. Maybe I'm not a nice guy. Not my job. We've being fucked over by &quot;social media&quot; for 19 years now, and the new ones who say they're open, and on the web, and decentralized, are not. The only way out of this mess is what Evan said. BTW, I &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@davew/115164714595757607&quot;&gt;sent&lt;/a&gt; Evan a &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.social/opml?screenname=davewiner&amp;catname=daveverse&quot;&gt;pointer&lt;/a&gt; to the subscription list which is my outflow. I use OPML for the list and RSS for the feeds. That's where you will find my writing. " created="Mon, 08 Sep 2025 15:06:06 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/09/10/kittyStamp.png"/>
				<outline text="I watched the movie &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seven_(1995_film)&quot;&gt;Seven&lt;/a&gt; last night, and I can't stop thinking about it. It got a shitty &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/1995/09/22/movies/film-review-a-sickening-catalogue-of-sins-every-one-of-them-deadly.html&quot;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt; in the NYT, which usually means I won't bother with something, but this time I decided to give it a try. The reviewer, Janet Maislin, didn't like the acting of Brad Pitt. I thought Pitt was an unlikeable jerk, but I also thought that was the role, but maybe I was wrong. I didn't care. I also couldn't figure out what city it was. It wasn't NY, but Maislin says it was. Usually in a movie set in NY, I recognize many of the locations. There are only a few places movies are shot in the city. But again, I didn't care. What keeps me thinking about it is the story. I'm not going to spoil it. Don't read any reviews before watching it, they pretty much all get in the way of the storytelling. " created="Mon, 08 Sep 2025 15:17:45 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/08/se7en.png"/>
				<outline text="How to be part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://this.how/blogosphere/&quot;&gt;rebooted blogosphere&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Mon, 08 Sep 2025 14:11:55 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 7" created="Sun, 07 Sep 2025 14:53:41 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="07">
				<outline text="Two videos every US resident should watch to prepare for what might be coming. 1. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lives_of_Others&quot;&gt;The Lives of Others&lt;/a&gt;. A drama set in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/East_Germany&quot;&gt;eastern part&lt;/a&gt; of post-war Germany before the wall came down. People lived their lives, but their relationship with the government and the military would seem very strange to an American of 2025, But more of this is definitely what's on the way, and the technology for watching what you do is much better now, and our neighbors aren't any different, which is what the Germans depended on. 2. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Handmaid%27s_Tale_(TV_series)&quot;&gt;The Handmaid's Tale&lt;/a&gt;. Same kind of police state as in Lives of Others with a Christian twist. Everyone is a member of a caste. Most women are infertile since some unspecified disaster, and the ones who can reproduce exist only to reproduce. There are women who clean the house, and do a few other things. There are certainly other books, movies and series worth tuning into, but these are the ones I recommend now. Handmaid's Tale is also a book, which I have read, but the show on Hulu goes into more detail." created="Sun, 07 Sep 2025 14:53:42 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/07/livesOfOthersPoster.png"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://socketdemo.feedland.org/&quot;&gt;New demo app&lt;/a&gt;. FeedLand communicates back to the client app via websockets. This is absolutely the easiest way to get flow from feeds to apps running on servers or in a browser, or other desktop app. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebSocket&quot;&gt;Websockets&lt;/a&gt; is a mature &lt;a href=&quot;https://websockets.spec.whatwg.org/&quot;&gt;standard&lt;/a&gt;, and incredibly useful. I'm now working on a toolkit for it, along with all the other projects going on in parallel, so other developers can hook into &quot;FeedLand&quot; to get the flow of new items. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://socketdemo.feedland.org/&quot;&gt;demo&lt;/a&gt; shows you the JSON version of every news item as it appears on the wire. There's no limit to the kinds of apps you can build for this. My &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22Chuck%20Shotton%22&quot;&gt;friend&lt;/a&gt; Chuck Shotton has a market-predicting LLM app that gets its news this way. Nothing to install on a server. FeedLand does all the work. I expect to have a toolkit out sometime in the few weeks. " created="Sun, 07 Sep 2025 17:15:37 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Another application for websockets. You could actually put a web server on your desktop without exposing your home network to the world. I can't wait till I have time to play around with this. " created="Sun, 07 Sep 2025 17:21:26 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 6" created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 12:24:33 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="06">
				<outline text="New version of FeedLand" created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 13:22:04 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="There's a new version of FeedLand, v0.7.0. " created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 13:22:09 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Here's the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedlandInstall/issues/68&quot;&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt; where we discussed the testing of the new release. It worked everywhere we installed it, so it seems fair to open it up to people running their own FeedLand instances. " created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 13:22:24 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The only features it adds are ones needed to use it with the new version of &quot;WordLand&quot;, coming soon now. " created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 13:23:46 GMT"/>
					<outline text="But if you have the time, it requires an update to the database, so it's not the usual thing. It explains at the beginning of the thread what the change is to the database. " created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 13:28:28 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Here are the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedlandInstall/blob/main/docs/sep2025transition.md&quot;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt; for doing the upgrade. " created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 13:24:56 GMT"/>
					<outline text="If you're installing a new instance, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedlandInstall/blob/main/docs/setup.md&quot;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt; are the same as always." created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 13:27:00 GMT"/>
					<outline text="If you have trouble, post a note on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedlandInstall/issues/68&quot;&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 13:25:18 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Thanks to Scott Hanson for validating the new version. It's always important to have someone to check my work. " created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 13:25:51 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="About feedland.org" created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 12:24:34 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Yesterday's &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2025/09/05.html#a145720&quot;&gt;note&lt;/a&gt; on scripting.com about feedland.org was not the whole story. In the end I thought it made more sense to start the database over from the start.  " created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 12:24:50 GMT"/>
					<outline text="There were a few users who subscribed to feeds that were constantly updating, and they never came back to use FeedLand. So as soon as I started it back up it started loading new items at a very high rate, and after a couple of hours it was still going. There aren't that many people using feedland.org, so I thought the best thing to do is to start over and hopefully people will figure out how to resubscribe to the feeds they want to follow. " created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 12:25:25 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Then I felt that people might be able to use a few tips on how to get going again, so that's what this post is about. " created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 12:26:53 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;b&gt;Sign off and on&lt;/b&gt;" created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 12:27:17 GMT"/>
					<outline text="First thing you should do is sign off and sign back on. " created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 12:28:13 GMT"/>
					<outline text="You will still have the credentials in your browser, but the server doesn't know about them, so when you try to do something that requires you being logged in it will fail. But if you sign off and on again, that will take care of that problem. " created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 12:28:55 GMT"/>
					<outline text="To sign off, choose the command in the system menu at the right end of the menubar. " created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 12:29:50 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Once you're signed off the only option will be to sign back on. :-)" created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 12:42:37 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/06/signoff.png&quot;&gt;Screen shot&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 12:30:07 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;b&gt;Restore subscription list&lt;/b&gt;" created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 12:36:38 GMT"/>
					<outline text="How to restore from a backup of your subscription list." created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 12:36:44 GMT"/>
					<outline text="From the first menu, choose Subscribe/From an OPML File." created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 12:47:33 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/06/subscribeToOpml.png&quot;&gt;screen shot&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 12:39:26 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;b&gt;Questions?&lt;/b&gt;" created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 12:39:53 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I started a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedlandSupport/issues/248&quot;&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt; on the support site for questions." created="Sat, 06 Sep 2025 12:39:57 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 5" created="Fri, 05 Sep 2025 14:57:19 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="05">
				<outline text="I upgraded &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.org/&quot;&gt;feedland.org&lt;/a&gt; to a new version of the system software, still being tested. In the process I started a fresh items table. This means for the next day or so your timeline may have a lot of items for a few feeds, as it catches up with every feed it keeps track of. The server was down for a couple of hours while we did the upgrade. Still diggin! ;-) " created="Fri, 05 Sep 2025 14:57:20 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 4" created="Thu, 04 Sep 2025 14:14:45 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="04">
				<outline text="BTW, one of the things I should have mentioned in yesterday's &lt;a href=&quot;https://shownotes.scripting.com/scripting/2025/09/03/lastChanceForTheOpenWeb.html&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; is that the product isn't just WordLand, it's also FeedLand. The two are connected by a well-developed &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebSocket&quot;&gt;WebSocket&lt;/a&gt; interface, which I will provide code for, as well as docs for what goes over the wire. I think a lot of feed &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/aficionado&quot;&gt;aficionados&lt;/a&gt; will find this really interesting (and also really simple)." created="Thu, 04 Sep 2025 14:14:46 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2022/08/08/bootstrappingByEngelbart.png"/>
				<outline text="Another thing I should have mentioned, about the title of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://shownotes.scripting.com/scripting/2025/09/03/lastChanceForTheOpenWeb.html&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt;, I think this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the last chance for the open web. It may already be too late. Look at what's happening politically in the US now and ask how tolerant the government is going to be of an open web. We always had to deal with the possibility that they would shut down free speech here. It has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communications_Decency_Act&quot;&gt;tried&lt;/a&gt;, didn't work in the 90s. But the guardrails that existed then possibly don't exist now. The same things that are forcing CBS for example to become a controlled press, may affect the web too, but you won't read about it in the NYT or hear about it on Maddow because they have low regard for non-professional people writing on the web. " created="Thu, 04 Sep 2025 14:22:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="ChatGPT might not give you the best answer. Yesterday I hit a problem with the MySQL hosting service, and as we worked it out, ChatGPT and me, I ended up contacting the ISP's support asking them to restart the server, something I cannot do through the control panel. They don't do that, and made a couple of suggestions which didn't seem to make sense based on what ChatGPT had told me. So I tried what they suggested and it worked, and went back to ChatGPT and asked what it thought, and it said yes of course that worked, and would you like me to show you how to do it even better. I guess it takes a path and never goes back to see if there isn't a better one. We've been through this before. Anyway, always be circumspect about it's advice, it's not just hallucinations you need to watch for. That said, with help from both ChatGPT and Digital Ocean, I now have a better setup, and it should run without the problem we hit yesterday. " created="Thu, 04 Sep 2025 14:48:57 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="AI is as good at writing software as it is in creating competent visual art. It's only amazing in terms of how much more a novice can do. It doesn't mean what they create is interesting in more than a gee-wiz way, and the novelty fades pretty quickly I've found." created="Thu, 04 Sep 2025 15:27:13 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 3" created="Wed, 03 Sep 2025 15:32:00 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="03">
				<outline text="Podcast: &lt;a href=&quot;https://shownotes.scripting.com/scripting/2025/09/03/lastChanceForTheOpenWeb.html&quot;&gt;Last chance for the open web&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 03 Sep 2025 17:20:39 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I want to start reading a bunch of &lt;a href=&quot;https://canada.wordcamp.org/2025/wordpress-community-blogs/&quot;&gt;WordPress community blogs&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Wed, 03 Sep 2025 15:32:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 2" created="Tue, 02 Sep 2025 14:54:57 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="02">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/interactive-guide-to-grid/&quot;&gt;CSS Grid&lt;/a&gt; where have you been all my life? Very rational, simple.  " created="Tue, 02 Sep 2025 14:54:58 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="General note: When I say RSS, I recognize that there are other feed formats, but I don't want to confuse things. The software makes all that transparent, so let's make it transparent for the users too, ok? " created="Tue, 02 Sep 2025 21:56:27 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="WordLand + FeedLand will ask..." created="Tue, 02 Sep 2025 21:55:17 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="If all the people who love RSS and make software for it, feed readers, editors, blogging software, put our heads together, we could make a great network for people to write on, that would be so exciting, it would pull a lot of interest from the silos. If momentum builds, they will eventually add RSS as an inbound and outbound format because they will want to be on this network. " created="Tue, 02 Sep 2025 21:55:29 GMT"/>
					<outline text="We, as writers, shouldn't have to live with the compromises that come from having to make 5 versions of everything, and still you don't have a way to share a lot of the interesting stuff people write." created="Tue, 02 Sep 2025 21:56:43 GMT"/>
					<outline text="If we choose to work together, even just a few of us, we could make big change." created="Tue, 02 Sep 2025 21:55:43 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="My life has a musical track" created="Tue, 02 Sep 2025 20:41:24 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="How you know you’re &lt;i&gt;reallllly&lt;/i&gt; old. You tell Alexa to play songs by Elton John and you find yourself singing along with &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/75r0nQu-hMs?si=eB17vFtdknnE8lbJ&quot;&gt;Crocodile Rock&lt;/a&gt; with tears streaming down your face. Then they play &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gM4Xm2MGLNQ&quot;&gt;Philadelphia Freedom&lt;/a&gt;. Mama mia." created="Tue, 02 Sep 2025 20:39:15 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="The thing about Crocodile Rock is that it's twice-nostalgic. He's singing about a generation-older than mine. Yet it planted in my memory connected to a period in my own life. I was a freshman at Lehman College in the Bronx, recovering from a raucous high school experience where I dropped out and moved into an apartment in the Bronx at 16 and came pretty close to losing my middle-class education-valuing upbringing. At Lehman, I was investing in myself and found out I was good at the things I thought I was no good at because the teachers were so awful. I got a good math teacher, Dr Isaacs, who treated me special because I had a good mind for math, it turns out. And thus I became a programmer when I thought I would likely go into politics before that. I still had the taste for politics, and as it turns out, writing, so I combined all of them into one, and out comes blogging and podcasting, and complicated algorithms that do simple easy to understand things. " created="Tue, 02 Sep 2025 20:42:26 GMT" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/02/captainFantastic.png"/>
					<outline text="And now &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scott_Knaster&quot;&gt;Scott Knaster&lt;/a&gt; who has had an exciting &lt;a href=&quot;https://tidbits.com/2025/03/18/check-out-scott-knasters-adjacent-to-greatness-substack-newsletter/&quot;&gt;Adjacent to Greatness&lt;/a&gt; career &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dave.winer.12/posts/pfbid0nDyfb6C6UQg8vFxWDM4Z1NZPNg5r2mVXGaDSKNMgwsqSCp8kotQ786aPZ49T5h5nl?comment_id=643762492104935&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; that Philadelphia Freedom is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eltonjohn.com/stories/billie-jean-king-talks-about-philadelphia-freedom&quot;&gt;about&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Billie_Jean_King&quot;&gt;Billie Jean King&lt;/a&gt;. I did not know that!" created="Tue, 02 Sep 2025 20:44:17 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="September 1" created="Mon, 01 Sep 2025 13:09:15 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="01">
				<outline text="AI chatbots should drop the pretense of being human." created="Mon, 01 Sep 2025 14:18:06 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I want my blog on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/scripting.com/post/3lxroa6khd22j&quot;&gt;same network&lt;/a&gt; as my social media." created="Mon, 01 Sep 2025 13:09:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="A new &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/01/spammy.png&quot;&gt;kind of spam&lt;/a&gt; or phishing email. Appears to be a challenge by Twitter of one of my posts there as a copyright infringement, which it most definitely is not. You have to look closely at the URL it takes you to, which is on this domain. assents-x.com. Hmm at first looks legit, but look more closely. " created="Mon, 01 Sep 2025 16:29:41 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I've been watching a lot of baseball recently. Over the years I've developed as a programmer, and they've radically changed the way baseball is played. Pitchers used to try to pitch a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Complete_game&quot;&gt;complete game&lt;/a&gt;, but now that never happens. Sometimes they take a pitcher out in the first inning if he's pitched over say 70 pitches, because there's no point, what he's doing obviously isn't working, and he's getting close to the maximum pitches they'd let him do, esp if he's young and a hot prospect, they don't want to burn him out. I find that no matter what, after four hours of development work I start getting sloppy, and I can't think big picture as I could in the beginning of the session. I'm trying to finish things up for the day, and leave myself in a good place to pick up in the next session. And like a pitcher you have to stay focused. The phone doesn't ring for the pitcher when he's on the mound, that's why programmers, good ones, who are performing at or near their limit of ability to focus, so totally don't welcome interruptions. " created="Mon, 01 Sep 2025 15:57:20 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/01/sandyKoufax.png"/>
				<outline text="A motto for &quot;WordLand&quot;. &quot;All the tools you need right where you write.&quot;" created="Mon, 01 Sep 2025 22:24:00 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			</outline>
		</body>
	</opml>
