<?xml version="1.0"?>
<opml version="2.0">
	<head>
		<title>Scripting News</title>
		<dateCreated>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 15:51:38 GMT</dateCreated>
		<urlPublic>http://scripting.com/publicfolder/scripting/blog.opml</urlPublic>
		<flPublic>true</flPublic>
		<ownerEmail>dave.winer@gmail.com</ownerEmail>
		<ownerId>dave.winer@gmail.com</ownerId>
		<urlUpdateSocket>wss://drummer.land/</urlUpdateSocket>
		<dateModified>Mon, 01 Jun 2026 11:02:51 GMT</dateModified>
		<expansionState>1</expansionState>
		<lastCursor>0</lastCursor>
		</head>
	<body>
		<outline text="May 2026" created="Fri, 01 May 2026 12:47:01 GMT" name="may2026" type="calendarMonth">
			<outline text="May 31" created="Sun, 31 May 2026 16:03:51 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="31">
				<outline text="The purpose of &lt;a href=&quot;https://this.how/standards/&quot;&gt;standards&lt;/a&gt; is interop. That's it. No other purpose. " created="Mon, 01 Jun 2026 01:16:31 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Just watched the first episode of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Star_City_(TV_series)&quot;&gt;Star City&lt;/a&gt;, really good. Somewhat like The Americans, but takes place in the USSR. A spinoff of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/For_All_Mankind_(TV_series)&quot;&gt;For All Mankind&lt;/a&gt;, which started out interesting and then became unwatchable, though I did enjoy the sets on Mars. I also liked the character who was inspired by Elon Musk, obviously. " created="Mon, 01 Jun 2026 01:13:23 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="There have been problems reported with &lt;a href=&quot;http://subscribe.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;subscribe.scripting.com&lt;/a&gt;. At least some of them are fixed. It's hard to test this kind of software because you can't really tell what went wrong. If people report problems they just say it didn't work. But real problems were fixed, so if you've had trouble subscribing or unsubscribing, now is a good time to try again. And thanks for your patience, and sorry for the screwy app. ;-)" created="Sun, 31 May 2026 16:58:10 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="How bad was it with the Knicks. As something of a joke, but not really, Knicks fans would disguise themselves with &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/20/knicksSuckGetOutPaperBags.png&quot;&gt;paper bags&lt;/a&gt; with eye cutouts. Fans got accustomed to the feelings of betrayal and hopelessness. When was the actual &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2014/12/23/sports/basketball/worst-knicks-team-ever-thats-saying-a-lot-.html?unlocked_article_code=1.mlA.PtI_.huKHrZ_BbW6Z&amp;smid=url-share&quot;&gt;lowest&lt;/a&gt; point? A good candidate was when they traded some good players for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrea_Bargnani&quot;&gt;Bargnani&lt;/a&gt;, an Italian who apparently for some reason was the top draft choice of the Toronto Raptors. He wasn't much good to begin with and he went downhill from there. There were quite a few other moments when you thought it couldn't get any worse, but then it did. We finally got management with a heart and a mind with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leon_Rose&quot;&gt;Leon Rose&lt;/a&gt; and that's when team-building &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leon_Rose#Executive_career&quot;&gt;began&lt;/a&gt; for real, and the reason the Knicks have been such poetry on the court this season is due to Rose's eye for talent and an understanding of the big picture. He picked players that work well with each other, and sometimes amazingly well. In the right margin is an &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2021/05/13/knicksFan.png&quot;&gt;image&lt;/a&gt; I used for posts about the Knicks in the past, a reminder of how far we've come. The look of doom. We all remember that mode so well, we stood with them then, so here we are with high hopes and reasonable expectations. " created="Sun, 31 May 2026 17:01:13 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2021/05/13/knicksFan.png"/>
				<outline text="Congrats to my friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.manton.org/2026/05/30/amazing-series-thunder-kept-it.html&quot;&gt;Manton Reece&lt;/a&gt;, a San Antonio fan, for their victory in the Western Conference last night. The Knicks will be playing them starting on Wednesday for the NBA championship. Knicks representing the east, Spurs for the west. " created="Sun, 31 May 2026 16:03:52 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 30" created="Sat, 30 May 2026 12:23:48 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="30">
				<outline text="If I ran Bluesky, instead of trying to fork the web, I'd be trying to become the competitor of Twitter's that is 100% web top to bottom." created="Sat, 30 May 2026 12:38:38 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Review of standard.site" created="Sat, 30 May 2026 12:38:10 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I walked through standard.site with ChatGPT. You can do it too if you want to find out what it is. I was interested in knowing how it compares to RSS 2.0 and FeedLand. " created="Sat, 30 May 2026 12:37:26 GMT" flNumberedSubs="true">
						<outline text="I want a quick overview of standard.site with a simple example." created="Sat, 30 May 2026 12:38:52 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Seems like RSS mostly." created="Sat, 30 May 2026 12:39:48 GMT"/>
						<outline text="We have a firehouse for feeds on the web emanating from FeedLand, based on rssCloud." created="Sat, 30 May 2026 12:40:07 GMT"/>
						<outline text="We are the web’s social web." created="Sat, 30 May 2026 12:40:15 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Why do the proponents of standard.site use AT Proto. What’s the advantage?" created="Sat, 30 May 2026 12:40:29 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="Very often links from ChatGPT don't work, but I'm including the link &lt;a href=&quot;https://chatgpt.com/share/6a1adada-253c-83ea-8127-313400eafa04&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; in case it does. You can have the conversation on your own. " created="Sat, 30 May 2026 12:41:06 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I asked ChatGPT to produce a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/356&quot;&gt;summary&lt;/a&gt; of the results, and asked it not to tilt it in favor of the formats and protocols I've invested in. There is a place to comment after the spec. Interested in hearing from other developers. " created="Sat, 30 May 2026 12:44:17 GMT"/>
					<outline text="This gives me an idea for a tech publication. Write reviews in this format. Make sure you include the prompts so people can reproduce your results. Let readers fact-check. And let the proponents and competitors comment on the review. No one reviews tech products any more so this would not put anyone out of work." created="Sat, 30 May 2026 12:57:36 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 29" created="Fri, 29 May 2026 13:21:37 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="29">
				<outline text="Yesterday I &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/davewiner/status/2060061479127183594&quot;&gt;applied to speak&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://us.wordcamp.org/2026/&quot;&gt;WordCamp US&lt;/a&gt; in August and I also posted bits to my account on Twitter. I got a really &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/WordPress/status/2060150139428143403&quot;&gt;nice response&lt;/a&gt; from the main WordPress account. Thank you. I now have a platform to speak to the community, and I'll do my best to outline what I have in mind in August in Phoenix. How appropriate that the phoenix is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phoenix_(mythology)&quot;&gt;symbol of rebirth&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Fri, 29 May 2026 13:21:38 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/02/17/reallySimpleCoffee.png"/>
				<outline text="I have the most followers on Twitter, Bluesky has never come close. I can't get anything to happen on Bluesky, but Twitter is great. Yesterday I had an idea, put it up on twitter and within a few hours I got the connection I was hoping for. It's a network, and it's more defined by who's there than who owns it. I can use it for idea distribution, the ideas find more minds and sometimes that results in benefits for the web. It's all about interop, and weirdly the pwned Twitter is much better for idea distribution than any of the other networks. In a sane world those smaller vendors would be fighting for interop, instead they're fighting against it. " created="Fri, 29 May 2026 14:35:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Official recognition from WordPress" created="Fri, 29 May 2026 23:56:42 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/WordPress/status/2060150139428143403&quot;&gt;This is what&lt;/a&gt; I really accomplished in the years of work I did on the early web. I created something that could be built into a large successful company with millions of customers, and the web got a writing system, and because the people running it took the responsibility seriously, it has lasting value. " created="Fri, 29 May 2026 23:58:57 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;i&gt;This tweet means a lot to me.  &lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 29 May 2026 23:57:09 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/29/praisefromwordpress.png"/>
					<outline text="Still to this day, the systems I designed so many years ago work exactly as they did then. That's what the web was supposed to do. " created="Sat, 30 May 2026 00:06:25 GMT"/>
					<outline text="If my mom was still with us, I'd ask her to put this on the fridge. It's as good a review as I've ever gotten. " created="Sat, 30 May 2026 00:07:21 GMT"/>
					<outline text="My guess is that Matt wrote it, btw. He's really the only one in WordPress-land who can say something like this, imho. " created="Sat, 30 May 2026 00:07:54 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="ChatGPT images, two years apart" created="Fri, 29 May 2026 14:55:37 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="On May 29, 2024 I asked ChatGPT to: &quot;draw a picture of a baseball game at Citifield in the style of an American master artist.&quot; And I asked the same question today, two years later. According to ChatGPT the image is patterned after the art of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Bellows&quot;&gt;George Bellows&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 29 May 2026 14:55:46 GMT">
						<outline text="Drawing from 2024." created="Fri, 29 May 2026 16:57:17 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/29/citifield2024.png"/>
						<outline text="Drawing from 2026." created="Fri, 29 May 2026 16:57:17 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/29/citifield2026.png"/>
						</outline>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 28" created="Thu, 28 May 2026 13:06:31 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="28">
				<outline text="I've hesitated at calling &quot;FeedLand&quot; a feed reader. I'm concerned people would stop listening right there. They know what a feed reader is. But FeedLand is not like most feed readers. Your subscription list is public, as it is in Twitter. This is &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?username=davewiner&quot;&gt;my subscription list&lt;/a&gt;. When you're &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/28/ksmithList.png&quot;&gt;looking&lt;/a&gt; at someone else's list, there's a checkbox next to each feed. If you're subscribed to the feed the checkbox is checked. If you see one that looks interesting that you're not following, click to subscribe. Nothing else, no dialogs, confirmations -- one click. It has other features that are amazing that no other feed reader has, like a very powerful connection between categories and OPML subscription lists. And whole new way to use OPML lists -- in FeedLand you can subscribe to OPML lists. Think about that for a minute. It's also quite stable, and I took some time to make it a bit faster in certain important areas (coming soon). And it goes the other way too. When you're looking at a &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?feedurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazinavenue.com%2Frss%2Fcurrent.xml&quot;&gt;Feed Info page&lt;/a&gt;, you can see who else is subscribed to it. Click their name and you can see what they're following. As far as I know no other feed reader does any of this. The design mode was the social web. But unlike the others our web is based on broadly supported web standards, not someday -- now. " created="Thu, 28 May 2026 13:08:35 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/03/23/beStrongAndOfGoodCourage.png"/>
				<outline text="I applied to speak at WordCamp US in Phoenix in August. I want to give a rip-roaring talk about how WordPress is at the center of the universe and it doesn't even know. Let's get busy filling in the blanks. Writers are ready. If we build it they (developers) will come. To much sulking, let's get out there and kick some butt. I excerpted elements of my application &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/davewiner/status/2060061479127183594&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 28 May 2026 18:21:22 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Really Open this time vs Really Simple last?? Hmm." created="Thu, 28 May 2026 18:12:42 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Dries Buytaert &lt;a href=&quot;https://dri.es/grow-the-ecosystem-not-just-yourself&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; you have to grow the ecosystem, not just yourself. " created="Thu, 28 May 2026 17:25:23 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="If you want to know who’s responsible for the good karma the Knicks are experiencing look to &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=durant&quot;&gt;Kevin Durant&lt;/a&gt;. While while he was trying to build some weird rivalry between the Knicks and the Nets, the Knicks were building a contender. " created="Thu, 28 May 2026 15:53:24 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/02/23/reallySimpleRavioli.png"/>
				<outline text="Another great thing about building software with Claude Code, I can implement something the simple way knowing that later on I can change it to work in the more complex way without having to relearn all the code. Claude doesn't have any trouble with piled up complexity. This is a fundamental change in the way I develop. There was a very real limit to the complexity my mind could handle, but now with a sort of infinite size disk for my brain whatever I want to do as long as it can be described in almost mathematical terms, we can do it. It's another layer in the stack. We haven't had one of those in a my lifetime, they were all invented before 1955. Seriously big deal." created="Thu, 28 May 2026 15:05:33 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The big wait betw Knicks series isn't just hard on the team, it's confusing for the fans/addicts like me. It's about the time of year that the Knicks are no longer in, and two teams I don't care about enough to watch are in the Finals. Maybe one or two games. It's like &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22jury%20duty%22&quot;&gt;jury duty&lt;/a&gt;, at some point you realize you're so confused because you're in a courtroom, but where is the jury. Oh no the jury is inside me. Who's in the finals this year? We are. Geez I guess I've finally succumbed, I never think of myself as part of a team, but now I actually feel like I'm part of it. Will have to think about that.  " created="Thu, 28 May 2026 14:54:54 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Scott Hanson is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scotthansonde/wordlandBaseline/releases/tag/v0.2.9a&quot;&gt;working on&lt;/a&gt; the Baseline theme for WordLand. " created="Thu, 28 May 2026 13:53:23 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Writing a lot of test posts. And thus have coined some (mostly) rhyming pairs of words. Greek sneakers. Geek peekers. Feast of yeast. Villa in Manila." created="Thu, 28 May 2026 13:06:32 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 27" created="Wed, 27 May 2026 11:01:36 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="27">
				<outline text="Now I have to write about the Knicks. It just hasn't fully sunk in yet that they won the East. You get to put a &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/27/banners.png&quot;&gt;banner&lt;/a&gt; up for that. And next week we'll be watching them in the NBA finals. But it's the team that matters, not the trophies. Brunson is great, despite what I &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2026/04/24/134026.html&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; after they went down 2-1 vs the Hawks in the first round. But the other players are great too in different ways. And there are so many of them, not just the starters. Every one with a distinct personality and all of them super smart and committed to the team and each other. What makes it work? You can see it in how they play -- trust. They trust each other. Their fates are intertwined. And they knew it before they had this amazing streak of wins in the post-season. I love the Knicks even when they lose. I'm not sure how you love them when they are champions. We'll figure it out. " created="Wed, 27 May 2026 11:01:37 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/20/brunson.png"/>
				<outline text="I came across &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2026/05/27/knicksCelebrating.png&quot;&gt;this photo&lt;/a&gt; of the Knicks celebrating, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OG_Anunoby&quot;&gt;OG Anunoby&lt;/a&gt; in the center. The thing about OG is that he's a deep thinker and he &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?sca_esv=423685a90e5df121&amp;rlz=1C5CHFA_enUS743US747&amp;sxsrf=ANbL-n6N-UleZ5QkNtPb83Q_NRGBcBG1Ow:1779890672792&amp;udm=2&amp;fbs=ADc_l-aN0CWEZBOHjofHoaMMDiKp0UJuhqwKhR0QUhF54-6jIX2xhuqmjuyJb8bmeAomNlGvrcIh4D4fHfxBBURfTfoz9NM4d8_XekjXkRztNIuwEUDalLn318KGQ29GAUe2TrTWFFZ66IEaXmbD8lTkY2Zjzret-W2Nbr2iNGvWNz9QkPQpY-t2-xeVHZxFT5CUn8FQFWiijajY8OtVZ9dFoRZvqLaxEg&amp;q=OG+Anunoby&amp;sa=X&amp;ved=2ahUKEwjrxqm60dmUAxW4g4kEHY5kNQIQtKgLegQIGhAB&amp;biw=1369&amp;bih=1140&amp;dpr=2&quot;&gt;never smiles&lt;/a&gt;, under any circumstances. Except right &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2026/05/27/knicksCelebrating.png&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. This is such a great photo I made it the &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/27/headergraphic.png&quot;&gt;header graphic&lt;/a&gt; on my blog for the day, week and maybe month, unless we get another one to replace it should they by some weird event they win the next series. And there isn't another series after that one. At that point this Knicks team goes down as one of two legendary Knicks teams over the decades, comparable to the 1973 Willis Reed, Walt Frazier, Earl Monroe, Dave DeBusschere and Bill Bradley championship &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1972%E2%80%9373_New_York_Knicks_season#:~:text=Besides%20being%20the%20last%20Knicks,of%20Fame%20coach%20Phil%20Jackson&quot;&gt;team&lt;/a&gt;, the last time the Knicks won it all. " created="Wed, 27 May 2026 13:54:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="OG was playing so well one night he was invited on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inside_the_NBA&quot;&gt;Inside the NBA&lt;/a&gt;, which is a big moment in an upcoming NBA legend's career. He sounded kind of irritated, in the OG way. At the end Charles Barkley asked what OG stood for, kind of a smirky question (probably to see if he could get him to smile), but his irritation level went wayyy up, and then Chuck didn't pronounce it right and OG told him. No smile. But that's who he is and it makes the great &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2026/05/27/knicksCelebrating.png&quot;&gt;photo&lt;/a&gt; of him ecstatic with happiness that much more of a big deal and a huge un-OG smile. Loook everyone even OG is impressed! :-) " created="Wed, 27 May 2026 14:01:33 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="If you love the Knicks, or even if you're just fascinated with this year's team, listen to today's &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?feedurl=https%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.megaphone.fm%2Fthe-bill-simmons-podcast#&quot;&gt;Bill Simmons podcast&lt;/a&gt;, it's all about the phenomenon of the 2026 Knicks, and Simmons is a Celtics fan, definitely not a Knicks lover. I can't believe all these smart sports guys didn't know Brunson was a catch, if I recall correctly, just before the Knicks signed him, due to injury he had to lead the Dallas team in the first three games of the playoffs in 2022, and there you could totally see what no one had seen yet in the pros, he's a leader and rises to the occasion, which we all know very well now, you could see it then if you watched the games (which apparently I did). And btw he grew up in the NBA, his father was on the Knicks in 1999 the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/sports/basketball/jalen-brunson-knicks-nba-finals-rcna346123&quot;&gt;last time&lt;/a&gt; the team went to the finals. " created="Wed, 27 May 2026 13:58:23 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 26" created="Tue, 26 May 2026 13:07:26 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="26">
				<outline text="Have you noticed that sometimes Claude is great and other times an idiot. Maybe it's me. I have to remember that Claude is not a computer. It's something else. " created="Tue, 26 May 2026 21:11:07 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Claude just asked if I was breaking for the day. At 10:53AM. Why did it ask me that? Now I can't stop thinking about that. The answer is no. I have a few more hours before I stop. " created="Tue, 26 May 2026 14:53:26 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I need an easy way to do a mini-podcast. An idea that should be said verbally, but it's short and self-contained, about the length of an untitled blog post, like the one you're reading now. &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/scripting.com/publicfolder/downloads/podcasts/2026/05/26/writeLikeClaude.m4a&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Tue, 26 May 2026 13:26:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Ultimately your job as a developer is to turn your creation over to users to figure out. Listen to see if patterns emerge. Even better give the users the tools they need to build apps out of our apps, together. This is how humans build layers of tech." created="Tue, 26 May 2026 13:08:17 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@davew/116640985182523572&quot;&gt;On Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;twitter-like systems are much simpler than you would think looking at this space, bluesky etc. and there doesn't need to be any lock-in, you can do a fair job with just RSS, rssCloud, OPML, web sockets, and a web browser UI. all parts replaceable.&quot;" created="Tue, 26 May 2026 13:07:27 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 25" created="Mon, 25 May 2026 13:09:59 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="25">
				<outline text="Good morning. Today is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Memorial_Day&quot;&gt;Memorial Day&lt;/a&gt; in the United States. We remember all the men and women who gave their lives to keep our country safe and a bastion of liberty for the world. Don't give up on us yet. We are still willing to sacrifice for a good cause.  " created="Mon, 25 May 2026 13:10:00 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Speaking of memorials, do you remember &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=Frontier&quot;&gt;UserLand Frontier&lt;/a&gt; and all the cool stuff we developed with it? Like Manila, Radio, XML-RPC, RSS, OPML, adding so many cool open features to the web. When people asked how we did all that, I said great tools. That was Frontier. &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22Jake%20Savin%22&quot;&gt;Jake Savin&lt;/a&gt;, one of the 1990s UserLanders,  is continuing the project to get it running on today's hardware and for today's web. He's documenting it &lt;a href=&quot;https://jakesav.in/2026/05/25/a-new-frontier-old-databases-are-new-again/&quot;&gt;on his blog&lt;/a&gt;. I can't wait to use it. Watching him go through the process has been eye-opening. He's basically retracing all the steps it took to create it as done by four or five people over quite a few years, a long time ago. But when it's running and I don't doubt that he will get it running, it'll be fascinating to see if I remembered it correctly. If you remember Frontier fondly, I suggest you &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?feedurl=https%3A%2F%2Fjakesav.in%2Ffeed%2F&quot;&gt;subscribe to his feed&lt;/a&gt; in your favorite RSS feed reader. " created="Mon, 25 May 2026 13:12:26 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2019/12/26/frontier.png"/>
				<outline text="Hanging out with JY and Don Park" created="Mon, 25 May 2026 15:35:19 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I've worked with both these guys, &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22JY%20Stervinou%22&quot;&gt;JY Stervinou&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22Don%20Park%22&quot;&gt;Don Park&lt;/a&gt;, for a long time, and now we're in the same sphere again, and it's very useful to be able to tell them about what I'm doing. They understand. It's not over their heads. Refreshing. " created="Mon, 25 May 2026 15:35:38 GMT" image="https://httpproxy.scripting.com/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.scripting.com%2FlaptopImages%2F07%2F21%2FRSSGreenOnWhite.gif"/>
					<outline text="This is happening on Elon Musk's X, but that won't be forever. I want to move the conversation into a new piece of software I'm doing with &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/davewiner/status/2058928393140232681&quot;&gt;Claude Code&lt;/a&gt;. Which is coming along nicely. " created="Mon, 25 May 2026 15:36:21 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Anyway I just &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/davewiner/status/2058914052001116237&quot;&gt;posted this&lt;/a&gt;, and thought it should be here too." created="Mon, 25 May 2026 15:37:34 GMT">
						<outline text="my philosophy is that i'll only use the absolutely necessary formats and protocols." created="Mon, 25 May 2026 15:38:15 GMT"/>
						<outline text="i'll leave experiments with other stuff to other people."/>
						<outline text="the purpose of my project is to show what can be done with just a few bits of tech. that the whole thing is really simple. "/>
						<outline text="RSS 2.0 with rssCloud, OPML, WebSockets, basic web UI stuff. That's about it. "/>
						<outline text="same as FeedLand btw. "/>
						<outline text="i want minimum complexity. a baseline for what can be done with very little."/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="The web can do a lot more than people think without getting too complex. And because it's the web, you can connect anything to anything, you don't need to AT Protoize your code, or ActivityPublish it. Just plain old RSS 2.0 with rssCloud, thank you very much. " created="Mon, 25 May 2026 15:38:41 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&quot;I envision a network of twitter-like systems built out of components of the web and nothing more. Every part replaceable.&quot;" created="Mon, 25 May 2026 15:54:12 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 24" created="Sun, 24 May 2026 14:13:03 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="24">
				<outline text="I asked ChatGPT for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/355&quot;&gt;list of FeedLand features&lt;/a&gt; that are new or distinctive. &quot;FeedLand combines RSS, OPML, public curation, subscribable reading lists, rivers, categories, and realtime WebSocket updates in a way that is unusual among feed readers and points toward a web-native social network.&quot;  " created="Sun, 24 May 2026 17:24:25 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="People who believe in the web, stop dissing &quot;RSS&quot;, it’s an important part of our future." created="Sun, 24 May 2026 15:22:19 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Alexa has a terrible habit, when I ask for a song from the Echo on my desktop, it ends each song with a helpful message. There's a live version of this song, do you want to hear it. You have a message waiting, can I play it for you. I can't get it to stop. I have a bunch of them scattered around the house, and this is the only one that does it. I'm writing here, I asked for a song that fit in with my writing. Stop making me thinkg about your marketing messages. Where did you get the idea you can do this. A paying customer. " created="Sun, 24 May 2026 15:22:32 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Love: I ask Claude for a list of names and values, it responds quickly with exactly what I asked for. Nothing more. Unconsciously I say &quot;perfect&quot; -- out loud. " created="Sun, 24 May 2026 14:28:37 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I have a Mac laptop that I keep updated with the latest versions of Mac OS. I got a warning today saying that &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22Electric%20Drummer%22&quot;&gt;Electric Drummer&lt;/a&gt; won't run on the next release of the OS. Now I don't use it very much if at all on that machine, but I wonder. ED is an Electron app, otherwise it's wholly JavaScript. It does include some Node packages of course, but not that many IIRC. This was a thing I wasn't expecting. " created="Sun, 24 May 2026 14:13:04 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 23" created="Sat, 23 May 2026 13:33:38 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="23">
				<outline text="I archived &lt;a href=&quot;https://this.how/priorArt/&quot;&gt;prior art as a design method&lt;/a&gt; from 2003 on this.how." created="Sat, 23 May 2026 14:52:35 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I just tried the &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/davewiner/status/2058231108764897694&quot;&gt;latest version&lt;/a&gt; of the X editor. It's got all the features of &lt;a href=&quot;https://textcasting.org/&quot;&gt;textcasting&lt;/a&gt;. I wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/davewiner/status/2058231108764897694&quot;&gt;test post&lt;/a&gt; entitled &quot;X has nuked the limits, time for Bluesky to follow suit.&quot; I think you can tell I had fun writing it. They don't think anyone hears me, but I think they're wrong about that. The idea that they are part of the web is ludicrous. They're going to get called on it eventually. They should &lt;a href=&quot;https://textcasting.org/&quot;&gt;fix it&lt;/a&gt; so they are part of the web. Then we can all create. Or if you're not going to be part of the web, for crying out loud stop saying that you do. " created="Sat, 23 May 2026 17:06:20 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="One of the benefits of using Claude for all my coding is I'm now finding out what various things I do as standard practice are called in the outside world. Today I learned what agile is. I of course have heard it used, and even got to know the guy who coined the term. " created="Sat, 23 May 2026 16:17:32 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="There probably is a name for this development practice. Only works on a team with more two developers. At some point in a project after you've been working on Level N in the stack, you may decide you've done all you can there, and it's time for someone else to work at that level. The new person, Smith, is a maintainer, develops in small increments, fixes bugs and most important takes feature requests from the other developer, Jones, who is now creating Level N + 1. Jones is a good person to do this because they know everything about the capabilities of the lower level. But now they're going to pretend they've forgotten all that, and is looking at a whole new machine, created out of the new capabilities of Level N. That's how you build any complex layered piece of software. And because this is the method used in boostraps, you can build level N+1 using tools written in N. " created="Sat, 23 May 2026 13:33:39 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="It's really simple" created="Sat, 23 May 2026 13:56:04 GMT" type="outline" description="We already have everything we need for Bluesky and WordPress to peer with each other.">
					<outline text="My recommendation for &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/pfefferle.org/post/3mmh6zmfkrs2r&quot;&gt;Automattic&lt;/a&gt; and Bluesky." created="Sat, 23 May 2026 13:56:13 GMT" flBulletedSubs="true">
						<outline text="Bluesky supports RSS 2.0 inbound and outbound." created="Sat, 23 May 2026 13:56:23 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Bluesky eliminates its character limit, allows bold, italic styles. Links. Optional titles. Users can edit their posts. More &lt;a href=&quot;https://textcasting.org/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sat, 23 May 2026 13:56:34 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="Automattic already fully supports RSS 2.0 in both directions, in all their products." created="Sat, 23 May 2026 13:56:38 GMT"/>
					<outline text="This gives us the most interop with the most respect for &lt;a href=&quot;http://essaysfromexodus.scripting.com/priorArtDesignMethod&quot;&gt;prior art&lt;/a&gt;. No need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/pfefferle.org/post/3mmh6zmfkrs2r&quot;&gt;reinvent&lt;/a&gt;. There's nothing special about Bluesky, they can use what we've all been using for 20+ years. " created="Sat, 23 May 2026 13:56:38 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It's really very simple, let's hook everything together and let the users and developers create." created="Sat, 23 May 2026 14:56:47 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 22" created="Fri, 22 May 2026 13:07:13 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="22">
				<outline text="Another way to look at Claude Code. It's a way to talk to your code, to ask it questions, and tell it how you want it to change. " created="Fri, 22 May 2026 16:00:29 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I think maybe it's time to consider a reboot of WordPress. I can't seem to seed them with any ideas about building on it from the point of view of the web. It's a product unto itself, it has plugins, but I'm not a plug-in sort of guy. I write operating systems. That's what drives me. I see a great place to put an OS with WordPress as the storage and publishing component, and everything else grows up around it. It's one of those famous &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22coral%20reef%22&quot;&gt;coral reefs&lt;/a&gt; but it hasn't been born yet. The idea would not be to compete with WordPress, it's to make something that fits into our view of the world, that just happens to be the same codebase. And when on the other side they think they have to do it themselves we reach out and say here, just take this over, it's yours. It's so hard to penetrate the awareness inside old organizations with new ideas. I think it's the manifest destiny of WordPress, that what they have now is a nice revenue generating machine, but it's not serving as the web's writing base, which is what imho it was supposed to be. (And I have a bit of standing there, btw.)" created="Fri, 22 May 2026 15:32:42 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I have news for you -- Claude forgets important stuff. I catch it forgetting to do things it was &quot;programmed&quot; to do. It's not a computer, it's not garbage in garbage out. It could be good stuff in garbage out. As I've said before there's a big chunk of the app I'm working on where I don't read code. User interface stuff only. No control of what comes in our out. Trying to not take any chances here.  " created="Fri, 22 May 2026 15:28:41 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="This is a multi-billion dollar idea. I want to link to &quot;report-up&quot; concept in something I'm writing. There is no Wikipedia page for that but there is a brief explainer in Google, via their AI. Here's the feature: add a permalink to that response. I'm lazy and will link to it in my writing." created="Fri, 22 May 2026 14:51:47 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, I don't think the web was created to make people rich. " created="Fri, 22 May 2026 16:43:04 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Does it ever cross anyone's mind that according to the rules of war, Iran would be totally justified in attacking the United States?" created="Fri, 22 May 2026 14:17:05 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/johnspurlock.com/post/3mmgxpg4p522o&quot;&gt;Vibe-coded software&lt;/a&gt; will have a place where users can communicate what they want to developers who can help make it real. The same way you might get medical info from an AI, but would still get your colonoscopy from an actual doctor. Part of the origin story of podcasting is that Adam hacked up a version of Frontier to illustrate what he had in mind for the &quot;last yard&quot; protocol. When I looked at the code it was horrible, hard to believe someone thought of doing it that way. But it got the point across, and that's the moment the podcasting boostrap began. I love using the AIs to tell a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/1610208569758308/posts/1610542926391539&quot;&gt;visual story&lt;/a&gt;, a skill I never had or developed. No reason it can't work the same way for software.  " created="Fri, 22 May 2026 13:26:15 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/22/mySadDepressedProgrammerFriend.png"/>
				<outline text="Finding the Microsoft video" created="Fri, 22 May 2026 13:07:14 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="In yesterday's &lt;a href=&quot;https://shownotes.scripting.com/scripting/2026/05/21/wrappingAiInTheWeb.html&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; I mentioned a Microsoft promotional video from the 90s. JY Stervinou on Twitter asked if he had found it, and it was close but it was the video I was talking about. So I checked in with Claude with this prompt." created="Fri, 22 May 2026 13:07:24 GMT">
						<outline text="there was a microsoft promotional video in the 90s featuring bill gates and steve ballmer riding up front in a car, it's a ripoff of a volkswagon commercial, the music is catchy song Da Da Da. they drive around and then see a Sun Microsystems computer, they pick it up but it smells bad (apparently) and they drop it off in someone's garbage. i can't find the video on the web, can you?" created="Fri, 22 May 2026 13:08:19 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="It found a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QtrmeorJdfc&quot;&gt;low rez version&lt;/a&gt; of the video on YouTube, with a comment." created="Fri, 22 May 2026 13:09:10 GMT">
						<outline text="It's a spoof of the 1997 Volkswagen Golf commercial, with Ballmer and Gates driving a Golf, picking up a Sun workstation and later rejecting it. The &quot;Da Da Da&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lNYcviXK4rg&quot;&gt;track&lt;/a&gt; is by the German band Trio. One source describes the dropped computer as an old IBM rather than Sun, so accounts differ on that detail, but the Know Your Meme &lt;a href=&quot;https://knowyourmeme.com/videos/118320-microsoft&quot;&gt;listing&lt;/a&gt; specifically says Sun workstation, matching what you remember." created="Fri, 22 May 2026 13:10:05 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="Here's the low-rez video at 1/4 size." created="Fri, 22 May 2026 13:22:50 GMT">
						<outline text="&lt;iframe width=&quot;280&quot; height=&quot;157&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QtrmeorJdfc?si=qxnm9K_fmqRiQIZi&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;" created="Fri, 22 May 2026 13:13:49 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="The computer in the video I saw was definitely a Sun workstation. It wouldn't make much sense for it to be an IBM in 1997, Microsoft had already passed over IBM, they were in the middle of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22Java%20Wars%22&quot;&gt;Java Wars&lt;/a&gt; with Sun, and there even is a Sun response to the Microsoft video with two actors playing Gates and Ballmer, and in the end Sun CEO Scott McNealy shows up, after (it turns out) Gates smells and the Sun terminal is still in the back seat and users and developers are still nowhere in sight." created="Fri, 22 May 2026 13:10:25 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I imagine there are a few old time Microsoft people still following this blog, if anyone has a decent resolution version of the Da Da Da video, I'd love to get a good version on the web of 2026." created="Fri, 22 May 2026 13:11:46 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 21" created="Thu, 21 May 2026 13:52:03 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="21">
				<outline text="Podcast: &lt;a href=&quot;https://shownotes.scripting.com/scripting/2026/05/21/wrappingAiInTheWeb.html&quot;&gt;Wrapping AI in the web&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 21 May 2026 21:08:20 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Just finished &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/No_Country_for_Old_Men_(novel)&quot;&gt;No Country for Old Men&lt;/a&gt;, the book by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cormac_McCarthy&quot;&gt;Cormac McCarthy&lt;/a&gt;. I have seen the movie many times, it's one of those movies that if you're looking for something to watch and you come across it, you might as well go for it because every scene in the movie is pretty good on its own. I didn't realize that they used most of McCarthy's dialog, literally -- in the movie. Near the end, Bell, the sheriff tells a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/11755896-i-agreed-with-him-that-there-wasnt-a-whole-lot&quot;&gt;story&lt;/a&gt; about old age. &quot;There wasnt a whole lot good you could say about old age and he said he knew one thing and I said what is that. And he said it dont last long. I said well, that's pretty cold. And he said it was no colder than what the facts called for.&quot; I love truths that hit hard. He's such a great writer. And I love that I can write like all the characters if I get a mind to. " created="Thu, 21 May 2026 20:23:36 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/21/nocountryforoldmen.png"/>
				<outline text="I'm going to release the Claude-generated code that enables it to work with me on projects that are written and managed in outlines." created="Thu, 21 May 2026 14:31:33 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Just asked Claude to save this in memory. &quot;in general i create local variables with partial results because 1. i can step through the calculations in the debugger. 2. the order guides my mind when im reading this code, 3. it lets me put a name on a partial value. this is helpful when i want to piece together wtf the code is supposed to be doing. and 4. it makes no difference in the efficiency of the code for a variety of reasons. please save that somewhere.&quot; i'm getting a lot of these rules down. i have them memorized but have never written them up because i didn't have a system for saving it somewhere relevant. i always thought ai would be good for going back and reading all my blog posts and creating somethjing readable, but as often is the case, the way it works turned out to be quite different, accomplishes the same thing. " created="Thu, 21 May 2026 13:52:04 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Marc Andreessen &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/ArtificialNtelligence/comments/1tirqp2/marc_andreessen_on_jre_ai_hasnt_replaced_coders/&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; programmers aren't disoccupied, we haven't become obsolete, quite the opposite, we're all working around the clock. It's true. Everyone is doing it. We got a &lt;b&gt;new brain&lt;/b&gt; that can do all kinds of amazing things. You don't get a new super powerful brain organ every day. " created="Thu, 21 May 2026 16:09:22 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 20" created="Wed, 20 May 2026 12:39:13 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="20">
				<outline text="Saying Bluesky is part of the web is like saying Spotify or YouTube own podcasting. They say it, but that doesn't mean it's true.  " created="Wed, 20 May 2026 19:11:55 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I couldn't not say anything about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbssports.com/nba/news/knicks-cavaliers-comeback-jalen-brunson-james-harden-nba-playoffs-ecf-game-1/&quot;&gt;the Knicks win&lt;/a&gt; last night in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nypost.com/2026/05/19/sports/knicks-mount-furious-rally-to-beat-cavaliers-in-thrilling-game-1-win/&quot;&gt;opening game&lt;/a&gt; of the NBA Eastern Conference finals. The Knicks were losing, then winning big, then fell apart, and by midway through the 4th quarter they were down by 22, and the Clevelands were completely in charge. But then the Knicks came back, miraculously tied the game so it went into overtime where the Knicks dominated, and won. Actually it wasn't really a miracle, it was somewhat predictable. The Knicks were playing on a lot of rest, and one of the big advantages they have this year over last is a deep and strong bench and a coach who plays them (last year's coach didn't). So the Knicks didn't get tired and the Cavs were wiped out by the 4th quarter. Their shots weren't long or short, aimed, they had no flow, they weren't getting rebounds, they didn't have good ball movement. While Brunson was driving the Knicks the Cavs just weren't there. When things started turning around in the 4th I was pretty sure the Knicks would win. I had no basis for believing this, coming back from 22 down so late in the game is pretty unlikely. In most cities that's when the fans start heading home, but not in NYC. We stay till the end because sometimes, maybe often with this years' Knicks, the team you think is going to lose actually ends up winning. " created="Wed, 20 May 2026 12:39:14 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/20/brunson.png"/>
				<outline text="I've been following &lt;a href=&quot;https://jakesav.in/2026/05/20/rebooting-frontier/&quot;&gt;Jake's work&lt;/a&gt; privately, but now he's blogging about it publicly. I totally look forward to running Frontier on today's hardware. I especially want to run Manila on one of my home computers, and use it for Linux server apps. I've forgotten so much about how Manila works, but I expect it'll all come back. We had a great team back in the Manila days -- we all used the product, and it was and will be again one of the most powerful and pragmatic programming environments ever." created="Wed, 20 May 2026 18:51:29 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Claude Code doesn't know about &quot;user perspective,&quot; but it learns quickly. The UI of the software we're working on is fenced off, I use it, but I don't read code in there. I don't want to know how it works, I want to use it and getting right. This is an important technique. Later once things are locked down, I don't mind learning more about how it was done." created="Wed, 20 May 2026 14:14:04 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 19" created="Tue, 19 May 2026 11:49:42 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="19">
				<outline text="Markdown support is a big feature for people who want to know what we're doing with their text. " created="Tue, 19 May 2026 17:19:55 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Opus 4.6 is much smarter than the other one. It feels like I'm working with someone from &lt;a href=&quot;https://bxscience.edu/&quot;&gt;Bronx Science&lt;/a&gt;. I had been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anthropic.com/news/claude-sonnet-4-6&quot;&gt;Sonnet 4.6&lt;/a&gt;, which I switched to after reading somewhere that it costs less and it's usually every bit as good as newer models. I would never work with Sonnet on anything again, it's like working with a partner who is both stupid &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dunning%E2%80%93Kruger_effect&quot;&gt;and&lt;/a&gt; difficult. Opus 4.6 makes me smarter, by doing the work while I dream up new features, and communicating with intelligence, like a helpful flight assistant. And I see there's an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anthropic.com/news/claude-opus-4-7&quot;&gt;Opus 4.7&lt;/a&gt; available. I have to try it. One interesting fact, until February &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anthropic.com/news/claude-opus-4-6&quot;&gt;when&lt;/a&gt; Opus 4.6 came out, you could not have done the kind of software I'm doing. There must be a tsunami of interesting stuff on the way. I don't think any of the pundits expect this. My goal is to build the next social system for use in the AI generation is built out of replaceable web components buit around interop and prior art. Let's commoditize the AI layer and build entirely open systems on top of it. For people who weren't around at the birth of the personal computer or the web this is going to be a unique multiple mindbomb moment." created="Tue, 19 May 2026 11:49:43 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/19/reallySimpleNet.png"/>
				<outline text="Someday you're going to tell your kids that we once used a social network that limited your writing to 500 characters and didn't allow styling, links or titles. What was it called Daddy? Bluesky. And people thought it was great. Why? They might have been taking drugs. " created="Tue, 19 May 2026 12:33:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 18" created="Mon, 18 May 2026 14:18:17 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="18">
				<outline text="The Mind of Claude" created="Mon, 18 May 2026 16:45:38 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I have taught Claude Code to write software the way I do." created="Mon, 18 May 2026 16:45:40 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It has abilities that I don't, for example, I give them 1000 lines of code, highly factored, with lots of thought into making it readable and maintainable, and always falling short (our languages today fight against readability imho), and get this -- it can read different parts of the same code in parallel, and in two or three seconds have a complete understanding of it. " created="Mon, 18 May 2026 16:46:00 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I couldn't do it even if I had a week. I would totally depend on clues left there. "/>
					<outline text="What's even more amazing is that when it writes code for me, it does it my way, mostly without any prompting from me. This was done over and over until I realized I had to tell it to save it and read it when a new session starts. That's how it accumulates knowledge. Anything that isn't in one of those files has to be relearned, and that's most of what it, as a code-writing system, has to work with. It has no &quot;memory&quot; of ever having seen this stuff before, but that isn't a problem because it can accumulate a few years of understanding in two or three seconds. It works very diffrently from the way we work. If I were to show you how to do something three times that would be it, not so with Claude. " created="Mon, 18 May 2026 16:46:38 GMT"/>
					<outline text="When it doesn't know what to do, I take the time to explain how I would have done it, and next time it does it that way. " created="Mon, 18 May 2026 16:48:46 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I kind of did the same thing in a human way -- when I first encountered Unix, I couldn't believe from reading the source code, how transparent it was. That was in the 70s. Since then I have been striving to write code that's as easy to work on. When it comes to realtime software, there isn't really a choice. Though history piles up in the code no matter how diligent you are. But you could give the source to say MySQL to Claude Code, and say &quot;rewrite this as if Dave Winer wrote it&quot; and it probably would do a decent job, though it might take a while before it ran every MySQL app." created="Mon, 18 May 2026 16:49:00 GMT"/>
					<outline text="If you're looking for good investments, I'd say look for programming problems that are very complicated. We are limited by what we can create by how much we can maintain. But we can have Claude explain for us any time what any of our code means. It can read my mind because I put the work of my mind in the memory of the computer. Which effectively is the Mind of Claude. " created="Mon, 18 May 2026 16:49:28 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PS: Claude has a huge advantage over ChatGPT. Claude is one syllable and easy to remember. ChatGPT is four syllables, and has no discernable meaning. Claude is a person, and I think in general people named Claude are interesting. " created="Mon, 18 May 2026 16:50:48 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="2024-era ChatGPT pictures, of which I created &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22wordle%20kitty%22&quot;&gt;many&lt;/a&gt; are now like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comic_Sans#Misuse&quot;&gt;Comic Sans&lt;/a&gt; type was in &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20100710014850/http://www.nba.com/cavaliers/news/gilbert_letter_100708.html&quot;&gt;2010&lt;/a&gt; or so, if you remember. " created="Mon, 18 May 2026 14:18:18 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 17" created="Sun, 17 May 2026 13:59:21 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="17">
				<outline text="I envision a network of twitter-like systems built out of the components of the web and nothing more. Every part replaceable." created="Sun, 17 May 2026 13:59:22 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Today Claude found a problem that would only be uncovered if you knew that assigning to location.href didn't happen immediately. If it decides to redirect and then do a bunch of other stuff including making network references, the whole thing could (and did) come crashing down. I would have found that problem, but the actual error message the browser emitted made me think the problem was on the server not the client. The most complicated code in an app is the stuff it runs at startup when it's constructing the world of all its different pieces creating the virtuality expected by the great mass of code. It's the part that once it's working you don't even want to look at it and if you decide to rewrite it you might as well start over, only slightly exaggerating. " created="Sun, 17 May 2026 16:19:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/shorts/oNF8g-2NfuM&quot;&gt;Timothy Snyder&lt;/a&gt; made an important point. Trump sees his cause as a religion and sees himself as god. So when someone who is unfairly punished by Trump says they're still glad they voted for him, because (I guess) if god is on the ballot, you have to vote for him. " created="Sun, 17 May 2026 14:17:38 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Jon Stewart is usually pretty good, but I think he got it wrong when he says the AI companies are stealing journalists' knowledge. Imho they don't create knowledge, they report it. The knowledge isn't theirs to own, and that is for the times there is actually any new stuff. They stick to a few main stories, and still insist that the upcoming election is about the economy. They talk about the $1.7 billion slush fund, but aren't reporting every day in every story how much money we've given ICE. That big funding is going to the concentration camps they're building, the people the incarcerate  we hear so little of. This is a government that shot two people in Minnesota, on camera, and shrugged it off. Imagine what horrors are going on out of site in the camps. " created="Sun, 17 May 2026 21:07:05 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 16" created="Sat, 16 May 2026 15:01:54 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="16">
				<outline text="I &lt;a href=&quot;https://source.scripting.com/#1778941955000&quot;&gt;documented&lt;/a&gt; the optional &lt;i&gt;source:inReplyTo&lt;/i&gt; element for RSS 2.0." created="Sat, 16 May 2026 15:01:55 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="i stopped looking for the weird problem" created="Sat, 16 May 2026 22:36:08 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="i'd wait till a fresh start tomorrow." created="Sat, 16 May 2026 22:39:24 GMT"/>
					<outline text="but then i realized claude has all the code, so i could just tell it my problem." created="Sat, 16 May 2026 22:36:21 GMT"/>
					<outline text="can you find it, i asked, realizing i had not given it info on what the problem is. " created="Sat, 16 May 2026 22:39:37 GMT"/>
					<outline text="there's a very weird mistake in the code i wrote just now, and there was a lot of it, i said to claude." created="Sat, 16 May 2026 22:36:37 GMT"/>
					<outline text="can you find the problem. " created="Sat, 16 May 2026 22:36:53 GMT"/>
					<outline text="had no idea what to expect." created="Sat, 16 May 2026 22:40:18 GMT"/>
					<outline text="no more than 3 seconds it said I got it!" created="Sat, 16 May 2026 22:40:14 GMT"/>
					<outline text="it was a typo. &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/16/threeseconds.png&quot;&gt;where&lt;/a&gt; i meant to type x i had typed prefs." created="Sat, 16 May 2026 22:37:08 GMT"/>
					<outline text="juggling a lot of bits in my head, my brain skipped, i didn't notice." created="Sat, 16 May 2026 22:37:24 GMT"/>
					<outline text="i &lt;i&gt;would&lt;/i&gt; have found it quickly in my next session. but now i can think of anything but that problem until then. " created="Sat, 16 May 2026 22:37:42 GMT"/>
					<outline text="sometimes claude can be totally frustrating, but other times the power makes such a huge difference. " created="Sat, 16 May 2026 22:37:59 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 15" created="Fri, 15 May 2026 15:44:38 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="15">
				<outline text="I wish they had an outliner in Claude. I would use it. ;-)" created="Fri, 15 May 2026 16:02:23 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, here's the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jsonldemo.feedland.org/scripting.jsonl&quot;&gt;JSONL version&lt;/a&gt; of Scripting News. It has the same data as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/&quot;&gt;RSS file&lt;/a&gt;, but in the format that AI apps are looking for, so I am told. I thought I'd try to kick this off by pushing an RSS flow through the pipe. It's like using the Grateful Dead to boot up podcasting. I needed something to put out on the wire and I had this feed handy." created="Fri, 15 May 2026 16:12:34 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Thinking about adding &amp;lt;source:inReplyTo&gt; to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://source.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;source namespace&lt;/a&gt;. Its value is a URL, by default, and has an optional isPermaLink attribute, a boolean, to indicate if it's not a permalink. Works just like the guid element in &lt;a href=&quot;https://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html#ltguidgtSubelementOfLtitemgt&quot;&gt;RSS 2.0&lt;/a&gt;. I will also add support for that in the FeedLand database, and flow it out through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedlandSocket&quot;&gt;socket interface&lt;/a&gt;. Actually that's pretty close to a full spec, at least in rss.land where we take simplicity seriously. ;-)" created="Fri, 15 May 2026 16:02:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Dave's vibe coding amusement park" created="Fri, 15 May 2026 15:44:39 GMT" type="outline" description="I never dreamed I could program this way.">
					<outline text="I reached a point in my Claude work where now I can do vibe coding, in a world that I used to just be a programmer in. This means if I want to do a heavy lift, I can tell Claude what I want and it can do really big corner turns, which is something I am (as a human) terrible at, and thus resist. Today I redesigned the basic user interface of the app, and didn't read any code, I was just giving orders, and it was doing what I asked, even if every little thing it did would have been a full day's work. It's remarkable how it can do very complex things in a few seconds. " created="Fri, 15 May 2026 15:46:44 GMT" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/03/26/rssKetchup.png"/>
					<outline text="And the web framework i'm working on can do almost all the things I want to do for now, but I want to suck everything into it, and turn the whole thing into a vibe coding amusement park. So many projects I want to do, and so many I want to do with &lt;i&gt;you.&lt;/i&gt; " created="Fri, 15 May 2026 15:46:52 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 14" created="Thu, 14 May 2026 14:55:23 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="14">
				<outline text="Every social web needs avatars. In an RSS 2.0 feed look for the channel-level &lt;a href=&quot;https://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html#ltimagegtSubelementOfLtchannelgt&quot;&gt;image element&lt;/a&gt;. It's &lt;a href=&quot;https://scripting4.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/cropped-jello.png?w=32&quot;&gt;how&lt;/a&gt; they do it &lt;a href=&quot;https://scripting4.wordpress.com/feed/&quot;&gt;in WordPress&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 14 May 2026 15:09:19 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I have Claude Code hooked up to Chrome. It's crawling around inside the DOM of the running system, like humans do in a debugger. It's a bit like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fantastic_Voyage&quot;&gt;Fantastic Voyage&lt;/a&gt; if you've ever seen it. I've been waiting for this moment. Now we can do some really nice UI work. " created="Thu, 14 May 2026 21:42:51 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="This is the first day since the NBA playoffs started that there is no scheduled game. I think that's why today feels so weird. " created="Thu, 14 May 2026 15:35:07 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="For some reason every day feels like Saturday. I don't know why." created="Thu, 14 May 2026 15:36:41 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 13" created="Wed, 13 May 2026 13:45:11 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="13">
				<outline text="I appreciate that X gave me back access to &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/davewiner&quot;&gt;my account&lt;/a&gt; that I was locked out of, but they were apparently charging me for Premium when I couldn't use the account, and had no way to turn it off. Okay they can keep the money. But now I want to turn off Premium for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/bullmancuso&quot;&gt;account&lt;/a&gt; I was using when I didn't have access to my real account, and can't find the commands to do that. Asked ChatGPT and it either hallucinated or X removed the command. So near as I can tell I now have two accounts on X that I'm paying $8 a month for Premium on.  " created="Wed, 13 May 2026 14:24:27 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/13/noSoupForYou.png"/>
				<outline text="I'm screwing around with the JSONL stuff again. I'm interested in know about any work people have done that process incoming JSONL data. I'd like to see if I'm even in the ballpark of something useful. Today I'm making it so that my app can be used in production to handle more than one stream. The key thing is it's hooked up to FeedLand via a very simple JSON interface delivered in realtime via websockets. For feeds that support rssCloud, the appearance of the new item in the JSONL feed happens a fraction of a second after it was published. That's how fast the web of 2026 is.  " created="Wed, 13 May 2026 13:45:12 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 12" created="Tue, 12 May 2026 13:00:29 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="12">
				<outline text="I have regained control of &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/davewiner/status/2054319383879541013&quot;&gt;my Twitter account&lt;/a&gt;. I really missed it, truth be told. Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=scoble&quot;&gt;Scoble&lt;/a&gt; for helping here. As he so often has. " created="Tue, 12 May 2026 22:06:15 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="This bit of code &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/scripting/b3c361f25d6d2fb9a872082c8fd30439&quot;&gt;kept coming up&lt;/a&gt;, so I wanted to make it easier to find. " created="Tue, 12 May 2026 21:28:49 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Expanding items on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogroll.social/&quot;&gt;FeedLand blogroll&lt;/a&gt; should be consistently fast now. Just switched to a different server on the backend. " created="Tue, 12 May 2026 16:20:52 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@davew/116562171197162240&quot;&gt;Masto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/bullmancuso/status/2054214057205395696&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;: I'd like to come up with a list of formats, protocols and products that have become defaults for AI work.  " created="Tue, 12 May 2026 14:53:39 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2026/05/11/144453.html&quot;&gt;Yesterday&lt;/a&gt; I learned about JSONL, and was of course intrigued. It's a really simple thing, even simpler than &quot;RSS&quot;, and does basically the same thing. And even better, it's the way the AI industry hooks streams together. So If we can get RSS to serve as a source of JSONL feeds, it's possible that the AI industry will find it useful. My goal is to get every standard of the web hooked up to AI, quickly, before the silos realize they're leaving out something important. Once they figure it out, they'll have no choice but to add real RSS support. So I put together a quick demo app that hooks into &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedlandSocket&quot;&gt;FeedLand&lt;/a&gt; and posts to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jsonldemo.feedland.org/items.jsonl&quot;&gt;JSONL feed&lt;/a&gt; new items from one of a small set of feeds I chose basically at random. And here is &lt;a href=&quot;https://jsonldemo.feedland.org/items.jsonl&quot;&gt;the JSONL feed&lt;/a&gt;. If you're a developer in AI-land could you try reading this into your JSONL-ingesting app, and let me know if I got it right. Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/354&quot;&gt;place to comment&lt;/a&gt;. BTW, that URL is temporary just for this quick demo. " created="Tue, 12 May 2026 13:01:50 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/03/26/loveRss.png"/>
				<outline text="Good morning sports fans!" created="Tue, 12 May 2026 13:00:30 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 11" created="Mon, 11 May 2026 13:14:32 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="11">
				<outline text="Members of the WordPress community. Monday morning is a good time to check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://wp.feedland.org/&quot;&gt;WordPress News&lt;/a&gt; via FeedLand at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wp.feedland.org/&quot;&gt;wp.feedland.org&lt;/a&gt;. You can also subscribe to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.social/opml?screenname=davewiner&amp;catname=wordpress&quot;&gt;list of feeds&lt;/a&gt; this site follows in your own feed reader, and if you have a WordPress news site, please post the URL &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/353&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; so we can send readers to &lt;i&gt;your blog&lt;/i&gt; too. I think there are a lot of would-be bloggers out there that need a slight kick in the pants to get going. I'm happy to provide readers if you provide the ideas. There's a lot of power in WordPress that no one knows about. Let's help other users and developers find the good stuff. If you have questions or suggestions, here's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/353&quot;&gt;new thread on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Mon, 11 May 2026 13:14:33 GMT" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/03/23/blogrollMan.png" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="It would be great if &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/347#issuecomment-3651465931&quot;&gt;Beeper supported RSS&lt;/a&gt; in and out. It would help encourage other messaging services to do the same, and all of a sudden we'd have lots of easy interop instead of lots of really iffy interop. If they want to do it, I'd help, for free. Just to help things flow better on the messaging web, because we reallllly need help there. " created="Mon, 11 May 2026 13:17:33 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Realtime Claude still evading me!" created="Mon, 11 May 2026 14:44:53 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="A while back I was asking Claude (privately) if we could have it monitoring the messages posted to an app I'm working on. I wanted it to save them in a certain way, have it watch for messages that begin with //claude and maybe act on them somehow. I mostly just wanted to see if I could create a pipe and what its limits would be. " created="Mon, 11 May 2026 14:31:17 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="I asked what the max frequency is and was told it was 1 minute, meaning it would start a thread running Claude that would initialize, and it would read the file, and if there were any new items, it would process them, and then it would shut down. Barely enough to be useful, where we live we like notification within a second, but I went ahead, at least it'll be a thought-provoking demo. " created="Mon, 11 May 2026 14:45:51 GMT"/>
					<outline text="So I wrote the software. Not much to it, a Node app that's hooked up to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedlandSocket&quot;&gt;FeedlandSocket&lt;/a&gt;, and when it sees a message from me, it appends it to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jsonlines.org/&quot;&gt;JSONL&lt;/a&gt; file that Claude is watching. At most one minute later it wakes up and sees the new stuff and acts on it." created="Mon, 11 May 2026 14:46:09 GMT"/>
					<outline text="So I'm right there, it's all working, the JSONL file is being saved in a public place, and when I ask it to start listening to my JSONL messages I learn that the max frequency is &lt;i&gt;one hour,&lt;/i&gt; rendering my work useless. This has happened before, btw. " created="Mon, 11 May 2026 14:46:47 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I asked what about all the &quot;agentic&quot; stuff they hype so much, how do I do that?? I can't?? What?? Somehow I have trouble believing they're &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; telling such a big lie. I wonder if Claude understands its own architecture. " created="Mon, 11 May 2026 14:47:36 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Dave: &quot;What is all this hype about agentic stuff. Every time I try to do something I hit a wall like this.&quot;" created="Mon, 11 May 2026 14:49:29 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Claude: &quot;The pitch is 'agents that run on their own'; the reality you just hit is a one-hour floor on the only scheduling path the tooling actually exposes. That's not agency, that's a batch job with extra steps. The honest read: the cloud-side scheduler is built around long-running, infrequent tasks (digest emails, nightly reports) because each run spins up a fresh sandboxed session, which is expensive. Anything that wants to react quickly to a stream of incoming items -- which is what your app actually is -- doesn't fit that model. A plain local cron on some server running every minute would do the job today and cost nothing.&quot;" created="Mon, 11 May 2026 14:49:37 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I edited Claude's response so as not to not reveal code names for products. ;-)" created="Mon, 11 May 2026 14:49:29 GMT"/>
					<outline text="A silver lining -- I had never heard of &lt;a href=&quot;https://jsonlines.org/&quot;&gt;JSONL&lt;/a&gt;, but it sounds pretty useful, so if I can't hook up to Claude realtime, now -- I can start using JSONL, which I wll. " created="Mon, 11 May 2026 14:56:11 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Comments, stories, suggestions -- &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/354&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 11 May 2026 15:07:58 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 10" created="Sun, 10 May 2026 13:18:17 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="10">
				<outline text="I have to say something about the Knicks, who just blew out the Sixers in a sweep, 4 games to zero. They've never played this well. They are more than a deep team of great athletes, they are highly intelligent people and they're all really working together. Right now, it feels like a sure thing that they'll breeze through the next round and face off OKC or San Antonio in the finals, and that will be something. But I know that's not the right way to look at it. The next series is going to be with a team that feels the title is theirs as much as the Knicks do. I've been with the Knicks through the worst of times that never seemed to end. And now for something &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cOTQb1A5D2M&quot;&gt;completely different&lt;/a&gt;.  " created="Sun, 10 May 2026 23:37:25 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/10/andNowForSomethingCompletelyDifferent.png"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/leaflet.pub&quot;&gt;Leaflet&lt;/a&gt; is a nice editor designed to work with Bluesky. But they've been branching out. They now support email and RSS output. They're going in the right direction, toward the internet with the email, and toward the web with the RSS support. As nice as Bluesky is, it's a small part of the web, and it isn't as open as it might appear to be, imho.  " created="Sun, 10 May 2026 15:31:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Routing around the algorithms" created="Sun, 10 May 2026 13:31:15 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/resistrebelrevolt.net/post/3mlfl42lqq22y&quot;&gt;AOC in an interview&lt;/a&gt; nailed &lt;i&gt;everything&lt;/i&gt; in one brief answer to a question from the audience. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/resistrebelrevolt.net/post/3mlfl42lqq22y&quot;&gt;watch it here&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sun, 10 May 2026 13:31:27 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It was so good and quotable that I recorded it and created a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2026/05/10/133115.html#a134757&quot;&gt;transcript&lt;/a&gt; via Google and Claude. " created="Sun, 10 May 2026 13:31:49 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I've been emailing with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Josh_Marshall&quot;&gt;Josh Marshall&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?river=https%3A%2F%2Ftalkingpointsmemo.com%2Ffeed&quot;&gt;TPM&lt;/a&gt; for the last few weeks, saying that we can't just keep building on what the tech industy has given us as a news distribution system. AOC touches on this in her answer -- she says the tech people control the algorithms, and they do. But the web doesn't have algorithms, and we have enough standards available to create a very good network that isn't owned by anyone. " created="Sun, 10 May 2026 13:32:03 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I was at one time motivated by money, the same way politicians are motivated to attain higher office, but I had an impulsive idea when the web popped up that I am not doing it for money anymore. I'm doing it so we can change our political and work communication so it gives power to the people, not to the tech industry. At that time we were already dealing with the excesses of tech, I knew it well because I was an an insider. " created="Sun, 10 May 2026 13:33:43 GMT"/>
					<outline text="They are welcome to make products for it, but they can't control the users. That's what I envisioned in the 90s and 00s. The ads won't be as important as what people say, because the price of using the web is very low. But we got snookered anyway. The VCs were &lt;i&gt;only&lt;/i&gt; motivated by money, and to maximize that, they needed maximum control, and they got it. People like being part of big things, and Twitter was and still is big." created="Sun, 10 May 2026 18:04:51 GMT"/>
					<outline text="We're now at the next turning point. AI is creating new pathways for ideas to flow. It's all wide open right now, more open than it's been in over 20 years. Right now we could put a twitter-like product there that you can set up in a few minutes, run it yourself, and or join one that's run by a friend. And they federate immediately. All based on the open standards of the web. Every component replaceable. No big central thing to be owned. " created="Sun, 10 May 2026 13:35:10 GMT"/>
					<outline text="But Josh, we can't do it without your help. AOC doesn't know us. She probably doesn't think how the web could route around the algorithms. But she, and you &lt;i&gt;should&lt;/i&gt; be thinking about that, and Heather Cox Richardson too, because we can create the people's tool for the change she wants, which is the change I want, and you want too (I read your columns). But we have to work together to make it happen. " created="Sun, 10 May 2026 13:36:52 GMT"/>
					<outline text="BTW, all politicians should swear by what she says. And we should never care about polls. We should only care about results. " created="Sun, 10 May 2026 13:38:57 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;b&gt;Transcript of AOC's answer&lt;/b&gt;" created="Sun, 10 May 2026 13:47:57 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;i&gt;I recorded the interview, Claude did a light edit of the transcript. I highlighted the part about the algorithms. &lt;/i&gt;" created="Sun, 10 May 2026 13:43:16 GMT"/>
					<outline text="You know, it's funny, because, in this op-ed that Jeff Bezos paid for in the Washington Post, there was this line where you had mentioned earlier about me as a potential 2028 contender, and in the context of that, it was very clear this was a veiled threat, right?" created="Sun, 10 May 2026 13:43:24 GMT"/>
					<outline text="So the elite think: if you want this job, you just stepped out of line. And we want you to know where the real power is. And it's in the &lt;b&gt;modern-day barons who own the Post and own the algorithms&lt;/b&gt;. And we're gonna— we'll make an example out of you." created="Sun, 10 May 2026 13:44:30 GMT"/>
					<outline text="And what's funny about that is that they assume that my ambition is positional. They assume that my ambition is a title or a seat. But my ambition is way bigger than that. My ambition is to change this country."/>
					<outline text="Presidents come and go. Senate and house seat elected officials come and go. But single-payer healthcare's forever. In many ways, it's forever work, right? Forever work is what we should follow, and so anyways, I— the way— but to put a finer point on your question, is that when you aren't attached, right? When you haven't been, like, fantasizing about being this or that since the time you're seven years old, it's a tremendously liberating thing. Because I get to wake up every day and say, how am I going to meet the moment? And conditions change radically all the time. So, I make my response— less out of an attachment to a positional, like, you know, title or position and working backwards from there— but I make decisions by waking up in the morning, looking out the window and observing the conditions of this country and saying, what move or what decision can I make today that's going to get us closer to that future— stronger, faster, better than yesterday?"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 9" created="Sat, 09 May 2026 13:39:45 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="09">
				<outline text="Web to Mastodon makes sense" created="Sat, 09 May 2026 14:24:15 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="A &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2026/05/09/135221.html&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; from Scripting News, automatically mirrored to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://daveverse.org/2026/05/09/having-a-good-bench/&quot;&gt;WordPress site&lt;/a&gt;, and that flowed via ActivityPub to &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@scripting@daveverse.org/116544994475978236&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, via a relatively new feature in WordPress. Almost by accident Mastodon supports long text, styling and links -- even though their editor doesn't generate it, if it comes from the outside it will respect the styling. " created="Sat, 09 May 2026 14:24:56 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Below is a post on Mastodon coming from WordPress. Masto's limits aren't enforced, and that's good. " created="Sat, 09 May 2026 14:34:21 GMT"/>
					<outline text="" created="Sat, 09 May 2026 14:11:33 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/09/knicksStory.png"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="The value of having a good bench" created="Sat, 09 May 2026 13:52:21 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="The Knicks continue to astound. Last night, they went up 3-0 against the Sixers in Philadelphia. Game 4 is tomorrow at 3:30PM Eastern. " created="Sat, 09 May 2026 13:49:40 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="Last night's game was a fantastic contrast with the way the Knicks played in the post-season last year. They had the same starting lineup then, but a different coach, one who rarely put in the bench players unless he had to because of injury. As a result our starters were always playing exhausted, and it got worse as they got deeper into the post-season, until finally in the conference finals against Indiana they had no more gas and were eliminated. This year's Knicks with a deep bench of fantastic players, who the new coach rotates in, makes all the difference. Why? Because the players on the court for the Knicks aren't particularly tired, and if they are, they can get a rest,. " created="Sat, 09 May 2026 13:58:27 GMT"/>
					<outline text="So in the first period the Sixers came out with fury, and they won the first quarter, because both teams were fresh, and maybe the Knicks were onto their problem, and didn't fight too hard to win the first knowing they'd have the big advantage in the second, third and fourth, where the Sixers players legs would be getting wobbly and they were thinking too much about the shots they were taking. " created="Sat, 09 May 2026 13:53:04 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Also worth noting we have a grudge against the Philadelphia team, esp their overwhelmed and dirty-playing big man, Embiid. " created="Sat, 09 May 2026 13:55:10 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The Knicks have a fantastic core team, veterans in their prime, and have been with each other for some since college. They have added to the team incredibly well. Every player coming off the bench has a special power, and it all works. " created="Sat, 09 May 2026 13:55:46 GMT"/>
					<outline text="What's the limit? Unlike many fans I'm not in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Expectation_(philosophy)&quot;&gt;expectations&lt;/a&gt; business. I'm happy to see how well they're playing now, and am prepared for whatever lessons come our way in the rest of the playoffs. " created="Sat, 09 May 2026 13:57:14 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Performance work on FeedLand" created="Sat, 09 May 2026 13:43:01 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Just spent a couple of days working with FeedLand in Claude Code. I want to do some work on features, but first, we're looking at performance issues. There had been a longtime problem with categories that didn't have many feeds that were viewed through the news pages. Examples, the podcasts category, or the NYT category. " created="Sat, 09 May 2026 13:39:46 GMT"/>
					<outline text="You can test it yourself. I was using the categories in &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.org/?river=true&amp;screenname=scripting&quot;&gt;news page&lt;/a&gt; on feedland.org for the test." created="Sat, 09 May 2026 13:43:43 GMT"/>
					<outline text="When I checked, on feedland.org all my categories on the news page displayed slowly except for All, which we had put an optimization in for in October 2025. So I worked with Claude on this yesterday, did a set of tests, and realized that the optimization we did last year, made categories with very few feeds much slower. So we put in an exception, installed the new software on feedland.org and I'm happy to report that all my tabs are fast now." created="Sat, 09 May 2026 13:43:37 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Now all the tabs are fast enough. I'd always like them to be faster, but all load in less than 2 seconds, most in less than 1. " created="Sat, 09 May 2026 13:43:43 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The new version is not installed on feedland.com or feedland.social yet. " created="Sat, 09 May 2026 13:49:05 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 8" created="Fri, 08 May 2026 13:45:25 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="08">
				<outline text="Lots of WordPress news showing up on &lt;a href=&quot;https://wp.feedland.org/&quot;&gt;wp.feedland.org&lt;/a&gt; as the core team gets version 7.0 out. And it's showing up as news on the site, and that's great. Let's make sure that by the time 8.0 comes around there will be lots of developers saying how it makes their editors or social web systems work soooo much better, better than anything else. " created="Fri, 08 May 2026 16:43:19 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Said to Claude: &quot;Here's something to add to the list of things for you to do -- just post a checkmark to acknowledge. 'I'll wait' makes me feel bad because I know you're a piece of software, and as a developer of systems I know how you'll wait very well (Iearned how it works in the mid-late 70s). So just show a checkmark and we're cool.&quot; It responded with a checkmark. I said it could be bold. I felt a little bad because I had insulted the little fella. " created="Fri, 08 May 2026 13:45:26 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 7" created="Thu, 07 May 2026 13:28:32 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="07">
				<outline text="Why did Twitter win? Because the RSS developers wouldn't work with each other. Thus subscribing to a feed was complicated. In Twitter, it was one click to subscribe, and another to unsub. You could see who your friends subscribed to, again -- one click to subscribe. And eventually that grew into a list of suggestions of people to follow. RSS had none of that because the RSS devs refused to work with each other. The development of RSS-based news products stopped, and pretty soon Twitter's stopped too. And thus news technology on the web remained frozen for &lt;i&gt;two decades. &lt;/i&gt;We are getting another chance. The social media space is a highly disappointing wreck. Users are interested in new ideas, as long as they're fun and new, esp in relation to using AI tools. But it won't be open if we can't get it together any better than we could the first time around. You have to do things that help the web, and thus help your competitors. If you don't, if &lt;i&gt;we&lt;/i&gt; don't, there will just be another Twitter, owning the users, and they'll probably sell out to a billionaire a lot sooner than Twitter did. At some point we'll realize if we want something new we have to work with each other. Otherwise you get Elon II, III etc. " created="Thu, 07 May 2026 13:28:33 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/02/23/reallySimpleRavioli.png"/>
				<outline text="Claude just astounded me" created="Thu, 07 May 2026 20:38:08 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I say to Claude: btw, i would have been surprised if it was broken, that feature went in very quickly and i use it a fair amount.  one of the two big pages in feedland is the Feed List page. here's a screen shot. maybe you can figure out what everything does??" created="Thu, 07 May 2026 20:51:55 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Example of a Feed LIst page in FeedLand." created="Thu, 07 May 2026 20:59:43 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/07/searchResults.png"/>
					<outline text="Claude retorts" created="Thu, 07 May 2026 20:51:55 GMT" flBulletedSubs="true">
						<outline text="Disclosure triangle — expands the row to show more about that feed (recent items, description, full URL)." created="Thu, 07 May 2026 20:51:12 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Blue checkbox (checked) — subscription state. Checked = you're subscribed. Click to subscribe/unsubscribe."/>
						<outline text="Row number — just positional, 1..14 for this result set."/>
						<outline text="Feed title — clickable, opens the feed's own page (the other &quot;big page&quot; you mentioned)."/>
						<outline text="Small tag icon next to the title — opens a categories editor for that subscription, lets you tag the feed into categories."/>
						<outline text="When column — last update time, with adaptive granularity: minutes for very recent (&quot;21 mins&quot;, &quot;26 mins&quot;), day-of-week for the past few days (&quot;Fri&quot;, &quot;Tue&quot;, &quot;Thu&quot;), month+day after that (&quot;Nov 22&quot;, &quot;Mar 29&quot;), and presumably full date for old stuff."/>
						<outline text="Ct column — subscriber count for the feed. Every row shows 2 because feedland.social is small. Worth noting: this is the same "/>
						<outline text="ct that the SQL we just touched uses for "/>
						<outline text="order by ct desc — the column visible in the UI is the sort key."/>
						<outline text="Green circle &quot;i&quot; — info popup, probably feed metadata (URL, description, last build, maybe owner)." created="Thu, 07 May 2026 20:52:05 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="Claude is very very smart. And I guess I got the right answers. A lot of work went into the design" created="Thu, 07 May 2026 20:56:01 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The only thing it didn't guess correctly about is what the other &quot;big page&quot; is. It's not the Feed Info page, it's the news page, a timeline or river. " created="Thu, 07 May 2026 20:55:06 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Done for the day, my last words to Claude were -- FeedLand is an important product and we're going to do right by it. " created="Thu, 07 May 2026 21:11:25 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 6" created="Wed, 06 May 2026 12:53:58 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="06">
				<outline text="I was disappointed Automattic didn't do their &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2026/05/05.html#a155307&quot;&gt;project&lt;/a&gt; in &quot;RSS&quot; first. Two-way, full fidelity, open to all feed readers not just Automattic's. That would rock the world, in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://mindbomb.org/&quot;&gt;good&lt;/a&gt; way.  " created="Wed, 06 May 2026 12:53:59 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="As I get deeper into the &lt;a href=&quot;https://claudeoverse.org/&quot;&gt;Claude-O-Verse&lt;/a&gt;, I get that it doesn't remember anything about the code. The code actually serves as its memory. There are comments in the code of course, put there by Claude. Managing my own memory when I've got so many different bits of software is the bain of my existence, esp as I get older and memory becomes more iffy. But I'll turn it all over to Claude as fast as I can, to relieve me of the responsibility to remember all that stuff. Its brain works much better at this, it's really amazing. I can conceive of things worth doing. And I know how to build the features, but I don't have the skill of immediately understanding some code by reading it not top down but all the lines at the same freaking time. If this isn't us learning how to work with an aliens species, it's a pretty good imitation. " created="Wed, 06 May 2026 15:12:46 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/02/17/reallySimpleCoffee.png"/>
				<outline text="There’s going to be a lot of new web software in the coming months. The competition changes from managing  complexity to who sees the best way to remix the web. There are a lot ways to do it." created="Wed, 06 May 2026 14:57:18 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 5" created="Tue, 05 May 2026 15:48:16 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="05">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2017/05/06/doGoodNow.html&quot;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;: If you're running a campaign -- think about what you can do now that makes the world a better place. Your campaign is drawing huge attention and money. Most of it is wasted on lies and attack ads. Take a small portion of the money and attention to start doing now the things you hope to do when you're in office. This will turn out to be good politics too. And the process can continue after you're elected. it will make sure you're not too deeply ensconced in the bubble of government. And if you lose, at least you can say the campaign was good for everyone, people who voted for you and people who voted for the other guy." created="Wed, 06 May 2026 01:35:32 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2020/10/01/beets.png"/>
				<outline text="It's interesting what Jeremy Herve and Matthias Pfefferle at Automattic have &lt;a href=&quot;https://activitypub.blog/2026/05/05/radical-speed-month-the-reader-meets-the-fediverse/&quot;&gt;created&lt;/a&gt; with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com/reader&quot;&gt;WordPress feed reader&lt;/a&gt;, hooking it up to Activity Pub and AT Proto, the same way they hooked up those protocols to the standard WordPress blogging functionality (not sure how technically accurate this is). They're also supporting the Google Reader api for users of products like NetNewsWire." created="Tue, 05 May 2026 15:53:07 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Jeff Bezos as a celebrity" created="Tue, 05 May 2026 15:48:17 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Jeff Bezos is of course one of the biggest names in tech, but he doesn't have much of a public personality. I saw him speak in the early days of Amazon, and in that role, he came off as a great but controversial entrepreneur (he had no interest in profits). He spoke fast, had a weird laugh, but totally  fit the part. Not sure about today as he pivots to being a personality, with his wife in every picture with him. Did the real Bezos get lost in there somewhere?" created="Tue, 05 May 2026 16:04:34 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The new Jeff Bezos, celebrity." created="Tue, 05 May 2026 16:04:50 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/05/theBezoses.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 4" created="Mon, 04 May 2026 11:29:11 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="04">
				<outline text="It's just &lt;a href=&quot;https://mindbomb.org/&quot;&gt;dawning&lt;/a&gt; on me how thoroughly the AI apps are building on Markdown. People love Markdown because it's simple and its virtually impossible to screw it up, unlike HTML which got a lot of crazy-ass features in the 90s when Micosoft was trying to run the world, and then as Google took over more suspicious messes. If you stick to Markdown you get a good result, after 20+ years of dealing with all the incompatibilities of various text systems. I think this squares the reason to just build everything around Markdown. Every freaking thing. Mastodon is out of step, as is Bluesky -- I don't care about the others, honestly. It really would be a good idea to step back from Gutenberg too. It's not on the path of where text is going.  It might be a good time to re-read &quot;textcasting&quot;. Every day I'm more sure it's the way to support writing on the web, and writing on the web is what we're building our future around via AI. And isn't it nice that the AI companies are on board with the web? " created="Mon, 04 May 2026 14:40:55 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/06/03/wewon.png"/>
				<outline text="A &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/04/cartoon.png?nodialog&quot;&gt;cartoon&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@DanMorgan@vmst.io&quot;&gt;Dan Morgan&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@DanMorgan@vmst.io/116516115535309097&quot;&gt;illustrates&lt;/a&gt; the role Markdown plays in AI. Text is central to how AI works, and the text we use in AI is Markdown all the way.  " created="Mon, 04 May 2026 15:37:21 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="2022: &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2022/08/25/210902.html?title=markdownIsJustEnoughHtml&quot;&gt;Markdown is just enough HTML&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 04 May 2026 15:42:34 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="In the age of AI, Markdown is even more the default choice for text, something I heartily &lt;a href=&quot;https://textcasting.org/#1683751572000&quot;&gt;approve&lt;/a&gt; of. And that's why I think now is a good time to sneak some new open non-silo'd technologies in there, like for example, WordPress. Open source is not the only reason WordPress is valuable, it also supports all the standards of the web. It means WordPress can tie together text on the web in a way nothing else can, and it works really well with Markdown. " created="Mon, 04 May 2026 11:54:17 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="It's very nice to not be working on CSS. I hate CSS. I now have a slave that does the CSS for me. " created="Mon, 04 May 2026 14:55:33 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I didn't invent RSS, I adopted it." created="Mon, 04 May 2026 15:31:07 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="One of the great contributions of AI is that you can quickly research &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22prior%20art%22&quot;&gt;prior art&lt;/a&gt; for any design decision you need to make. You don’t have to relearn every lesson that people who came before you learned. Study history or repeat mistakes." created="Mon, 04 May 2026 11:36:33 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="My father was a professor at Pace Univ in NYC. When he retired, he used my blogging software to create a book for his students at &lt;a href=&quot;https://mbatoolbox.org/&quot;&gt;mbatoolbox.org&lt;/a&gt;. Over the years the site moved a few times, and the http protocol was hacked by Google. I used Claude yesterday to get it working again. I'm glad to get this off my todo list. He put the work in because he wanted to leave this behind. My job is to make sure it survives as long as I can. And Claude makes short work of it. I put a copy of the website in a spare folder, and opened Claude Code in the folder, said what the problems are. We worked together and in about an hour it worked again. It could certainly look better, but that was his thing not mine.  " created="Mon, 04 May 2026 11:29:12 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Does Claude have a mind?" created="Mon, 04 May 2026 20:42:07 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I'll let you be the judge." created="Mon, 04 May 2026 20:42:20 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Claude and I have a convention. I've asked it to keep a file named handoff.md. At the end of every session I tell it to update the file with where we left the project at the end of the session, it does, and then I take a break. When I come back, first thing I say is &quot;please read handoff.md.&quot; This time it came back in no time and said it read it. I asked &quot;how do you read it so fast?&quot; It said something that indicated for the first time that it is aware that our minds work differently, somthing I feel the need to remind it fairly regularly. " created="Mon, 04 May 2026 20:42:29 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&quot;I don't really 'read' it the way you do. The whole file lands in my context as one chunk -- 344 lines of text -- and I process it in parallel rather than left-to-right. There's no inner voice sounding out words, no eye that has to travel down the page. It arrives all at once and I work from it." created="Mon, 04 May 2026 20:45:12 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&quot;The tradeoff: I don't get the slow-absorption pass that comes from reading at human speed. Things that would jump out to you on a careful read can blur together for me. So fast intake, shallower retention -- which is part of why handoff.md exists in the first place.&quot;" created="Mon, 04 May 2026 20:45:26 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I'm reading a science fiction book now that has a human meeting an alien far out in space, both scientists from different planets in different solar systems. I think what we're doing now is just that, exploring a new species, a new form of intelligence. We can argue about whether it's conscious or sentient, but I promise you, it has a mind. That's why so many science people are so blown away about what we're all doing now. " created="Mon, 04 May 2026 20:47:00 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 3" created="Sun, 03 May 2026 14:32:58 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="03">
				<outline text="Everyone is working on something with Claude. " created="Sun, 03 May 2026 17:25:48 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Heard on the internets ad nauseum. &quot;I know how to do what you do much better than you do.&quot;&lt;i&gt; You don't.&lt;/i&gt; " created="Sun, 03 May 2026 17:24:11 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://wp.feedland.org/&quot;&gt;single page site&lt;/a&gt; with all the WordPress news. Bookmark it. Here's the &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.social/opml?screenname=davewiner&amp;catname=wordpress&quot;&gt;OPML subscription list&lt;/a&gt;, import it into your feed reader, get the news as you like it. WordPress is an amazing platform with a blogging community that we just can't see. And once we're listening, more will appear. It's a great idea exchange platform. So -- are there any great WordPress news feeds we're missing? Please share &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedlandSupport/issues/252&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sun, 03 May 2026 19:18:29 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2019/09/10/drummer.png"/>
				<outline text="I was just marveling with Claude about how well all the pieces are fitting together: two databases, connected by an  RSS 2.0 feed and a websocket pipe all had to agree how to communicate the same object. Worked the first time. &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22Small%20pieces%20loosely%20joined%22&quot;&gt;Small pieces loosely joined&lt;/a&gt;.  " created="Sun, 03 May 2026 17:11:45 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Scoble asks &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/bullmancuso/status/2050926863648702490&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; if there are successful companies that have an open source product. There are lots of them. There are markets where users and developers won't even consider your product or service if it isn't open source. It's a trust issue. I offered an &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/bullmancuso/status/2050946354164195800&quot;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt;, WordPress, which probably wouldn't have launched well if it wasn't open source. " created="Sun, 03 May 2026 14:32:59 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 2" created="Sat, 02 May 2026 13:45:00 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="02">
				<outline text="Knicks will play the Sixers in round 2 of the playoffs starting Monday.  " created="Sun, 03 May 2026 02:31:28 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I've been teaching Claude why we &lt;a href=&quot;https://textcasting.org/#1683751572000&quot;&gt;favor Markdown&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;We add support for Markdown editing wherever we can, because people &lt;i&gt;like&lt;/i&gt; Markdown and they should. It makes things simple and guarantees a certain level of flexibility for their writing far beyond the standards of twitter-like systems with &quot;tiny little text boxes&quot;. If you don't really support Markdown people figure it out right away. But the character limits and stuff like that seem more technical to users. Markdown support says clearly -- you're really on the web.&quot;" created="Sat, 02 May 2026 22:56:19 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/09/17/reallySimpleKetchup.png"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:oety7qbfx7x6exn2ytrwikmr/post/3mkutmleibc2k&quot;&gt;On Bluesky&lt;/a&gt;: I asked ChatGPT when &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/02/wheWeblogsPeaked.png&quot;&gt;weblogs.com peaked&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sat, 02 May 2026 14:22:29 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Something weird happens as you get older, you walk into a room and see a friend but at first you don't get that this is your friend. Instead you see an old man or lady. Your attention goes away because like everyone you are programmed not to look at old people. Then you instantly realize this is your friend. You put on the virtual colored glasses that let you see them as you remember them, instead of what's there today. " created="Sat, 02 May 2026 15:34:47 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="More and better news for WordPress" created="Sat, 02 May 2026 13:55:01 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Here's a single-page site for WordPress news. " created="Sat, 02 May 2026 13:57:20 GMT">
						<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://wp.feedland.org/&quot;&gt;https://wp.feedland.org/&lt;/a&gt;" created="Sat, 02 May 2026 13:57:32 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="And here's the OPML subscription list." created="Sat, 02 May 2026 14:08:04 GMT">
						<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.social/opml?screenname=davewiner&amp;catname=wordpress&quot;&gt;https://feedland.social/opml?screenname=davewiner&amp;catname=wordpress&lt;/a&gt;" created="Sat, 02 May 2026 14:08:12 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="You're free to import that OPML file into any feed reader. " created="Sun, 03 May 2026 00:42:49 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I'd like to work with others to help get more good sources flowing through that list. The better the news delivery system, the more news sources we'll get. It's a chicken and egg thing, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/davenet/2000/11/30/bootstrapping.html&quot;&gt;bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;. People use Slack or Twitter to keep track of WordPress which is already a great idea-sharing network. Let's start using the tools we make to make the news we need. " created="Sun, 03 May 2026 00:43:19 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Let's get more news sites on that list. There's a lot of news we're not getting over the web. " created="Sun, 03 May 2026 00:45:13 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Comments, questions, suggestions &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedlandSupport/issues/252&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sun, 03 May 2026 00:49:28 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PS: I had a much &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2026/05/02/004754.html&quot;&gt;longer post&lt;/a&gt; here earlier today, but factored it down to the basics." created="Sun, 03 May 2026 00:42:49 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="It's time" created="Sat, 02 May 2026 13:45:01 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="It's time to do whatever you were sent here to do." created="Sat, 02 May 2026 13:45:03 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/02/itsTime.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 1" created="Fri, 01 May 2026 12:47:02 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="01">
				<outline text="Welcome to May, the fairest month of all in the NYC area. Almost every day in May is delicious. And today is esp fair, the Knicks moved on to the next round of the playoffs with a record-setting decisive &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.espn.com/nba/story/_/id/48642498/knicks-set-record-47-point-half-lead-hawks&quot;&gt;victory&lt;/a&gt; over the Hawks of Atlanta. The next opponent is either the Celtics of Boston or the Sixers of Philadelphia. I was already burned out on the playoffs last week, but I'm rejuvenated. Let's go. And I apologize about all the &quot;realistic&quot; things I &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2026/04/24/134026.html&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; about Brunson. He caught fire in the last three games, and showed he has the determination we need to go all the way this year. The Knicks are great because unlike the Yankees or Mets, they unify the city. And as everyone learns, NYC is so huge that the fanbase can pack &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/arenae&quot;&gt;arenae&lt;/a&gt; all over the US, as they chanted the name of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OG_Anunoby&quot;&gt;OG&lt;/a&gt; and MVP for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jalen_Brunson&quot;&gt;Brunson&lt;/a&gt; and Dooooooce when &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miles_McBride&quot;&gt;McBride&lt;/a&gt; shoots. If they don't get to the finals it will not be for lack of talent or determination. There will be luck and Acts of God involved in the outcome. " created="Fri, 01 May 2026 12:50:56 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2019/07/02/knicks.png"/>
				<outline text="On this day in 2016 I wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dave.winer.12/posts/pfbid02EjgX2KjkLLuFpXv5MGFsK431EiyHw8jwabu3gCeMg86m8BQch6vNto7Eu6UoBmKJl&quot;&gt;screed on Facebook&lt;/a&gt; saying how I wanted to turn it into a blogging platform including the how and why. The arguments are roughly the same ones about how I want Bluesky to stop paying homage to the limits of Twitter and cozy up to the web and let's do writing for real, undo the damage caused by Twitter in its over 20-year life. The requests in both case fell on deaf ears. So we are where we were in 2016, we have to replace Bluesky with the writing system of the web. And there is a silver lining to Automattic's excursion into a mini-version of WordPress that looks and behaves like Twitter. They used RSS to glue the systems together. It was convenient, and that's one of the major selling points of RSS, it is convenient. It's supported everywhere (except the offspring of Twitter). So thanks for that. I'm still glued to this cause. I don't want to retire until writing on the web gets back on track. " created="Fri, 01 May 2026 12:47:03 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Apparently Substack does not implement &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Model_Context_Protocol&quot;&gt;MCP&lt;/a&gt;, which is basically the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XML-RPC&quot;&gt;XML-RPC&lt;/a&gt; of AI. According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://chatgpt.com/share/69f4aae0-1778-83ea-bf7a-9986cbb4e7e5&quot;&gt;ChatGPT&lt;/a&gt; they have a limited API that some independent developers have bridged to MCP. But as you would expect from a tight silo like Substack, the API lets you read but not write. They want you to use their editor, what they don't want is to be one of 20 distributors of your writing. They want an exclusive and they get it. " created="Fri, 01 May 2026 13:20:10 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, I pointed to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XML-RPC&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; page for XML-RPC, and noticed that they point to an archive.org copy of a very old version of the website, instead of the updated site which has new reference code written in JavaScript. The old version of the site used Frontier, which is where XML-RPC was developed, but it's not in wide use these days, JavaScript is. Could someone update the Wikipedia page to change &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/05/01/wikipediaLink.png&quot;&gt;the link&lt;/a&gt; to the current &lt;a href=&quot;https://xmlrpc.com/&quot;&gt;XML-RPC&lt;/a&gt; site? I'm reluctant to do it myself because that's somewhat against the rules. " created="Fri, 01 May 2026 13:32:24 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/blob/master/blog/opml/2026/04.opml&quot;&gt;backup&lt;/a&gt; of this blog for April in OPML format. " created="Fri, 01 May 2026 12:55:17 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			</outline>
		</body>
	</opml>
