<?xml version="1.0"?>
<opml version="2.0">
	<head>
		<title>Scripting News</title>
		<flPublic>true</flPublic>
		<longTitle>Editorial outline for Scripting News</longTitle>
		<description>Scripting News, the weblog started in 1994 that bootstrapped the blogging revolution. 🚀</description>
		<dateModified>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 22:06:19 GMT</dateModified>
		<expansionState></expansionState>
		<lastCursor>0</lastCursor>
		<ownerId>https://twitter.com/davewiner/</ownerId>
		<ownerName>scripting.com</ownerName>
		<ownerTwitterScreenName>davewiner</ownerTwitterScreenName>
		<urlUpdateSocket>ws://electricserver.scripting.com:5383/</urlUpdateSocket>
		<copyright>&amp;copy; 1994-2019 &lt;a href=&quot;http://davewiner.com/&quot;&gt;Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
		<ownerFacebookAccount>dave.winer.12</ownerFacebookAccount>
		<ownerGithubAccount>scripting</ownerGithubAccount>
		<ownerLinkedinAccount>scripting</ownerLinkedinAccount>
		<disqusGroup>scripting</disqusGroup>
		<type>blogpost</type>
		<urlPublic>http://scripting.com/</urlPublic>
		<urlJson>http://electricserver.scripting.com/users/davewiner/electric/blog.json</urlJson>
		<urInstant>http://instantoutliner.com/61</urInstant>
		<oldSchoolBlogName>dave</oldSchoolBlogName>
		</head>
	<body>
		<outline text="May 2019" created="Wed, 01 May 2019 14:15:14 GMT" name="may2019">
			<outline text="May 31" created="Fri, 31 May 2019 14:28:06 GMT" name="31">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://freedomfarts.org/&quot;&gt;freedomfarts.org&lt;/a&gt; is available. " created="Fri, 31 May 2019 19:34:43 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/2016/03/25/oldhat.png"/>
				<outline text="I really enjoyed last night's &lt;a href=&quot;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/does-torontos-game-1-win-spell-doom-for-the-warriors/&quot;&gt;NBA Finals game&lt;/a&gt;. Because it was a real contest. Playoff basketball is like nothing else. You can go to a regular season game if you want, but it's like spring training. The problem with the Warriors is that they, like other dominant teams before them, forced the league to form around them. For example the Rockets, an excellent team, can't get by Golden State, so they'll rip up the team this summer and start over. Possibly the only player who's untouchable is James Hardin. When KD went to the Golden State that's when the NBA turned a bad corner imho at least for this fan who just likes a real game, not a rout, at the very end of the season. We got that last night. Looking forward to the rest of the playoffs. I don't really care who wins btw, I just love great basketball. " created="Fri, 31 May 2019 15:46:51 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="You don't hear this on the news, but I assume at least some of the strange behavior of American politicians is due to blackmail or threats of physical harm." created="Fri, 31 May 2019 14:28:07 GMT" type="tweet" tweetId="1134466636709318656" tweetUserName="davewiner"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 30" created="Thu, 30 May 2019 18:19:27 GMT" name="30">
				<outline text="What &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RockyPruitt/status/1133861965246455808&quot;&gt;Steve Jobs says&lt;/a&gt; here is true. You find new ways of doing things by building tools to do them, and follow your nose. " created="Thu, 30 May 2019 18:42:06 GMT" type="outline" urltweet="https://twitter.com/RockyPruitt/status/1133861965246455808"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/30/us/census-citizenship-question-hofeller.html?fbclid=IwAR0PsJh711Itk-D7GIDBcOJgOffER_Qe70knWIg5_x2Wnt0Rv8WFRkMVQbU&quot;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Files on those drives showed that he wrote a study in 2015 concluding that adding a citizenship question to the census would allow Republicans to draft even more extreme gerrymandered maps to stymie Democrats.&quot;" created="Thu, 30 May 2019 18:46:13 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Leon Redbone died. His &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2019/05/30/728315252/leon-redbone-an-unusual-singer-from-a-bygone-era-has-died?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=musicnews&quot;&gt;obit&lt;/a&gt; is of course a total kick. For me his most memorable song is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xSdSn9J2J8U&quot;&gt;Lazy Bones&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 30 May 2019 18:19:28 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xSdSn9J2J8U"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 29" created="Wed, 29 May 2019 15:13:30 GMT" name="29">
				<outline text="Request to journalists. When impeachment is discussed instead of talking about Democrats, say it's the House that's taking it up. That's more accurate, and it helps reduce the partisanality of it. Esp now that there's a Repub pushing for impeachment." created="Wed, 29 May 2019 16:50:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I always thought, for some reason, that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yacc&quot;&gt;YACC&lt;/a&gt; source for Frontier was lost, but I looked in the repo and searched for YACC, and there it was in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/frontier/blob/856cccf694b3d4c8c27d2fe3634221564e331e59/Common/source/langparser.y&quot;&gt;langparser.y&lt;/a&gt;. I still want a nice scripting language for my JavaScript outliner, and it can't be JavaScript.  There's some great food for thought here, and lots of memories. The last time I worked at this level was in the late 80s. Thinking maybe of starting with this syntax for a simple scripting language that can be plugged into JS apps. " created="Wed, 29 May 2019 16:31:12 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I wish the Mueller Report was an HBO or Netflix series. The actor who plays Trump should be a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiewire.com/2017/08/best-tv-presidents-ever-1201868686/&quot;&gt;TV president&lt;/a&gt;, yet do the corrupt, desperate and sad things he does. Create a contrast betw the president we deserve and the one we have." created="Wed, 29 May 2019 16:15:14 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=emmPSEgYkP0"/>
				<outline text="I just realized that Mueller is like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Clayton_(film)&quot;&gt;Michael Clayton&lt;/a&gt;. Specifically, the scene at the end of the movie with Tilda Swinton and George Clooney. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6E2z-1Mi6Zo&amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;t=81&quot;&gt;pivotal line&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I'm not the guy that you kill.&quot; Translated to Mueller, &quot;I'm not the guy that testifies.&quot; He's right. Like Michael Clayton, Mueller is a fixer. He was given a mess to sort out, and he did. Along the way there were indictments. But he did his job. It's now Congress's job. " created="Wed, 29 May 2019 15:24:38 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/29/truthAdjustment.png"/>
				<outline text="Mueller: &quot;Read the report.&quot;" created="Wed, 29 May 2019 15:13:31 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 28" created="Tue, 28 May 2019 14:54:01 GMT" name="28">
				<outline text="One way of doing things is easier than two, no matter how much better the second way is. &lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/927/&quot;&gt;Also&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 28 May 2019 18:40:27 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://bingeworthy.io/tv/&quot;&gt;Bingeworthy&lt;/a&gt; is pretty good, my first real SQL app. I never do enough to promote these things or even finish them. It needs features to draw you back into it. " created="Tue, 28 May 2019 17:33:55 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The Wikipedia page for podcasting still has some misleading info about how the name was arrived at. How it &lt;a href=&quot;http://threads2.scripting.com/2013/april/howPodcastingGotItsName&quot;&gt;actually happened&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 28 May 2019 15:04:57 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I remember watching the series finale of Mad Men realizing that one of the hundreds of fan theories I had read was right! That doesn't mean the author came up with the ending. Another analogy. I thought Apple's phone was going to be called iPhone. I didn't get credit for naming the phone, however. The naming of the podcast is very well documented, the archives all there. There's no reason for the Wikipedia page to carry this mistake forward. All the reporters echo the mistake. It's not fair to Dannie Gregoire who actually coined the term, or respectful of the open process we used to develop it. It was all very deliberate, took a lot of trial and error, hard work, cooperation, patience and creativity. " created="Tue, 28 May 2019 15:11:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 27" created="Mon, 27 May 2019 19:14:08 GMT" name="27">
				<outline text="Feeling much better. My appetite has returned, somewhat, and I took a 20-minute walk at a brisk pace through the woods. Very uplifting. And I watched two excellent movies today, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cold_War_(2018_film)&quot;&gt;Cold War&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roma_(2018_film)&quot;&gt;Roma&lt;/a&gt;. It was not part of a plan, I just stumbled on them while browsing on Amazon and Netflix. Both were slow and quiet, very dramatic, and beautiful in every way. Perfect movies. Such an unusual thing! Two in one day? Wow. " created="Mon, 27 May 2019 19:14:09 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Over the last few days I've also watched the full second season of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barry_(TV_series)&quot;&gt;Barry&lt;/a&gt;, am caught up on Gentleman Jack and Chernobyl, all on HBO.  I know people rave about Barry, but like the second season of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Killing_Eve&quot;&gt;Killing Eve&lt;/a&gt;, it is a letdown. It's funny that's for sure because Bill Hader is an amazing comedian, like a Jim Carrey or Robin Williams. It's easy to watch, it kills a few hours, but won't give you a lot to think about. It's like popcorn. I think both shows were hurt by running while Game of Thrones was finishing up, btw. It kind of sucked all the air out of the room. Amazingly, now I have absolutely no interest in reading about GoT, where just a week ago, that's pretty much all I wanted to read about. " created="Mon, 27 May 2019 19:18:41 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I was intrigued by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gentleman_Jack_(TV_series)&quot;&gt;Gentleman Jack&lt;/a&gt; through the first few episodes. The principal character, Anne Lister, played by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suranne_Jones&quot;&gt;Suranne Jones&lt;/a&gt;, is very appealing and has an unusual problem, which she sets out to solve, all while leading her remarkable life. I'm not being sarcastic. I was drawn to it because I watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Doctor_Foster_(TV_series)&quot;&gt;Doctor Foster&lt;/a&gt; which also starred Jones, and it was riveting, and kept my attention through two seasons. But the potential of Gentleman Jack never seems to come together and the show drags and repeats, for what? She's brilliant, but we see before she does that what's she's chasing is unattainable. Or so it seems, the season is only half-done. But the elements of a great show are there so hopefully it's turn around. Episode 5 airs tonight on HBO at 10PM." created="Mon, 27 May 2019 19:22:42 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chernobyl_(miniseries)&quot;&gt;Chernobyl&lt;/a&gt;, a 5-part miniseries, is something you should watch. It's a really well done thriller about a historic event that I didn't really understand at the time, but I remember how freaked out we all were that it was the end of the world. Now it's easy to watch because we know that it more or less worked out, the world is still here. Episode 4 airs tonight on HBO at 9PM." created="Mon, 27 May 2019 19:30:12 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 24" created="Fri, 24 May 2019 23:32:55 GMT" name="24">
				<outline text="I have a really bad cold, or something. I'll start writing again when I feel better. For now I'm sleeping, hydrating and binge-watching. Just watched season 2 of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fleabag&quot;&gt;Fleabag&lt;/a&gt;. Not sure what's next. " created="Fri, 24 May 2019 23:32:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="At what point will cities license their name to companies. So San Francisco changes to Salesforce. &quot;I'm catching a flight from JFK to Salesforce, honey.&quot; You can imagine the rest. The United States is already spoken for. " created="Fri, 24 May 2019 23:43:25 GMT" type="tweet" tweetId="1132070064012898305" tweetUserName="davewiner"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 22" created="Wed, 22 May 2019 13:03:50 GMT" name="22">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OwzKWrNdg7I&quot;&gt;Turkeys in my back yard&lt;/a&gt;. I shot this through a window, unfortunately when I went outside to get a clearer picture they turned and ran away. I wasn't going to hurt them." created="Wed, 22 May 2019 20:23:18 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OwzKWrNdg7I"/>
				<outline text="A friend asked me now that it's over what do I think of Game of Thrones. She hasn't watched the show, but knows that I did. I don't have a ready answer. Here's an analogy. What do I think of San Francisco? I lived in the Bay Area for a long time, and for a very short time I lived in the city (on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/@37.7946708,-122.4315458,3a,75y,353.51h,107.8t/data=!3m7!1e1!3m5!1s9Q1ncHGu2Ee6BQC28d5WWg!2e0!6s%2F%2Fgeo2.ggpht.com%2Fcbk%3Fpanoid%3D9Q1ncHGu2Ee6BQC28d5WWg%26output%3Dthumbnail%26cb_client%3Dmaps_sv.tactile.gps%26thumb%3D2%26w%3D203%26h%3D100%26yaw%3D185.01842%26pitch%3D0%26thumbfov%3D100!7i13312!8i6656&quot;&gt;Broadway&lt;/a&gt;). There are some things that are incredible about it, the weather down the peninsula is about as perfect as weather can be about eight months a year. Food is excellent. Lots of smart people. I had a lot of very positive experiences there. But the traffic is awful and you always have to be prepared for an earthquake, and I've lived through one, and didn't like it. People are obsessed with money, I find that dull, which is probably the main reason I left. I've been watching GoT for a long time. It's impossible to say what I think of it. It's a thing. It's like asking me what I think of a close relative, perhaps one who just died. " created="Wed, 22 May 2019 13:03:51 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/22/khaleesi.png"/>
				<outline text="Now I think the best season finale ever was &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Six_Feet_Under_(TV_series)&quot;&gt;Six Feet Under&lt;/a&gt;. The show wasn't pretentious, in fact its point was to make mundane the most dramatic thing that happens to each of us. So the ending was an ending and nothing more. I'm not going to spoil it here. I think there needs to be a site where you can keep your watching history and you can write things like this with enough metadata so it knows not to show it to you if you haven't seen the finale of the show I'm writing about. Maybe in Internet 4.0. " created="Wed, 22 May 2019 13:17:11 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The only show that I can think of that didn't punt on the ending was &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mad_Men&quot;&gt;Mad Men&lt;/a&gt;. The end was a surprise, but someone I knew had guessed it. It was clever and satisfying. The Sopranos ending was almost a pure punt (we did find out the ending for a few characters in the last episode). Unlike a lot of people -- I liked the ending. I also liked the ending of Lost. Someday someone will do a show (like Seinfeld duh) that disclaims up front to be about nothing, therefore the finale, by definition will be nothing. I guess that was also Newhart. I didn't watch either of them. " created="Wed, 22 May 2019 13:19:30 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Exf63KPXF6w&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt; of the last scene in Mad Men." created="Wed, 22 May 2019 15:43:40 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Exf63KPXF6w"/>
				<outline text="One of the best things I read about GoT was in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/larry.ob/posts/10157254612263064&quot;&gt;Facebook post&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe you can read it. I'm not going to port it. Not my job. :-)" created="Wed, 22 May 2019 13:22:41 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="GoT spoiler. &lt;i&gt;NakedJen do not read. &lt;/i&gt;The sanest ending for GoT would be Khaleesi doesn't destroy Kings Landing. She takes the throne. (Keep the end of Cersei and Jaime.) She marries Jon Snow, and he takes up sculpting or pottery, maybe farming and bends the knee. Everyone relaxes and has a good time." created="Wed, 22 May 2019 13:50:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 21" created="Tue, 21 May 2019 15:17:58 GMT" name="21">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2019/05/21/fireEveryWeaponAtOnce.m4a&quot;&gt;Nancy Pelosi&lt;/a&gt;: It's time to get out every gun you have and fire it. Because you're about to lose all of them. You have to wake everybody up and say listen, this is it, after this point we do not have a government. " created="Tue, 21 May 2019 16:17:17 GMT" type="outline" enclosure="http://scripting.com/2019/05/21/fireEveryWeaponAtOnce.m4a" enclosureType="audio/mpeg" enclosureLength="4160608"/>
				<outline text="What CJ would &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DG0ch202prY&quot;&gt;say&lt;/a&gt; to Pelosi: &quot;The fall is gonna kill you.&quot; " created="Tue, 21 May 2019 16:56:02 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DG0ch202prY"/>
				<outline text="GoT fans, you must watch this &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/FoldableHuman/status/1130581319593783296&quot;&gt;alternate ending&lt;/a&gt; to series. " created="Tue, 21 May 2019 15:46:36 GMT" type="outline" urltweet="https://twitter.com/FoldableHuman/status/1130581319593783296"/>
				<outline text="Once a long time ago I wrote on this blog that we should have fewer humans, and the rage it provoked was awesome, and imho totally wrong. As we consume the life-sustaining ability of our planet, if we had &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2010/08/29/virgin.jpg&quot;&gt;fewer people&lt;/a&gt;, we'd consume it at a slower rate. I don't think there's any great reason to overpopulate the planet, esp when we're so resource-constrained. BTW, I'm a mystic, i.e. I believe in the mystery of it all. :-) " created="Tue, 21 May 2019 15:17:59 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/21/stillAVirgin.png"/>
				<outline text="BTW, I did an image search for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site:scripting.com+WTF&amp;safe=off&amp;source=lnms&amp;tbm=isch&amp;sa=X&amp;ved=0ahUKEwjs3dfB-KziAhUJZd8KHYFVA9cQ_AUIDigB&amp;biw=1320&amp;bih=960&amp;dpr=2&quot;&gt;WTF&lt;/a&gt; on this blog and the results were interesting." created="Tue, 21 May 2019 15:20:50 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 20" created="Mon, 20 May 2019 13:31:32 GMT" name="20">
				<outline text="I picked some of &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/20/wingSauce.png&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; up on impulse and it's great on everything. I imagine I'll get tired of it, but for now. " created="Mon, 20 May 2019 20:02:18 GMT" type="outline" urlexpandableimage="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/20/wingSauce.png"/>
				<outline text="I want to buy a cool exercise bike for home. I like the idea of taking virtual trips, and that there be inclines and declines. But I'm pretty sure I don't want to do cycling classes. Any recommendations? " created="Mon, 20 May 2019 18:42:12 GMT" type="tweet" tweetId="1130544333583736833" tweetUserName="davewiner"/>
				<outline text="So many things to say about the last episode of Game of Thrones, but I don't believe that was actually the last episode. :boom:" created="Mon, 20 May 2019 15:05:36 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="If you are pro-choice, as I am, focus your ire on people who vote for abortion restrictions. That's how we should divide ourselves. This isn't just a battle for women's rights, it's much broader than that. We need to unite, not divide. Keep that in mind when you post something clever that further divides us. You're doing someone else's work there, someone who is very much opposed to you and your values. " created="Mon, 20 May 2019 13:31:33 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 19" created="Sun, 19 May 2019 16:22:04 GMT" name="19">
				<outline text="Who's on the throne?" created="Sun, 19 May 2019 16:22:05 GMT" type="outline" description="I have a theory about who's on the throne after tonight's episode. Obviously full of spoilers. You have been warned! :-)">
					<outline text="Well here we go, the final episode of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game_of_Thrones&quot;&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/a&gt;, and the big question, assuming there still is a throne, who's sitting on it at the end of tonight's episode? Whoever it is is in some sense the winner.  " created="Sun, 19 May 2019 16:22:11 GMT" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/19/tyrionLannister.png"/>
					<outline text="I have a wacky theory about it, I posted it on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dave.winer.12/posts/949167355290670&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, might as well post it here too. " created="Sun, 19 May 2019 16:23:49 GMT"/>
					<outline text="What if..." created="Sun, 19 May 2019 16:24:22 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The person who ends up on the throne is..."/>
					<outline text="None other than..." created="Sun, 19 May 2019 16:24:44 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Tyrion Lannister! ;-)" created="Sun, 19 May 2019 16:24:39 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Hear me out." created="Sun, 19 May 2019 16:25:09 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I assume there's going to be a showdown between Jon Snow and Daenerys. What if they kill each other? Or elope to a romantic hiding place?" created="Sun, 19 May 2019 16:25:04 GMT" collapse="true">
						<outline text="Alterately, Arya kills Daenerys, and Jon Snow, who likes Tyrion (going back to season 1) returns to the north to be with his &lt;a href=&quot;https://awoiaf.westeros.org/index.php/Ghost&quot;&gt;dog&lt;/a&gt; and his &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tormund_Giantsbane&quot;&gt;red-haired friend&lt;/a&gt;. He could hook up with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brienne_of_Tarth&quot;&gt;Brienne&lt;/a&gt;, who is available now that Jaime is dead. There's your spinoff! He could pick up &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samwell_Tarly&quot;&gt;Samwell Tarly&lt;/a&gt; and family (son named Jon, btw) on his way north. " created="Sun, 19 May 2019 16:38:37 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="It's crazy to think the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gendry&quot;&gt;Baratheon bastard&lt;/a&gt; is going to be accepted on the throne. " created="Sun, 19 May 2019 16:38:21 GMT"/>
					<outline text="But Cersei was a Lannister. Tyrion is a Lannister. He's the next in line if you believe Cersei was a valid Queen. And why not. Everyone knows that Joffrey was a Lannister as was Tommen." created="Sun, 19 May 2019 16:25:38 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Seems old Tyrion has the best claim to the throne. And he's not a murderer, he drinks wine and likes to fuck (or at least he used to). He's been pretty good to everyone, and Sansa loves him. He would be a &lt;i&gt;good&lt;/i&gt; king (you can almost hear him saying it). " created="Sun, 19 May 2019 16:26:07 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I don't think too many Kings Landing folk are going to be begging for a Targaryen to take the throne." created="Sun, 19 May 2019 16:26:30 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I don't know if other people see this, but it seems reasonable to me. "/>
					<outline text="Tyrion for King! :-)" created="Sun, 19 May 2019 16:24:40 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 18" created="Sat, 18 May 2019 14:34:45 GMT" name="18">
				<outline text="I haven't watched season 2 of Fleabag yet. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metacritic.com/tv/fleabag/season-2&quot;&gt;reviews&lt;/a&gt; are incredible. The first season was &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2018/07/08.html#a124745&quot;&gt;great&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sat, 18 May 2019 17:44:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="This &lt;a href=&quot;http://antirez.com/news/129&quot;&gt;piece&lt;/a&gt; really resonated with me. So many good points. When a project catches on the work really changes. And the difference between this kind of creative work, and say writing music, is that software is used not just listened to. Another thing I've noticed is that people who come along and build off your open work expect you to step aside when they want to take over. This is a big disconnect, I create the software because I want to build on it, not to create a lifestyle for you, though I don't mind if you do that, that's why I made it open. But don't ever expect the originator of a project to step aside. That's a bug in your thinking. I've also noticed that the people who want to take over rarely have any original ideas other than they want to take over (and of course that's not original). " created="Sat, 18 May 2019 16:53:39 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2018/07/08/redAndBlueStates.png"/>
				<outline text="When people I follow blame a group based on race, gender, age, sexuality, I unfollow immediately without a second thought." created="Sat, 18 May 2019 15:08:12 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The town of Woodstock, where I live, is &lt;a href=&quot;https://hudsonvalleyone.com/2019/05/18/woodstocks-short-term-rental-regs-set-for-passage/&quot;&gt;working on a law&lt;/a&gt; to limit short-term vacation rentals. When I was shopping for a house here, I used the AirBnBs. But now that I own property here, I have conflicted views. I understand the reason they want the law is to have more housing available for full-time residents to rent.  " created="Sat, 18 May 2019 14:34:46 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I ran a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1129405186055782400&quot;&gt;poll&lt;/a&gt; yesterday asking what people expect from the GoT finale, &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2019/05/19.html&quot;&gt;tomorrow&lt;/a&gt; night. FWIW, I expect to be satisfied. They aren't going to pull any punches in the finale. They had something great last week, and they're going for the kill this week. I expect to be blown away. " created="Sat, 18 May 2019 15:30:27 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/07/dragon.png"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 17" created="Fri, 17 May 2019 13:14:08 GMT" name="17">
				<outline text="A good afternoon &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h_7q9_EJYvE&quot;&gt;song&lt;/a&gt; (no hidden meaning)." created="Fri, 17 May 2019 19:57:19 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h_7q9_EJYvE"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.memeorandum.com/190517/p3#a190517p3&quot;&gt;Look&lt;/a&gt; at what the AG is doing now. He's going to change the rules so the Mueller investigation is retroactively illegal. I bet they put some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foxnews.com/politics/trump-calls-2016-campaign-spying-treason-warns-of-long-jail-sentences&quot;&gt;FBI people&lt;/a&gt; on trial. That'll completely put an end to investigations. In their calculations, people who work in government have to decide who they fear most, Trump or what comes after Trump." created="Fri, 17 May 2019 16:56:27 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1129405186055782400&quot;&gt;Poll&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Thinking of famous series finales, Sopranos, Deadwood, Six Feet Under, Breaking Bad, Mad Men, Lost. Will the end of Game of Thrones give resolution, or will it leave you wanting more?&quot;" created="Fri, 17 May 2019 15:16:05 GMT" type="outline" urltweet="https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1129405186055782400"/>
				<outline text="Suppose the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C-fLC1dJi78&quot;&gt;worst person in the world&lt;/a&gt; has a great idea, but you aren't listening because you don't like this person. In normal times you would be the main loser. But if the idea could help us avert the climate or constitutional meltdowns, we all lose because of your pride. That's why I try to listen to smart people even if it hurts my ego." created="Fri, 17 May 2019 14:49:00 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Resist efforts to divide us. When people say that a certain &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/?q=old+white+men+abortion&amp;t=h_&amp;ia=web&quot;&gt;class&lt;/a&gt; of people, based on age, race or gender, is responsible for something bad, it probably isn't true. If it isn't and you perpetuate the lie, you're doing Trump's work, and you should &lt;i&gt;stop doing that. &lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 17 May 2019 14:24:13 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="My auto insurance company wants me to try a new app that will rate my driving safety using GPS and motion detector in my iPhone. What they don't say is if it will affect my insurance rates. " created="Fri, 17 May 2019 13:14:09 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Rating the integrity of guests" created="Fri, 17 May 2019 13:14:30 GMT" type="outline" description="A simple way of measuring the integrity of the people interviewed on cable news shows.">
					<outline text="I had an idea watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/IjbqLTFP8Rs?t=44&quot;&gt;this clip&lt;/a&gt; from MSNBC, where a reporter does something unusual, he stops the person he's interviewing for BS, and then for not answering his question. This is so common in cable news, it's the #1 reason I switch channels." created="Fri, 17 May 2019 13:14:39 GMT" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/17/scotchTape.png"/>
					<outline text="So here's the idea -- an organization, perhaps sponsored by Knight or Newmark, maintains a database of people who are interviewed on cable news. For each, the number of questions they were asked, the number of times they did and didn't answer the question. A simple way of measuring the integrity of the interviewee. And also the interviewer. " created="Fri, 17 May 2019 13:19:27 GMT"/>
					<outline text="You could publish an index for each of the shows. Do they tend to invite people on who actually answer questions? And then you could have an index for each network. They like horse race journalism. Turn it around, make the quality of their reporting a horse race. " created="Fri, 17 May 2019 13:29:06 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Twist: Penalize the show double if the person has been on before and evaded the questions both times. Fool me once, okay, ask to be fooled again, I'm a fool for listening to you. :boom:" created="Fri, 17 May 2019 13:20:48 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Another index: Time spent talking vs how many ideas discussed. For a few people the ratio would be infinite, they just speak in a word salad, they say nothing. A great &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Steele&quot;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt; is the former head of the RNC.  The best ratio, most substance to time talked would be interesting too. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michelle_Goldberg&quot;&gt;Michelle Goldberg&lt;/a&gt; seems to be the best. She ramps up quickly, says something interesting, doesn't repeat herself unless asked. " created="Fri, 17 May 2019 13:21:32 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 16" created="Thu, 16 May 2019 14:27:50 GMT" name="16">
				<outline text="Idea for a web app. A URL shortener that sanitizes and beautifies the writing on the page before displaying it. I often won't point to interesting stories because the HTML in the page is so obscene. &lt;a href=&quot;https://sportsday.dallasnews.com/dallas-mavericks/mavericks/2019/05/16/charles-barley-says-fight-bad-look-kristaps-porzingis-hall-famer-optimistic-mavs-one-two-punch&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/a&gt;. I thought Charles Barkley had some wise words for Kristaps Porzingis, worth passing on. I apologize in advance for the BS on that site. " created="Thu, 16 May 2019 14:27:51 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, this is what the post above &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/16/riverView.png&quot;&gt;looks like&lt;/a&gt; in my reader. It can be much better. I'm taking a look at this now. " created="Thu, 16 May 2019 14:39:35 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Also, this is what it &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/16/chatTabView.png&quot;&gt;looks like&lt;/a&gt; in the Chat tab." created="Thu, 16 May 2019 14:43:49 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="feedRead viewer app" created="Thu, 16 May 2019 16:24:44 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="&lt;i&gt;This is a specialized tool useful to a small number of people. I'm putting it here so I can easily find it by searching, when I need it in the future. &lt;/i&gt;" created="Thu, 16 May 2019 16:30:30 GMT"/>
					<outline text="As you may know I have a NPM package, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/davefeedread&quot;&gt;davefeedread&lt;/a&gt;, that makes it easy to read most kinds of feeds in Node.js projects. I use it in my apps that read feeds, so when I fix a bug, I just have to add it in this one place and rebuild any app that uses it. " created="Thu, 16 May 2019 16:24:54 GMT" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/16/weTryHarder.png"/>
					<outline text="I &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedRead/blob/master/examples/webapp/feedreadviewer.js&quot;&gt;share&lt;/a&gt; it because I want people to use RSS. :rocket: " created="Thu, 16 May 2019 17:02:34 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Today I was debugging an app that generates RSS, and wanted to get a close look at what davefeedread was generating, and decided once and for all to put it in a web app, to make it easy to debug a feed. Should've done it long ago." created="Thu, 16 May 2019 16:26:21 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Here's an example link:" created="Thu, 16 May 2019 16:27:26 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://feedread.scripting.com/?url=http://scripting.com/rss.xml&quot;&gt;http://feedread.scripting.com/?url=http://scripting.com/rss.xml&lt;/a&gt;" created="Thu, 16 May 2019 16:27:32 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It displays the structure that the davefeedread package returns for my feed. " created="Thu, 16 May 2019 16:30:07 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/danmactough&quot;&gt;Dan MacTough&lt;/a&gt; who wrote the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/feedparser&quot;&gt;feedparser&lt;/a&gt; package that this is built on.  " created="Thu, 16 May 2019 16:32:19 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 15" created="Wed, 15 May 2019 13:08:55 GMT" name="15">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2019/05/15/allYouNeedToKnowAboutGameOfThrones.m4a&quot;&gt;Quick podcast&lt;/a&gt;. All you need to know about Game of Thrones. " created="Wed, 15 May 2019 16:46:16 GMT" type="outline" enclosure="http://scripting.com/2019/05/15/allYouNeedToKnowAboutGameOfThrones.m4a" enclosureType="audio/mpeg" enclosureLength="2174151"/>
				<outline text="I wonder if anyone named their dog Alexa, and if any hilarity ensued thus." created="Thu, 16 May 2019 02:16:48 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="You know that old story about how first they came for the immigrants, but I wasn't an immigrant so I didn't worry about it? That's a good way to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/14/us/abortion-law-alabama.html&quot;&gt;news from Alabama&lt;/a&gt;, imho." created="Wed, 15 May 2019 16:53:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Yesterday &lt;a href=&quot;http://howardweaver.com/styled-12/index.html&quot;&gt;Howard Weaver&lt;/a&gt;, a long-time friend, journalist, asked &quot;What is an open identity server?&quot; I was able to answer the question &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1128674591201689602&quot;&gt;in a tweet&lt;/a&gt;. Briefly it's the part of Twitter that knows you're @howardweaver and I'm @davewiner. I need that in my software too. Rather than build my own, and make users establish a new &quot;identity&quot; for my apps, e.g. -- &quot;little outliner&quot;,  I just use Twitter's. That's the open part." created="Wed, 15 May 2019 15:40:16 GMT" type="outline" urltweet="https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1128674591201689602"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nIXK-inss34&quot;&gt;Syrio Forel&lt;/a&gt;: There is only one god, and His name is Death. And there is only one thing we say to Death: not today." created="Wed, 15 May 2019 13:48:31 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nIXK-inss34"/>
				<outline text="I used to sit in my hot tub in Calif, looking up at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Live_oak&quot;&gt;live oak trees&lt;/a&gt;, and tried to convince myself that I owned them. I said to one tree, &quot;I own you.&quot; The tree laughed: &quot;You just got here. I have been here a hundred years, and I will be here hundreds more after you're gone.&quot;" created="Wed, 15 May 2019 14:05:13 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="One of my reasons for moving to the country was to have a real kitchen and to re-learn basic cooking. I used to love preparing meals. Last night I hit a milestone. A very simple dish, &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/15/dinner.png&quot;&gt;broccoli, carrots&lt;/a&gt; -- cooked lightly, then lightly covered in olive oil, soy sauce and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sriracha_sauce&quot;&gt;Sriracha&lt;/a&gt;, over rice. Just perfect. Previous iterations were basically edible. Working my way up to a full dinner for guests, maybe by Thanksgiving. But for now I'm happy to be eating well. Living in NYC made it too easy to order delicious food that was too greasy and too much and made me unhappy. " created="Wed, 15 May 2019 13:08:56 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/15/broccoli.png"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 14" created="Tue, 14 May 2019 12:29:33 GMT" name="14">
				<outline text="I'm watching the HBO miniseries &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chernobyl_(miniseries)&quot;&gt;Chernobyl&lt;/a&gt;. The USSR had a lid on leaks, but the world was figuring out what was going on because the radiation spread far outside the USSR. There was huge fear that this was the end of everything. I don't recall how we survived. " created="Tue, 14 May 2019 20:33:53 GMT" type="tweet" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/14/ussrFlag.png" tweetId="1128399997484056576" tweetUserName="davewiner"/>
				<outline text="I made the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/davefeedread&quot;&gt;davefeedread&lt;/a&gt; package a little more robust. Under some circumstances the lower-level feedparser package will return a length for an enclosure of &quot;None&quot;. This is not what my apps were expecting and as a result we missed a bunch of podcasts due to errors. Zero is much easier to handle, and there really is no correct value if the length is omitted, since it is required by RSS 2.0. But what can you do -- this is the real world, and it happens. Examples -- Radio Lab, Here's the Thing. I added a simple workaround. If the value is None, we set it to 0. Result: More podcasts to listen to. :boom: " created="Tue, 14 May 2019 17:20:54 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Twitter is a great open identity server. I use it in all my apps. If they added simple storage, we'd be looking at a new world of networked apps. This was Jack Dorsey's original idea for Twitter as a platform, btw." created="Tue, 14 May 2019 20:17:33 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I gave in and ordered an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0794W1SKP/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o00_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Amazon Echo&lt;/a&gt;. No more &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2019/05/08/124434.html&quot;&gt;WAMC in the morning&lt;/a&gt;. And whatever else comes along with the Echo. I welcome Jeff Bezos new overlord of my home." created="Tue, 14 May 2019 12:29:34 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="You have no idea how strange it was to see &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jayrosen_nyu/status/1122702732090138625&quot;&gt;Jay Rosen&lt;/a&gt; in a comedy skit on Samantha Bee's show. If you had asked me to predict the probability that I would see that in my lifetime, I would have said infinitesimal, such a small number it's impossible to measure. Life is strange. And when people say things like &quot;We all know X&quot; -- remember this story. You never really know for sure what can happen. " created="Tue, 14 May 2019 17:35:16 GMT" type="outline" urltweet="https://twitter.com/jayrosen_nyu/status/1122702732090138625"/>
				<outline text="Someone please do an explainer on &quot;Constitutional Crisis&quot; because I'm not sure people get how serious it is. " created="Tue, 14 May 2019 17:43:30 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 13" created="Mon, 13 May 2019 17:56:49 GMT" name="13">
				<outline text="I searched for a 76ers logo this morning to decorate a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2019/05/13.html#a180022&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; on my blog. Now everywhere I go on the web they think I'm a fan of the team. I'm a Knicks fan you suckers. Fuck off. " created="Tue, 14 May 2019 00:21:01 GMT" type="tweet" tweetId="1128093182380650496" tweetUserName="davewiner"/>
				<outline text="I watched last night's Game of Thrones instead of Game 7 of the playoff series between Toronto and Philadelphia. No regrets, I had more invested in the GoT story than the story of either of the NBA teams, though I do have a thing for the Sixers and respect the hell out of the Raptors. When I came out from GoT the first thing I checked was the NBA schedule, and I could see that Toronto had won. But, like everyone else, I was struck to learn &lt;i&gt;how&lt;/i&gt; they won. So many stories in this &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/13/waitingForTheResult.png&quot;&gt;fantastic photo&lt;/a&gt;, taken while the stars of the both teams wait to see if the at-the-buzzer &lt;a href=&quot;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/kawhis-buzzer-beater-might-be-felt-around-the-league/&quot;&gt;shot&lt;/a&gt; would go in. It would bounce four times before they knew the result. So much pent up energy in this, one of the greatest sports pictures of all time. Wonderful. " created="Mon, 13 May 2019 18:00:22 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/13/sixers.png"/>
				<outline text="Maybe FB should be broken up. The identity system (with storage) becomes an ICANN-like thing, and everything else is a for-profit company." created="Mon, 13 May 2019 17:56:50 GMT" type="tweet" tweetId="1127996746964066305" tweetUserName="davewiner"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 12" created="Sun, 12 May 2019 13:17:07 GMT" name="12">
				<outline text="My &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2018/02/26/024939.html&quot;&gt;mother&lt;/a&gt; was in my dreams last night. I remember one part. She's in the other room lying down reading, something she did a lot, and for some reason I called her on the phone. We hadn't spoken in a long time. She said &quot;an angel is calling&quot; in a very sentimental way. She never said stuff like that. This morning I wonder maybe I was the one who died? Happy Mother's Day mom, where ever you are, or where ever I am. :heart:" created="Sun, 12 May 2019 13:17:08 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2017/11/15/kristaps.png"/>
				<outline text="If you need reading glasses and use a computer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00NHUVFGS/ref=ox_sc_saved_title_1?smid=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;these are great&lt;/a&gt;, because they are multifocus. Good for reading the screen (medium distance) as well as up-close." created="Sun, 12 May 2019 17:31:42 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="New feature in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/?tab=chat&quot;&gt;chat tab&lt;/a&gt;, permalinks. If you roll your mouse over &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/12/permalink.png&quot;&gt;the time&lt;/a&gt;, next to the author's name, you'll see it's a link. Click the link to get to a page with just that item on it. It's a permalink to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://chat.scripting.com/story?day=2019/05/12/&amp;id=136&quot;&gt;story page&lt;/a&gt; for the item. That means you can point to a comment the same way you'd point to a blog post. It will continue to work even after there's a rollover of the chat stream (a fresh start that I'll do periodically). However story pages will not survive moderation, so this isn't a place to write a blog post. Respect the &lt;a href=&quot;http://guidelines.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;comment guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. :boom:" created="Sun, 12 May 2019 15:12:28 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="My Facebook Manifesto" created="Sun, 12 May 2019 16:22:46 GMT" type="outline" description="We have to have more than Zuck's mind working on this.">
					<outline text="We're getting the downside of networking and not enough of the upside because progress is stalled due to Facebook's dominance. " created="Sun, 12 May 2019 16:22:51 GMT" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/12/chairmanMeow.png"/>
					<outline text="If they had created a thriving ecosystem not underneath them but alongside them, no one would be talking about about breaking it up, it would already be in pieces." created="Sun, 12 May 2019 16:23:04 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Everyone who's ever pursued a monopoly in tech should see (now) why it's a dead end. And people who in their hearts felt the web should stay open, you were right, it's the only sustainable option." created="Sun, 12 May 2019 16:23:09 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It's easy and economical for Zuck to give up his monopoly and it doesn't require divestiture or breaking up. And it's necessary to get the web growing again." created="Sun, 12 May 2019 17:28:17 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Key point: We have to have more than Zuck's mind working on this." created="Sun, 12 May 2019 16:23:16 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 11" created="Sat, 11 May 2019 14:12:14 GMT" name="11">
				<outline text="Doc Searls has an &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.harvard.edu/doc/2019/05/11/podcasting/&quot;&gt;interesting idea&lt;/a&gt;. Ask the big search engines to add another &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/11/searchCategories.png&quot;&gt;category&lt;/a&gt; to search -- Podcasts. That would help make clear that podcasts are a thing of the web." created="Sat, 11 May 2019 18:00:58 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I haven't listened to a podcast in two weeks, not even the Daily podcast. I plan to come back. But right now I'm reading an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Power_Broker&quot;&gt;audiobook&lt;/a&gt; about Robert Moses and how power works. I had read it a long time ago, before I knew much about power myself. It's interesting in new ways at the other end of my life. :boom:" created="Sat, 11 May 2019 15:36:52 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Mother's Day could benefit from being split in two, one holiday for people whose mothers are alive and one for those who aren't. For the latter, it would be a time of reflection and forgiveness. Holding on to the lessons and the love, and letting the other stuff go." created="Sat, 11 May 2019 14:38:35 GMT" type="tweet" tweetId="1127221569925918720" tweetUserName="davewiner"/>
				<outline text="In 1985, Apple did something bold and brave with the Mac, they included &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AppleTalk#AppleTalk&quot;&gt;networking&lt;/a&gt; with every Mac they made. This meant that if the APIs were easy for developers to adopt, to build on, the Mac would have gotten a huge wave of Mac-only networking software. There's no doubt that in my mind that the web would have booted up on the Mac, possibly years before it did on the NeXT platform. But the Apple networking APIs were impenetrable, so only a few developers, who probably secretly got help from Apple, or who were especially good at reverse-engineering APIs, managed to break through. Too bad, because when the web finally came along in the early 90s it didn't have a GUI, it wasn't WYSIWYG, and since this was the basis of Mac software, it's why Apple was slow to adapt to the web, even if their developers, now liberated from Apple's lock-in, rushed to adapt and led the early web. Apple definitely &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Desktop_publishing&quot;&gt;benefited&lt;/a&gt; from their decision to build-in networking, but they could have hosted the web, and we all would have gotten the benefit of the Mac user interface. The web would be very different, and imho much better. This should be a lesson for Facebook. If they bend down to be &lt;i&gt;part of the web&lt;/i&gt; instead of casting the web aside, long-term they'll own a huge share of the growth that comes from lots of independent developers working alongside them. " created="Sat, 11 May 2019 14:15:44 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/11/mac.png"/>
				<outline text="Things have really changed politically in our country, but it doesn't &lt;i&gt;feel&lt;/i&gt; that way. Maybe each of us should take responsibility for changing something really big about ourselves, how we present ourselves to the world, to mark the change so we all feel it more." created="Sat, 11 May 2019 14:15:03 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="We need Facebook to have competition from independent developers. Breaking it up organizationally or financially won’t help. Breaking their lock-in will." created="Sat, 11 May 2019 14:14:50 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 9" created="Thu, 09 May 2019 11:28:20 GMT" name="09">
				<outline text="When I was a kid, my parents rented a ski house with a few other families in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Barrington,_Massachusetts&quot;&gt;Great Barrington&lt;/a&gt;. We'd go up there &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/dir/Flushing,+Queens,+NY/Great+Barrington,+Massachusetts/@41.4865615,-74.1485058,9z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m14!4m13!1m5!1m1!1s0x89c260054dc0633f:0xfaec24d1b474281e!2m2!1d-73.833079!2d40.7674987!1m5!1m1!1s0x89e6d20ba5c5f965:0xf17f6f05a00ad904!2m2!1d-73.362008!2d42.1959798!3e0&quot;&gt;via&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taconic_State_Parkway&quot;&gt;Taconic Parkway&lt;/a&gt;, and would exit at &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_York_State_Route_23&quot;&gt;Route 23&lt;/a&gt;, and that's where the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/@42.2082784,-73.6345615,3a,75y,167.81h,80.2t/am=t/data=!3m7!1e1!3m5!1sDu5bvkTav7KMcfXsIjtzWw!2e0!6s%2F%2Fgeo2.ggpht.com%2Fcbk%3Fpanoid%3DDu5bvkTav7KMcfXsIjtzWw%26output%3Dthumbnail%26cb_client%3Dmaps_sv.tactile.gps%26thumb%3D2%26w%3D203%26h%3D100%26yaw%3D45.264877%26pitch%3D0%26thumbfov%3D100!7i13312!8i6656&quot;&gt;Chief Diner&lt;/a&gt; is. I bet my brother and I, when we saw &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yelp.com/biz/martindale-chief-diner-craryville&quot;&gt;the diner&lt;/a&gt;, begged our parents to stop. It was the middle of the night (or so it felt to me, then) and they must've been tired. Kids are a pain in the ass. Anyway, I was driving on 23 today and passed the diner, remembered it from childhood, so I stopped and took a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/09/chiefDiner1.jpg&quot;&gt;couple&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/09/chiefDiner2.jpg&quot;&gt;pictures&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 09 May 2019 18:07:30 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/09/coffeeCup.png"/>
				<outline text="People say &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZybYIJtbcu0&quot;&gt;Tuca and Bertie&lt;/a&gt; is the next level of Bojack Horseman and it is that for sure. For example, in T&amp;B there are people and animals, as in Bojack, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/09/plantAsACharacter.png&quot;&gt;plants&lt;/a&gt; also have intelligence and speak and have legs and can walk and go places (and are teenagers). Also they include little bits of non-animated &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/09/humanInTuca.png&quot;&gt;human stuff&lt;/a&gt; in it. And the snarky Easter eggs are even better. But it's also got a bit of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Studio_Ghibli&quot;&gt;Studio Ghibli&lt;/a&gt; in it and trippy &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spirited_Away&quot;&gt;Spirted Away&lt;/a&gt; type stuff. I love the &lt;a href=&quot;https://deadline.com/2019/05/tiffany-haddish-ali-wong-tuca-and-bertie-interview-tribeca-1202605920/&quot;&gt;actors&lt;/a&gt;. I'm only on Episode 4 and savoring every moment." created="Thu, 09 May 2019 11:30:11 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I've been saying this for many years -- I wish as part of the publicity materials for shows, movies, even products, they produced standalone images that have a transparent background, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2015/08/30/bojack.png&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; for Bojack. I love putting them in the right margin when I'm writing about your product. It's &lt;i&gt;good&lt;/i&gt; for you. " created="Thu, 09 May 2019 11:44:46 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I use Facebook the same way I use Exxon. I need their product to get where I want to go. I don’t like what the products do to the ecosystem or the crazy attitude of the people who run the companies. But I don’t have any power over that." created="Thu, 09 May 2019 11:28:21 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 8" created="Wed, 08 May 2019 12:44:33 GMT" name="08">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZybYIJtbcu0&quot;&gt;Tuca and Bertie&lt;/a&gt; is changing my life. " created="Thu, 09 May 2019 03:04:01 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZybYIJtbcu0"/>
				<outline text="At least we know one leading Democrat won't compromise. Elizabeth Warren said it so &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.realclearpolitics.com/video/2019/05/07/warren_defends_call_to_impeach_trump_no_political_convenience_exception_to_the_constitution.html&quot;&gt;clearly&lt;/a&gt; last night on MSNBC. Our moment of compromise will come when we are forced to take a loyalty oath to Trump. You may be sure you won't do it, but in the moment you will have a conundrum as to whether or not you sign the pledge." created="Wed, 08 May 2019 15:41:23 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/08/uncleSam.png"/>
				<outline text="New &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/?tab=chat&quot;&gt;chat&lt;/a&gt; feature. Ted posted a chat message yesterday that I didn't see for many hours. Not good. Disqus used to send me an email message when a new comment is posted. So I added that feature here. I now get an email when a message is posted. So I should be responding more quickly, if I have a response that is. :rocket:" created="Wed, 08 May 2019 15:08:32 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;i&gt;Meddled&lt;/i&gt; is the wrong word for what the Russians did to the 2016 election. The proper word is hacked. The Russians hacked the 2016 election. I'm a longtime software developer and know what hacking is. This was hacking." created="Wed, 08 May 2019 13:59:06 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/column/paul-krugman&quot;&gt;Paul Krugman&lt;/a&gt; has been writing for decades about how Repubs are wrong and hypocritical about economics. He's very persuasive and of course I totally agree. Now the Dems have been wrong too, also for decades, about not standing up to the Repubs breaking our system of government. At &lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2019/05/nancy-pelosi-impeachment-obama-wall-street-torture.html&quot;&gt;every step&lt;/a&gt; they choose to ignore and overlook instead of investigating and fighting. It happened regarding torture in Iraq, the financial crisis, the Merrick Garland nomination, etc. It'd be interesting if Krugman could write one of his famous pieces about the Dems. Repubs aren't listening to him, but Democrats are. There is no option now but to stand up for the Constitution, or there will be no election to win in 2020. They can't put it off any longer, this is the end of Congress if they don't. Someone outside of government who people listen to, needs to say this. " created="Wed, 08 May 2019 13:48:06 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/08/krugman.png"/>
				<outline text="Feedback for WAMC" created="Wed, 08 May 2019 12:44:34 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I have something to say about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wamc.org/&quot;&gt;WAMC&lt;/a&gt;. Every time I tune in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wamc.org/topic/alan-chartock-message-president&quot;&gt;Alan Chartock&lt;/a&gt; is talking. He's their expert on everything, but all he says are platitudes. The first time he got my ire up he said &quot;Everyone knows that X&quot; and it pissed me off because X is not true (imho). He likes Joe Biden and Israel. He talks and talks and no one interrupts him, no wonder -- he owns the station (or so it seems)." created="Wed, 08 May 2019 12:44:57 GMT" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/08/curiousGeorge.png"/>
					<outline text="I have to listen to NPR to retain my sanity in the morning over coffee while getting my mind organized for the day ahead."/>
					<outline text="I can't believe everyone doesn't hate him."/>
					<outline text="Someone tell him to chill out please. Or retire. Yeah that would do it." created="Wed, 08 May 2019 14:02:20 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PS: There was a Law &amp; Order &lt;a href=&quot;https://lawandorder.fandom.com/wiki/Seed&quot;&gt;episode&lt;/a&gt; where it turned out that a fertility doctor had been impregnating patients with his own sperm. There was a small army of his children in NYC. Not sure if it was based on a true story. Anyway that's what it's like." created="Wed, 08 May 2019 14:02:21 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 7" created="Tue, 07 May 2019 12:57:50 GMT" name="07">
				<outline text="Living in Manhattan, with no car, I got used to FreshDirect where you order groceries via a &lt;a href=&quot;https://freshdirect.com/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, and they deliver what you ordered the next day. You develop a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/07/freshDirectList.png&quot;&gt;list&lt;/a&gt; of items you buy regularly, and shopping is a matter of reviewing that list, and re-ordering the things you need more of. Very efficient, and I rarely forgot basic items, because they floated to the top of the list. Now I'm shopping in grocery stores, basically walking around through their warehouse in realspace, doing the job FD employees do in NY, and while I like the experience in general, I often forget to restock things I've run out of. Which makes me wonder why stores don't adopt the FreshDirect user interface, let me shop for basic stuff from home via the web, even if they can't deliver.  " created="Tue, 07 May 2019 18:08:28 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/07/fdBox.png"/>
				<outline text="Political &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dabeard/status/1125780054011785219&quot;&gt;cartoon&lt;/a&gt; of the day. " created="Tue, 07 May 2019 15:14:45 GMT" type="outline" urltweet="https://twitter.com/dabeard/status/1125780054011785219"/>
				<outline text="My organization tool should help me be organized even if I am very badly organized at the moment." created="Tue, 07 May 2019 17:53:42 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="With the help of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ouchiko&quot;&gt;ouchiko&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jmgs&quot;&gt;jmgs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tommy-carlier&quot;&gt;tommy-carlier&lt;/a&gt;, yesterday's &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/116&quot;&gt;JavaScript challenge&lt;/a&gt; is solved. I learned that there's a built-in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/116#issuecomment-489985995&quot;&gt;browser function&lt;/a&gt; that does exactly what was called for, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Element/scrollIntoView&quot;&gt;scrollIntoView&lt;/a&gt;. Makes sense, in 2019 this is something every app shouldn't have to do itself. This will be part of a new app I'm working on. " created="Tue, 07 May 2019 14:08:27 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="My friend NakedJen who to me is the Mother of Dragons, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2013/11/16/nakedjensBlissBag&quot;&gt;magical person&lt;/a&gt; who can do the stuff only Daenerys Stormborn can do (and more), is now watching Game of Thrones, finally. She's in season 1. I can't say any more (here) because I know she reads this blog. I envy her, I would love to never have watched the first few seasons so it could all be new again. Also I expect to be able to hear her shriek at certain points even though she's in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/dir/Salt+Lake+City,+UT/Catskill+Mountains,+Shandaken,+NY+12464/@40.1479294,-111.1033669,4z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m14!4m13!1m5!1m1!1s0x87523d9488d131ed:0x5b53b7a0484d31ca!2m2!1d-111.8910474!2d40.7607793!1m5!1m1!1s0x89dc665668f82f31:0x3b012376423b8efa!2m2!1d-74.3821116!2d42.0092908!3e0&quot;&gt;Salt Lake City&lt;/a&gt; and I'm in the Catskills. " created="Tue, 07 May 2019 12:57:51 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/07/dragon.png"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 6" created="Mon, 06 May 2019 14:22:35 GMT" name="06">
				<outline text="A browser JavaScript challenge. Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/playingcards/&quot;&gt;demo app&lt;/a&gt;. Use the up and down arrow keys to move from card to card. When you get to the bottom of the screen the cursor moves to an object that is not visible. I want to scroll the window vertically to make the cursor object fully visible. If you look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/playingcards/code.js&quot;&gt;the code&lt;/a&gt;, you'll see a routine named  &lt;i&gt;scrollToMakeVisible. &lt;/i&gt;The goal is to fill in the body of that routine. I've opened a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/116&quot;&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt; to discuss. " created="Mon, 06 May 2019 20:19:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, if the House doesn't impeach Trump we've &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/trump-obstruction-of-justice-former-prosecutors-b5599d27-681f-4944-b04c-9743224f55e2.html?utm_source=facebook&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_campaign=organic&amp;utm_content=1100&amp;fbclid=IwAR0t5DISMJo8hs8ixlZCKEzT8t2eqBe3B7q5-3K8lqt5d68mEIemBkMo370&quot;&gt;established&lt;/a&gt; a precedent that will be hard to undo. It means an end to co-equal branches. It's a license for the executive to do whatever it wants. I wonder if people who think there's a good outcome possible from non-impeachment have thought this through. Trump may or may not be a bumbling fool with evil intent. But it's not hard to imagine a more competent fascist taking his place, and then what." created="Mon, 06 May 2019 18:55:23 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2018/05/17/mrNatural.png"/>
				<outline text="I find GORKA! fascinating because of his utter depravity and smarminess and the fact that some people obviously feel he is educated and sophisticated. I like GORKA! even better when he is being humiliated &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/existentialfish/status/1125414269179310082&quot;&gt;to his face&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 06 May 2019 16:26:13 GMT" type="outline" urltweet="https://twitter.com/existentialfish/status/1125414269179310082"/>
				<outline text="I tried cross-posting but it doesn't work. I &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2016/09/04/endingAnExperiment.html&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; it up. The problem is that the silos don't support cross-posting in any direction. They really want to be worlds unto themselves. The web, as far as they're concerned, isn't worth supporting, even though they couldn't exist without it. " created="Mon, 06 May 2019 16:12:57 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Facebook is to the web what a text editor is to a spreadsheet." created="Mon, 06 May 2019 14:22:36 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The Netflix documentary, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knock_Down_the_House&quot;&gt;Knock Down the House&lt;/a&gt;, is very good. I'm only half way through it, but it's opened my eyes." created="Mon, 06 May 2019 14:23:07 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 5" created="Sun, 05 May 2019 15:19:29 GMT" name="05">
				<outline text="Want to run against Trump and win? Nominate a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=best+woman+comedian&amp;rlz=1C5CHFA_enUS743US747&amp;oq=best+woman+comedian&amp;aqs=chrome..69i57j69i61l2j0l3.6581j0j4&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8&quot;&gt;great comedian&lt;/a&gt;, because that's Trump's &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2018/09/03/154301.html&quot;&gt;schtick&lt;/a&gt;. That's why he wins. " created="Sun, 05 May 2019 17:26:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The open web still &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1125056238209859585&quot;&gt;needs&lt;/a&gt; a great for-the-record writing system. " created="Sun, 05 May 2019 15:19:30 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="What pisses me off" created="Sun, 05 May 2019 18:15:29 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="You know what pisses me off. A guy writing the best political blog out there, on Facebook. So after I read his piece and think &quot;everyone should see this&quot; I can't send the link outside of Facebook." created="Sun, 05 May 2019 18:15:46 GMT" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/05/nemo.png"/>
					<outline text="We have this incredible thing called the web and we don't use it." created="Sun, 05 May 2019 18:15:50 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Same thing when a person I admire and who is doing great stuff to help keep the web open, writes her latest report on Medium, where it is already behind a paywall and will likely disappear the day Medium runs out of ideas how to monetize news." created="Sun, 05 May 2019 18:16:00 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Streaming in the kitchen" created="Sun, 05 May 2019 15:29:45 GMT" type="outline" description="In the last decade connectivity has gone from a promise to reality. ">
					<outline text="Now that I live in the country, in upstate NY, the only NPR station I get is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wamc.org/&quot;&gt;WAMC&lt;/a&gt;, which I'm not crazy about, primarily because there's this &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_S._Chartock&quot;&gt;one guy&lt;/a&gt; who I think is obnoxious who seems to always be on. I'm thinking it might be time to get an Amazon Echo, even though I dislike the idea of bringing an always-on listening device into my home. " created="Sun, 05 May 2019 15:29:50 GMT" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/05/kitchenRadio.png"/>
					<outline text="I posted the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1125047788499275777&quot;&gt;item above&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter without enough background info. This is for the kitchen. Of course I already know about streaming stations available in a web browser. There's no place for a laptop on the kitchen counter, along with the toaster, coffee maker, microwave, etc. People have also recommeded Sonos, but they are doing the same thing as the Amazon Echo, they run the exact same software. " created="Sun, 05 May 2019 15:29:58 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I think I know what I have to do..." created="Sun, 05 May 2019 15:30:57 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Sangean-WR-2-AMWooden-Receiver-Walnut/dp/B0009ZAA4M&quot;&gt;Sangean WR-2&lt;/a&gt; radio I currently have, which I bought in 2007 for the house in Berkeley, is a lovely product. Not cheap. But I've used it almost every day since then. Listening to the radio in the morning is part of my daily ritual. I love that I've had it so long. But of course there is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B075313J1R/ref=sspa_dk_hqp_detail_aax_0?psc=1&quot;&gt;new model&lt;/a&gt; that has all the features I want. The best one is simply that it supports Bluetooth and that means anything I can play on my iPhone that's always in my pocket I can play on the kitchen radio. It means however that I'll have to replace the radio I love so much. Oh well. " created="Sun, 05 May 2019 15:31:06 GMT"/>
					<outline text="This is a lot like replacing the 10-year-old Sony screen that I have with a new 4K screen. The quality is better, for sure, but the biggest reason to buy the newest version are all the new standards they support. Without that it remains an island, it can't connect to the other devices. In the last decade connectivity has gone from a promise to reality. " created="Sun, 05 May 2019 15:41:01 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 3" created="Fri, 03 May 2019 13:26:47 GMT" name="03">
				<outline text="God bless &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PaulLeeTicks/status/1124028655024463873&quot;&gt;William Barr&lt;/a&gt;.   " created="Fri, 03 May 2019 13:26:48 GMT" type="outline" urltweet="https://twitter.com/PaulLeeTicks/status/1124028655024463873"/>
				<outline text="Rant du jour" created="Fri, 03 May 2019 15:33:33 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I watched a little MSNBC last night and don't like the way it's going. They're turning the crisis in DC into a horse race. " created="Fri, 03 May 2019 15:33:50 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It's not Democrats vs Republicans. " created="Fri, 03 May 2019 15:33:54 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It's the United States of America vs a gang of thugs." created="Sun, 05 May 2019 19:05:10 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Don't make the Dem leadership responsible, we all did this." created="Fri, 03 May 2019 15:34:13 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It's time for the US to grow up. We've had it very very very easy. We fought two wars with no discomfort at home. We are fat and spoiled. This is not the Democrat's problem &lt;i&gt;it's all our problem.&lt;/i&gt; Including asshole moderators on TV and Republicans." created="Fri, 03 May 2019 15:34:14 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 2" created="Thu, 02 May 2019 13:57:36 GMT" name="02">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1124099138327597056&quot;&gt;Poll&lt;/a&gt;: If the final three episodes of Game of Thrones leaked tonight, would you stop everything and watch them or would you wait?" created="Thu, 02 May 2019 23:52:28 GMT" type="outline" urltweet="https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1124099138327597056"/>
				<outline text="Lots of people were working on classified ads on the web in the 90s. I had my own project, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/ads/helpWanted.html&quot;&gt;archive&lt;/a&gt; is still &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/fatpages/suites/classAds.html&quot;&gt;there&lt;/a&gt;. Journalists should stop &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2019/05/the-markup-craig-newmark-journalism?verso=true&quot;&gt;saying&lt;/a&gt; Craig Newmark is responsible. Progress happens. The web is better at classified ads. That's the story." created="Thu, 02 May 2019 19:51:09 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/02/piano.png"/>
				<outline text="The Trump obstruction has &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/02/metaObstruction.png&quot;&gt;gone meta&lt;/a&gt;. It's now layers deep, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inception&quot;&gt;Inception&lt;/a&gt;. First Trump obstructed. Now &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SpeakerPelosi/status/1123967382450515976&quot;&gt;Barr&lt;/a&gt; is obstructing Trump's obstruction. " created="Thu, 02 May 2019 15:04:54 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="As the Airplane used to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=clXoGIzUN50&quot;&gt;sing&lt;/a&gt;, one pill makes you larger... " created="Thu, 02 May 2019 15:07:08 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=clXoGIzUN50"/>
				<outline text="I've been taking pictures of my countryside explorations, and found that my top of the line &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPhone_XS&quot;&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; isn't doing a good enough job, so I thought I'd try dusting off the old &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canon_EOS_5D&quot;&gt;Canon EOS 5D&lt;/a&gt; my father left me, and see what it can do. I went though some of the pictures, the quality is amazing, esp for a camera that's over ten years old. Here's a small bit of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/02/lafayetteStreet2011.png&quot;&gt;picture&lt;/a&gt; I took on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Bleecker+St+%26+Lafayette+St,+New+York,+NY+10012/@40.7259294,-73.9968293,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x89c259855fdd5293:0xd39ec45d9866811e!8m2!3d40.7259294!4d-73.9946406&quot;&gt;Lafayette St&lt;/a&gt; in NYC. It does beautiful work. " created="Thu, 02 May 2019 14:12:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="A longtime blogging friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.danconover.com/&quot;&gt;Dan Conover&lt;/a&gt; is writing on Facebook these days, which is a shame, because his best pieces get me thinking enough that I want to write my own post that expands on his thinking, like the one he wrote the other day about splitting the US in two. Dan lives in South Carolina. Former journalist. I met him on my visit to Spartanberg in &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2005/02/15.html&quot;&gt;2005&lt;/a&gt;, as part of a great auto tour through the south. I learned a lot at every stop. So Dan wrote that the problems of the US are much bigger than a terrible choice for president in 2016, it has to do with the compromise that was made at the beginning of the country when it was just 3 million people (today's population of Oklahoma) because they built a country around two very different economies and cultures -- agrarian and urban. It's only grown more pronounced in 2019. We just can't live together. The US needs a Brexit. Of course we aren't going to get one (it's impossible). I wish you could read his whole piece. " created="Thu, 02 May 2019 13:57:37 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/05/02/southCarolinaMap.png"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="May 1" created="Wed, 01 May 2019 14:15:15 GMT" name="01">
				<outline text="New version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/davefeedread&quot;&gt;davefeedread&lt;/a&gt; with simple support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.blog.wordpress.com/2009/09/07/rss-in-the-clouds/&quot;&gt;rssCloud&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 01 May 2019 14:35:02 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedRead/blob/master/examples/cloud/read.js&quot;&gt;A new demo&lt;/a&gt; -- a realistic feed polling app, gets realtime updates from feeds with &amp;lt;cloud&gt; elements as spec'd in RSS 2.0. " created="Wed, 01 May 2019 14:45:20 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The Attorney General is not the people's lawyer, he represents the United States. The whole thing. The history of the US, the future, the international interests, it's laws, the justice system, and on and on. It a huge job." created="Wed, 01 May 2019 19:40:57 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The Globe and Mail are starting to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AMcKie/status/1123629325939617792&quot;&gt;re-introduce RSS feeds&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Wed, 01 May 2019 17:51:04 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I wrote: &quot;If I were the CEO of a news org I would change priority from collecting members to collecting sources.&quot; I was asked to expand on this. Why would sources want to affiliate with a news organization. What would the benefits be? I &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1123583308485492742&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; there were three. 1. To have his or her point of view reflected in news stories. 2. To network with other experts, learn from them, discuss, advance the art. 3. Prestige, validation.   " created="Wed, 01 May 2019 14:15:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="My new &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/owillis/status/1123592455952191488&quot;&gt;ringtone&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Wed, 01 May 2019 15:18:21 GMT" type="outline" urltweet="https://twitter.com/owillis/status/1123592455952191488"/>
				</outline>
			</outline>
		</body>
	</opml>
