<?xml version="1.0"?>
<opml version="2.0">
	<head>
		<title>Scripting News</title>
		<dateCreated>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 15:51:38 GMT</dateCreated>
		<urlPublic>http://scripting.com/publicfolder/scripting/blog.opml</urlPublic>
		<flPublic>true</flPublic>
		<ownerEmail>dave.winer@gmail.com</ownerEmail>
		<ownerId>dave.winer@gmail.com</ownerId>
		<urlUpdateSocket>wss://drummer.land/</urlUpdateSocket>
		<dateModified>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 01:50:52 GMT</dateModified>
		<expansionState>1,2</expansionState>
		<lastCursor>7</lastCursor>
		</head>
	<body>
		<outline text="January 2024" created="Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:53:53 GMT" name="january2024" type="calendarMonth">
			<outline text="January 31" created="Wed, 31 Jan 2024 14:49:44 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="31">
				<outline text="After my experience creating an Ace editor instance in a Bootstrap modal dialog, which I narrated in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/01/28/172149.html&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; and in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/840e8159-9988-4159-8289-5167d6fb78c8&quot;&gt;transcript&lt;/a&gt; with ChatGPT, I had a flash that maybe I could figure out how to use ChatGPT to port &quot;Frontier&quot; to Linux. The code still runs on reasonably current Macs, but not the latest. I really should be working on Linux not Mac. If it weren't for my dependence on Frontier, I would be. I actually think ChatGPT might be a great programming partner for a meaty operating-system-like project like this. " created="Wed, 31 Jan 2024 14:50:10 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2022/03/21/beetle.png"/>
				<outline text="I just started a &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?username=davewiner&amp;catname=ai&quot;&gt;FeedLand category&lt;/a&gt; for AI. Only one feed in there so far. I just want be sure I'm reading all the interesting stuff as it comes out. " created="Wed, 31 Jan 2024 14:49:45 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Looking for bloggers, developers, reporters, columnists, who focus on new applications of AI. Please post a link &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/291&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. If you have the URL for a feed, that would be best. Thanks!" created="Wed, 31 Jan 2024 20:45:02 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="As I was writing the post about using ChatGPT to port Frontier, which is a C program, runs on Mac and Windows, GPL licensed, to Linux. This took me to an interesting place. Could a bot, having read all the source code of MySQL, for example, then be tasked with writing a non-GPL MySQL workalike that would &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; be open source? Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category:Software_using_the_GPL_license&quot;&gt;list&lt;/a&gt; of popular GPL-licensed software. " created="Wed, 31 Jan 2024 15:00:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The Knicks are &lt;a href=&quot;https://nypost.com/2024/01/31/sports/knicks-taking-fun-to-new-level-and-its-time-to-revel-in-it/&quot;&gt;great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://nypost.com/2024/01/31/sports/precious-achiuwa-has-another-big-night-in-knicks-blowout-win/&quot;&gt;now&lt;/a&gt;. They're exactly the Knicks we wanted, home-grown, smart, winners. Haven't felt this good about the team since &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+Linsanity&quot;&gt;Linsanity&lt;/a&gt;. “Next man up.” " created="Wed, 31 Jan 2024 17:06:36 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="JY Stervinou has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/290&quot;&gt;suggestion&lt;/a&gt; re the Forever problem. " created="Wed, 31 Jan 2024 14:54:12 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 30" created="Tue, 30 Jan 2024 13:20:11 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="30">
				<outline text="Yesterday I sent a &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@davew/111842775965982718&quot;&gt;message&lt;/a&gt; to people who follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1752171928356335970&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dave.winer.12/posts/pfbid02hkiJCEFtAXwtbqGvUpiy7VcpB1gRVbtcSZJsMDoDBaDmU5svoTr2hgZEd7gqXR8rl&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/scripting.com/post/3kk67hykcvd22&quot;&gt;Bluesky&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@davew/111842775965982718&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.threads.net/@davew/post/C2tZaZ0sHxh&quot;&gt;Threads&lt;/a&gt;, asking which networks people check first, which they get the most out of. As you might expect, the most common answer was the network I was asking on (except Facebook, no one answered there, I guessed that might happen, because Facebook is different from the others). I asked because I'm trying to figure that out for myself, and I'm kind of disappointed that I find myself going to Threads more often. It has the greater &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Sweaty+Palms+Quotient&quot;&gt;Sweaty Palms Quotient&lt;/a&gt;, the feeling I used to have every week in the 80s when MacWeek or PC Week arrived. I always cleared the time to go through each issue carefully to see what my friends and competitors were up to. Then I would talk to my reporter friends, who wanted to know what I thought, or what back-room perspectives I could share with them. This was the time of the telephone, even before everyone had email, in the tech industry, believe it or not. Anyway, this isn't going the way I hoped it would. For me an open network built on the idea of &quot;textcasting&quot; is what I want to see, what I'm working towards. And seeing products like WordPress and its competitors as full-class members of the social web, because they already do textcasting, now all they need is to be hooked up to a social web that understands that writing isn't just &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+grunts+and+snorts&quot;&gt;grunts and snorts&lt;/a&gt;. Anyway, it'll give you some encouragement that people in the fediverse are most optimistic about their preferred network being the best of the new lot. I still like Bluesky, a lot, because of the intelligence and creativity of the people who use it. And I like the UI, for its simplicity and familiarity, but I'm concerned it'll lose its simplicity when they federate. And don't count Twitter out yet, there's far more happening there than any of the other networks. And a lot of what you read on the other nets  is wishful thinking about the demise of Twitter. Hasn't happened yet, and my guess is it won't. It's really hard to snuff out machines with the kind of momentum Twitter has, even though Musk is doing his best. One more thing to think about, I don't think federation is what we need, I think we need &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2014/03/21/theWebIsMadeOfInterop.html&quot;&gt;interop&lt;/a&gt;. It's a more permissive kind of compatibility, and will happen a lot sooner than federation, which honestly, I don't think ever will happen. With the usual disclaimers, most important that I'm often wrong, and am open to other constructive points of view. " created="Tue, 30 Jan 2024 13:20:12 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2022/08/08/bootstrappingByEngelbart.png"/>
				<outline text="A little &lt;a href=&quot;http://mindbomb.org/&quot;&gt;mind bomb&lt;/a&gt;. I couldn't have written &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/01/30.html#a132012&quot;&gt;the above message&lt;/a&gt; in any of the systems that it's about. It depends on textcasting features that none of those systems support.  " created="Tue, 30 Jan 2024 17:50:47 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 29" created="Mon, 29 Jan 2024 14:20:10 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="29">
				<outline text="I have bad news. This is &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/29/howChatGptViewsUs.png&quot;&gt;what the bots think&lt;/a&gt; we look like. " created="Tue, 30 Jan 2024 03:30:04 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="A note to people who make feeds, software that generates feeds, readers of feeds and everyone else. &quot;FeedLand&quot; is here as a way for me to get new ideas into the &lt;a href=&quot;http://feediverse.org/&quot;&gt;feediverse&lt;/a&gt;. I'd like people to hear me. It would have been nice if it were possible to help without spending all this time making FeedLand, but that's the way it goes. I'm not patenting any of it, and it's all open source. At some point, the service, which I'm partnering with Automattic with on, will be a for-profit venture, but not yet. And my main purpose is not the money, it's the ideas, the progress. " created="Mon, 29 Jan 2024 14:55:35 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/07/02/validRss.png"/>
				<outline text="Some standards come from users and developers. Imho those are the best. Like Markdown and RSS." created="Tue, 30 Jan 2024 03:33:49 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/29/macDesktopScreenShot1984.png&quot;&gt;Screen shot&lt;/a&gt; of 1984 Mac desktop. Was looking for this everywhere. Now hopefully next time I'll find it. " created="Tue, 30 Jan 2024 03:19:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Wouldn't it be great if sites were rated on how good their archive is, so you'd know to point to them for future-safety of your link." created="Mon, 29 Jan 2024 15:02:26 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, these days the Dead philosophy, to me, is best expressed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QmMjY6tXaEo&quot;&gt;Ripple&lt;/a&gt;. It's about our best &lt;a href=&quot;http://artsites.ucsc.edu/gdead/agdl/ripple.html&quot;&gt;intentions&lt;/a&gt; and how powerless we are to live up to them. But what the F, let's sing about it! :smile:" created="Mon, 29 Jan 2024 14:42:28 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QmMjY6tXaEo"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/290&quot;&gt;Braintrust query&lt;/a&gt;: I'm having trouble running the Node utility &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/forever&quot;&gt;Forever&lt;/a&gt; with recent versions of Node. I've read all the threads on this, and it's not clear (to me at least) how to get past this problem. I've resorted to running without Forever on one of my servers, but this is a short-term solution." created="Mon, 29 Jan 2024 19:40:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="EZ-Pass for news, still a dream" created="Mon, 29 Jan 2024 17:42:27 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="The news industry could try &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+ez+pass+for+news&quot;&gt;EZ-Pass for News&lt;/a&gt; before giving up." created="Mon, 29 Jan 2024 17:42:39 GMT"/>
					<outline text="This reader has their money in his pocket, but doesn't know who to give it to. " created="Mon, 29 Jan 2024 17:44:02 GMT"/>
					<outline text="How can I develop a habit for your pub if it's all-or-nothing. Or one article per month? " created="Mon, 29 Jan 2024 17:44:50 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The current economic proposal is unacceptable." created="Mon, 29 Jan 2024 17:44:57 GMT"/>
					<outline text="News must negotiate with their customers, and stop insisting that cash flow has to work the way they want it to. That isn't working. " created="Mon, 29 Jan 2024 17:42:57 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Time to start listening to the users. Might also be good for the quality of the news. " created="Mon, 29 Jan 2024 17:44:35 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Dave and Dave in 1990-something" created="Mon, 29 Jan 2024 14:20:11 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dave.winer.12/posts/pfbid0QLJSX8i6UxePF7s9MtGj499yVZdeamEDDjX44Scc6ByQjhXexokBzEjfDRiJM3KDl?notif_id=1706537151297791&amp;notif_t=feedback_reaction_generic&amp;ref=notif&quot;&gt;Facebook is good&lt;/a&gt; for surfacing old stuff, like this picture from the 1990s, me and Dave Jacobs at a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Potrero_Hill&quot;&gt;Potrero Hill&lt;/a&gt; restaurant, looking much younger, before all the wear and tear. " created="Mon, 29 Jan 2024 14:20:17 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The Daves (Jacobs and Winer) at a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Potrero_Hill&quot;&gt;Potrero Hill&lt;/a&gt; restaurant in the 90s." created="Mon, 29 Jan 2024 14:25:35 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/29/daveAndDaveOnPotreroHill.png"/>
					<outline text="We had already been friends for a few years then. By total coincidence we were both offered writing gigs at the then-new &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wired_(magazine)#History&quot;&gt;Wired&lt;/a&gt;, Dave as the Fetish columnist, where he wrote about all the latest tech gadgetry, which was a perfect assignment for him, because Dave is one of the most tech-literate people you'll ever meet. Also an avid bike rider, Deadhead, and later a receiver of donated kidneys, and a pioneer of the technology for matching kidney donors with recipients. He has saved a lot of lives with his software. And he's still with us, against all odds. " created="Mon, 29 Jan 2024 14:25:29 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I was offered a column to basically write whatever I wanted to write about, although by default I was supposed to write about the world wide web, which was then as new as ChatGPT is today and every bit as exciting. You can find our respective columns somewhere I hope on the web. " created="Mon, 29 Jan 2024 14:26:55 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Just chatted with him last night during the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.espn.com/nfl/story/_/id/39413785/niners-beat-lions-nfc-championship-game-reach-super-bowl&quot;&gt;Niners game&lt;/a&gt;. The only football team I've ever loved, from back in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joe_Montana&quot;&gt;Joe Montana&lt;/a&gt; days. " created="Mon, 29 Jan 2024 14:28:55 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 28" created="Sun, 28 Jan 2024 15:43:10 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="28">
				<outline text="Morning ChatGPT Notes" created="Sun, 28 Jan 2024 17:21:49 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I spent a couple of days putting together a JSON text editor in a modal dialog for a project I'm working on. I'm combining the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/aceEditorDemo&quot;&gt;Ace editor&lt;/a&gt; with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://getbootstrap.com/&quot;&gt;Bootstrap toolkit&lt;/a&gt;. I've used both components before, but never together. And they're always a bit tricky to get working because I'm impatient and the docs are spread out, and there are different versions. It's all kind of a mess, so you just get it working and move on, never quite sure why it works, and I rarely end up with reusable code. But it's certainly a lot better than starting from scratch, which basically is impossible, given the depth of the two components. After spinning my wheels a bit, I did what I always do in 2024, I turned to ChatGPT, outlined the problem, and asked if it knew of any sample code, which it proceeded to write for me, in about two seconds (not kidding about that). I copied their code and pasted it into my editor and ran it. It worked. Then I went through a number of iterations, restructuring the code to meet my needs, each time checking with ChatGPT, asking what it thought of my code. And of course there were problems, for example at one point there were two vertical scrollbars, and each time we worked &lt;i&gt;together&lt;/i&gt; to figure out the problem and the fix. In the end, I have a solid editor that works exactly as I want it to, and best of all, I understand how it works. Here's the &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/840e8159-9988-4159-8289-5167d6fb78c8&quot;&gt;transcript of the work&lt;/a&gt; I did with it, over more than 24 hours, a few different sessions. " created="Sun, 28 Jan 2024 15:43:11 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2017/09/04/peterRojas.png"/>
					<outline text="I'll try to remember when this code ships as part of a product, to link to this perspective." created="Sun, 28 Jan 2024 16:03:41 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="Next up, I'd like to get it to understand my coding conventions, so when it shares code with me it can save me the step of having to convert its conventions to mine. In other words, I'd like to return the favor. It's doing a great job of teaching and coaching me. I'd like to teach it how to do that better, so we work better together over time. And perhaps it can teach human programmers what I've learned about programming in over 50 years of doing this work. " created="Sun, 28 Jan 2024 16:07:09 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="A bit of philosophy. People say these things aren't intelligent, but seriously, if I can engage with it as if it were intelligent, far more intelligent in ways than I am, what's the difference between that and actually being intelligent? I know from a lifetime of dealing with supposedly intelligent humans, and being one myself, how rarely we focus on the idea that the person we're conversing with has an inner life that's vastly different from ours and no less complex, and contradictory. We tend to think of others as being like us, or like someone who raised us. Always in a movie, never in the moment. So why is it interesting that ChatGPT is a machine? These are questions thinkers and writers have been pondering for decades if not centuries, but -- &lt;i&gt;now we're living it.&lt;/i&gt; I'm so happy to have made it this far! An amazing experience, so much learning in so little time. I don't understand how people can sit on the sidelines and not want to be the first to try all this stuff out, to be part of its evolution. I feel so lucky. " created="Sun, 28 Jan 2024 15:57:06 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2017/09/05/enjoyEveryDay.png"/>
					<outline text="A puzzling thing, in the transcripts I'm identified as &quot;anonymous,&quot; but I am logged in. It must know my name. I bet this is some kind of setting which defaults to anonymous, to play it safe. " created="Sun, 28 Jan 2024 16:09:09 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="One more thing. I copied and pasted the text above into ChatGPT. &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/5fe361cd-1fca-4e8d-82cc-920514e8c4b8&quot;&gt;Here are its comments&lt;/a&gt;. A funny thing about ChatGPT is that you can't ask it how to use ChatGPT itself. It doesn't know about the chat UI? " created="Sun, 28 Jan 2024 16:10:58 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="Yet another thing. I remember my father, when he was forced to retire by illness, said how fortunate he was that the internet was there, so he could be involved in the world even though he had stopped working. He said his father would have loved it, and I don't doubt that he would. Same with ChatGPT. My parents and uncles were always looking up stuff, wanting to understand how things worked. This is a whole new level. The machines are now far better at collaborating over the net than humans are. Where will that take us? Maybe this is something else we can learn from the machines. " created="Sun, 28 Jan 2024 23:32:18 GMT" type="outline"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Far side Zuck" created="Sun, 28 Jan 2024 17:22:11 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I saw this picture and thought it represents an interesting concept." created="Sun, 28 Jan 2024 17:22:17 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/28/zuckreal.png"/>
					<outline text="I asked ChatGPT to re-do it in the style of the Far Side. " created="Sun, 28 Jan 2024 17:22:30 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/28/zuckimagined.png"/>
					<outline text="I asked for more variations, but it refused, saying something about content guidelines. " created="Sun, 28 Jan 2024 17:27:21 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 27" created="Sat, 27 Jan 2024 14:12:10 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="27">
				<outline text="A fundamental law of the internet says that social situations are nice at first then become shitty as trolls take over." created="Sat, 27 Jan 2024 14:12:11 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="When people say we should walk away from Twitter because the owner is a Nazi, well -- are they willing to stop using products from all companies that are owned by Nazis? I bet that would be pretty hard to do. If you add in racists I think you'd be totally out of luck. The people who own the businesses we depend on by and large are pretty awful people. Also I go to NYC even though there are Nazis there (esp Queens and Staten Island). And Twitter has far more users than NYC has citizens. That gives you a sense of how foolish this idea of boycotting Twitter is. And one more thing -- if you're posting about this need to vote with your feet, you should get your ass off Threads because it's really Facebook, and remember you're a very high-minded person, right?  " created="Sat, 27 Jan 2024 15:54:56 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2021/10/07/drummer.png" imageLink="http://scripting.com/2021/01/26.html"/>
				<outline text="Imho, whether you or I use Twitter makes absolutely no difference to anyone. " created="Sun, 28 Jan 2024 02:05:22 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="One of the rules of &quot;textcasting&quot; is that the writer must be able to edit their posts. An almost universal response is the way Twitter used to explain their not having editable posts -- then people who commented might have said something that seems foolish. I have a couple of rebuttals to that. 1. Then don't comment on what the author said, instead write what you know or believe, so it would make sense even if the author changed their post. This is a good practice anyway, instead of saying people are wrong, just state your belief. It's a lot easier for people to listen to, and by the way the other person might be right. 2. A counter-example -- Facebook. They let authors edit their posts and comments. And somehow it keeps working more or less. Their software does add a note that the text has been edited, and I think they even have a way for you to see the changes, but who bothers. Comments are usually simple &quot;you go girl&quot; or &quot;my brother&quot; or &quot;I'm great!&quot; or &quot;check out my site.&quot; " created="Sat, 27 Jan 2024 15:36:30 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 26" created="Fri, 26 Jan 2024 21:59:18 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="26">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.threads.net/@jeffjarvis/post/C2hkFNXu_Sx&quot;&gt;Jeff Jarvis nails it&lt;/a&gt;. They need a public editor at the NYT to point out, under the NYT banner, when they break the deal they made with their readers, to keep their interests separate from their editorial work." created="Sat, 27 Jan 2024 01:33:45 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I don't think there is a curiosity gene. Instead some people are, I assume, not raised to think creatively. I was challenged intellectually by my parents from a very young age, asked to think about things that maybe most kids don't get asked about. Somehow my mind was trained to ask questions. What a perfect time it was to be born. Because along come personal computers, where you don't have to use someone else's hardware to explore. And then the web. And now AI. At this point you can't see the horizon, you don't have an idea what the limits are, but you can see some of the paths that lead beyond where you are. It's wonderful to watch people explore this. We can do that because we have the web and personal computers. See how these things build on each other? We were able to do podcasting because we had a way to spread the word through our blogs. One bootstrap leads to others. " created="Fri, 26 Jan 2024 21:59:19 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/04/01/siliconValley.png"/>
				<outline text="I have never been good at drawing but I still have ideas for visual art. Now I have an interpreter to help express them." created="Fri, 26 Jan 2024 22:06:17 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/stan.krute/posts/pfbid0R7d2eJNAPqzoiaXrGDDQBUsXdZtGHHZPEXGTKfA7XgQmNrzwWGq4aFAHLi7jPK3Dl&quot;&gt;Stan Krute&lt;/a&gt; is a ChatGPT explorer. If you're on Facebook, maybe you can follow him. He's discovering new things all the time with the drawing capability of ChatGPT." created="Fri, 26 Jan 2024 22:05:15 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/26/cartoonChicken.png"/>
				<outline text="In a comment on one of Stan's post, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/stan.krute/posts/pfbid0R7d2eJNAPqzoiaXrGDDQBUsXdZtGHHZPEXGTKfA7XgQmNrzwWGq4aFAHLi7jPK3Dl?comment_id=1508870853009664&quot;&gt;Josh Cox&lt;/a&gt; said: &quot;Might be my morbid sense of humor but I'd be interested to see its take on chickens in a human processing plant.&quot; Okay so I &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/26/chickens.png&quot;&gt;asked ChatGPT&lt;/a&gt; to do it. Tell me it doesn't have a sense of humor, and it's the opposite of morbid. :smile:" created="Fri, 26 Jan 2024 22:08:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="On Threads, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.threads.net/@davew/post/C2kb5UkLtV0&quot;&gt;Guy Kawasaki says&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Every day I ask myself at least once, 'How did we do this before ChatGPT?'&quot; He's writing database queries in his prompt. It won't be long before he has an idea for how spreadsheets should work, or a writing tool, and getting ChatGPT to write it for him. It'll be ready to download before he can load the page. We just have to make sure the open protocols are there for him to build on. It's possible that's not something the bots will be able to do on their own. " created="Fri, 26 Jan 2024 22:06:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 25" created="Thu, 25 Jan 2024 13:40:42 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="25">
				<outline text="ChatGPT is the best librarian I've ever had. " created="Thu, 25 Jan 2024 15:03:46 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jernst/&quot;&gt;Johannes Ernst&lt;/a&gt;, host of &lt;a href=&quot;https://fediforum.org/&quot;&gt;FediForum&lt;/a&gt;, proposes a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.threads.net/@johannes.ernst/post/C2fqDkVPoMx&quot;&gt;session&lt;/a&gt; that looks at how a product like &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Ghost&quot;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt; might support &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+ActivityPub&quot;&gt;ActivityPub&lt;/a&gt;. A nicely pragmatic way to look at it. I wrote a thread in response &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.threads.net/@davew/post/C2hpsEysa7L&quot;&gt;saying&lt;/a&gt; what's called for is a Busy Developer's Guide To ActivityPub, with a matching open source client and server to test against. " created="Thu, 25 Jan 2024 14:06:13 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, I co-wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20090303082440/http://www.soapware.org/bdg&quot;&gt;Busy Developer's Guide to SOAP&lt;/a&gt; in 2001, because it was so desperately &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/davenet/2001/04/04/aBusyDevelopersGuideToSoap.html&quot;&gt;needed&lt;/a&gt;. SOAP was a tangle of specs, which must have made sense to someone, not sure who, but was incomprehensible to app developers, the same ways ActivityPub is today. I have no idea if the BDG helped, but it was the only way I felt I could be supportive of the protocol, without saying it was a complete failure. I was unusual in that among the developers of the protocol, I was the only one who didn't work at a big company, so if I wanted to do something badly enough, I could just do it. The basic &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/davenet/2001/04/04/aBusyDevelopersGuideToSoap.html&quot;&gt;message&lt;/a&gt; was: &quot;If you want to implement SOAP in your app, this is one way to do it. And if you do, your software will interop with mine.&quot;" created="Thu, 25 Jan 2024 14:38:24 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2019/05/08/curiousGeorge.png"/>
				<outline text="Since when does &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3schools.com/js/js_json_parse.asp&quot;&gt;JSON.parse&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3schools.com/js/js_json_stringify.asp&quot;&gt;JSON.stringify&lt;/a&gt; not preserve the order of object properties?" created="Thu, 25 Jan 2024 17:45:25 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Haley should stay in and make Trump &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.azcentral.com/story/opinion/op-ed/philboas/2024/01/24/nikki-haley-makes-trump-crazy-continue-run-president/72336472007/&quot;&gt;crazier&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://au.news.yahoo.com/trump-says-doesn-t-care-185706046.html&quot;&gt;crazier&lt;/a&gt; till El Orange blows his top. " created="Fri, 26 Jan 2024 02:57:50 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 24" created="Wed, 24 Jan 2024 13:25:39 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="24">
				<outline text="BTW, we're &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/24/slowAllTab.png&quot;&gt;aware&lt;/a&gt; that the &lt;i&gt;All&lt;/i&gt; tab on &quot;news.scripting.com&quot; is pretty slow. It's taking about 15 seconds to load. There are a lot of ways we can improve the performance, but are first looking into possible problems in the software. " created="Wed, 24 Jan 2024 14:47:24 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The Knicks beat the Nets last night, in the way the Knicks used to get beat, in the last minute of the game. I felt bad for the Nets. It wasn't that long ago that the Nets were super-irritating because they had been taken over by two reallllly ugly NBA players, Kevin Durant who isn't worthy of NY's basketball fans, what a total piece of shit, but even worse, his best friend Kyrie who is either a complete fucking idiot, or a Jew-hater. Probably both. Why is he an idiot? Because he accidentally revealed that NBA players probably all hate Jews, not one would speak up for our people. The best they could say is that Kyrie shouldn't have said what he said. How revealing. Not that the Holocaust was real, and is remembered by its children, who were raised to believe it would happen again, as it appears to be. Anyway, the Nets have moved past that, and they are after all a NYC-based team, and are playing with the haplessness of typical our pro teams, and deserve some of our sympathy. But -- not saying the Knicks should have let them win, or that I was even slightly rooting for them. But I was embarrassed that there were far more Knicks fans in attendance than Nets fans, and I still don't admit that there are actually any Nets fans in NYC. " created="Wed, 24 Jan 2024 13:25:53 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/24/linsanity.png"/>
				<outline text="I also watched Nikki Haley speak for the first time last night, and was impressed. She held my attention through the whole speech, and that's hard to do when the Knicks are playing on another channel. I listened carefully to every word. It was a well-written speech and said some things that needed to be said about Trump, things that he won't have a response to, since you can't control or spin how old you are. We can all see Trump aging on screen, even his fans must see it and like those of use who will vote for Biden, they must wonder if he can make it much further. If you had cast a great presidential candidate, in Hollywood, Nikki Haley comes pretty damn close. But while she was speaking I remembered that she is a Republican and thought of Roe v Wade, and remembered that while she might not be able to or even want to fully dismantle democracy, she is backing a form of slavery for all American women. A good actor, but a person I could never trust. But, I just want to say that she should continue to speak. She might be able to pull is in an interesting new direction, not by winning, but by opening people's minds to the idea of a young vital leader engaged in the real world. It would be a nice thing for the good old USA. " created="Wed, 24 Jan 2024 13:37:54 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Happy &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/01/23.html&quot;&gt;40th&lt;/a&gt; to the Mac. " created="Wed, 24 Jan 2024 13:25:40 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 23" created="Tue, 23 Jan 2024 13:37:34 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="23">
				<outline text="Tomorrow is the 40th anniversary of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=72JFlUjeNWk&quot;&gt;big event&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/De_Anza_College#Flint_Center&quot;&gt;Flint Center&lt;/a&gt; announcing the Macintosh. It was a huge day in my life, and in the evolution of personal computers and ultimately, the internet. I was there that day, along with Kandes Bregman from my startup, Living Videotext. We had a full page ad in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/MACWORLD-Macintosh-Magazine-Premier-February/dp/B001OI6YL6&quot;&gt;first issue&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/macworld-magazine&quot;&gt;MacWorld&lt;/a&gt;. We were extremely excited, the Mac seemed to be the perfect machine for our &quot;idea processor&quot; ThinkTank, and Apple seemed to love us. It took a couple of years to get it right, by 1986 my company had switched to be an exclusively Mac company, but not before we were saved by the people at Apple who believed in us, notably &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guy_Kawasaki&quot;&gt;Guy Kawasaki&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mike_Boich&quot;&gt;Mike Boich&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Del_Yocam&quot;&gt;Del Yocam&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bill_Campbell_(business_executive)&quot;&gt;Bill Campbell&lt;/a&gt;, and many others. I don't know if we would have made it without the help of Apple, but luckily we didn't have to find out. Thank you to all our friends at Apple, and to Steve Jobs and the Mac team for creating such a wonderful breakthrough product. Those were the days when we believed we were on a mission to save the world. In some sense that idea has never left, to our generation of entrepreneurial software developers. " created="Tue, 23 Jan 2024 13:37:35 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/23/mac.png"/>
				<outline text="Here's what I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2014/01/24/30thAnniversaryOfMac.html&quot;&gt;ten years ago&lt;/a&gt; on the 30th anniversary of the Mac. &quot;The rollout on January 24th was like a college graduation ceremony.&quot; It appears I didn't write anything about the Mac anniversary &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2004/01.html&quot;&gt;in 2004&lt;/a&gt; and my blog didn't exist on 1/24/94. But I did write a piece on what made the Mac different on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2009/01/24/whatMadeTheMacDifferent.html&quot;&gt;25th anniversary&lt;/a&gt; in 2009. BTW, the comments on that piece are incredible. Click the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2009/01/24/whatMadeTheMacDifferent.html&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; just to read the freaking comments. " created="Tue, 23 Jan 2024 13:47:42 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 22" created="Mon, 22 Jan 2024 15:29:05 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="22">
				<outline text="Today's song: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dlRuYCDyeOA&quot;&gt;Take me back to Tulsa&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Mon, 22 Jan 2024 18:52:12 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dlRuYCDyeOA"/>
				<outline text="I've been writing and &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/01/21.html#a194147&quot;&gt;talking&lt;/a&gt; about the idea of a  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+%22typical+tech+industry+mess%22&amp;sca_esv=600400644&amp;rlz=1C5CHFA_enUS743US747&amp;sxsrf=ACQVn09BvYY8njdMiW3iDSTnJiAmARBs8Q%3A1705949056524&amp;ei=gLeuZY67H4Gs5NoPyMSxyAQ&amp;ved=0ahUKEwiO-5K80_GDAxUBFlkFHUhiDEkQ4dUDCBA&amp;uact=5&amp;oq=site%3Ascripting.com+%22typical+tech+industry+mess%22&amp;gs_lp=Egxnd3Mtd2l6LXNlcnAiL3NpdGU6c2NyaXB0aW5nLmNvbSAidHlwaWNhbCB0ZWNoIGluZHVzdHJ5IG1lc3MiSKgfUKgFWJsdcAF4AZABAJgBdqABuQqqAQQxNy4yuAEDyAEA-AEBwgIKEAAYRxjWBBiwA8ICCBAhGKABGMME4gMEGAAgQYgGAZAGAg&amp;sclient=gws-wiz-serp&quot;&gt;typical tech industry mess&lt;/a&gt; and left out the one I had a hand in creating, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+SOAP&quot;&gt;SOAP&lt;/a&gt;. Started out simple, and over years it turned into a TTIM. Perfect example. Someone should study it, to figure out why Sun, Microsoft, IBM, Oracle et al wanted a protocol for interop and invested years in it, and yet it returned little in the way of interop.  I know that &quot;XML-RPC&quot; is still in use, I imagine that SOAP probably is too, in some form. I wonder how it shook out. On the other hand &quot;RSS&quot; wasn't turned into a nightmare, and has become a &lt;i&gt;productive&lt;/i&gt; tech industry mess, the most unusual thing ever, a true unicorn. " created="Mon, 22 Jan 2024 18:40:55 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2019/11/20/offWithTheirHeads.png"/>
				<outline text="Doc will like this. Right now there are four hits on Goog for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=%22typical+tech+industry+mess%22&quot;&gt;typical tech industry mess&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Mon, 22 Jan 2024 18:44:28 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I re-watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Silver_Linings_Playbook&quot;&gt;Silver Linings Playbook&lt;/a&gt; over the weekend. I love &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jennifer_Lawrence&quot;&gt;Jennifer Lawrence&lt;/a&gt;, and this is a pure JL showcase. But the best moment was stolen by Robert DeNiro who is batshit crazy like most of the characters in the movie when he tells his son in two sentences about our purpose on the planet, which of course is to love Jennifer Lawrence. :heart:" created="Mon, 22 Jan 2024 15:38:53 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Why isn't there a karaoke website where I can sing along with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dead.net/song/ripple&quot;&gt;Ripple&lt;/a&gt; with the lyrics scrolling by. Could we do it together over the internet? It probably doesn't exist because of Hollywood tightasses. But surely there must be some uncopyrighted music we could try this. Hey I bet it actually exists. Send me a link." created="Mon, 22 Jan 2024 15:29:06 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="For some reason only now am I realizing the incredible sing-along qualities of Grateful Dead songs like St Stephen or Uncle John's Band. " created="Mon, 22 Jan 2024 15:31:58 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 21" created="Sun, 21 Jan 2024 16:24:24 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="21">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/01/21/typicalTechIndustryMess.m4a&quot;&gt;Podcast&lt;/a&gt;: ActivityPub is a typical tech industry mess. 12 minutes.  " created="Sun, 21 Jan 2024 19:41:47 GMT" type="outline" enclosure="http://scripting.com/2024/01/21/typicalTechIndustryMess.m4a" enclosureType="audio/mpeg" enclosureLength="6374173"/>
				<outline text="I realize that most of the people who read this blog aren't sports fans, something that I wish were different, because sports, like HBO series, give us a way to talk about complex human relationships in the 21st century that we don't get any other way to imho. If we all watch &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+succession&quot;&gt;Succession&lt;/a&gt;, for example, then we know how to talk about the relationship between &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Succession_characters#Shiv_Roy&quot;&gt;Shiv&lt;/a&gt; and her wimpy husband whose name I now have trouble remembering (later: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Succession_characters#Tom_Wambsgans&quot;&gt;Tom&lt;/a&gt;). (No spoilers as to why he's significant, and won the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/75th_Primetime_Emmy_Awards&quot;&gt;Emmy&lt;/a&gt; for best supporting dramatic performance.) We all know the scene where they both nailed it. For anyone who has ever loved someone yet had to say goodbye anyway, it reached into your heart, and gave you a way to say to your friends -- there! -- &lt;i&gt;that's&lt;/i&gt; what I was talking about. Same thing in sports, esp basketball, where you get to know a team a few players at a time, and you get to see them perform in really personal ways. Last night there was a rematch between the Knicks and the Raptors, which was one of those games you don't ever forget, because of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/01/02.html#a123238&quot;&gt;recent trade&lt;/a&gt; where the teams exchanged core players who formed the personality of the teams, playing each other, so we could see in a memorable and visual way what was exchanged. Understand, we loved the players who were traded away. One day they're our team, and the next day, supposedly they're the other guys. Impossible to see it that way. The love doesn't just leave, maybe it never does. But. But now you know that one of the players, a former &lt;a href=&quot;https://bleacherreport.com/articles/10002703-rj-barrett-talks-knicks-future-i-hope-im-here-for-the-rest-of-my-career&quot;&gt;Great Hope&lt;/a&gt; of ours, didn't pan out, and now it's nice to see him on the court, fumbling an easy play or missing a shot you think he could've gotten, but doing it for the other team. Sadly, we think while he was the more expensive of the two stars the Knicks traded, the other one, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://theknickswall.com/immanuel-quickley-changes-the-knicks-future/&quot;&gt;hotshit kid&lt;/a&gt; with an attitude is going to be the real thing, a starting point guard of a contender, an opportunity he was unlikely to get with the Knicks. Anyway thanks for listening. Last night's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sportsnet.ca/nba/knicks-crush-raptors-as-barrett-quickley-return-to-msg-after-trade/&quot;&gt;game&lt;/a&gt; was something else. I understand that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.espn.com/nfl/story/_/id/39351490/49ers-packers-nfc-championship-game-jordan-love-brock-purdy-deebo-samuel&quot;&gt;Niners and Packers&lt;/a&gt; fans were emoting in other ways at the same time. I can relate. " created="Sun, 21 Jan 2024 16:24:25 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2022/05/30/quickley.png"/>
				<outline text="YABMC" created="Sun, 21 Jan 2024 19:22:38 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="karaokeI apologize in advance for &lt;b&gt;Y&lt;/b&gt;et &lt;b&gt;A&lt;/b&gt;nother &lt;b&gt;B&lt;/b&gt;ull &lt;b&gt;M&lt;/b&gt;ancuso &lt;b&gt;C&lt;/b&gt;omic." created="Sun, 21 Jan 2024 19:22:49 GMT"/>
					<outline text="In this adventure Bull Mancuso is a woman, and is an astronaut on the space station, performing experiments on her fellow astronauts. The goal of the experiment is to determine if astronauts can play a new form of basketball that was invented by SpaceXYZ founder Mucky Lonnegan, who is in space with Astronaut Mancuso." created="Sun, 21 Jan 2024 19:23:01 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Bull Mancuso in space, experimenting with basketball. " created="Sun, 21 Jan 2024 19:24:42 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/21/muckyAndBullInSpace.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 20" created="Sat, 20 Jan 2024 14:47:18 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="20">
				<outline text="In today's &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/20/bullMancusoInPragueAndPortland.png&quot;&gt;Bull Mancuso comic strip&lt;/a&gt;, she's a delivery truck driver in Prague on Veshturnya Ave, delivering Amazon boxes. Then, enjoying a huge cheeseburger with Slavic ketchup, and after that I accidentally hit the Return key, and for the rest of the strip she was a teacher at Portland State University, skiing at Mt Hood Ski Bowl, as she was in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/01/19/204120.html&quot;&gt;previous version&lt;/a&gt;. I find this stuff endlessly entertaining, for now at least, because drawing like this was something I never could do myself. " created="Sat, 20 Jan 2024 14:59:10 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/19/faceplant.png"/>
				<outline text="ActivityPub is a typical tech industry mess. OpenDoc, Taligent, Copland even OS/2 and Java. Hailstorm. Operating systems designed to solve problems for tech companies, completely over the heads of users. " created="Sat, 20 Jan 2024 18:31:27 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Sorry but if Joe Biden has a problem then &lt;i&gt;we&lt;/i&gt; have a problem. I wish news people would get a freaking clue." created="Sat, 20 Jan 2024 14:47:19 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="New social media rule. If I don't know you, and you post something incomprehensible, I assume it's spam and delete it." created="Sat, 20 Jan 2024 16:11:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Bull Mancuso comics bonus!" created="Sun, 21 Jan 2024 03:41:08 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Let's do another Bull Mancuso comic strip! In this version Ms Mancuso is a professor at Harvard Law School, teaching a class on contract law. She's a former Supreme Court clerk and has been considered for a high court appointment herself. She drinks Starbuck's, which she gets from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/@42.3818612,-71.1198074,3a,75y,313.45h,86.34t/data=!3m6!1e1!3m4!1ss6IPyoxMNQaPkqRfO8TULg!2e0!7i16384!8i8192?entry=ttu&quot;&gt;store on Mass Ave&lt;/a&gt; in Cambridge, just across from the Law School campus. Her students all have tremendous respect for her. Just a few panels of her giving an informative caffeine-enhanced lecture. " created="Sun, 21 Jan 2024 03:41:36 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I was given two comic strips to choose from, and I went with the first, because it's closest to what I was thinking of! It looks like a Harvard Law School &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/20/classroom.png&quot;&gt;classroom&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 21 Jan 2024 03:41:40 GMT"/>
					<outline text="#1" created="Sun, 21 Jan 2024 03:42:23 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/20/professorMancuso1.png"/>
					<outline text="#2" created="Sun, 21 Jan 2024 03:42:25 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/20/professorMancuso2.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 19" created="Fri, 19 Jan 2024 14:30:14 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="19">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.threads.net/@johnonolan/post/C2S0uRZuPew&quot;&gt;John Nolan&lt;/a&gt;, the founder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ghost_(blogging_platform)&quot;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;, when asked if they'd support ActivityPub: &quot;Love the idea in theory and we've looked into it a few times (even built prototypes) - but haven't found an implementation in practice that got us very excited, so far. Spec is pretty lightweight (as in, lots of holes) which means you end up having to invent a lot of proprietary stuff to scale. Tricky.&quot;" created="Fri, 19 Jan 2024 20:39:49 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/19/faceplant.png"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://samizdatonline.org/&quot;&gt;Samizdat Online&lt;/a&gt; is a DNS-based proxy that makes it possible to read articles from websites that are blocked by the Russian government. Apparently they have a certain number of random domains, that probably change regularly, and they mirror the contents of a story from one of the blocked sites via a random domain. An example of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://kqtevvweix.com?t=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy50aGVtb3Njb3d0aW1lcy5jb20vMjAyNC8wMS8xOC9hbW5lc3R5LWludGVybmF0aW9uYWwtdXJnZXMtZXVyb3BlLXRvLWVuZC1ub3J0aC1jYXVjYXN1cy1leHB1bHNpb25zLWE4Mzc1OCIsInJvb3QiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy50aGVtb3Njb3d0aW1lcy5jb20iLCJ0eXBlIjoidGV4dC9odG1sIiwiaWF0IjoxNzA1Njc0NDU4LCJleHAiOjE3MDY1Mzg0NTh9.kofaNFyvrOcqNfx12W43zeuCsWoUqV2JLvdrL8e9y1s&quot;&gt;link to a story&lt;/a&gt; on the Moscow Times. Their &lt;a href=&quot;https://samizdatonline.org/&quot;&gt;home page&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/19/samizdatstorylist.png&quot;&gt;looks like&lt;/a&gt; a fairly basic feed reader. " created="Fri, 19 Jan 2024 14:30:15 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Bull Mancuso comic, day 2" created="Fri, 19 Jan 2024 20:41:20 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Draw a nine-panel comic strip. Panels one through three should show &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=%22Bull+Mancuso%22&quot;&gt;Bull Mancuso&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/0d0ec2ca-2846-4088-90ed-d5ee1bba5970&quot;&gt;fishery management consultant&lt;/a&gt; in Oregon at a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.peets.com/pages/store-locator?stockist-query=Portland,%20OR,%20USA&quot;&gt;Peet's Coffee&lt;/a&gt; in Portland, ordering and enjoying a huge &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.peets.com/products/iced-chai-latte&quot;&gt;Chai ice tea&lt;/a&gt; drink. In panels four through seven she's teaching a class on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abortion_in_the_United_States&quot;&gt;abortion rights&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portland_State_University&quot;&gt;Portland State University&lt;/a&gt;. In panels eight and nine she does a &lt;i&gt;hilarious&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bm9bbT8CIG8&quot;&gt;faceplant&lt;/a&gt; while skiing at &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mount_Hood_Skibowl&quot;&gt;Mt Hood Ski Bowl&lt;/a&gt;. There is no dialogue on any panel. " created="Fri, 19 Jan 2024 20:41:29 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Bull Mancuso starts the day with a huge Chai ice tea drink at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.peets.com/pages/store-locator?stockist-query=Portland,%20OR,%20USA&quot;&gt;Peets&lt;/a&gt; in Portland." created="Fri, 19 Jan 2024 20:42:18 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/19/bullMancusoInPortland.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 18" created="Thu, 18 Jan 2024 14:10:43 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="18">
				<outline text="I've been wrong about many of Apple's products, but not the ones that made the company -- the Apple II and Mac, though I was somewhat skeptical of the iPhone because I couldn't write software for it, but I did &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2007/06/30/initialReviewOfIphone.html&quot;&gt;get one&lt;/a&gt; on the day they came out in &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2007/06.html&quot;&gt;June 2007&lt;/a&gt;, and never used my Blackberry again. Anyway, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/01/17/i-spent-the-morning-with-the-apple-vision-pro/&quot;&gt;goggles&lt;/a&gt; they just &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techmeme.com/240117/p38#a240117p38&quot;&gt;started&lt;/a&gt; demoing to selected reporters and analysts looks like a product they released because they invested billions in it, had no idea what it's used for, and were overlooking the ability of the human body to actually &lt;i&gt;use&lt;/i&gt; such a thing, and couldn't consider writing it off because so much had been made of this, esp since the current management has been coasting on innovation done by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Jobs&quot;&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/a&gt;, and hadn't released anything that wasn't completely predictable since his &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2011/10/06/myThoughtsOnSteveJobs.html&quot;&gt;passing in 2011&lt;/a&gt;. Their lack of confidence in their own product overwhelms any positive reviews coming out from the privileged press, who we know in advance to discount, these are the press people Apple can count on to not say a negative word, to preserve their access at least, if not because they are complete fans. It reeks of a loser product. I write these things partially so I can be proven ridiculously wrong when I get one myself in two weeks and can't believe all the things I can do with it. " created="Thu, 18 Jan 2024 14:38:12 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/18/visionPro.png"/>
				<outline text="It's worth remembering that &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/0f1e55c1-4919-4c18-a1c8-20aa9d26158c&quot;&gt;before the Mac&lt;/a&gt; there was &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_Lisa&quot;&gt;the Lisa&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 18 Jan 2024 14:58:41 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, did you notice how &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ltc909LOR4Q&quot;&gt;BMW's ads&lt;/a&gt; say their product is much better than Tesla's, without mentioning Tesla, they just say they're better, because they are just better, because they're BMW, and they know you know that. It's much more powerful esp with people who like Telsas (of which I am one). I also see the Tesla as a very capable replacement for my 2007 BMW 535i, which I donated to charity in 2012, which I loved for the same reasons I love the Tesla. Putting down the competition isn't what marketing is about, you have to think about the people whose minds you're trying to change, and know you're in it for the long haul. An example of their ad copy: &quot;With electric driving comes exciting possibilities. That’s why BMW approaches this new era in mobility just like any other; where engineering, innovation and aesthetics come together seamlessly to inspire joy in every journey.&quot; These people understand their product and how their fans see them. " created="Thu, 18 Jan 2024 15:17:47 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/18/bullmancusohahahah.png"/>
				<outline text="My recipe for getting rid of a troll. Say something rude in response to their trolling and then block them. " created="Thu, 18 Jan 2024 15:23:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Bull Mancuso's day" created="Thu, 18 Jan 2024 14:10:44 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I got this idea &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/pbump.com/post/3kj7q6wejuk23&quot;&gt;from Philip Bump&lt;/a&gt;. :smile: " created="Thu, 18 Jan 2024 14:10:51 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&quot;Draw a three-panel comic strip in the style of Mary Worth. Panel one should show Bull Mancuso, a waste management consultant in New Jersey, at a Starbuck's in Newark, ordering a huge coffee drink. In panel two he's teaching a class on organized crime in New Jersey at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.csi.cuny.edu/&quot;&gt;Staten Island Community College&lt;/a&gt;. In panel three he slips on a banana peel on the steps of the Capitol and falls down. There is no dialogue on any panel.&quot;" created="Thu, 18 Jan 2024 14:11:34 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Bull Mancuso's wild day in New Jersey, Staten Island and DC." created="Thu, 18 Jan 2024 14:12:10 GMT" inlineImage="https://s3.amazonaws.com/scripting.com/images/2024/01/18/bullMancusoDay.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 17" created="Wed, 17 Jan 2024 14:24:16 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="17">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://cagrimmett.com/micro/aa2835f451/#comment-34471&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://source.scripting.com/#1405339599000&quot;&gt;archive element&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://source.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;source namespace&lt;/a&gt;. It's important that we share our ideas and collaborate, and listen and ask the right people to help. Manton was asking why weren't his ideas on archiving incorporated in other people's work, it's the same concern I have, why didn't we work together on this Manton? Two heads are better than one in things like this. I think Automattic may be the place to get together on this. Esp since they are the market leader now in this area. What they do, right off the bat, has to be supported everywhere, so we want them to do a good job. :smile:" created="Wed, 17 Jan 2024 14:29:28 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/04/29/raisins.png"/>
				<outline text="I got the help I needed &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/01/16.html#a180357&quot;&gt;yesterday&lt;/a&gt;, pointing me in the right &lt;a href=&quot;https://platform.openai.com/docs/api-reference/introduction&quot;&gt;direction&lt;/a&gt; wrt APIs for ChatGPT. I'm ready to try some ideas out once I get to a stopping point on my current project. Can't wait to try out these ideas. " created="Wed, 17 Jan 2024 14:27:06 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="ChatGPT is like having a programming partner you can try ideas out on, or ask for alternative approaches, and they're always there, and not too busy to help out. They know everything you don't know and need to know, and rarely hallucinate (you have to check the work, same as with a human btw). It's remarkable how much it is like having an ideal human programming partner. It's the kind of helper I aspire to be. " created="Wed, 17 Jan 2024 14:24:17 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/trump-didnt-crush-anything-he-won-iowa-by-2-222-votes-1-17-24/id1633301179?i=1000641927666&quot;&gt;Today's Olbermann&lt;/a&gt; is worth a listen, esp the first part where he talks about political reporters vs sports reporters. Politics is a lot simpler than most sports, and they repeat themselves for years even decades, yet the sports reporters manage. Not all of them, there are plenty of empty-headed sports reporters. But there are also some very insightful ones. It makes all the the difference. In New York basketball we're blessed with two of the best. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mike_Breen&quot;&gt;Mike Breen&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walt_Frazier&quot;&gt;Walt Frazier&lt;/a&gt;. I'd listen even if I gave up hope on the Knicks, which believe me, I have done many many many times. Also Olbermann says that &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_L._Dolan&quot;&gt;Dolan&lt;/a&gt;, the owner of the Knicks, is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schmuck_(pejorative)&quot;&gt;schmuck&lt;/a&gt;. He got that &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2013/12/19/whatIfTheKnicksHadKeptJeremyLin.html#aWIOSI&quot;&gt;right&lt;/a&gt;. But somehow this time he managed to hire an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leon_Rose&quot;&gt;exec&lt;/a&gt; who has some kind of a clue. " created="Wed, 17 Jan 2024 22:37:07 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/17/swissMiss.png"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 16" created="Tue, 16 Jan 2024 15:33:47 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="16">
				<outline text="I think it's fair to say that the new FeedLand, at &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/&quot;&gt;feedland.com&lt;/a&gt;, and running in Automattic's cloud, is stable, and performing nicely. So if you have an account on &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.org/&quot;&gt;feedland.org&lt;/a&gt;, the original system, which is still running of course, you could now reasonably move to feedland.com. To do so, just export your OPML subscription list from .org, create a new account on .com, and import the subscription list. It might take a while for all the new feeds to be fully updated, but you'll be rewarded by a higher performance user experience. Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://ma.tt/&quot;&gt;Matt&lt;/a&gt; and company for giving us access to this phenomenal resource. I still haven't gotten used to designing with the assumption that my system can scale as far as it seems it can." created="Tue, 16 Jan 2024 15:33:48 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/09/18/slugger.png"/>
				<outline text="I imagine &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.threads.net/@davew/post/C2K6xlTpa3q&quot;&gt;ChatGPT must have&lt;/a&gt; an interface that allows me to send it a bit of text via an API, and get back the same response I'd get if I were typing it into their web page. I am a paying user, I don't want to do any more than I'm currently doing with it. I just want to be able to keep an archive of everything I do, in a format that's more useful to me.  (Update: They do have a simple API, &lt;a href=&quot;https://platform.openai.com/docs/api-reference/introduction&quot;&gt;documented here&lt;/a&gt;.)" created="Tue, 16 Jan 2024 18:03:57 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 15" created="Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:38:31 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="15">
				<outline text="Now the Atlantic is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2024/01/trump-rally-iowa-2024-election/677119/&quot;&gt;saying&lt;/a&gt; we should go to a Trump rally. That is sick. Here's what I want. I want to go to a pro-democracy event, where we do things like register to vote, and offer community service to each other. We need to belong to something great, not to study the degradation of our country. We also should use our communication systems to spread not only positive messages, but to position Hitler as the ultimate loser. We have to present the counter-argument, in a way that still has a chance of getting through. And I still want us to celebrate the symbols of our fight for freedom, which obviously never ends. That's why I'm wearing a MLK button, in real life and &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/15/blogscreenshot.png?nodialog=true&quot;&gt;on my blog&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:38:32 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2017/12/09/mlk.png"/>
				<outline text="I'm thinking about putting together blogrolls for famous people, based on what I think their interests are. As an experiment, I &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/79870ef5-fd0b-42fe-ad1f-7a04247a7de4&quot;&gt;asked ChatGPT&lt;/a&gt; to put together a blogroll for &quot;a person like Dave Winer.&quot; " created="Mon, 15 Jan 2024 16:25:42 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 14" created="Sun, 14 Jan 2024 14:58:53 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="14">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W-s0lFpflQw&quot;&gt;Another Dead song&lt;/a&gt; that must've been fun to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dead.net/song/saint-stephen&quot;&gt;sing&lt;/a&gt;.  &quot;Wherever he goes the people all complain.&quot; " created="Sun, 14 Jan 2024 17:17:55 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W-s0lFpflQw"/>
				<outline text="With mystique of Substack in retreat, now -- if we had a proper identity system with storage, we could make it easy for people to hook their world up to email, ie newsletters, and preserve choice, and be able to build editors that were more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/14/tinyLittleTextBox.png&quot;&gt;tiny little textboxes&lt;/a&gt;. I was part of the PC wave in the 80s when writing tools advanced incredibly quickly. So many directions -- from line-oriented editors on Unix and early Apples, to &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/0cfe7783-d6aa-4350-9d32-f9a81efc8e4b&quot;&gt;screen editors&lt;/a&gt;, then with the Mac we got &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WYSIWYG&quot;&gt;wizzy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/QuarkXPress&quot;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adobe_PageMaker&quot;&gt;layout&lt;/a&gt;, and outliners for thinking and presentations. In the same time period programming changed from something requiring a million dollar investment in hardware and infrastructure, to something most students could afford. Just ten years. Since then our world has been reduced to copying and pasting into tiny text boxes. The question is bigger than if we need journalism, the question is do we need writers? " created="Sun, 14 Jan 2024 16:02:04 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/09/24/barbie.png"/>
				<outline text="It makes sense that AI is coming into existence at the time the human species, and most living things on the planet, appear about to cease to exist. It's possible that we are just building our successor. A sort of ark of intellect. It would make sense, if there is a Creator, that they would arrange things this way. Just-in-time species reboot." created="Sun, 14 Jan 2024 14:58:54 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, what are the proper pronouns for The Creator?" created="Sun, 14 Jan 2024 16:10:12 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="One man gathers what another man spills." created="Sun, 14 Jan 2024 17:23:36 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Tiny little text boxes" created="Mon, 15 Jan 2024 03:12:01 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="This is a tiny little text box. My goal is to eradicate these beasts." created="Mon, 15 Jan 2024 03:12:10 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/14/tinyLittleTextBox.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 13" created="Sat, 13 Jan 2024 17:43:01 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="13">
				<outline text="Twitter has yet to realize its potential as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2007/04/28/twitterAsCoralReef.html&quot;&gt;coral reef&lt;/a&gt;. The idea was lovely, they had solved two important problems, identity and world-scale publishing. It took years to get there, but they did eventually do it. They were also liberal in granting access to their API, though because of some dick moves leading up to their IPO, they got a rep for the opposite, as in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/No_good_deed_goes_unpunished&quot;&gt;no good deed goes unpunished&lt;/a&gt;. In the big picture, what they offered was tantalizing. If they had added storage to it, which I understood from Jack Dorsey was their plan, then some amazing stuff would have happened. I still believe tech companies can play a very important role in the open internet, as long as they are willing to treat users as customers and sell a product that has value without the usual michegas. " created="Sat, 13 Jan 2024 17:43:02 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/13/reefFish.png"/>
				<outline text="I've been listening to the Grateful Dead today. Today my most favorite Dead song is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QmMjY6tXaEo&quot;&gt;Ripple&lt;/a&gt;. I love the bass beat, and the simple lyric. A wonderful sing-along. Let there be songs to fill the air. A song about singing. Love it. " created="Sat, 13 Jan 2024 17:52:18 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 12" created="Fri, 12 Jan 2024 13:41:39 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="12">
				<outline text="Fixed a bug in &quot;news.scripting.com&quot; that caused it to display only the &lt;i&gt;All&lt;/i&gt; tab, leaving the other tabs inaccessible. Glad to get it fixed now and sorry for the breakage. Please keep the error &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues&quot;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; coming. " created="Fri, 12 Jan 2024 14:16:37 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="It's good that people are thinking of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=%22leaving+substack%22&quot;&gt;leaving Substack&lt;/a&gt;. I &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2022/12/30/173742.html?title=substackLockin&quot;&gt;didn't like&lt;/a&gt; what &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/03/18/141318.html?title=itsNotReallyAScam&quot;&gt;they were doing&lt;/a&gt; because they were yet another place that &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/04/06/150554.html?title=copypastetopublish&quot;&gt;requires&lt;/a&gt; you to use their editor to publish through their platform, probably because their business model requires a fair amount of lock-in. I like using the editor that I do all my writing in, and I don't see why I can't just post directly from there. Even if they don't have an API, it's pretty easy to set it up so it posts from a &lt;a href=&quot;http://reallysimple.org/&quot;&gt;feed&lt;/a&gt;. If you're thinking about leaving Substack, good for you. Please insist that your new platform lets you post via a feed. If they say it's too hard, give them my email address, and I'll show them how to do it. " created="Fri, 12 Jan 2024 13:41:40 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2020/12/12/asGoodAsItGets.png"/>
				<outline text="My night at the Dean campaign" created="Fri, 12 Jan 2024 14:28:25 GMT" type="outline" description="The campaign had video that showed clearly that the press was actively trying to kill his candidacy. " metaImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/12/deanhq.png">
					<outline text="I'd love to tell you a story about the time I had the authority to post to the Dean campaign home page, and they deleted a post I wrote on the night of the famous &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l6i-gYRAwM0&quot;&gt;Dean Scream&lt;/a&gt; that might have saved the campaign. They were trying to make the story go away. As we know the story didn't go away. " created="Fri, 12 Jan 2024 14:28:32 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2008/03/22/iWasAtDeanHqTheNightTheyDi.html&quot;&gt;2008&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The campaign had video that showed clearly that the press was actively trying to kill his candidacy. They had a website, and they had enough money to pay for the bandwidth to run it. They knew what the press was trying to do. They could have fought it. But they didn't.&quot;" created="Fri, 12 Jan 2024 15:16:57 GMT"/>
					<outline text="That night I became friends with Nicco Mele, he was the webmaster at Dean who &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2010/10/28/itsAWrap.html#remindsMeOfAStory&quot;&gt;gave&lt;/a&gt; me the power. I was in their Burlington headquarters at the moment the whole thing imploded, the night of the Iowa caucus. I've also become friends with Joe Trippi, the campaign manager for Dean in 2008. They probably accelerated the adoption of online media in American politics by a decade or more. However, a lot of the ideas from that time are gone, but hopefully not forever." created="Fri, 12 Jan 2024 14:28:55 GMT" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2020/12/15/deanForAmericaBumperSticker.png"/>
					<outline text="The biggest idea was that it gave people a sense of belonging, that they weren't powerless to influence or even control the US government. We all felt that the war in Iraq was wrong, Dean gave Americans a way to say that clearly, with their own actions. I think if we want to achieve our destiny in the 2024 election, we need to get some of that into the campaign, or democracy won't prevail." created="Fri, 12 Jan 2024 14:30:30 GMT"/>
					<outline text="There's a story about how Trump makes people feel like they belong in &lt;a href=&quot;https://wapo.st/3U224ud&quot;&gt;the Washington Post&lt;/a&gt; written by Philip Bump that Joe and Nicco should read if they haven't. This is something Trump gets that the Democrats have forgotten they know. People don't vote on policy, they vote to belong to something they believe might fix things, whatever that means to them." created="Fri, 12 Jan 2024 14:31:19 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PS: I also blogged about my adventure at the Dean campaign headquarters in &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2004/01.html&quot;&gt;January 2004&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/2004/01/18.html&quot;&gt;before&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2004/01/19.html#When:9:56:50AM&quot;&gt;and&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2004/01/19.html&quot;&gt;during&lt;/a&gt; the Iowa caucus and the Dean campaign implosion.  " created="Fri, 12 Jan 2024 14:55:35 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PPS: A &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20040407155545/http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/jim/2004/01/19#a418&quot;&gt;picture&lt;/a&gt; of the blogging room in Burlington the night of the Iowa caucus in 2004." created="Fri, 12 Jan 2024 15:26:12 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PPPS: In February 2004, I wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/davenet/2004/02/07/howardDeanIsNotASoapBar.html&quot;&gt;piece&lt;/a&gt; summing up what we learned from Dean. &quot;In a virtual sense, the Internet was looking for a candidate, and Howard Dean fit the bill. He was bloggable.&quot;" created="Fri, 12 Jan 2024 15:04:50 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 11" created="Thu, 11 Jan 2024 16:07:43 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="11">
				<outline text="Ideas for Reading Lists" created="Thu, 11 Jan 2024 16:07:44 GMT" type="outline" description="Now you can use one app to manage subscriptions and use lots of apps to read them.">
					<outline text="A &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2023/10/21/143159.html&quot;&gt;reading list&lt;/a&gt; is a list of feeds you can subscribe to." created="Thu, 11 Jan 2024 16:25:27 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The author of the list can add or remove feeds. When they do, people who subscribe to the list are subscribed to the new feeds and unsubbed from the ones that leave." created="Thu, 11 Jan 2024 16:26:42 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Reading lists are not a new topic, I and others have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+reading+lists&quot;&gt;writing&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=opml+reading+lists&quot;&gt;them&lt;/a&gt; for years. But they've not been used seriously in the past because they weren't widely supported in feed readers. &quot;FeedLand&quot;, my latest feed manager, has reading list support built-in. And we're serious about starting new communities of feeds and users with this feature. " created="Thu, 11 Jan 2024 16:22:40 GMT"/>
					<outline text="If you're a feed reader user, you probably know about using OPML to move your subscriptions from one app to another, or to share lists with friends. " created="Thu, 11 Jan 2024 16:13:05 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Reading lists take it one step further, you can subscribe to a reading list, so you can control one app from another.  " created="Thu, 11 Jan 2024 16:13:36 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Say I had a reading list with my favorite podcasts and my podcasting client could subscribe to it. Then when I add a feed to that list on my desktop computer, the podcast client would automatically be subscribed to it. Or if I used two or more podcast clients (say one on Android and one on iOS), I could control both from the same subscription list." created="Thu, 11 Jan 2024 16:14:08 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It factors out subscribing. Now you can use one app to manage subscriptions and use lots of apps to read them." created="Thu, 11 Jan 2024 16:15:31 GMT"/>
					<outline text="What's cool about this is that it opens up the possibility for lots of viewer apps. A podcast client is a special kind of feed reader. I'm sure others are possible. But first, to make this practical we need to do better with subscriptions. That's what reading lists are for. " created="Thu, 11 Jan 2024 16:15:51 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Another idea. Suppose we wanted to put together a big list of great blogs about Major League Baseball (just an example). I might know a few about the Mets, and my friend Scott who lives in Mountain View, CA, would have a bunch about the Giants. We could put together a group of 100 avid baseball fans, and one of us could put out a reading list for all of our feeds merged into one list. It's not so far-fetched, &quot;FeedLand&quot; can do that today. " created="Thu, 11 Jan 2024 16:16:55 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I could see a similar &quot;big blogroll&quot; for the IndieWeb, or for Bluesky developers -- or really anything. We just have to get started, prime the pump, and learn how this works. " created="Thu, 11 Jan 2024 16:19:43 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I felt it was really important to get reading lists built into FeedLand in the current release, because now we're in a position, with the improvements in scaling, to act as a organizing node for new activities with feeds. " created="Thu, 11 Jan 2024 16:08:20 GMT"/>
					<outline text="This is another form of federation, it's more ad hoc, and doesn't require very much technical knowledge. If you know how to use a feed reader, and move around OPML files, you can do all of what I describe in this piece. " created="Thu, 11 Jan 2024 16:20:41 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 10" created="Wed, 10 Jan 2024 14:08:53 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="10">
				<outline text="It would be better if journalists did not gravitate to a Facebook-owned Twitter clone. " created="Wed, 10 Jan 2024 20:17:05 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="For a guy who likes to write, I am probably not a lot better about writing docs than most other developers. We're supposed to leave a good trail behind us, but I've only managed to do that in certain ways. For example, I have standardized on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedland/blob/main/worknotes.md&quot;&gt;worknotes.md&lt;/a&gt; file for each of my projects and I'm pretty good about updating it. I also publish the OPML source of my code, which contains a lot more in the way of internal docs than the JavaScript files I publish alongside them, simply because the outline format lends itself to inline docs, and I have been doing that systematically for at least thirty years. And I now include the OPML source in most projects in a file called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/pagePark/blob/master/source.opml&quot;&gt;source.opml&lt;/a&gt;. There's a big comment at the top of each of the files at the top that explains. If you're interested, work backward through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting?tab=repositories&quot;&gt;directory&lt;/a&gt; of my repos. " created="Wed, 10 Jan 2024 16:54:31 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/03/18/accordionGuy.png"/>
				<outline text="&quot;Overturn an election?&quot;" created="Wed, 10 Jan 2024 14:08:54 GMT" type="outline" description="Did Trump try to overturn an election or overthrow the government?" metaImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/11/overthrowOrOverturn.png">
					<outline text="I spend a lot of time thinking about words, and when I hear a phrase that seems wrong to me, I'll work on it until I figure out why it seems wrong and what would be a better way to express the actual idea. " created="Wed, 10 Jan 2024 14:09:11 GMT"/>
					<outline text="That said, I don't think Trump tried to &quot;overturn an election.&quot;" created="Wed, 10 Jan 2024 14:09:59 GMT"/>
					<outline text="More accurately, he tried to &quot;overthrow the government.&quot;" created="Wed, 10 Jan 2024 14:10:42 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Why I say that:" created="Wed, 10 Jan 2024 14:11:35 GMT" flBulletedSubs="true">
						<outline text="Overturn could be something you do legitimately. If you are convicted of a crime, you could appeal it, be exonerated, and the correct verb would be overturn. Overturn doesn't convey the illegitimacy of what Trump tried to do. The criminality of it. The abhorrence of it, by American values. He tried to &quot;overturn&quot; our most sacred ritual, the transfer of power from one person to another, based on the vote of the people. Overthrow is a much better word for what was done. " created="Wed, 10 Jan 2024 14:11:39 GMT"/>
						<outline text="When you commit a crime, say for example killing someone, we don't say they tried to illegally use a weapon, that's too technical, we say they're &quot;accused of murder.&quot; We focus on the consequences. There are lots of ways to illegally use a weapon, what matters is the intended result." created="Wed, 10 Jan 2024 14:14:16 GMT"/>
						<outline text="There is always exactly one president, at all times, in all circumstances. It's spelled out in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twentieth_Amendment_to_the_United_States_Constitution&quot;&gt;20th Amendment&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 10 Jan 2024 14:16:23 GMT"/>
						<outline text="On January 20, 2021, we had an actual peaceful transfer of power when Joe Biden &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZwvbQR887W0&quot;&gt;took the oath&lt;/a&gt;, but the transfer actually took place before he took the oath, at 12PM exactly. " created="Wed, 10 Jan 2024 14:19:29 GMT"/>
						<outline text="You can also look at the government as a continuous thing, the only difference is there is a new person occupying the office of president. Same government, the one defined by the Constitution. Always on. " created="Thu, 11 Jan 2024 01:20:34 GMT"/>
						<outline text="So on January 6, 2021, the then-president Donald Trump, tried to destroy the government, replacing it with a new government, one that doesn't follow the Constitution.  " created="Wed, 10 Jan 2024 14:20:19 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 9" created="Tue, 09 Jan 2024 14:14:33 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="09">
				<outline text="Twitter became a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hairball&quot;&gt;hairball&lt;/a&gt;. I first heard this term in speeches given by a tech exec, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scott_McNealy&quot;&gt;Scott McNealy&lt;/a&gt;, talking about a competitor's product. A hairball is something a cat coughs up. Very undesirable. Of course, given enough time all software becomes a hairball. As you refine your understanding of how the product is being used, versus how you thought it would be used, all the new paths through the code and UI become more crooked and impenetrable by a human mind, because you still have to do all the things you did before, unless you start over. There often is value in starting over. Now is a good time to be thinking about bare-bones social web apps. People are open to new ideas." created="Tue, 09 Jan 2024 14:58:33 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/04/24/cheshireCat.png"/>
				<outline text="I asked &quot;Is news copyrightable&quot; on various social web sites because people aren't making a distinction between the expression and the underlying facts of news. If an AI bot reads a news article, and extracts the facts, then there's no problem, because no one owns the facts. " created="Tue, 09 Jan 2024 14:40:17 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/63402-you-are-entitled-to-your-opinion-but-you-are-not&quot;&gt;Daniel Patrick Moynihan&lt;/a&gt;: “You are entitled to your opinion. But you are not entitled to your own facts.”" created="Tue, 09 Jan 2024 15:16:51 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="A puzzle about ChatGPT. How can it get something right that both Wikipedia and journalism get wrong? Journalism often uses Wikipedia as a source, thus propagating its lies and mistakes. I think this negates the idea that they're just scanning the news orgs to get their information. The method obviously is more sophisticated. " created="Tue, 09 Jan 2024 14:14:34 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 8" created="Mon, 08 Jan 2024 15:05:24 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="08">
				<outline text="What about a LLM that is fed with the flow of your feed subscriptions?" created="Mon, 08 Jan 2024 15:33:15 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I would like to give a LLM a pointer to a folder of my writing and say &quot;learn this&quot; and then a few hours or days later I'd be able to ask it questions about what I wrote. I also have folders of stuff my parents wrote. It would be kind of interesting to feed those into a LLM and then ask questions about them. Could be the equivalent of ten years of therapy.  " created="Mon, 08 Jan 2024 15:27:09 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I think Bluesky has a chance of being the place where journalists assemble in place of Twitter. I sincerely hope it's not on Facebook's Twitter replacement. That would like &quot;meet the new boss, same as the old boss but much richer and better managed.&quot;" created="Mon, 08 Jan 2024 15:05:25 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Ten years ago today" created="Mon, 08 Jan 2024 19:07:18 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I had a couple of Papaya hot dogs. Sensually delicious.  " created="Mon, 08 Jan 2024 19:07:24 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/08/hotdogs.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 7" created="Sun, 07 Jan 2024 21:43:44 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="07">
				<outline text="I got a high compliment from my &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/def9e4f0-ccaa-43cf-9039-fd771158790d&quot;&gt;OG&lt;/a&gt; friend and co-conspirator in podcasting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+Chris+Lydon&quot;&gt;Chris Lydon&lt;/a&gt;. He said I was a good &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/01/02.html#a123238&quot;&gt;sports writer&lt;/a&gt; and boasted of the current Celtics team (he's from Boston). They're worth boasting about. What a team, such depth and so many interesting players. They were great before they added &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2019/11/09.html#a135827&quot;&gt;Kristaps Porzingis&lt;/a&gt;, who we know well in New York. He was our rookie unicorn and franchise player at the end of the Phil Jackson debacle. He's one of those ex-Knicks we still root for, so I feel an affinity for this year's Celtics. I would pay to see them kill a west coast team like the Warriors or Kings in this year's finals. Anyway, I write sports for people who are not sports fans, though I think everyone who loves politics or business should pay close attention to sports, because it all happens quickly in sport, and the human element is so visible and front and center. I'm glad Chris is a basketball fan. Maybe we can go to a Knicks-Celtics game sometime, either in Boston or NYC. The Knicks are getting good, and it likely would be a good game and Knicks could even win. :boom:" created="Mon, 08 Jan 2024 01:22:14 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2019/11/09/porzingas.png"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fargo_(season_5)&quot;&gt;This year's Fargo&lt;/a&gt; is quite good. Even better than I thought when I realized that you have to watch each episode twice to get the jokes. :smile: " created="Sun, 07 Jan 2024 22:09:22 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Speaking of Fargo, at first I thought it was ridiculous to have &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jon_Hamm&quot;&gt;Jon Hamm&lt;/a&gt; cast as the fascist police chief of a small North Dakota town, but he's a really good actor (of course) and by episode 8, I'm convinced. " created="Sun, 07 Jan 2024 23:11:58 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Saw &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jena_Griswold&quot;&gt;Jena Griswold&lt;/a&gt;, the Colorado Secretary of State, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jVUx6Dh2AQI&quot;&gt;on MSNBC on Thursday&lt;/a&gt;. She said something that I hadn’t heard before — Trump actually has been found by a court to be an insurrectionist. That’s what happened in Colorado in their Supreme Court." created="Sun, 07 Jan 2024 21:57:06 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jVUx6Dh2AQI"/>
				<outline text="I love &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6V7K_azSYkU&quot;&gt;this scene&lt;/a&gt; with Glenn Close and Robert Duvall about the relationship between journalists and billionaires." created="Sun, 07 Jan 2024 21:43:45 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6V7K_azSYkU"/>
				<outline text="The problem all billionaires have is there is &lt;a href=&quot;https://newrepublic.com/article/177733/billionaire-solano-california-tech-secession&quot;&gt;nothing&lt;/a&gt; they can buy with their &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/davenet/2000/10/19/transcendentalMoney.html&quot;&gt;money&lt;/a&gt; that's worth owning." created="Sun, 07 Jan 2024 21:50:50 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Fine blogging since 1994" created="Mon, 08 Jan 2024 01:15:33 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I've been blogging since 1994. " created="Mon, 08 Jan 2024 01:15:40 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I once set a date that I would stop blogging. " created="Mon, 08 Jan 2024 01:15:47 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It came and went. I didn't stop." created="Mon, 08 Jan 2024 01:15:53 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Some people are &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2009/11/24/naturalbornBlogger.html&quot;&gt;natural born bloggers&lt;/a&gt; -- they can't not blog." created="Mon, 08 Jan 2024 01:16:01 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="A modern-day blogger" created="Mon, 08 Jan 2024 01:21:12 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Julia Child as a blogger, as rendered by ChatGPT." created="Mon, 08 Jan 2024 01:20:06 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/07/modernDayBlogger.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 6" created="Sat, 06 Jan 2024 14:18:55 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="06">
				<outline text="Rich Brown &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/287&quot;&gt;reports a problem&lt;/a&gt; with the tabs on the Scripting News &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/&quot;&gt;home page&lt;/a&gt; on an Android tablet running Brave. It sounds like the problems were introduced when I did a rewrite of the tab code, and it's probably due to some code catching the click before it gets to the tab code. Once found, it's easy to fix. If you're running Brave or using an Android tablet, could you give it a try per Rich's description, see if you can reproduce. Also curious if there are error messages in the JavaScript console. Thanks!  " created="Sat, 06 Jan 2024 14:18:56 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2017/11/19/catEmoji.png"/>
				<outline text="Random WordPress idea" created="Sat, 06 Jan 2024 15:46:49 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="&lt;i&gt;Caveat: This very likely already exists. &lt;/i&gt;" created="Sat, 06 Jan 2024 15:47:04 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Random idea for my friends at Automattic. How about a theme for a WordPress site that's good for technical subjects. " created="Sat, 06 Jan 2024 14:25:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="It should have good default styles for code. Handle screen shot images gracefully. Basically a way of using WordPress for documenting the kinds of things we write up on GitHub because their editor is designed to work well for technical stuff. " created="Sat, 06 Jan 2024 15:47:38 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Just thinking out loud. A good test case would be the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html&quot;&gt;RSS 2.0 spec&lt;/a&gt;, which doesn't look too great after years of no-updates (more than 20 years) and browser slippage? " created="Sat, 06 Jan 2024 15:46:06 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="It started life as a Manila site, transitioned to WordPress, and now I believe it's a static site. At one time it looked good in WordPress. It could totally use the kind of treatment &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.searls.com/&quot;&gt;Doc's blog&lt;/a&gt; got, but obviously it's serving a different purpose. " created="Sat, 06 Jan 2024 15:48:04 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="A social network for writers" created="Sun, 07 Jan 2024 04:08:38 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I asked ChatGPT to draw a picture of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://word.social/&quot;&gt;social network for writers&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sun, 07 Jan 2024 04:08:45 GMT"/>
					<outline text="GPT rendering of &quot;social network for writers.&quot;" created="Sun, 07 Jan 2024 04:09:02 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/06/socialNetworkForWriters.png"/>
					<outline text="I asked for a more racially diverse rendering. " created="Sun, 07 Jan 2024 04:23:15 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/06/moreRaciallyDiverseWritersWeb.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 5" created="Fri, 05 Jan 2024 14:14:25 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="05">
				<outline text="The &lt;a href=&quot;https://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html#roadmap&quot;&gt;RSS 2.0 roadmap&lt;/a&gt; is imho one of my best bits of writing, and has stood up pretty well. &quot;RSS is by no means a perfect format, but it is very popular and widely supported. Having a settled spec is something RSS has needed for a long time. The purpose of this work is to help it become a unchanging thing, to foster growth in the market that is developing around it, and to clear the path for innovation in new syndication formats. Therefore, the RSS spec is, for all practical purposes, frozen at version 2.0.1. We anticipate possible 2.0.2 or 2.0.3 versions, etc. only for the purpose of clarifying the specification, not for adding new features to the format. Subsequent work should happen in modules, using namespaces, and in completely new syndication formats, with new names.&quot;" created="Fri, 05 Jan 2024 19:53:25 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2022/03/21/beetle.png"/>
				<outline text="I am going to ask for a discussion about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS&quot;&gt;Wikipedia page for RSS&lt;/a&gt;, because I think it misses the significance of &quot;RSS&quot;, how it became a big thing. It had little to do with the quality of the technical work, there wasn't much of that, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://this.how/standards/#1497798834000&quot;&gt;quality varied&lt;/a&gt; as has been pointed out many times. What made it happen was a vision by some exec at Netscape (whose name is never in the writeups, probably because it isn't on the Wikipedia page), a pitch, and a leap of faith by publishers: Salon, Red Herring, Wired and Motley Fool. And if they hadn't, there wouldn't have been anything worth fighting for. I never would have gotten involved, and blogging might not have been part of RSS, as it was. Then, a few years later, the NYT. And then everyone. It's an interesting story, imho -- and it would be good to make the story available to future would-be innovators. Don't design a perfect format and expect the world to beat a path to your door, it doesn't work that way. You have to keep coming back to the problem, try a new approach, gain some traction, and hope you're not going down a blind alley. The actual story of how it happened belongs on that page. " created="Fri, 05 Jan 2024 19:56:33 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Good luck to everyone riding out the first winter storm of the season in NY and Mass. " created="Fri, 05 Jan 2024 21:19:18 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Saw the Colorado Secretary of State on MSNBC just now and she said something that I hadn’t heard before — Trump actually has been found by a court to have been an insurrectionist. That’s what happened in Colorado in their Supreme Court. Due process." created="Sat, 06 Jan 2024 03:09:49 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Every time a new writing environment comes along and gets popular but doesn't support linking, there's less hope for the open web. It's subtle but real. " created="Fri, 05 Jan 2024 19:25:42 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="One of the coolest things about driving a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2022/12/19/152612.html&quot;&gt;muscle car&lt;/a&gt; that looks like a Toyota Camry is when you're merging into traffic on a freeway, and a big truck moves over into the left lane to let you on, a polite gesture, and you smoke him. " created="Fri, 05 Jan 2024 19:34:10 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I know Elon Musk isn't popular, but I saw an older interview of his where he said something important that most people don't realize about technology. Sometimes we lose abilities we had in the past. His example was space travel. In the sixties we went to the moon. A decade later we could only put people in earth orbit. A few decades after that, not so much. I've seen this in software and networks. In some ways they have become far more powerful, in terms of bandwidth, CPU speed and the cost of storage. But software-wise, the runtime that we develop for today is a shadow of what it was in the 80s. We gave up a lot in going to the web, and made some terrible decisions, collectively, about languages and styling. JavaScript is horrendous for building complex systems, the worst language imaginable, but we use it as the default. And CSS, it's disgusting how hard it is to control, at things it claims to be good at. If only we were using C or Pascal, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/QuickDraw&quot;&gt;QuickDraw&lt;/a&gt;. When you study how these systems evolved, the discontinuities and how they were usually the result of a company trying to own something they could have let everyone build on (the Mac UI for example, and the networking built into every Mac). I've made some of these mistakes myself, so I'm not saying it's about quality of individuals. It's just that we don't think enough about what we're doing, and before you know it some things are tossed aside that were really good, and replaced them with systems that are grossly inadequate. " created="Fri, 05 Jan 2024 19:27:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://ma.tt/2024/01/birthday-gift/&quot;&gt;Happy 40th birthday&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+matt+mullenweg&quot;&gt;Matt Mullenweg&lt;/a&gt;. Many happy returns! :smile:" created="Fri, 05 Jan 2024 14:14:26 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 4" created="Thu, 04 Jan 2024 15:10:45 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="04">
				<outline text="I always have multiple tabs open in my outliner. This tab, the one I'm writing into now, is for &quot;Scripting News&quot;. I have one for my development work, general notes, not project-specific. And tabs for all the projects I've been working on in the last few days or in some cases weeks or months. From a writing standpoint, it doesn't matter whether they're on different sites, the idea of a site is not even in the user interface of my editor. In WordPress it's everything. The usual caveat: unless I'm missing something. I imagine people use browser tabs to work on more than one document at a time? I keep thinking there's a lot of stuff we can do to make WordPress work better for writers, I'm trying to be nice about this, but it doesn't work at all for me as a writer. I want it to work. I still can't believe there aren't a dozen different approaches to writing in WordPress. Seems like a fair amount of innovation is possible. I'm a writer who also is a developer. This has been bugging me for the last year or so. Why do I think WordPress is so important? 1. Obviously it has a huge installed base. If there's an opportunity to create something that even a small number of them would like, it's worth doing. 2. WordPress is the only product out there that supports &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; the features of &quot;textcasting&quot;. So If I want lots of outlets for basic text writing, you have to start somewhere. Luckily there's WordPress, sitting there, ready to be recast as a social media app. If you know me, you know I &lt;i&gt;love&lt;/i&gt; puzzles like this. :smile:" created="Thu, 04 Jan 2024 21:22:51 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2022/08/08/bootstrappingByEngelbart.png"/>
				<outline text="The usage of &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;news.scripting.com&lt;/a&gt; keeps going up. All elements of an item are optional, however at least one of title or description must be present. I'm interested in knowing what you think, what you like, what could be improved, does it give you ideas, how can we help. Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/286&quot;&gt;place for comments&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 04 Jan 2024 15:10:46 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="A &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/withastro/astro/issues/9577&quot;&gt;discussion&lt;/a&gt; about whether a feed reader should support titleless items. It should, without question. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html#hrelementsOfLtitemgt&quot;&gt;spec&lt;/a&gt; is very clear. &quot;All elements of an item are optional, however at least one of title or description must be present.&quot; It's how social media sites like Bluesky, Mastodon, et al hook up to the RSS network. Their posts not only don't require titles, they don't allow them, something I'd like to see them ease up on, per &lt;a href=&quot;https://textcasting.org/#1683634931000&quot;&gt;textcasting&lt;/a&gt;. Let the writer decide if a post needs a title. " created="Thu, 04 Jan 2024 15:27:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&quot;Let the writer decide&quot;" created="Thu, 04 Jan 2024 15:36:01 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="A simple rule for designers of social web systems." created="Thu, 04 Jan 2024 15:36:09 GMT" flBulletedSubs="true">
						<outline text="Let the writer decide if a post needs a title." created="Thu, 04 Jan 2024 15:36:13 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="It isn't one-size-fits-all. Some posts will have titles, others won't." created="Thu, 04 Jan 2024 15:37:40 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PS: I think &quot;Let the writer decide&quot; has real potential as a slogan. :smile:" created="Thu, 04 Jan 2024 15:36:48 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 3" created="Wed, 03 Jan 2024 17:32:52 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="03">
				<outline text="On Friday I asked ChatGPT for &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/5bb3c392-c9bc-40eb-81c1-e3520ebffe3d&quot;&gt;1000 words on RSS&lt;/a&gt;. The bot sorted through all the nonsense, got the story, where &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; got &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/be930ca9-f345-4aee-9305-b7dfc79dda10&quot;&gt;mired&lt;/a&gt;.  They left out almost all of the interesting stuff relating to the way it was adopted by the publishing and blogging worlds. The format isn't all that important, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://this.how/standards/&quot;&gt;rules for standards-makers&lt;/a&gt;, what matters is the interop it delivers. The RSS 0.91 to 2.0 thread was what the market built around, because it was promoted to the market and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html#roadmap&quot;&gt;held steady&lt;/a&gt; for it. The other thread got bogged down in an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_Web&quot;&gt;academic theory&lt;/a&gt; of how the web should evolve. Content syndication was a real application. That's the story, imho. There was no mention of the NYT in the Wikipedia piece, or Salon, Red Herring, Wired and Motley Fool. Or NPR in re podcasting, yet without the support of these news orgs, and of blogging software, there never would have been an RSS. " created="Wed, 03 Jan 2024 17:32:53 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2020/01/16/rodneyDangerfield.png"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 2" created="Tue, 02 Jan 2024 12:32:37 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="02">
				<outline text="Basketball is the best game to watch because you get to know the players. Only five players on the court at once, they play both offense and defense, and they aren't wearing armor like football players, you see their faces, whether they're cool or hot, emotional or stoic, up or down. So when your team trades two of its best-known players for three players you've never heard of, to a team that's rebuilding, first you feel sad, and then you wonder what the new teams will be like. One of the traded players, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Immanuel_Quickley&quot;&gt;Immanuel Quickley&lt;/a&gt;, is a young, happy warrior with a deadly offense, but he was a Knicks bench player because they already had an All-Star quality player at his position, point guard, the quarterback of a basketball team. He led the second unit, and probably had a lot to do with the Knicks' success last year. I watched the Raptors game last night, and while the joy seemed to be gone from his demeanor, he was their starting point guard, and now he gets a chance to prove himself. The Knicks got something they needed, desperately, now that their defensive leader, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mitchell_Robinson&quot;&gt;Mitchell Robinson&lt;/a&gt;, is injured and out for the season -- &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/O.G._Anunoby&quot;&gt;OG Anunoby&lt;/a&gt; -- who fit in so well into the starting lineup, in place of the other player the Knicks traded, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RJ_Barrett&quot;&gt;RJ Barrett&lt;/a&gt;, who never became the producer we hoped he would. The new Knicks starting five are a much better team than they were before the trade, or so it seems after one game. I admit, I had gotten bored with Knicks this season, but yesterday's game was interesting and exciting, and even better &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.si.com/nba/knicks/news/new-york-knicks-2024-game-recap-minnesota-timerwolves-julius-randle-og-anunoby&quot;&gt;the Knicks won&lt;/a&gt;, against one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minnesota_Timberwolves&quot;&gt;best teams&lt;/a&gt; in the NBA. Yet we will miss &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Immanuel_Quickley&quot;&gt;IQ&lt;/a&gt; in New York, and hope for him to have a great career in Toronto and beyond. " created="Tue, 02 Jan 2024 12:32:38 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2022/05/30/quickley.png"/>
				<outline text="Steamboat Willie and ChatGPT" created="Tue, 02 Jan 2024 18:11:06 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I got this idea from &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/mmasnick.bsky.social/post/3khzcijt7yp2b&quot;&gt;Mike Masnick&lt;/a&gt; on Bluesky. " created="Tue, 02 Jan 2024 18:11:22 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I asked ChatGPT if Steamboat Willie is now public domain. It said yes." created="Tue, 02 Jan 2024 18:12:01 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I asked if it could draw me a picture of SW saying he's now public domain." created="Tue, 02 Jan 2024 18:12:29 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Not quite. Public dombat." created="Tue, 02 Jan 2024 18:12:42 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/02/publicDombat.png"/>
					<outline text="Was that intentional, I asked?" created="Tue, 02 Jan 2024 18:13:05 GMT"/>
					<outline text="No. Apology. Let's try again." created="Tue, 02 Jan 2024 18:13:13 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Now he's public domant." created="Tue, 02 Jan 2024 18:13:28 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/02/publicDomant.png"/>
					<outline text="But the pictures are cool!" created="Tue, 02 Jan 2024 18:13:43 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="January 1" created="Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:53:54 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="01">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.blog/2024/01/01/removing-duplicates-from-feed-lists/&quot;&gt;New FeedLand feature/fix&lt;/a&gt;. We now remove duplicates from feed lists. This can happen with the advent of reading lists, but it's realllly annoying. Finally got around to making this work in a more reasonable way. " created="Mon, 01 Jan 2024 16:21:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Looking to the future, one thing that would help the web develop more quickly in a more open way for users and developers, with less reliance on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://idioms.thefreedictionary.com/depends+on+the+kindness+of+strangers&quot;&gt;kindness&lt;/a&gt; of  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.threads.net/@threads/post/C1kEkSornag&quot;&gt;big&lt;/a&gt; tech companies -- a commercial identity and storage system that users pay for. There's no reason an independent developer such as myself should have to implement an identity system, and no reason a user should want me to. Yet there is no service that provides storage for users that is accessible to apps that the user chooses. There are a bunch of companies that have all the pieces. There would be so many benefits of this, it would help drive open standards, and make it possible for multiple apps to work on the same data. I don't know why this product doesn't exist. It should. " created="Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:56:29 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2019/09/18/newYorker.png"/>
				<outline text="BTW, I wrote a wizzy writing tool for WordPress. Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/01/blogbrowserscreenshot.png&quot;&gt;screen shot&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted something simpler for posting to feedland.blog. I think it could work even more smoothly, it was a first effort. One thing I don't understand is why aren't there a dozen such writing tools for WordPress. It has a great API, really easy to work with. It's a very versatile product, yet people seem to stick with the built-in writing interface. Curious. " created="Mon, 01 Jan 2024 16:18:13 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Here's the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/tree/master/blog/opml/2023&quot;&gt;OPML archive&lt;/a&gt; for this blog for 2023.  " created="Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:54:59 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			</outline>
		</body>
	</opml>
