<?xml version="1.0"?>
<opml version="2.0">
	<head>
		<title>Scripting News</title>
		<dateCreated>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 15:51:38 GMT</dateCreated>
		<urlPublic>http://scripting.com/publicfolder/scripting/blog.opml</urlPublic>
		<flPublic>true</flPublic>
		<ownerEmail>dave.winer@gmail.com</ownerEmail>
		<ownerId>dave.winer@gmail.com</ownerId>
		<urlUpdateSocket>wss://drummer.land/</urlUpdateSocket>
		<dateModified>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 14:38:07 GMT</dateModified>
		<expansionState>1</expansionState>
		<lastCursor>0</lastCursor>
		</head>
	<body>
		<outline text="February 2024" created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 15:08:26 GMT" name="february2024" type="calendarMonth">
			<outline text="February 29" created="Thu, 29 Feb 2024 16:12:16 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="29">
				<outline text="If the state of journalism is so bad from a business side, and if it's not serving the people very well, I wonder if we could work out some kind of deal here?" created="Thu, 29 Feb 2024 20:52:57 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="If we want even a modest reboot of blogging, as a community thing, we're going to have to start with something like blogrolls. I wrote a bit &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/02/28.html#a154126&quot;&gt;yesterday&lt;/a&gt; about how blogrolls came about, then weblogs.com and how that led to RSS and feed readers. This time, we don't have to wait for feeds to show up, they're already here. It should happen more quickly. " created="Thu, 29 Feb 2024 16:22:46 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Today's song: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5eq1m2s3rzE&quot;&gt;Will The Circle Be Unbroken&lt;/a&gt;." created="Thu, 29 Feb 2024 16:12:17 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5eq1m2s3rzE"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 28" created="Wed, 28 Feb 2024 15:41:25 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="28">
				<outline text="There are a lot of blogging communities out there in 2024, but we don't think of them that way. But they totally behave like a blogging community. I remember when I was starting &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20000621103057/http://www.weblogs.com/&quot;&gt;weblogs.com&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted to get an idea of when sites were updating, so I didn't have to go hunting through a blogroll, clicking on links to find out if there was anything new. So I wrote a script that worked off a list of blogs, read each one in turn, and compared it with the last version we read, and if there was a change, it would move it to the top of the list. I didn't just make it for myself, I shared it with everyone. There was a mail list where people were freaking out about this. The server that would read their blog every so often was called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+subhonker&quot;&gt;subhonker&lt;/a&gt;. This was something new and they were scared. I couldn't show them the benefit until the script had been running for a while. Everyone got upset. I remember being confused and scared, but I guess from their point of view it looked scary. I don't know. In the end weblogs.com became really popular, it became the central place to find out what's new with blogs, and then &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20010123225500/http://weblogs.com/stories/&quot;&gt;evolved&lt;/a&gt; to use &quot;RSS&quot; so we could find changes in even more detail. I guess the thing is people should see the benefit before they see the price? And as an innovator, we have to be aware of this, people may not see the benefit until they can &lt;i&gt;use&lt;/i&gt; it.  " created="Wed, 28 Feb 2024 15:41:26 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/scriptingNewsAd.gif"/>
				<outline text="I'm waiting for someone to give me the tools to index my own content so ChatGPT knows about it. I want it to learn my codebase so I can ask it questions about places I've used a feature before. I want to write code in a very high level language I invent as I go and have it compile it to JavaScript. Come on, what's holding things up. This will be the ultimate productivity software. The first one who gets there owns the world or at least deserves a nice prize and our thanks. " created="Wed, 28 Feb 2024 17:05:10 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I use Safari on my iPad. The software just updated, and they widened the width of icons in the browser chrome. This knocked three of my links over into the menu, out of easy reach. Why did they feel they could change something so basic? After using the iPad for 14 freaking years, why shake up this tiny little corner of the system? What's the possible benefit. Or maybe this is just a bug and they'll fix it? This is the kind of thing that makes me put off updating. Yeah I know it sounds small, but I really use my freaking iPad. It isn't just for watching movies. I can't tell you how many iPads I've bought. It's ridiculous. Come on Apple, I'm a customer not a slave. " created="Wed, 28 Feb 2024 17:00:47 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Re the Michigan primary returns -- I think it's great that 15% of Democratic voters voted &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/michigan-biden-president-uncommitted-democrats-94205d47d3fed9c3ec8deb12b56193c1&quot;&gt;uncommitted&lt;/a&gt; -- because that's democracy, and it does not hurt Biden at all to have the voters express themselves, esp when I'm pretty sure he agrees. Biden is a Democrat, and Netanyahu is a MAGA. Remember that. They are not friends, and Biden has dropped very explicit hints that he's thinking that way. So give him an excuse to kick Netanyahu in the ass, and he'll be happy to do it. But he can't openly threaten Israel now, not with Trump over there saying he'd cut NATO, and thanks to him we're ditching Ukraine, even though Trump isn't in office. All of our alliances are fragile now, and getting worse every time Trump says or does something awful. Biden has to take it steady. I listened to the interviews with advocates for uncommitted, and no one even remotely suggested they'll vote for Trump or a Republican. This is democracy. It's good. That's as American as it gets. " created="Wed, 28 Feb 2024 16:25:14 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2020/12/29/bidenBioCover.png"/>
				<outline text="Another way to think about it. What if, say in California or New York, 15% of the Democrats voted uncommitted to make sure Biden knows he's expected to stand up strong for reproductive rights. That helps clear the way with any Democrats who feel they should go slowly. Voters expressing their political strength. Again, that's pure democracy. It's the best." created="Wed, 28 Feb 2024 16:48:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Think of it this way -- voting is governing. We have a lot of power but only if we use it." created="Thu, 29 Feb 2024 02:46:23 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 27" created="Tue, 27 Feb 2024 12:45:36 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="27">
				<outline text="There's a new faster version of &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;news.scripting.com&lt;/a&gt; coming. I was originally thinking I'd do the switch today, but decided to hold it for a bit. I want to do more testing and development." created="Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:55:27 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/02/27/climate/scientists-are-freaking-out-about-ocean-temperatures.html&quot;&gt;Ocean warming&lt;/a&gt; is a bad thing. Ocean currents determine the weather all around the world, accounting for a relatively mild environment in Europe, for example, even though a city like London is on the same parallel as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Winnipeg#Climate&quot;&gt;Winnipeg&lt;/a&gt;. Once the current is disrupted, people will find their buildings are not prepared for the change, or the cost of heating homes, or growing food. " created="Tue, 27 Feb 2024 23:06:41 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/26/cartoonChicken.png"/>
				<outline text="In the 80s there was a tech press that reviewed software, and explained OSes and hardware, so you really had a good idea what was going on. They just don't do that anymore. Haven't for many years. But along comes ChatGPT and I can get a &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/e8b8e861-4345-45c4-a5bb-8e5b7432b240&quot;&gt;comparitive review&lt;/a&gt; of hosting services that compete with Digital Ocean, just by asking for it. I wanted to get an idea of how easy it would be to create an open source app so it could be easily deployed, on any of them and what the pros and cons were. I asked for a comparison between Digital Ocean (where I host my servers now) and Amazon, Microsoft, Google and I threw in &lt;a href=&quot;https://glitch.com/&quot;&gt;Glitch&lt;/a&gt;, just to anchor the whole thing simplicity-wise. Even InfoWorld wouldn't have done such an in-depth review. This is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Productivity&quot;&gt;productivity&lt;/a&gt; revolution, at least." created="Tue, 27 Feb 2024 19:47:25 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="My &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.threads.net/&quot;&gt;Threads timeline&lt;/a&gt; is full of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.threads.net/@davew/post/C30_luzJBQa&quot;&gt;Kara Swisher&lt;/a&gt; the last few days. She has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/s?k=kara+swisher+burn+book&amp;hvadid=673834124081&amp;hvdev=c&amp;hvlocphy=1023511&amp;hvnetw=g&amp;hvqmt=b&amp;hvrand=4553868743109009067&amp;hvtargid=kwd-2231804831244&amp;hydadcr=22122_13323353&amp;tag=googhydr-20&amp;ref=pd_sl_1th6nk73pi_b&quot;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; coming out. I think she's popular with other journalists. Her theme appears to be that it's the personalities that matter, not what the companies do. I don't think she has a whole lot of insight into the products and technology. For some reason tech, which mystifies a lot of history and english majors, is considered irrelevant or optional, or maybe kind of cute, by the typical reporter. So she expresses tech in terms the journalists understand, therefore they like her.   " created="Tue, 27 Feb 2024 12:45:37 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/27/burnbook.png" imageLink="https://www.amazon.com/Burn-Book-Tech-Love-Story/dp/B0CFYPHG5Z/ref=sr_1_2?crid=3A5HZAPQIQFN8&amp;dib=eyJ2IjoiMSJ9.FM8cBCpWVjk-hhWnwzpLlX0FMjTZPzKAoZCVc70s5piiJcGsYN7gIJYoFxVwo_4v0KHWDRlnMsEaF51rlZN16HeQKQMc4sW4J056RoRAXZT32fFR-c5UJ-4DqGA5dfnesjv2jr2CHTAoQwcR9r43FN43u9_5-gF_fmdDysqBV10WWx5CZ5yn3GManiF5uyQQrq4RX1ZecFx71TZJQPWulhU7jlhI5L1i7KZt2ckiiLeXV9zdCQ3sWXZBjyQb74URk6ltIZS9gZR0AuLOrM4VVI203z1ufKePtL3RPWzbs8E.wF9wf4LkD-HHDyWm9SSu_j9cDqNW_4bCxHA-p9izwIY&amp;dib_tag=se&amp;keywords=burn+book&amp;qid=1709038706&amp;sprefix=burn+book%2Caps%2C106&amp;sr=8-2"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 26" created="Mon, 26 Feb 2024 22:54:48 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="26">
				<outline text="Not much blogging here today. A lot of writing in other contexts. " created="Mon, 26 Feb 2024 22:54:49 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 25" created="Sun, 25 Feb 2024 13:46:41 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="25">
				<outline text="Went out to eat, nice pizza place in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phoenicia,_New_York&quot;&gt;Phoenicia&lt;/a&gt;. There was a guy wearing a brand new Trump hat. I've never seen that in a public place. Otherwise he looked perfectly normal. I wondered what kind of weirdo has that kind of hate in his heart. Is he listening to what Trump is saying these days? I didn't want to ask him. These are our Nazis. They've hated us their whole lives. Until now, I never knew they existed. And now they get to parade around in public with these obscene hats on. When will the swastikas start appearing on the hats. I wonder if this is the first of many. Like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cOeFhSzoTuc&amp;t=24s&quot;&gt;Germans&lt;/a&gt; partying at &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rick%27s_Caf%C3%A9_Casablanca&quot;&gt;Rick's place&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Casablanca_(film)&quot;&gt;Casablanca&lt;/a&gt;. One more thing. Have you heard about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Civil_War_(2024_film)&quot;&gt;Civil War&lt;/a&gt; movie coming out later this year. Watch the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aDyQxtg0V2w&quot;&gt;trailer&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe wait till morning, because you might have trouble sleeping. " created="Mon, 26 Feb 2024 02:29:25 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/25/oldbutton.png"/>
				<outline text="BTW, apparently my &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/02/24.html#a161904&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; yesterday where I said I was &quot;doing some of my best writing in ChatGPT&quot; was confusing. I meant literally what I said. &lt;i&gt;My&lt;/i&gt; writing. Not that I was using ChatGPT to do my writing for me. I can understand that some people do that, writing isn't one of their things. However writing is one of my things. I've been writing every day for almost &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/davenet/&quot;&gt;thirty years&lt;/a&gt;. My writing style has changed a lot over the years. I don't necessarily think it's gotten better, it's just different. I would never post writing publicly written by a anyone other than me without saying it was. Writing for me is very personal. On the other hand, I don't draw very well, never have. I used to be good at box diagrams with arrows, but I'm really out of practice. So if you see something colorful here, that &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; drawn by a bot, unless it says otherwise. I think we all have to be very clear about that. Now, I do write a lot in ChatGPT because I'm trying to get it to help me solve problems, almost always technical. Basically you have to &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/b4235922-c4e2-4996-89cf-48c34cf2af67&quot;&gt;sketch&lt;/a&gt; out the problem in English very specifically so it gives you back what you want. I never thought I'd be programming in English, but here I am doing it. I really want a copy of everything I write, because someday I might want to feed it into a bot other than ChatGPT. There's the lock-in. &lt;i&gt;They own part of me, and I don't even get a copy. &lt;/i&gt;Yes yes I know I can download individual conversations, but not if they include an image btw, did you think of that? And who has time to remember to download them. This is fucked up. One of my action items is to hook &quot;Drummer&quot; up to their API so I'm not relying on their editor. Every time you find yourself typing into a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/01/14/031201.html&quot;&gt;tiny little text box&lt;/a&gt; the alarms should go off. " created="Sun, 25 Feb 2024 15:44:45 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/25/tinytinylittletextbox.png"/>
				<outline text="There's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bJVWZy4QOy0&quot;&gt;Beatles song&lt;/a&gt;, by John Lennon, that was written by cribbing promotional items from a 19th-century &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Being_for_the_Benefit_of_Mr._Kite!#Background&quot;&gt;circus poster&lt;/a&gt;. It's kind of like asking ChatGPT to give you some random phrases and presenting that as your creativity. I think I'm going to &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/4aafde35-2903-48e3-88c0-bcd8725ac702&quot;&gt;try that now&lt;/a&gt;. I asked ChatGPT to write a poem using ideas from a random song written by John Lennon. It chose Imagine. I asked that it write a poem using the ideas in Day Tripper. And finally I asked it to write a song based on the story of The Matrix. " created="Sun, 25 Feb 2024 17:36:54 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="When I see the word &quot;blogrolls&quot; on my screen, in big letters, my brain always sees &quot;bagels&quot; first. I guess we know what's on my mind. :boom:" created="Sun, 25 Feb 2024 13:46:42 GMT" type="outline" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/25/blogrollOrBagel.png"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 24" created="Sat, 24 Feb 2024 16:19:03 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="24">
				<outline text="It just occurred to me that I'm doing some of my best writing in ChatGPT, and I don't automatically get a copy of all that text somewhere I can access it if they go away. Also that writing is not going into any search engine. Normally I watch out for this, but they got me, and you, to write for them for free, and I pay them $20 a month for the privilege. However in balance it is worth it, at least in the short term." created="Sat, 24 Feb 2024 16:19:04 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/13/commanderDataStarTrek.png"/>
				<outline text="Unfortunately ChatGPT has been down just when I needed it for some SQL coding help, so I turned to Google's service, and then thought to paste the post above into it's &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/01/14/031201.html&quot;&gt;tiny little text box&lt;/a&gt;, and see what &lt;a href=&quot;https://gemini.google.com/share/eed40f15f42e&quot;&gt;it had to say&lt;/a&gt;. It suggests, among other things, that I reconsider whether ChatGPT is a good deal. Heh. :smile:" created="Sat, 24 Feb 2024 17:27:31 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 23" created="Fri, 23 Feb 2024 14:02:38 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="23">
				<outline text="The other day I &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/02/21/024211.html&quot;&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt; if an op-ed columnist at the NYT or WP would ever criticize their employer for showing poor judgment on what to report on, esp re the election. I was thinking of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://thehill.com/homenews/administration/4456879-special-counsel-describes-biden-as-elderly-man-with-a-poor-memory-in-eye-raising-report/&quot;&gt;story&lt;/a&gt; about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_K._Hur&quot;&gt;special prosecutor&lt;/a&gt; who did something highly unethical in writing a public, official, condemnation of someone he investigated yet decided not to prosecute. We have judges and juries for that. Only in a police state can a prosecutor pass judgment on an accused person. The news orgs took the bait, I didn't read one report on who &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Robert+K.+Hur&quot;&gt;Robert K. Hur&lt;/a&gt; is, and the ethics of what he did. Is it appropriate to quote a person who was behaving so openly unethically, esp if you don't disclaim that up front. It's not that democracy is on the ballot this year, we're already over the line. Our journalism is acting as if it were already controlled by the authoritarians. Our lack of trust in journalism is our biggest problem. How can we force journalism to start to be a &lt;i&gt;little&lt;/i&gt; accountable. Right now they're the only part of our ruling class that can't have their choices reviewed. " created="Fri, 23 Feb 2024 14:24:25 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/23/hur.png"/>
				<outline text="Old enough to know besteer" created="Fri, 23 Feb 2024 14:02:39 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I came up with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/02/22.html#a031907&quot;&gt;motto&lt;/a&gt; for Joe Biden's presidential campaign -- Old Enough to Know Better." created="Fri, 23 Feb 2024 14:02:46 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I asked ChatGPT to draw a campaign rally with a banner that said that, but it wouldn't do it for Joe Biden, so I changed the name to Bull Mancuso, and had him run for governor of Calif instead of president of the US. "/>
					<outline text="It still couldn't spell the banner correctly but it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; pretty inspiring." created="Fri, 23 Feb 2024 14:02:58 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The banner should read &quot;Old Enough to Know Better.&quot;" created="Fri, 23 Feb 2024 14:03:03 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/23/campaignAdForBiden.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 22" created="Thu, 22 Feb 2024 13:58:17 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="22">
				<outline text="I have the motto for the Biden campaign: &lt;i&gt;Old enough to know better.&lt;/i&gt; Uncle Joe, sit down with a reporter you can relate to, and explain what aging is about. How there's good and bad that come with getting on, and Repubs (of course) have been focusing on the bad but the journalists aren't getting the other side. One thing is for sure, it's hard to put one over on someone who's been in politics at the highest level for as long as President Joe has been. That's what the &quot;know better&quot; part is about. Whatever you can say about him, he knows a lot about being president. I've been using this motto as my own tagline for a while. But in the interest of protecting our democracy, I think the president should use it for his re-election campaign. No charge. :smile:" created="Fri, 23 Feb 2024 03:19:07 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/14/bidenActionFigure.png"/>
				<outline text="Another Beatles post " created="Thu, 22 Feb 2024 13:58:18 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Even though they are, for me, the biggest band ever, I've never been able to see the connection to the John Lennon of the early Beatles, and the long-haired bespectacled wild John Lennon that came later. I don't &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?sca_esv=a2fe021a8e3ee580&amp;rlz=1C5CHFA_enUS743US747&amp;sxsrf=ACQVn09xZcYYO14qGpQ6FPXz7LE5WADxEw:1708610594208&amp;q=john+lennon&amp;tbm=isch&amp;source=lnms&amp;prmd=ivnhsmbtz&amp;sa=X&amp;ved=2ahUKEwjPwJu8jr-EAxVoGtAFHWOfBiQQ0pQJegQIDRAB&amp;biw=1511&amp;bih=1029&amp;dpr=2&quot;&gt;see them&lt;/a&gt; as the same person. Not the other Beatles, they all make sense to me. Sometimes they have longer hair or a beard or whatever, but it's still the same face as before. Also I have trouble figuring out which Beatle is singing sometimes. On some songs it's perfectly obvious, others I have no clue. For example Norwegian Wood, Come Together, Strawberry Fields and Lucy in the Sky, that's John of course. Right? Hey Jude, that's clearly Paul, as is Let it Be, Yesterday. But for years I didn't know who sang Lady Madonna. Martha My Dear? Paul could sing so many different kinds of music. John, not so much. I guess. I'm still pretty unsure. " created="Fri, 23 Feb 2024 03:25:39 GMT" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/22/youngLennon.png"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="ChatGPT designed a civilization" created="Thu, 22 Feb 2024 19:12:11 GMT" type="outline" description="No rule of law for you! You are the law. " metaImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/22/simsGPTCity.png">
					<outline text="What I asked for: Imagine a version of The Sims or SimCity that had ChatGPT integrated,. You could create whole civilizations and then explore them, and if there was something you didn't like, you could have your way. No rule of law for you! You are the law. I wonder if you could draw me a Sims-like community as ChatGPT would design it." created="Thu, 22 Feb 2024 19:12:22 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&quot;Here's a visual representation of a vibrant, utopian community as imagined with the integration of ChatGPT's design principles. This community blends futuristic architecture harmoniously with nature, featuring energy-efficient homes, community centers, and public spaces all connected by pedestrian pathways and lush gardens. Solar panels and wind turbines integrate seamlessly into the buildings, and the central plaza acts as a hub for gatherings, surrounded by parks, sports fields, and a lake for water activities. This illustration embodies an ideal balance between technology and nature, promoting health, well-being, and environmental stewardship.&quot;" created="Thu, 22 Feb 2024 19:13:02 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/22/simsGPTCity.png"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="I don't care if you're at a BigCo" created="Thu, 22 Feb 2024 15:12:40 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I don't care if you work at a big company or are an individual developer. " created="Thu, 22 Feb 2024 15:13:05 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I care if you can make a contribution toward interop on the open web.  " created="Thu, 22 Feb 2024 15:13:11 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I've found over the years that sometimes devs at bigco's can help enormously (eg microsoft, netscape, automattic) but more often they are harmful (apple, ibm, sun, google stand out as the worst). Sometimes companies play both roles (apple)." created="Thu, 22 Feb 2024 15:13:25 GMT"/>
					<outline text="But i also know that bigco's because they are big, have lots of different ideas how the world should work. And that can help."/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Twitter's big competitive advantage" created="Thu, 22 Feb 2024 15:11:30 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="&lt;i&gt;I wrote this &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1760681139407360255&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; this morning. Re-posted here with minimal editing. The fact that I could write it on Twitter was the point.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Thu, 22 Feb 2024 15:11:40 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Twitter has one advantage over all the other social webs. no character limit. " created="Thu, 22 Feb 2024 15:14:11 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I started typing a post on Threads which has a large character limit compared to the others, but ran out of space and decided to write it over here in twitter instead. "/>
					<outline text="yes they charge me $8 a month for it, but it's worth it. "/>
					<outline text="we have to get used to the idea of paying for value, it's how we avoid the messes of the last 20 years. esp if we can make sure we retain copies of everything we write (guaranteed by using our own writing tools, btw) which is another requirement for the new blogosphere. "/>
					<outline text="btw, i'm having a blast these days. it's like tinkerbell in peter pan. all the open web needed was people to believe it exists for it to come (back) into existence."/>
					<outline text="still diggin. "/>
					<outline text="ps: i also like they have simple styling, but where are the freaking links, twitter. do I have to pay another $8 to get those??"/>
					<outline text="pps: the worst character limit is bluesky, i can't write anything there. too bad, it's a really nice system otherwise."/>
					<outline text="ppps: it would be nice to give something like this a title so you don't have to read pgf after pgf to try to figure out where i'm going and if you're interested. so i gave it a title, using markdown syntax. maybe they could just support markdown. hmmm."/>
					<outline text="pppps: i asked chatgpt to draw an illustration. that light in the middle of the room is the open social web. it's a vision of self-reliance, empowerment and cooperation. I asked for the light to be &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tinker_Bell&quot;&gt;tinkerbell&lt;/a&gt;, but i guess they were concerned the image might belong to someone. creeping shitification. " created="Thu, 22 Feb 2024 15:15:33 GMT"/>
					<outline text="This is not a picture of Tinkerbell." created="Thu, 22 Feb 2024 15:15:35 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/22/tinkerbellAndKids.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 21" created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 14:15:12 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="21">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8Zeyej5bfZE&quot;&gt;Today's song&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Old enough to know better.&quot; " created="Thu, 22 Feb 2024 03:03:28 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8Zeyej5bfZE"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.threads.net/@davew/post/C3ojf4gMDwe&quot;&gt;Threads&lt;/a&gt; is like a new airport, like Denver's airport was a few years ago, and Twitter feels like the old &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LaGuardia_Airport&quot;&gt;LaGuardia&lt;/a&gt;. Not sure what Mastodon feels like. I'll have to think about that. Maybe the airport in New Orleans which is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Louis_Armstrong_New_Orleans_International_Airport&quot;&gt;Armstrong Field&lt;/a&gt; now, IIRC. It used to be called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Louis_Armstrong_New_Orleans_International_Airport#:~:text=The%20airport%20was%20originally%20named,Airport%20retained%20the%20code%20NEW.&quot;&gt;MSY&lt;/a&gt; and it still is actually, even though the name changed. Power of standards. " created="Thu, 22 Feb 2024 03:05:39 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Consider this quote from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://wapo.st/48uLvKF&quot;&gt;WP article&lt;/a&gt; about a court ruling on abortion in Alabama. “Women who actually know what happened, feel under attack and almost powerless.” When historians look back on this election, they will be amazed that all the attention wasn't focused on reproductive rights, esp when 1. It mattered so much to virtually every American, in very real non-abstract ways, and 2. There was such a dramatic difference between the two parties and candidates on this issue. I think I understand why journalism can't get there. Because they would have to turn the agenda over to the people, and give up a power they have and enjoy, even if that power has repeatedly sent us wildly in the wrong direction, focusing on things that don't matter as much as the gut-wrenching decision Americans have to make this year. Do we want to let Republicans enslave women, 1/2 half the populace, or do we want to return to the way things were before Dobbs. I don't have to explain. Very few people on the fence here. What we need are people directly affected by this situation, women of childbearing age, and let them speak, over and over, every day, about all the ways their lives are turned upside down by the direction the Repubs are taking us. No longer &lt;i&gt;trying&lt;/i&gt; to take us. There isn't much to argue about here, it's fairly black and white and it is a real division, not one of the bullshit devisions the Repubs have been able to trick the journalists to focus on. " created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 14:15:13 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2019/12/23/you.png"/>
				<outline text="Are there any gutsy NYT op-ed columnists?" created="Thu, 22 Feb 2024 02:42:11 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Certainly &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; of the NYT columnists must have noticed that the management is playing a dangerous game with our election." created="Thu, 22 Feb 2024 02:42:17 GMT"/>
					<outline text="When are they going to write a column raising the question of how non-transparent the process is, and how dangerous it has become. "/>
					<outline text="Might take a bit of courage to do that, and being willing to put your career on the line, for all of us."/>
					<outline text="Just asking the question, even if they fired you, seems as big an issue as the question raised by the special prosecutor re Biden's age?"/>
					<outline text="I've been a columnist for a somewhat major publication myself, and I promise you, if I were witnessing what's going on at the NYT, I'd submit the column, and if they didn't run it, I'd offer it to their competitors, and if they wouldn't take it, I'd run it publicly on a blog, and say that they wouldn't run it. "/>
					<outline text="You can't really witness something like this without speaking up. They gave you the platform, you should use it." created="Thu, 22 Feb 2024 02:43:16 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Feed cleaning" created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 22:46:20 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I'm doing a feed cleanup, unsubbing from broken feeds, and ones that haven't updated since last summer. " created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 22:46:27 GMT"/>
					<outline text="There are some people and orgs whose feeds no longer update who I miss. I'm going to call them out here. If your name appears here that means at least one person misses your blogging. Do with that as you may. However if you start blogging, I would be very upset if you didn't let me know the URL of your site or feed. " created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 22:46:47 GMT" flBulletedSubs="true">
						<outline text="David Weinberger" created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 22:48:10 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Douglas Rushkoff" created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 22:47:53 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Eli Pariser" created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 22:49:13 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Farhad Manjoo" created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 22:50:56 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Fivethirtyeight" created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 22:48:15 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Fred Wilson" created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 23:00:40 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Heather Cox Richardson (podcast, she may no longer have one)" created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 22:51:25 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Jeff Jarvis" created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 23:06:18 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Joel Spolsky" created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 22:48:03 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Mother Jones podcast" created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 23:02:14 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="NYT sports feeds all appear to be gone, I think this is probably because they've stopped covering sports?" created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 22:49:39 GMT" flBulletedSubs="true">
						<outline text="NYT &gt; Sports &gt; College Basketball" created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 22:50:39 GMT"/>
						<outline text="NYT &gt; Sports &gt; College Football" created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 22:58:29 GMT"/>
						<outline text="NYT &gt; Sports &gt; Tennis" created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 22:58:29 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="Blogs I subscribed to for sentimental reasons" created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 22:52:06 GMT" flBulletedSubs="true">
						<outline text="One of my &lt;a href=&quot;http://bullmancuso.com/blog/rss.xml&quot;&gt;RSS test feeds&lt;/a&gt; from 2001. " created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 22:52:15 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="Existential questions" created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 23:03:34 GMT" flBulletedSubs="true">
						<outline text="Does &lt;a href=&quot;http://openrss.org&quot;&gt;openrss.org&lt;/a&gt; have a feed? It seems like it should. :-)" created="Wed, 21 Feb 2024 23:05:27 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 20" created="Tue, 20 Feb 2024 13:30:55 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="20">
				<outline text="Journalists like everyone in America should pray President Biden stays healthy, because our only alternative is Putin. And btw in Russia, the non-government-owned news people had to leave, to go into exile. The journalists are playing with fire not just for us, but for themselves too. It's not ridiculous to ring the bells really loud about this because we've already lived through &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2016_United_States_presidential_election#Results&quot;&gt;this nightmare&lt;/a&gt; once. " created="Tue, 20 Feb 2024 18:38:55 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2022/05/05/butheremails.png"/>
				<outline text="Surely there must be people inside the NYT that find &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/20/exhaustedPeopleAtNYTimes.png&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; as exhausting as we do. How can we set up a receptacle for leaks from inside the NYT and WP so we can get the truth about who's selling us out to Trump and Putin inside those supposedly great public-serving news orgs? " created="Tue, 20 Feb 2024 13:30:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I don't like Twitter/X -- it's stupid, it already had a perfectly good name. It is what it is. I use Twitter, I don't imagine stopping, certainly not as some kind of demonstration. But it isn't X or Twitter/X. It's just stupid old fucked up Twitter, only now it's fucked for a different reason. I might go for Twitter/F as in Twitter is Fucked thank you very much. And have a nice day. :smile:" created="Tue, 20 Feb 2024 17:27:29 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/07/30/birdAndHBO.png"/>
				<outline text="Ski boot sizing" created="Tue, 20 Feb 2024 15:29:34 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="One thing that's great about ChatGPT is they can help you make a decision in an area you lack expertise and where there is no human you can ask for help making the decision. It's making this human smarter, and it's hard to see the downside of that. " created="Tue, 20 Feb 2024 15:24:11 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="Here's an &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/be9ca3a4-4e74-4fe0-a778-d5595fe8482d&quot;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt;. I'm trying to decide whether I should get size 11 rental ski boots or size 11.5. The person behind the counter at the rental place isn't capable of having a long conversation about this, where I get to ask two follow-up questions. " created="Tue, 20 Feb 2024 15:35:52 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Instead they would say sorry, what size did you say you wanted sir? " created="Tue, 20 Feb 2024 15:36:48 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The kid isn't thinking about the old dude. :smile: " created="Tue, 20 Feb 2024 15:29:47 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/20/skibootsizing.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 19" created="Mon, 19 Feb 2024 14:04:21 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="19">
				<outline text="I've had a recent change of direction. Now I'm factoring into my thinking and planning that there will be a rebirth in blogging, because I see there are people willing to work on making the systems work together in new interesting ways. That's what it's going to take -- we have to capture the imaginations of the smartest web writers. And the only thing that's going to get their attention is developers working together to create new experiences for everyone. Now I believe it's going to happen. " created="Mon, 19 Feb 2024 17:16:59 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2021/06/14/strongman.png"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/293&quot;&gt;Random thought&lt;/a&gt; -- maybe the fastest way to get full ActivityPub support for WordPress is to offer a feature in any WP site to cross-post to a Mastodon gateway operated by Automattic. It's possible I don't understand the problem of course. But Mastodon is open source, so it's not like depending on another vendor to do this for you. And then you avoid all the hassles with having to say what part of the protocol is ActivityPub and what part is Mastodon's API." created="Mon, 19 Feb 2024 14:50:33 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Eagle on a tree" created="Mon, 19 Feb 2024 18:18:54 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="This eagle was perched on a tree near my house. " created="Mon, 19 Feb 2024 18:18:59 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/19/eagleOnTree.png"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="I look forward to dumping Trump again" created="Mon, 19 Feb 2024 14:06:17 GMT" type="outline" metaImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/19/trumpAndHisMaster.png" description="Putin's little buddy.">
					<outline text="I've mostly kept Trump off the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/&quot;&gt;home page&lt;/a&gt; of this blog since he left office in 2021, but things are changing, and this is shaping up as a Trump year. I read today in the NYT that the resistance &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/02/19/us/politics/trump-resistance-democrats-voters.html?unlocked_article_code=1.Wk0.0hoY.duTfLtk_PUxj&amp;smid=url-share&quot;&gt;is exhausted&lt;/a&gt;. Bullshit. We're very well rested. Anyway I look forward to once again, pretending Trump doesn't exist, next year or the year after, Murphy-willing. " created="Mon, 19 Feb 2024 14:04:22 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/04/10/trumpBeingCarriedAway.png"/>
					<outline text="The other day when I was skiing at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.belleayre.com/&quot;&gt;Belleayre&lt;/a&gt;, I got to ride up on a chairlift with a Trump supporter. He told me he got Covid but it wasn't a big deal, just like a cold. I said a lot of people died from Covid. He said most were already sick or overweight. I said yeah but they deserve to live too. He said he didn't get vaccinated, he doesn't like to put drugs in his body. What bullshit I muttered under my breath. I looked at him, maybe ten years younger than me. From New Jersey, a house painter. I said that my life has been saved by drugs at least twice, once when I was perfectly healthy other than having a ruptured appendix at 9 years old. I also said you're really lucky not to have needed medical care, but before you die I bet you will. And I thought to myself but didn't say out loud that what about your parents and grandparents, siblings even children? Have they all been perfectly healthy until they died? Anyway a chairlift is not a safe place for real anger, but -- you also can't walk away from the other person. There's a lot of soul-sharing on rides like that.  " created="Mon, 19 Feb 2024 14:23:15 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="What Trump means by making America great." created="Mon, 19 Feb 2024 14:06:24 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/19/whatMagaReallymeans.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 18" created="Sun, 18 Feb 2024 18:16:15 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="18">
				<outline text="I'm trying out using various social networks to start threads. Still going to use GitHub for serious stuff, but the last few days, some of my posts on Mastodon and Twitter have gotten unexpected interest. Not sure what to attribute it to, some people have theories, but why not just go with the flow. " created="Sun, 18 Feb 2024 19:43:38 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2020/12/15/myOrangeJelloBox.png"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.threads.net/@davew/post/C3fj0TfM11F&quot;&gt;Threads&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Blogrolls may have seemed silly to outsiders, even to the bloggers of the day, but they were the first step after basic writing on the web (blogs) that led to the social web we're using on Twitter, Mastodon, Threads, Bluesky or Facebook. The blogroll says 'these are the sites and people I follow.'&quot;" created="Sun, 18 Feb 2024 19:44:48 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I'm &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@davew/111954173806083779&quot;&gt;looking&lt;/a&gt; for an example of a WordPress site that has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com/support/wordpress-editor/blocks/blogroll-block/&quot;&gt;block-oriented&lt;/a&gt; blogroll on it." created="Sun, 18 Feb 2024 19:39:00 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Any billionaire could probably buy Trump now for $500 million, and thus put a bet down on the 2024 election. It could probably payoff 100-to-1 easy. " created="Sun, 18 Feb 2024 18:19:04 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="ChatGPT has been down for me for the last couple of hours. I am really dependent on this thing. " created="Sun, 18 Feb 2024 18:16:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 17" created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 14:34:10 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="17">
				<outline text="Hope you like blogrolls, I'm focusing on them for a while. :smile:" created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 15:12:36 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Yesterday I posted the ChatGPT &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/02/16/174119.html&quot;&gt;explainer&lt;/a&gt; for blogrolls, but realized later there was an important use of blogrolls it didn't mention. I kept a blogroll on my home page because those were the sites I wanted to check regularly to see what's new. So I was thinking about my own use of my blog, not just helping out sites I support or giving ideas to people who read my blog. Also they didn't provide an illustration of what a blogroll looks like. Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20000815061940/http://scripting.com/&quot;&gt;snapshot&lt;/a&gt; from August 2000, and sure enough, in the left margin, there's the blogroll. Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/17/blogrollScreen.png&quot;&gt;screen shot&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 14:34:11 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="A &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20030501151324/http://scripting.com/&quot;&gt;snapshot&lt;/a&gt; from May 2003. The template was redesigned, and there are changes to what's in the blogroll, but it's still there, in the same place. " created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 14:49:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20040901012553/http://scripting.com/&quot;&gt;By August 2004&lt;/a&gt;, the blogroll is gone. I don't remember why I took it down, probably because I wasn't using it very much, because by then we had feeds, and Radio UserLand (a feed reader and blogging tool) and the blogroll was just a list, and didn't have any way of telling me in advance that a site had updated. " created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 14:54:09 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="All of a sudden my posts &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@davew/111947246973482688&quot;&gt;on Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; are getting liked and forwarded a lot more than on the other platforms. What changed? Hmm." created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 14:45:55 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Beatles" created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 21:08:23 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="My #1 Beatles song these days is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2IbPn5j2YKk&quot;&gt;Day Tripper&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 21:08:30 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Most of my listening has been to John Lennon, and more reading.  " created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 21:08:41 GMT"/>
					<outline text="A lot of his lyrics intentionally mean nothing. " created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 21:08:55 GMT"/>
					<outline text="My current infatuation is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gimme_Some_Truth&quot;&gt;Gimme Some Truth&lt;/a&gt; from Imagine is pretty great because the lyrics are super clear, and quite forceful and beautiful. Of course we want the truth, some of us at least, and you can't tiptoe around that. Most people have arranged their lives so they avoid the truth at all costs. In the end the truth prevails for everyone no matter how hard you try." created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 21:09:16 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Then I saw a quick interview with Ringo and Paul, current day, and Ringo is being kind of a bitch saying that Paul was a workaholic, and he's standing right there, but he isn't disagreeing in fact he's nodding his head, basically saying he likes to do things. " created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 21:10:54 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I always wish as a child of their breakup that they had found a way to work together, and for John and George to have their independence from Paul. He definitely took the brunt, but it looks to me like he was desperate to keep the Beatles from breaking up and that brought out his powerful control freak side." created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 21:11:41 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Thing is to people my age, these were our uncles. But maybe there was nothing after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=12R4FzIhdoQ&quot;&gt;The End&lt;/a&gt;? Maybe they really were done. We like to believe there was more, but maybe there wasn't.  " created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 21:12:57 GMT"/>
					<outline text="And of course the people who were Beatles were just people, strangers to us really, we were just projecting our dreams on them. Until the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beatles:_Get_Back&quot;&gt;Get Back&lt;/a&gt; show, which answered so many of our questions were answered and got us thinking and dreaming again. " created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 21:13:51 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_Jackson&quot;&gt;Peter Jackson&lt;/a&gt; changed the world of 20s as much imho as the Beatles did in the 60s. He did a great thing. " created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 21:16:22 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Journalism isn't responsible" created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 17:47:49 GMT" type="outline" description="The Trump-size debacles are journalism's responsibility. " metaImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/17/gratefulDeadBandPhoto.png">
					<outline text="There is no organized oversight of journalism. No one whose criticism they respect. And they don't criticize themselves. It's a monopoly, with no reason to change, and that's a formula for a festering mess. Their sense of entitlement is legendary. Such chutzpah. Until it shakes up, we're going to keep getting Trump-size debacles. " created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 17:48:02 GMT"/>
					<outline text="They could easily blame their employers for creating Trump. If it weren't for his reality show would his followers see him as anything other than a pathetic East Coast blowhard with a bad combover. Instead they blamed Facebook. Not that FB didn't profit enormously from Trump, but you just can't see the role journalism plays because they can't bite the hand that feeds them. But we can. I don't owe them anything, do you?" created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 17:56:41 GMT"/>
					<outline text="BTW it would be incredible to see an investigative report of how the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/OutOfTheLoop/comments/5tbx4y/where_did_the_but_her_emails_image_meme_come_from/&quot;&gt;But Her Emails&lt;/a&gt; meme was birthed? What does it say about cynicism about the press. Did any journalists hear it? Do any of them feel it?" created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 17:49:23 GMT"/>
					<outline text="We feel this. Was journalism paying attention?" created="Sat, 17 Feb 2024 17:49:50 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/17/butHerEmails.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 16" created="Fri, 16 Feb 2024 17:41:18 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="16">
				<outline text="What is a blogroll?" created="Fri, 16 Feb 2024 17:41:19 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I asked ChatGPT to &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/972ad854-8975-4397-9bff-9b03af9e7577&quot;&gt;explain&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 16 Feb 2024 17:41:29 GMT">
						<outline text="A blogroll is a list of links to other blogs or websites that a blogger enjoys or finds relevant. It's often found in the sidebar of a blog. The purpose of a blogroll is to share recommendations with readers and to connect with the broader blogging community. By including a blogroll, a blogger can provide their audience with access to additional resources, opinions, or communities that share similar interests. It can also serve as a tool for networking and building relationships with other bloggers, through mutual linking or acknowledgment. Blogrolls were more prominent in the early days of blogging but can still be found on many sites today." created="Fri, 16 Feb 2024 17:41:36 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="I couldn't improve on that, so I published it as-is." created="Fri, 16 Feb 2024 17:41:37 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 15" created="Thu, 15 Feb 2024 19:31:31 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="15">
				<outline text="I thought ChatGPT could &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/02/15/openais-newest-model-can-generate-videos-and-they-look-decent/&quot;&gt;make a movie&lt;/a&gt; for me, so I sketched one out. &quot;I'd like a video showing a middle-aged man skiing down an intermediate slope, looking excellent and confident. It's sunny and there are bumps on the hill, and a few other skiers on the side of the slope with expressions of astonishment that such an old person can be such a snazzy skier.&quot; Instead of making the video for me, it wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/578996d7-3e42-4fa8-8a9a-f827059234ed&quot;&gt;creative plan&lt;/a&gt; for me. That wasn't what I had in mind! :smile:" created="Thu, 15 Feb 2024 20:39:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Skiing is falling" created="Thu, 15 Feb 2024 19:40:50 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I went skiing again today, second time in two weeks. Feeling pretty good. And I learned something I'd like to share. A different way of looking at skiing. Here's the story..." created="Thu, 15 Feb 2024 19:31:32 GMT"/>
					<outline text="First thing in the morning the snow was hard and while they had done a good job of grooming, you do a lot of sliding when you edge when the snow is so hard. Much more than in the powder you get in the Rockies. So I'm always totally thinking about staying in control and it's stressful. In this mode I ask myself why I'm doing this if it's so unpleasant. " created="Thu, 15 Feb 2024 19:44:01 GMT"/>
					<outline text="But as the snow softened during the day, and my body warmed up, and my brain remembered more about this strange thing that I used to do so well, I started going faster, not worrying as much, and then started going faster, and I started feeling like wow I'm doing this well, and then boom, for an instant I completely lost control and was tilted one way, but had to land the other way, and without any conscious thought and absolutely no time to worry, my brain and body did exactly what you have to do to make this look and feel super elegant, almost as if I must have planned it this way. " created="Thu, 15 Feb 2024 19:44:26 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I kept skiing a bit after that and then stopped and breathed the cold air, and looked at another ski area far in the distance (Hunter?) and realized something -- skiing is falling. You go to a mountain top, pull down your goggles, get to the top of some steepness, and you jump. The question is -- do you look and feel beautiful while doing it, or are you scared and trying to stay in control. But that's the thing, falling is all about letting it go and trusting your mind and body will know what to do when you fall one way, and also when you fall another. " created="Thu, 15 Feb 2024 19:44:51 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 14" created="Wed, 14 Feb 2024 15:11:20 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="14">
				<outline text="I've taken to cross-posting to various social media accounts, by opening a new window, creating the post in one service's &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/01/14/031201.html&quot;&gt;little text box&lt;/a&gt;, and then opening tabs for each of the others and copy-pasting. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1757524645773754675&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@davew/111926409460785756&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:oety7qbfx7x6exn2ytrwikmr/post/3klddy3d2ps2k&quot;&gt;Bluesky&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.threads.net/@davew/post/C3TbfkspurD&quot;&gt;Threads&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/photo/?fbid=2188904567983603&amp;set=a.113966572144090&amp;notif_id=1707865039746710&amp;notif_t=feedback_reaction_generic&amp;ref=notif&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. I'm getting good at it. Yesterday I did that with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/02/13.html#a214721&quot;&gt;piece&lt;/a&gt; about President Biden and how he probably would rather be doing anything than be President, for a mostly thankless country, at age 81. I imagine he has great-grandchildren he'd like to get to know. Maybe a book or two to read, maybe one to write. To get his affairs in order. At age 68 I'm trying to shed responsibility as much as possible. It's prudent, and has a point. When I was 25 I wanted to take over the world. Now I'd just like to feel good. As you get older you are capable of more depth of feeling, in some ways, and grow more numb in others. I spent time with my father at 80, his last year. He was always a curious man, wanting to learn about anything new, but in his last days he wasn't curious. No ambition. But he seemed okay with it, even happy at times (possibly due in part to the morphine he was allowed). Anyway, it's always interesting to see where people react to what among the different social web networks. And in this case, the most flow came from &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@davew/111926409460785756&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, by far. I would not have predicted that. And it's good to see, that interesting ideas and perspective may have more of a future outside the networks operated by the billionaire tech companies. " created="Wed, 14 Feb 2024 15:11:21 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/14/bidenActionFigure.png"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 13" created="Tue, 13 Feb 2024 14:15:45 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="13">
				<outline text="The &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/?tab=news&quot;&gt;News tab&lt;/a&gt; on the Scripting News &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/13/newstabscreen.png&quot;&gt;home page&lt;/a&gt; was set up to request the &lt;i&gt;All&lt;/i&gt; category from my FeedLand account. I switched to Tech, it's a bit faster, and probably a better fit. Still looking for a performance issue. " created="Tue, 13 Feb 2024 21:36:51 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="If you're thinking it might be good if President Biden stepped aside for someone younger and nicer to look at, what you really want is President Biden to be younger and nicer looking, and of course he probably wouldn't mind that either. But, as Keith Olbermann spells out so well in his latest &lt;a href=&quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/garland-must-stop-hurs-plans-to-testify-to-house-gop-2-13-24/id1633301179?i=1000645128033&quot;&gt;Countdown&lt;/a&gt;, if he were to step aside that would basically concede the election to Trump. So if you think the old man is being silly and vain, well, he's being a lot smarter than you are, and btw, paying a huge price. If you live to be 81, I bet the last thing you want to do, after the life he's had, is to be in this position. We should get behind him, and tell him so, let him know we don't want anyone else, and we want him to be happy, healthy and know that the smart, good people of the US appreciate what he's doing for all of us. " created="Tue, 13 Feb 2024 21:47:21 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2020/11/26/uncleSam.png"/>
				<outline text="I was happy to see &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jon_Stewart&quot;&gt;Jon Stewart&lt;/a&gt; back on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?app=desktop&amp;si=Y7FkIjfh53qr2Ib8&amp;v=NpBPm0b9deQ&amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;the Daily Show&lt;/a&gt;. I wish he would get over how he looks, all of us have aged in the time since he was last on the Daily Show. It was really good. He finally is back with the writers he belongs with, and this show obviously agrees with him, and I got the feeling I always used to get from his show &quot;we'll figure this out.&quot; " created="Tue, 13 Feb 2024 16:48:15 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NpBPm0b9deQ"/>
				<outline text="The next hurdle for AI is to teach the software to learn about you. I think that's what we all want. Start with the simplest things. This is my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedland/blob/main/database/database.js&quot;&gt;coding style&lt;/a&gt;, so give me all the example code you generate this way. Where does this end? No idea. But read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/54120408-klara-and-the-sun&quot;&gt;Klara and the Sun&lt;/a&gt;, a truly great story, beautifully told, for a truly creative application. " created="Tue, 13 Feb 2024 14:18:25 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/13/commanderDataStarTrek.png"/>
				<outline text="This is what I imagine we all yearn for, for someone to really know us before we die. Okay if it can't be other people, at least let it be a machine. Something like preserving a brain. Wouldn't it be great to know that when you're gone, the essential you, even if it doesn't include your consciousness, persists? You could visit a person like you visit a website. This is just evolutionary, and it's obviously going to happen. " created="Tue, 13 Feb 2024 14:24:20 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Today would be the perfect day to ski at Belleayre or Hunter, if you can get out of NYC where all the snow is falling. I have work to do and was planning on skiing tomorrow, expecting 8 inches of fresh snow. We're not getting much from this storm in the Catskills, NYC is getting the brunt. And any day you can't get here from the city means not many people on the mountain. :smile:" created="Tue, 13 Feb 2024 14:15:46 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="A powerful blogroll!" created="Tue, 13 Feb 2024 21:04:50 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I'd like a fanciful cartoon drawing of a blogroll that automatically sorts itself out when something new comes in. It's happy and fun but also &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; powerful!" created="Tue, 13 Feb 2024 21:05:02 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/13/powerblogroll.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 12" created="Mon, 12 Feb 2024 15:49:48 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="12">
				<outline text="The best &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/02/11/arts/television/super-bowl-commercials-ads-best-worst.html?unlocked_article_code=1.U00.Jgwq.OkuZtc0l9IOV&amp;smid=url-share&quot;&gt;SuperBowl ad&lt;/a&gt; according to my stringent quality standards was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sOH23Pup6AQ&quot;&gt;Reese's Peanut Butter Cups&lt;/a&gt;, proving that comedy isn't hard, just have people reacting to stupid stuff in ridiculous self-destructive ways. Physical comedy for some reasons is ROTFL funny. They can do this because everyone knows and loves their delicious product and while it isn't good for you, it won't kill you either. And the announcer is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+bojack+horseman&quot;&gt;Bojack Horseman&lt;/a&gt;, so you know that's pretty cool too. " created="Mon, 12 Feb 2024 23:50:40 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/12/reesesPeanutButterCups.png"/>
				<outline text="Big &lt;a href=&quot;https://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=42.0426&amp;lon=-74.1183#.XB1p8c9KiX0&quot;&gt;snowstorm&lt;/a&gt; coming in tonight. And working on some interesting new software. That's about all for now. " created="Mon, 12 Feb 2024 23:17:24 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The SuperBowl last night was an excellent sports game. I didn't like all the bullshit, but it was good sport. However it's all about gambling. I bet it's ruining a lot of lives. A way of sucking the last pennies from people who are already struggling. And it's so easy, just get an app for your phone, add your credit card, and give them all your money." created="Mon, 12 Feb 2024 15:49:49 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The Niners didn't win but Taylor Swift did, that's good enough for me. " created="Mon, 12 Feb 2024 19:49:02 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="There's a chain of beating hearts connecting back in time from you to a fish that crawled onto land, one of your many ancestors (assuming you believe in evolution, I guess). Actually, even if you don't believe. :smile:" created="Mon, 12 Feb 2024 23:42:35 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Just give me some truth" created="Mon, 12 Feb 2024 23:32:55 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I just found myself writing in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.threads.net/@davew/post/C3RBrhlJfgb&quot;&gt;tweet on Threads&lt;/a&gt; that the news industry has contempt for its readers that AI tools don't have. " created="Mon, 12 Feb 2024 23:33:02 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Actually the AIs also have a way better attitude about the truth than Wikipedia does (yes I know Wikipedia is a Ouija board, that the very worst people control)." created="Mon, 12 Feb 2024 23:33:22 GMT"/>
					<outline text="We weren't worried about the rise of fascism and the destruction of our ecology, but we were worried about preserving jobs for supposed truth-tellers who think we deserve garbage and don't disappoint. " created="Mon, 12 Feb 2024 23:33:07 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dynMUeKLCOA?si=jR6RmeQY0iBGpgg4&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;" created="Mon, 12 Feb 2024 23:34:51 GMT"/>
					<outline text="For ten points, who was the &lt;i&gt;Tricky Dicky&lt;/i&gt; he was singing about?" created="Mon, 12 Feb 2024 23:44:33 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 11" created="Sun, 11 Feb 2024 15:21:47 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="11">
				<outline text="I'm almost rooting for KC just so Taylor can be the total dominant uncontested Queen of America." created="Mon, 12 Feb 2024 02:51:25 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="If the Supreme Court had an ounce of guts they would say &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/trump-insurrection-14th-amendment-2024-colorado-d16dd8f354eeaf450558378c65fd79a2&quot;&gt;this isn't&lt;/a&gt; a state matter, it's a federal matter, and we are the federal government, so here's the deal. Trump tried to overthrow the government and he took an oath to protect the government, and therefore the 14th Amendment applies, and he can't be on the ballot anywhere, including Colorado." created="Sun, 11 Feb 2024 20:33:54 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Where did &lt;a href=&quot;http://isRssDead.com/&quot;&gt;RSS being D&lt;/a&gt; come from? The meme was started by VCs and tech influencers in the 00s. A bunch of VCs had RSS startups, hired people who didn't know anything about it to run the companies. " created="Sun, 11 Feb 2024 16:38:33 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/07/02/validRss.png"/>
				<outline text="Today's song: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XpqqjU7u5Yc&quot;&gt;How Deep is Your Love?&lt;/a&gt;" created="Sun, 11 Feb 2024 16:51:27 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XpqqjU7u5Yc"/>
				<outline text="One way is always better than two" created="Sun, 11 Feb 2024 15:35:10 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Most Hacker News threads devolve into people talking about personalities, not about tech stuff. But yesterday's &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39324847&quot;&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt; about OPML was the rare exception, until someone who says they like me (I guess) said something personal and ugly. " created="Sun, 11 Feb 2024 15:21:48 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="I wonder why after all this time we can't see how pointless it is to have opinions about people, esp online. Everything you hear is passed through someone else's filters, so you're getting a huge dose of their personality along with a sliver of insight into the person they're talking about. " created="Sun, 11 Feb 2024 15:41:01 GMT"/>
					<outline text="And don't forget to factor in that sometimes when someone has put an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+interop&quot;&gt;obstacle&lt;/a&gt; in the way of big companies, you can earn favor inside those companies by scandalizing the person whose work they object to. There was a lot of that happening as RSS crossed paths with some very big and rich companies with lots of employees, and an interest in appearing to interop without the cost of interop." created="Sun, 11 Feb 2024 15:41:33 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I've tried to add formats, protocols and software to the mix, always trying to compromise. It's not mentioned in the Wikipedia page on RSS that I had a format that does what RSS does, a year before it existed, but I gave it up so that Netscape and UserLand would build on the same format, RSS. " created="Sun, 11 Feb 2024 15:31:08 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I didn't invent RSS. I did something much greater, I compromised. We had the leading blogging software at the time, and Netscape had the feeds of four credible news orgs. When you put them together, that turned out to be huge power. We eventually pulled in all of social media and all of professional publishing into one format. Ask anyone who was active at the time. The blogging world adopted RSS in an instant, in 1999 and 2000. And in 2002, when the NYT adopted it, again, in an instant the entire news world all of a sudden all had RSS feeds. You can see it in the steady stream of announcements in the archive of &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/&quot;&gt;this blog&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sun, 11 Feb 2024 15:42:46 GMT"/>
					<outline text="BTW there was someone brilliant at Netscape who saw our compromise and responded with more compromise. Their next version of RSS had some of the features we had left behind in our format. We never asked them to do that, they just figured it out. Collaboration is something that requires two, one person can't collaborate on their own. I know that sounds ridiculous, but sometimes people don't look for the other party who made compromise possible." created="Sun, 11 Feb 2024 15:37:49 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I don't think even the people who were closest to it at the time understood the move. And I don't think very many appreciate the power that comes from being the one who throws in the towel on their pet project to attain unity. " created="Sun, 11 Feb 2024 15:33:33 GMT"/>
					<outline text="One way of doing something is always better than two. That's just a restatement of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robustness_principle#:~:text=It%20is%20often%20reworded%20as,an%20early%20specification%20of%20TCP.&quot;&gt;Postel's Postulate&lt;/a&gt;. Be conservative in what you send. " created="Sun, 11 Feb 2024 16:59:57 GMT"/>
					<outline text="That doesn't just apply to you, it applies to all of us collectively. Every time you add something that already exists we're all going to pay for it. " created="Sun, 11 Feb 2024 15:55:41 GMT"/>
					<outline text="If you think that saying this makes me &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/cantankerous&quot;&gt;cantankerous&lt;/a&gt; -- well, I say okay -- but you're wrong because it's generous and brilliant to push back when people add complexity. Of course people don't like to hear they're doing something wrong, but when it comes to accumulating complexity debt unnecessarily, well imho you have to listen to that. Complexity is a force against interop. " created="Sun, 11 Feb 2024 15:55:50 GMT"/>
					<outline text="We should be looking for opportunities to work together to create something greater than anything any one of us can create. " created="Sun, 11 Feb 2024 17:47:23 GMT"/>
					<outline text="See also: the role of &lt;a href=&quot;http://essaysfromexodus.scripting.com/priorArtDesignMethod&quot;&gt;prior art&lt;/a&gt; in design." created="Sun, 11 Feb 2024 15:39:38 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 10" created="Sat, 10 Feb 2024 13:36:28 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="10">
				<outline text="Steven Levy asked an interesting question on Bluesky or Threads, can't remember which. Would I feel differently if I knew a work of art that I found inspiring was created by an AI. At first I said no, because what matters in art is how it is received, not how it was created. What effect did it have on the viewer. That's the art. But then I remembered that when I found out that Wordle was edited by a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wordle#:~:text=In%20November%202022%2C%20the%20Times,checks%20each%20word%20for%20suitability.&quot;&gt;human&lt;/a&gt;, that the words were chosen by a person not at random, I found the game less interesting, because certain words obviously would be eliminated from consideration, even though they are in the dictionary and are used in normal writing and speech. I found myself guessing at who the editor is, and that's not why I play Wordle. I don't know why, but understanding this &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tracy_Bennett&quot;&gt;person&lt;/a&gt; isn't it. " created="Sat, 10 Feb 2024 15:23:19 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2017/10/04/goldenGirl.png"/>
				<outline text="Trump is treated by Big News the way they cover climate change, with a big shrug, what can we do. Meanwhile, they get all twisted up in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hillary_Clinton_email_controversy&quot;&gt;Her Emails&lt;/a&gt; and the like." created="Sat, 10 Feb 2024 13:36:29 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I enjoy blocking “top contributors“ on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dave.winer.12/posts/pfbid02GUFDRLGhcTvA2iGvBEAYTSo5CLrg8p4jneyd9zJoWvFkNgsVQJiqmMYA1F9W7pXVl&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; who respond with sarcasm to requests for help." created="Sat, 10 Feb 2024 16:18:18 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="A WordPress namespace?" created="Sat, 10 Feb 2024 14:27:50 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Thinking out loud. " created="Sat, 10 Feb 2024 14:22:05 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="It would be interesting if every feed for a wordpress.com site included the &lt;i&gt;site_ID&lt;/i&gt; of the site an item came from, and if every item had the &lt;i&gt;ID&lt;/i&gt; of the item it came from. Shorten the distance from seeing something that needs editing to actually being able to edit it. " created="Sat, 10 Feb 2024 14:28:02 GMT"/>
					<outline text="This was one of the big realizations of &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/davenet/1999/05/24/editThisPage.html&quot;&gt;Edit This Page&lt;/a&gt; in 1999.  " created="Sat, 10 Feb 2024 14:31:23 GMT"/>
					<outline text="A WordPress-aware reader might be able to do something with this. Or if it knew that the user owned the site it came from, it could open it in a simple editor. " created="Sat, 10 Feb 2024 14:28:22 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I was thinking through a use-case and came across this idea. " created="Sat, 10 Feb 2024 14:28:33 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Isn't it time for there to be a WordPress namespace? After all it's not only a big part of the web, it's also a big part of the feed world. " created="Sat, 10 Feb 2024 14:28:38 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 9" created="Fri, 09 Feb 2024 13:44:58 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="09">
				<outline text="The US government is incapable of defending itself. The tools are in the Constitution. Clearly, even if Trump loses, we're going to go through the same insurrection bullshit only this time around they'll be more practiced and determined. Our ancestors foresaw this event and provided for it. Speaking for them, after listening to the audio from yesterday's Supreme Court hearing, how could it be any more obvious this guy can't be given a second chance. You (Supreme Court) have a job to do. You're the only ones who can judge whether the former President violated his oath, the one you gave him if you recall (&lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/09/robertsTrump.png&quot;&gt;John Roberts&lt;/a&gt;).  I think it was set up that way so you'd get the point that you're the one who has to hold him to his oath. Now if you won't do it, step aside, and you all keep stepping aside until someone has the guts to stand up for the country and its Constitution. Tell the Repubs to nominate someone else because this dude broke his oath and as the 14th Amendment says so freaking clearly, &lt;i&gt;he can't serve again.&lt;/i&gt; How does it make sense to give him the same oath again when he violated it in such a craven way last time. If we as a country can't come together for this, then we don't deserve to survive." created="Fri, 09 Feb 2024 20:58:10 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2020/11/26/uncleSam.png"/>
				<outline text="If you have a new trend in tech, the absolute &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.citationneeded.news/review-read-write-own-by-chris-dixon/&quot;&gt;worst way&lt;/a&gt; to promote it is as a replacement for existing layers of tech with huge &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Installed_base#:~:text=Installed%20base%20of%20a%20product,a%20particular%20product%20or%20technology.&quot;&gt;installed bases&lt;/a&gt;. You can't win that kind of comparison. Installed bases generally don't disappear, and if they do, it happens very slowly. You almost certainly don't have the replacement, but you might have a useful product that would appeal to people, so be smart and explain it that way, if you just happen to &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/2ba3a8fb-8951-4c23-b955-b32199f3ebe6&quot;&gt;boil the ocean&lt;/a&gt; with it, you can thank your luck because that's what actually happened. " created="Fri, 09 Feb 2024 18:22:15 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="In other words you can't just wish something like the web into existence, you can't plan it, or architect it or envision it. It happens on its own. Look at all the time and energy &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tim_Berners-Lee&quot;&gt;TBL&lt;/a&gt; put into &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_Web&quot;&gt;reinventing&lt;/a&gt; the web. Never happened, and he's the guy who got the web started in the first place. I've been there when something small became huge and real, twice actually. But I couldn't tell you why, I just have theories. I called it &quot;media hacking&quot; at the time. Create a new media type and put it out there to see if it would stick. After a while nothing would stick because the pipes were controlled by Twitter, Google and Facebook and they weren't sharing. Now we're kind of letting Facebook own the pipes Twitter used to own. Maybe. So many people appear to be fooled into thinking FB is doing something open. They should learn the rules of tech, it's nowhere near as complicated as football or basketball. If everyone wants to interop with one company, nothing open can come out of that. Threads became the thing people wanted to interop with a couple of days after it came into existence. Now it must be orders of magnitude greater than Mastodon, and it's not going to hit any scaling walls because they've already scaled it, in every way. There's still time, I think, for new ideas, but maybe not much time. We'll see. " created="Fri, 09 Feb 2024 19:34:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 8" created="Thu, 08 Feb 2024 16:12:13 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="08">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/292&quot;&gt;What tool would you use&lt;/a&gt; to create and edit a blogroll?" created="Thu, 08 Feb 2024 18:16:04 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="When I was your age, if you're in your late teens or early 20s, there was nothing remotely like Apple Music or Spotify. If we wanted to listen to a specific album we'd have to buy a copy of the vinyl record at a music store. I used to go to a store called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.themushroomnola.com/&quot;&gt;Mushroom Too&lt;/a&gt;, on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Zimpel+St+%26+Broadway+St,+New+Orleans,+LA+70118/@29.941399,-90.1285116,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m6!3m5!1s0x8620a51059b4faf3:0xdf6e23353b2d059d!8m2!3d29.9413944!4d-90.1236461!16s%2Fg%2F11h9w_9m9_?entry=ttu&quot;&gt;Broadway and Zimpel&lt;/a&gt; in New Orleans. It was kind of like a head shop, smelled of incense, and they had a great sound system and they were always playing good music. It was on the second floor above a bar called &lt;a href=&quot;http://thebootnola.com/About.html&quot;&gt;The Boot&lt;/a&gt; that had the usual college stuff, beer, burgers, pinball. The record store had rows of racks of albums, like a library in a way, and you'd wander around looking for bands you knew or had heard about, and you'd stare at album covers, front and back and try to decide. Looking for &quot;something good to listen to.&quot; And you could only afford a certain number every year, so you listened to each album a lot. I don't know if it works that way for young folk today. In 50 years when you're looking back will you know the songs in the order they appeared on the album? I never bought singles, by the time I came along &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Album-oriented_rock&quot;&gt;album rock&lt;/a&gt; was the thing, stations like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WNEW-FM#WNEW-FM&quot;&gt;WNEW&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WPLJ#Album_rock_era_(1971%E2%80%931983)&quot;&gt;WPLJ&lt;/a&gt; in New York. I'd listen to the student station at Tulane, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wtulneworleans.com/&quot;&gt;WTUL&lt;/a&gt;. They'd play longer songs, and not always the most popular song on an album. You got the sense that the DJ was being creative with the songs they chose. BTW, both &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/@29.9412696,-90.1236609,3a,75y,126.2h,90.89t/data=!3m6!1e1!3m4!1so4ETHDqh4PD37X_ohhKMow!2e0!7i16384!8i8192?entry=ttu&quot;&gt;Mushroom and The Boot&lt;/a&gt; are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.themushroomnola.com/&quot;&gt;still&lt;/a&gt; there. What a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/@29.941323,-90.1235289,3a,75y,181.71h,82.36t/data=!3m6!1e1!3m4!1sB3XzunnLa0Afz58c3kgh2Q!2e0!7i16384!8i8192?entry=ttu&quot;&gt;trip&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 08 Feb 2024 23:00:54 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/08/woodstock.png"/>
				<outline text="There was also a local station that was like KFOG in the Bay Area, can't remember its name. And of course like everyone everywhere I &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ogWPyrlj_V8&quot;&gt;listened&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dr._Demento&quot;&gt;Dr Demento&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 08 Feb 2024 23:17:29 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Later, when I was a grad student in Madison, I lived in a house with nine roommates. We shared lots of stuff, including our record collections and all of a sudden new music worlds opened to me, including (memorably) Bonnie Raitt, Little Feat, Talking Heads and Saturday Night Fever (which I'm &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oALKAh_bL5g&quot;&gt;listening to&lt;/a&gt; as I write this). " created="Fri, 09 Feb 2024 03:05:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Jury duty is self-government" created="Thu, 08 Feb 2024 16:12:14 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Jury duty is an intensive bootcamp for American democracy." created="Thu, 08 Feb 2024 16:12:23 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The great thing about jury duty is you get a very clear sense of what self-government is about. It makes you feel empowered which can be even more uncomfortable than feeling powerless."/>
					<outline text="So much of the frenetic activity online is about that sense of powerlessness. So we give money to causes or we join in boycotts, but these aren't as powerful as participating in governing. Jury duty is a very quick way to do that."/>
					<outline text="We have to act more like citizens and less like subjects. I think that's the real message of the election of 2016. Subjects elect someone like Trump. People who think like citizens would elect someone very different." created="Thu, 08 Feb 2024 16:12:39 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;i&gt;I wrote this on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dave.winer.12/posts/pfbid0522gNDxHBUGssi5VFE2oLZeVkv4eYbRN7JtwkKAHcCM51CBAGFctyMHAs4Wrkgqpl&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; on this day in 2017. &lt;/i&gt;" created="Thu, 08 Feb 2024 16:12:40 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 7" created="Wed, 07 Feb 2024 20:16:15 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="07">
				<outline text="I went skiing today at &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Belleayre_Mountain&quot;&gt;Belleayre&lt;/a&gt;. First time in five years. It was great. I've been working out to get ready for it, and was concerned maybe I'm finally too old, but it's good. My body remembers how to ski. And being in shape makes the difference. No doubt at some point I will be too old for it. But not yet. And the snow was really good, for the east. Packed powder, very little ice. No lift lines. Sometimes a little crowded on the slopes but about the same as any ski area in the west. It pays to go on weekdays if you can. Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.belleayre.com/mountain/trail-map-and-mountain-stats/&quot;&gt;trail map&lt;/a&gt; and some stats on the area. " created="Wed, 07 Feb 2024 20:16:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Social networks and RSS. We really should be on the case for all social media networks to support RSS feeds outbound at least (inbound nice too). And also add features to make interop really useful. I've enumerated them &lt;a href=&quot;https://textcasting.org/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I am making software that builds on this feature in social networks. And yes we do have some examples of that, thinking of WordPress and competitors. I think they are perfectly good bases for social networks." created="Wed, 07 Feb 2024 20:17:29 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 6" created="Tue, 06 Feb 2024 14:09:35 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="06">
				<outline text="This is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.threads.net/@kteare/post/C2-MHcJL1L5&quot;&gt;first pitch&lt;/a&gt; I’ve heard for the Apple goggles that actually makes me want to buy a pair. If there were an Apple Store nearby I probably would have already gotten it." created="Tue, 06 Feb 2024 21:20:13 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I'm reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Oath-Honor-Warning-Liz-Cheney/dp/0316572063&quot;&gt;Liz Cheney's book&lt;/a&gt;, and forgot something I had guessed during the insurrection. While it was going on Trump was calling Congresspeople saying if you stop the count I'll call off the attack. In other words, trade your life for a vote. I suspected it before, but they have testimony that verifies it." created="Tue, 06 Feb 2024 15:32:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I asked ChatGPT to &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/01/06/040838.html&quot;&gt;draw&lt;/a&gt; a &quot;social network for writers.&quot; :heart:" created="Tue, 06 Feb 2024 14:45:21 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I'm doing some writing about writing and finding the phrase &quot;RSS, Atom and RFD&quot; too cumbersome. Most people don't care and see the distinctions as unnecessary. But I want to be accurate, and recognize that while RSS is the most-used kind of feed, there are others, and our software works with them. I'm trying this construction: &quot;RSS-compatible.&quot; I think that expresses the most important point, the choice of format is up to you, but now, by 2024, they all work pretty much the same way. " created="Tue, 06 Feb 2024 14:38:30 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Good morning. The main static server I &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/02/05.html#a143645&quot;&gt;mentioned&lt;/a&gt; yesterday has been relocated to a fresh, new and apparently healthy server to perform its past duties. We're off to a good start this Tuesday morning. " created="Tue, 06 Feb 2024 14:09:36 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 5" created="Mon, 05 Feb 2024 14:07:51 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="05">
				<outline text="I was asked about the difference between &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/&quot;&gt;feedland.com&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.org/&quot;&gt;feedland.org&lt;/a&gt;. Which should you create a new account on? " created="Mon, 05 Feb 2024 14:38:07 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2022/03/21/beetle.png"/>
				<outline text="feedland.org runs on a small &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.digitalocean.com/droplets/new&quot;&gt;Digital Ocean server&lt;/a&gt;, and Com runs in a data center. The first is a fixed-size relatively small scale server that can't expand, and the latter is designed to scale automatically according to demand. I spent most of 2023 converting the software to run in the scalable environment. " created="Mon, 05 Feb 2024 14:58:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="If you're creating something new, definitely create it on feedland.com. If you're already using feedland.org, for now you're welcome to continue, but in the back of your mind think about creating a new account on Com and importing your subscription list. Org is proving useful to have around, so I don't imagine it'll go away, it's much easier for me to work on a DO server than on the big cloud-based server. " created="Mon, 05 Feb 2024 14:58:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="You should assume that some day &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; these systems will disappear. The web is ephemeral. But -- my guess is &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/&quot;&gt;feedland.com&lt;/a&gt; will be around longer. However, honestly, I really have no idea, no one does. " created="Mon, 05 Feb 2024 15:00:12 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, while we're doing this transition in FeedLand, I also have a small crisis happening on my main static server, which depends on a combination of software that suddenly aren't getting along with each other. Obviously something changed. I'm running it in a somewhat crippled state, I may be figuring how to dig out of this hole. One of the downsides of having fun with server software." created="Mon, 05 Feb 2024 14:36:45 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Everyone's watching and listening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RealBrittain/status/1754316190552375724&quot;&gt;Fast Car&lt;/a&gt; this morning. It's a time capsule for so many of us. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fast_Car&quot;&gt;1988&lt;/a&gt;. A window back to good times." created="Mon, 05 Feb 2024 14:07:52 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 4" created="Sun, 04 Feb 2024 12:50:06 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="04">
				<outline text="One of the cool things about being a programmer is that you can decide to run code that you know has zero chance of working. &quot;Let all hell break loose,&quot; a programmer can be heard to say quietly before clicking the Run button. Very few design professions get to do this, I imagine, unless they're psychotic." created="Sun, 04 Feb 2024 14:25:04 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Wellll, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/02/03/171343.html&quot;&gt;Lakers&lt;/a&gt; beat the Knicks last night. No joy in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mudville&quot;&gt;Mudville&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 04 Feb 2024 12:50:07 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The pros and cons of &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/7368bddd-6a10-448a-8556-141a45f84379&quot;&gt;pre-ground cannabis&lt;/a&gt;, per ChatGPT." created="Sun, 04 Feb 2024 12:56:30 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 3" created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 14:11:06 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="03">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.org/&quot;&gt;feedland.org&lt;/a&gt; is back. Next up, new software features that build on the new back-end features. :smile:" created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 16:54:32 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/02/28/presidentCarter.png"/>
				<outline text="People are really gushing about the Apple goggles, now that they have them in their hands. I still can't get psyched about it. I was late to getting an &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2016/04/10/1175.html&quot;&gt;Apple Watch&lt;/a&gt;, and now I &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/03/appleWatch2024.png&quot;&gt;wear it&lt;/a&gt; every day, can't imagine not wearing it. So maybe I will get one eventually. But my vision is weak, and I kind of doubt it'll work for me. And I would much prefer if Apple had poured their vast resources and creativity into making mass transport work in the Bay Area instead, as a prototype for what might be possible in the rest of the world. &lt;i&gt;That&lt;/i&gt; I would cheer, unconditionally. " created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 21:06:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Too late for LeBron in NY" created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 17:13:43 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I have nothing against &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LeBron_James&quot;&gt;LeBron&lt;/a&gt; except in my mind he should be retired by now like Chris Paul, Carmelo Anthony or Dwyane Wade, his generation of NBA star, whose time has clearly passed. " created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 14:54:01 GMT" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2019/07/02/knicks.png"/>
					<outline text="I would be very very very offended if the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_York_Knicks&quot;&gt;Knicks&lt;/a&gt; did a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.si.com/nba/2024/02/02/espns-stephen-a-smith-pitches-blockbuster-lebron-james-trade-lakers-knicks&quot;&gt;trade&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/February_8&quot;&gt;deadline&lt;/a&gt; that brought him to NY to win one more championship. If they did that, I don't think I could ever see myself as a Knicks fan again. It would be the most serious form of betrayal, and would show that the management has no freaking clue about NY basketball. " created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 17:29:57 GMT"/>
					<outline text="We don't mind that the Knicks haven't won a championship since 1973. Obviously we don't mind, or we would not have suffered through all the bozo-osity of the owner and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phil_Jackson#New_York_Knicks_(2014%E2%80%932017)&quot;&gt;people&lt;/a&gt; he hires. We love this team, and we especially love the 2024 version of the Knicks. " created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 17:14:13 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The last trade was the best ever, even though we had to say goodbye to Quickley, knowing he never really got a chance to shine in NY. " created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 17:14:20 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LeBron_James&quot;&gt;LBJ&lt;/a&gt; on the Knicks in 2024 would be a terrible fit. About ten times worse the KD on the Nets. " created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 17:14:29 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Morning coffee notes" created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 14:28:11 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://ma.tt/2024/02/vision-pro-first-impressions/&quot;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ma.tt/2024/02/rowing-to-alcatraz/&quot;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matt_Mullenweg&quot;&gt;Matt Mullenweg&lt;/a&gt; last night. I asked friends at Automattic if it's my imagination or is Matt blogging a lot more now than he used to and they say yes. " created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 14:15:48 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Matt is a good writer, it turns out. I read his posts as he dealt with the Tumblr situation, which was evolving quickly in real time at the end of last year. You can tell he's done a lot of this, relating to users and developers. I was going to say I've never led a community as large as his, but that's not exactly true. In general people don't treat you very well if you're at the top of something large, esp if they don't pay anything for it, it seems. " created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 14:28:54 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Watching him deal with it has made me question the idea of me making software for other people. There was a brief period between 2017 and 2021 that I only made software for myself, and I liked that a lot, but it has the downside that the ideas have little chance of surviving to influence others. So as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2022/09/18.html&quot;&gt;20th anniversary&lt;/a&gt; of &quot;RSS 2.0&quot; approached, I convinced myself to try one more time. Now this morning, in the middle of a pretty huge transition for &quot;FeedLand&quot;, that's been going slowly and confusingly, and is far from done, I realize that such a major upheaval in an already-deployed server-based product, is really asking for trouble. I feel it in my digestive system, as I used to when I was a kid and internalized all the stress from home life. I'm feeling that stress in a way I haven't felt in a long time. So I think this is the last time I do this. My next product will be a writer's tool and will largely run on the user's machine, and have a small server component, by design, with software that's been well burned-in. I'm not worried about that. And it's okay, because I really think this is the last big corner-turn that FeedLand will need. " created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 14:34:55 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I probably should write a post explaining what this change is about, or at least record a podcast. If you want to see the details, it's all there in the narrated work &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedlandInstall/issues/56&quot;&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt;. And I will continue to post there until the transition is complete. " created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 14:31:24 GMT"/>
					<outline text="This morning, while I'm waiting for the last query to run, I'm looking through the old sites on the other server (mentioned &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/02/02.html#a162816&quot;&gt;yesterday&lt;/a&gt;) and have been looking through various archives I'm carrying with me, including the book my father wrote called &lt;a href=&quot;http://mbatoolbox.org/&quot;&gt;MBA Toolbox&lt;/a&gt;. It's a responsibility I feel, and I often think I should modernize the site. It's got the look of a Manila site from the late 90s or early 00s. But it doesn't look all that bad, and he did all the work himself, so this is the way he wanted it to look. " created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 14:11:07 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PS: I noted from his Wikipedia &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matt_Mullenweg&quot;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt; that Matt was born 15 days before the Mac was announced, an event we celebrated the 40th anniversary of last month, which adds up because Matt celebrated his 40th birthday a few days before all that. 🎉" created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 14:41:48 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PPS: It turns out we were closer than I thought when I wrote this piece this morning. By noon, the server was updated, the software had been modified to work with the new database schema, and it re-opened to users. What I thought initially would take a few hours took 1.5 days. Once the corner was turned, I took a nap, watched some &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BoJack_Horseman&quot;&gt;Bojack Horseman&lt;/a&gt;, am going to do a Peloton and then watch the Knicks, and I'm starting to feel human again. Whew. " created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 21:03:40 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 2" created="Fri, 02 Feb 2024 14:11:38 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="02">
				<outline text="We hit a &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/17824486/mysql-query-timing-out-70100-query-execution-was-interrupted&quot;&gt;snag&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedlandInstall/issues/54#issuecomment-1919574144&quot;&gt;upgrade&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.org/&quot;&gt;feedland.org&lt;/a&gt;. The work is narrated in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedlandInstall/issues/56&quot;&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt;. Here's what the snag was. We were low on storage starting at the beginning and eventually we ran out of space, and the error messages we got indicated the problem was something else. All the searching we did, none of the hits, or ChatGPT suggested looking at memory usage. Quite independently after thrashing around trying various theories, we finally got a message from the Digital Ocean service saying the server was out of space. When I doubled the space, that gave it enough room to do the tasks we had for it. Now running the last query. Looks like we may be over the hump. Let's just pray the software runs when we turn the server back on. :boom:" created="Fri, 02 Feb 2024 15:06:49 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2021/09/17/simpsonsBeeGuy.png"/>
				<outline text="At 10PM Eastern, we still haven't finished the upgrade. Will &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qp_djIuQ2Cw&quot;&gt;return&lt;/a&gt; to the job tomorrow AM. " created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 03:10:41 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qp_djIuQ2Cw"/>
				<outline text="If I were running Bluesky -- I'd think about incentives for people with the kind of following they want to cultivate to do most or all of their social media'ing there. Some people are already doing it or so it seems, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/neilhimself.neilgaiman.com&quot;&gt;Neil Gaiman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/andrewhickey.bsky.social&quot;&gt;Andrew Hickey&lt;/a&gt;, and I'm sure there are lots of others.  " created="Fri, 02 Feb 2024 22:22:10 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I have a server that handles all my old sites, and it needs to be replaced, so I'm trying to figure out where to put all the sites. Most are really small, 10 or fewer files. But &lt;a href=&quot;http://outline.land/treefun&quot;&gt;outline.land/treefun&lt;/a&gt; was large and interesting, so I thought I'd put a link here. I have forgotten so many of my little experiments. " created="Fri, 02 Feb 2024 16:28:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/02/frontierScriptToSortOutFolders.png&quot;&gt;script in Frontier&lt;/a&gt; to sort the folders by how many files they contain. I shudder to think how long it would take to write in JavaScript with all its synchronous difficulties." created="Fri, 02 Feb 2024 22:25:27 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Debugging misbehaving servers" created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 03:17:11 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Generally I wish I had a checklist that said: " created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 03:17:22 GMT" flNumberedSubs="true">
						<outline text="Do this." created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 03:18:02 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Then that." created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 03:18:05 GMT"/>
						<outline text="And finally this." created="Sat, 03 Feb 2024 03:18:07 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Cats are people too!" created="Fri, 02 Feb 2024 20:47:50 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="&quot;Cats are on the march in NYC, on 8th Ave between 57th and 45th streets. Thousands of cats carrying signs and handing out leaflets saying 'Cats are people too!' and 'Up with Cats!' -- they are angry but there's a sense of celebration in the march, that finally the time has come for cats.&quot;" created="Fri, 02 Feb 2024 20:47:57 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The first version had one of the themes as &quot;Down with Dogs!&quot; but ChatGPT rejected that as not being nice enough. So I changed it to &quot;Up with Cats!&quot; Please keep that in mind." created="Fri, 02 Feb 2024 20:49:55 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Cats are marching on 8th Ave" created="Fri, 02 Feb 2024 20:49:35 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/02/catsRUs.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="February 1" created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 15:08:27 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="01">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://textcasting.org/&quot;&gt;Textcasting&lt;/a&gt; is rewriting the rules of the social web." created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 15:38:22 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Here's what's going to happen. A bunch of new networks are forming, and they will melt into one, following a pattern established by the internet itself, when they formed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transmission_Control_Protocol&quot;&gt;net of nets&lt;/a&gt; based on a common protocol called TCP. On top of that HTTP was built, with a number of years following with very productive building and bootstrapping, and from there it was a lot of chaos, around the advent of Twitter, Facebook and Google Reader. The last time we had a common way of &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2014/03/21/theWebIsMadeOfInterop.html&quot;&gt;interop&lt;/a&gt; was 17 years ago. I think/hope we're incentivized to make one edit box suffice, in place of the 5-10 &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2024/01/14.html#a145854&quot;&gt;tiny little textboxes&lt;/a&gt; we now all have to copy-paste between, and btw one way of addressing nodes, and then we can start building again as we did last in the 90s and 00s. I see something brilliant in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/31/24057231/iconfactory-kickstarter-internet-reader-project-tapestry-twitterrific&quot;&gt;new path&lt;/a&gt; that Twitteriffic wants to go down (I gave &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/iconfactory/project-tapestry&quot;&gt;them&lt;/a&gt; $128). It's same path I've been going down, mostly without partners, for the 17 years since we crawled on land and started tweeting. I don't see the negative shit that's happening on Twitter, it's easy to avoid the mess -- I don't think that's the reason we're breaking out of that silo -- it's that all at once all the devs who had been quietly suffering with Twitter were set free. Boom. All at once. And it turns out perhaps we don't give up so easily. :smile:" created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 15:09:36 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/01/runner.png"/>
				<outline text="Every time you &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/01/14/tinyLittleTextBox.png&quot;&gt;see&lt;/a&gt; a tiny little textbox that's a sure clue they're trying to own you, and hoping you don't notice." created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 15:40:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedlandSupport/issues/236&quot;&gt;Heads-up&lt;/a&gt; to users of feedland.org. There will be a little downtime tomorrow AM, Eastern time, for a system upgrade. " created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 22:09:27 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="January's posts have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/blob/master/blog/opml/2024/01.opml&quot;&gt;archived to GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, now we start a new month. February. What wonders will happen this month??" created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 15:08:28 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Bard does pics" created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 23:02:20 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Google's Bard now does pictures. I asked for thousands of cats marching on 8th Ave in NYC between 57th St and 45th St. A very different style from what ChatGPT would have drawn and I like it. " created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 23:02:26 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Cats on 8th Ave." created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 23:02:43 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/01/catsOnEighth.png"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="What's up at Harvard?" created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 22:10:59 GMT" type="outline" description="In my two years at Harvard in 00s, I never saw or experienced antisemetism there." metaImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2024/02/01/catsHeaderImage.png">
					<outline text="I wrote this note to Chris Lydon re the &lt;a href=&quot;https://radioopensource.org/the-humbling-of-harvard/&quot;&gt;latest episode&lt;/a&gt; of his podcast. " created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 22:11:08 GMT">
						<outline text="Chris," created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 22:11:25 GMT"/>
						<outline text="I'm listening to your latest &lt;a href=&quot;https://radioopensource.org/the-humbling-of-harvard/&quot;&gt;podcast about Harvard&lt;/a&gt;, and totally appreciate this. " created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 22:13:15 GMT"/>
						<outline text="In my two years at Harvard in the 00s, I never:">
							<outline text="1. Experienced antisemitism." created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 22:13:23 GMT"/>
							<outline text="2. Saw antisemitism."/>
							<outline text="3. Even thought about the &lt;i&gt;possibility&lt;/i&gt; of antisemitism." created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 22:13:24 GMT"/>
							</outline>
						<outline text="On the Harvard campus."/>
						<outline text="That said, antisemitism is everywhere, even inside me, a man whose grandparents were Jews who fled for their lives with their children from the Holocaust before and during WWII. I am a product of that, in ways I didn't even realize until my parents were gone. It's everywhere, all around, inside myself, inside everyone, and the best we can hope for imho is that it will stay hidden. " created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 22:13:55 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Ask me about what happened in the NBA with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+kyrie&quot;&gt;Kyrie Irving&lt;/a&gt;, and how, by their silence, the players and coaches showed how huge and deep the problem is." created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 22:14:48 GMT"/>
						<outline text="To see the Repubs monetize this for political gain is par for the course. To see Harvard buckle under that, is weak and the people who made that decision imho should resign in disgrace. " created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 22:20:49 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Thanks for your continued and unique excellence. " created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 22:15:09 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Dave" created="Thu, 01 Feb 2024 22:15:10 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			</outline>
		</body>
	</opml>
