<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- RSS generated by oldSchool v0.8.16 on Sun, 11 Jan 2026 01:03:04 GMT -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:source="http://source.scripting.com/">
	<channel>
		<title>Scripting News</title>
		<link>http://scripting.com/</link>
		<description>Dave Winer, OG blogger, podcaster, developed first apps in many categories. Old enough to know better. It's even worse than it appears.</description>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 01:00:06 GMT</pubDate>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<generator>oldSchool v0.8.16</generator>
		<copyright>&amp;copy; copyright 1994-2024 Dave Winer.</copyright>
		<docs>http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 01:03:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<cloud domain="rpc.rsscloud.io" port="5337" path="/pleaseNotify" registerProcedure="" protocol="http-post" />
		<image>
			<title>Scripting News</title>
			<url>https://imgs.scripting.com/2025/06/04/curly.png</url>
			<link>http://scripting.com/</link>
			<description>Scripting News gets an image because it's part of a network that uses them. 6/4/25 by DW</description>
			</image>
		<source:account service="twitter">davewiner</source:account>
		<source:localTime>Sat, January 10, 2026 8:03 PM EST</source:localTime>
		<source:self>http://scripting.com/rss.xml</source:self>
		<source:blogroll>https://feedland.social/opml?screenname=davewiner&amp;catname=blogroll</source:blogroll>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/10/obituaries/bob-weir-dead-grateful-dead.html?unlocked_article_code=1.DlA.xKXc.U2YioCZ34UoE&amp;smid=url-share&quot;&gt;Bob Weir is gone&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:46:10 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/10.html#a004610</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/10.html#a004610</guid>
			<source:markdown>[Bob Weir is gone](https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/10/obituaries/bob-weir-dead-grateful-dead.html?unlocked_article_code=1.DlA.xKXc.U2YioCZ34UoE&amp;smid=url-share).</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/10/obituaries/bob-weir-dead-grateful-dead.html?unlocked_article_code=1.DlA.xKXc.U2YioCZ34UoE&amp;smid=url-share&quot;&gt;Bob Weir is gone&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:46:10 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/10.html#a004610"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Today's song: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S-NlpEbusLE&quot;&gt;Playing in the Band&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/10.html#a005000</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/10.html#a005000</guid>
			<source:markdown>Today's song: [Playing in the Band](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S-NlpEbusLE).</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="Today's song: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S-NlpEbusLE&quot;&gt;Playing in the Band&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:50:00 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/10.html#a005000"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>What’s happening with ICE is like January 6 four years later with billions of dollars behind it and many months of planning and studying history for prior art.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:45:23 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/10.html#a004523</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/10.html#a004523</guid>
			<source:markdown>What’s happening with ICE is like January 6 four years later with billions of dollars behind it and many months of planning and studying history for prior art.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="What’s happening with ICE is like January 6 four years later with billions of dollars behind it and many months of planning and studying history for prior art." created="Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:45:23 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/10.html#a004523"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>As I listened to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8M3GtZ_sqYI&quot;&gt;mayor of Minneapolis&lt;/a&gt; speak I thought he was going say &quot;get the fuck out of Minneapolis&quot; but of course he couldn't say that and then he said it.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 01:00:06 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/10.html#a010006</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/10.html#a010006</guid>
			<source:markdown>As I listened to the [mayor of Minneapolis](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8M3GtZ_sqYI) speak I thought he was going say &quot;get the fuck out of Minneapolis&quot; but of course he couldn't say that and then he said it.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="As I listened to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8M3GtZ_sqYI&quot;&gt;mayor of Minneapolis&lt;/a&gt; speak I thought he was going say &quot;get the fuck out of Minneapolis&quot; but of course he couldn't say that and then he said it." created="Sun, 11 Jan 2026 01:00:06 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/10.html#a010006"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>I'm doing little demos of stuff I'm working on in WordLand, here's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dW8nYtMIS-U&quot;&gt;narrated demo&lt;/a&gt; that shows how instant updates are going. As often the recording level is too low, so turn up the volume if you want to hear the comments. A productive Saturday session.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 18:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/10.html#a180300</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/10.html#a180300</guid>
			<source:markdown>I'm doing little demos of stuff I'm working on in WordLand, here's a [narrated demo](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dW8nYtMIS-U) that shows how instant updates are going. As often the recording level is too low, so turn up the volume if you want to hear the comments. A productive Saturday session.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="I'm doing little demos of stuff I'm working on in WordLand, here's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dW8nYtMIS-U&quot;&gt;narrated demo&lt;/a&gt; that shows how instant updates are going. As often the recording level is too low, so turn up the volume if you want to hear the comments. A productive Saturday session." created="Sat, 10 Jan 2026 18:03:00 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/10.html#a180300"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://johnjohnston.info/blog/watching-wordland-demo-2026/&quot;&gt;John Johnston&lt;/a&gt;, a longtime friend of UserLand and my newer products, asks how WordLand connects with FeedLand. Two ways. 1. FeedLand has an API, still working on it, but it will be public. 2. FeedLand has an outbound &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedlandSocket&quot;&gt;websockets interface&lt;/a&gt;, which is already public, so any can use it as their feed reader, and get notice of new items and updates to existing items as soon as FeedLand has the info. And if the site uses rssCloud, as WordPress does and has since 2009, the notices are instantaneous. So to the extent people thought RSS is a slow protocol, it's not. It runs at the speed of the internet. And FeedLand is all about RSS, as you know.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 21:44:55 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/10.html#a214455</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/10.html#a214455</guid>
			<source:markdown>[John Johnston](https://johnjohnston.info/blog/watching-wordland-demo-2026/), a longtime friend of UserLand and my newer products, asks how WordLand connects with FeedLand. Two ways. 1. FeedLand has an API, still working on it, but it will be public. 2. FeedLand has an outbound [websockets interface](https://github.com/scripting/feedlandSocket), which is already public, so any can use it as their feed reader, and get notice of new items and updates to existing items as soon as FeedLand has the info. And if the site uses rssCloud, as WordPress does and has since 2009, the notices are instantaneous. So to the extent people thought RSS is a slow protocol, it's not. It runs at the speed of the internet. And FeedLand is all about RSS, as you know.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://johnjohnston.info/blog/watching-wordland-demo-2026/&quot;&gt;John Johnston&lt;/a&gt;, a longtime friend of UserLand and my newer products, asks how WordLand connects with FeedLand. Two ways. 1. FeedLand has an API, still working on it, but it will be public. 2. FeedLand has an outbound &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedlandSocket&quot;&gt;websockets interface&lt;/a&gt;, which is already public, so any can use it as their feed reader, and get notice of new items and updates to existing items as soon as FeedLand has the info. And if the site uses rssCloud, as WordPress does and has since 2009, the notices are instantaneous. So to the extent people thought RSS is a slow protocol, it's not. It runs at the speed of the internet. And FeedLand is all about RSS, as you know." created="Sat, 10 Jan 2026 21:44:55 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/10.html#a214455"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;img class=&quot;imgRightMargin&quot; src=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2019/12/24/rooster.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;float: right; padding-left: 25px; padding-bottom: 10px; padding-top: 10px; padding-right: 15px;&quot;&gt;I get ideas when I go for a walk or drive somewhere in my car. This was one of those times, but it was not a comforting idea. I live in the mountains on the west side of the Hudson River near &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kingston,_New_York&quot;&gt;Kingston&lt;/a&gt;. On my drive to town yesterday I went through the small town of Woodstock, and I was thinking about how ICE is occupying Minneapolis, and wondered why wasn't I more concerned about it personally. The answer -- it's far away from here, and Woodstock, while it is a famous place, is on absolutely no one's radar. But then I remembered the astounding amount of money we allocated for ICE, far more than could be used for border enforcement, so obviously this all is a prelude for an American secret police and here's where the disquieting idea came up. Of course ICE will operate in every city and town in the US no matter how remote or small. But first they have to perfect their act, this is a form of training to teach the skinheads of America how to be part of an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schutzstaffel&quot;&gt;SS&lt;/a&gt;. Experiment first in a few cities before deploying, gradually, everywhere. We're all going to have to submit to loyalty oaths, and we will all be forced to denounce our neighbors as illustrated in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lives_of_Others&quot;&gt;Lives of Others&lt;/a&gt;, which if you haven't watched it yet, now is the time when you have to, to get an idea what it was like in East Germany before the wall came down, and where we're headed. It still may not be too late yet, but it's getting close.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 14:16:26 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/09.html#a141626</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/09.html#a141626</guid>
			<source:markdown>![](https://imgs.scripting.com/2019/12/24/rooster.png)I get ideas when I go for a walk or drive somewhere in my car. This was one of those times, but it was not a comforting idea. I live in the mountains on the west side of the Hudson River near [Kingston](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kingston,_New_York). On my drive to town yesterday I went through the small town of Woodstock, and I was thinking about how ICE is occupying Minneapolis, and wondered why wasn't I more concerned about it personally. The answer -- it's far away from here, and Woodstock, while it is a famous place, is on absolutely no one's radar. But then I remembered the astounding amount of money we allocated for ICE, far more than could be used for border enforcement, so obviously this all is a prelude for an American secret police and here's where the disquieting idea came up. Of course ICE will operate in every city and town in the US no matter how remote or small. But first they have to perfect their act, this is a form of training to teach the skinheads of America how to be part of an [SS](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schutzstaffel). Experiment first in a few cities before deploying, gradually, everywhere. We're all going to have to submit to loyalty oaths, and we will all be forced to denounce our neighbors as illustrated in [Lives of Others](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lives_of_Others), which if you haven't watched it yet, now is the time when you have to, to get an idea what it was like in East Germany before the wall came down, and where we're headed. It still may not be too late yet, but it's getting close.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="I get ideas when I go for a walk or drive somewhere in my car. This was one of those times, but it was not a comforting idea. I live in the mountains on the west side of the Hudson River near &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kingston,_New_York&quot;&gt;Kingston&lt;/a&gt;. On my drive to town yesterday I went through the small town of Woodstock, and I was thinking about how ICE is occupying Minneapolis, and wondered why wasn't I more concerned about it personally. The answer -- it's far away from here, and Woodstock, while it is a famous place, is on absolutely no one's radar. But then I remembered the astounding amount of money we allocated for ICE, far more than could be used for border enforcement, so obviously this all is a prelude for an American secret police and here's where the disquieting idea came up. Of course ICE will operate in every city and town in the US no matter how remote or small. But first they have to perfect their act, this is a form of training to teach the skinheads of America how to be part of an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schutzstaffel&quot;&gt;SS&lt;/a&gt;. Experiment first in a few cities before deploying, gradually, everywhere. We're all going to have to submit to loyalty oaths, and we will all be forced to denounce our neighbors as illustrated in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lives_of_Others&quot;&gt;Lives of Others&lt;/a&gt;, which if you haven't watched it yet, now is the time when you have to, to get an idea what it was like in East Germany before the wall came down, and where we're headed. It still may not be too late yet, but it's getting close." created="Fri, 09 Jan 2026 14:16:26 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2019/12/24/rooster.png" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/09.html#a141626"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Trump is president the same way people who do vibe coding are developers. I always thought he'd be much happier playing president on TV instead of actually being president. And people would think about this stuff more rationally if it were a TV show like Pluribus or Severance. Why did they &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; do what they did? Or the way we talk about the Mets or the Knicks and their various foibles. It's funny people have a clarity about fictional stuff that they don't have for real-world things like war, health insurance, the cost of eggs and gestapo tactics.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:30:09 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/09.html#a163009</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/09.html#a163009</guid>
			<source:markdown>Trump is president the same way people who do vibe coding are developers. I always thought he'd be much happier playing president on TV instead of actually being president. And people would think about this stuff more rationally if it were a TV show like Pluribus or Severance. Why did they _really_ do what they did? Or the way we talk about the Mets or the Knicks and their various foibles. It's funny people have a clarity about fictional stuff that they don't have for real-world things like war, health insurance, the cost of eggs and gestapo tactics.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="Trump is president the same way people who do vibe coding are developers. I always thought he'd be much happier playing president on TV instead of actually being president. And people would think about this stuff more rationally if it were a TV show like Pluribus or Severance. Why did they &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; do what they did? Or the way we talk about the Mets or the Knicks and their various foibles. It's funny people have a clarity about fictional stuff that they don't have for real-world things like war, health insurance, the cost of eggs and gestapo tactics." created="Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:30:09 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/09.html#a163009"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>A little fix that would make social web a lot more useful and less hate-filled and abusive... Make replies visible only to the person being replied to. If they feel the reply should be public, they can RT it.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:02:06 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/09.html#a150206</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/09.html#a150206</guid>
			<source:markdown>A little fix that would make social web a lot more useful and less hate-filled and abusive... Make replies visible only to the person being replied to. If they feel the reply should be public, they can RT it.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="A little fix that would make social web a lot more useful and less hate-filled and abusive... Make replies visible only to the person being replied to. If they feel the reply should be public, they can RT it." created="Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:02:06 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/09.html#a150206"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>Was the ICE murder pre-calculated?</title>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;When there's breaking news these days I check Fox News in addition to CNN, MSNOW, BBC, PBS. The best are the last two. But last night night when everyone was fixated on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Killing_of_Renee_Good&quot;&gt;story&lt;/a&gt; of Renee Nicole Good, the woman who was killed in cold blood, on video, by a masked ICE thug, I wondered what Fox was saying. They were showing the actual video over and over like the other networks. Their words were what Trump was saying, but they didn't hide what actually happened, at least as long as it's news. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Then I wondered how much this was pre-calculated. It clearly doesn't hurt ICE to signal that they're killing US citizens in the US with impunity. Next time will be soon, and it will be more than one dead, and maybe they'll be kids. What makes me think this was not planned by the higher-ups is that they killed a middle-aged white woman, mother of 3,, who writes poetry. Not a very likely cartel leader or narco-terrorist. There were dolls in the glove compartment of the car. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Every indication is that she was just afraid and trying to get out of there as quickly as possible. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;We also remember that in the aftermath of Jan 6, private texts from the top people at Fox indicated they were scared and appalled like most other relatively sane Americans. What had happened then was unthinkable. Well, what happened yesterday was just as unthinkable. Shocking. Makes you wonder what's next. Get ready, we're going to see a lot of ugliness now, hard to comprehend, hard to accept. We still have a skeletal democracy, and ICE isn't fully staffed yet (they have new billions of dollars to spend).&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;On Facebook, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dan.conover.714/posts/pfbid035Dzpcd13T73crrWxC85U6GMf1UH2qH148cJuYvEfHMzCUjMDypyha9vbrrMSKEDJl?comment_id=1185132377083238&amp;notif_id=1767891365875871&amp;notif_t=feedback_reaction_generic&amp;ref=notif&quot;&gt;Dan Conover said&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;This is what the collapse of the rules-based order looks like.&quot;  &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;I responded: &quot;Or it's a test of it. The guy wasn't very well disguised, I think he will be identified if he hasn't already been identified. Will he be arrested and tried? If yes, then we just validated the rule-based order. If no, we're fucked.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Or even better the state of Minnesota could go to court and sue ICE to get their officers to wear identifying information, and no masks. For just this reason. And then here's an arrest warrant for the guy who fired his gun 3 times at the head of a 37-year old mom who writes poetry and drives an SUV with teddy bears in the glove compartment. In other words I'm not sure this was intentional (on behalf of ICE), and I think they may have to turn this guy over, otherwise someone is getting impeached. The video is too compelling.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:52:52 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/08/155252.html?title=wasTheIceMurderPrecalculated</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/08/155252.html</guid>
			<source:markdown>When there's breaking news these days I check Fox News in addition to CNN, MSNOW, BBC, PBS. The best are the last two. But last night night when everyone was fixated on the [story](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Killing_of_Renee_Good) of Renee Nicole Good, the woman who was killed in cold blood, on video, by a masked ICE thug, I wondered what Fox was saying. They were showing the actual video over and over like the other networks. Their words were what Trump was saying, but they didn't hide what actually happened, at least as long as it's news.&#10;&#10;Then I wondered how much this was pre-calculated. It clearly doesn't hurt ICE to signal that they're killing US citizens in the US with impunity. Next time will be soon, and it will be more than one dead, and maybe they'll be kids. What makes me think this was not planned by the higher-ups is that they killed a middle-aged white woman, mother of 3,, who writes poetry. Not a very likely cartel leader or narco-terrorist. There were dolls in the glove compartment of the car.&#10;&#10;Every indication is that she was just afraid and trying to get out of there as quickly as possible.&#10;&#10;We also remember that in the aftermath of Jan 6, private texts from the top people at Fox indicated they were scared and appalled like most other relatively sane Americans. What had happened then was unthinkable. Well, what happened yesterday was just as unthinkable. Shocking. Makes you wonder what's next. Get ready, we're going to see a lot of ugliness now, hard to comprehend, hard to accept. We still have a skeletal democracy, and ICE isn't fully staffed yet (they have new billions of dollars to spend).&#10;&#10;On Facebook, [Dan Conover said](https://www.facebook.com/dan.conover.714/posts/pfbid035Dzpcd13T73crrWxC85U6GMf1UH2qH148cJuYvEfHMzCUjMDypyha9vbrrMSKEDJl?comment_id=1185132377083238&amp;notif_id=1767891365875871&amp;notif_t=feedback_reaction_generic&amp;ref=notif): &quot;This is what the collapse of the rules-based order looks like.&quot;&#10;&#10;I responded: &quot;Or it's a test of it. The guy wasn't very well disguised, I think he will be identified if he hasn't already been identified. Will he be arrested and tried? If yes, then we just validated the rule-based order. If no, we're fucked.&#10;&#10;&quot;Or even better the state of Minnesota could go to court and sue ICE to get their officers to wear identifying information, and no masks. For just this reason. And then here's an arrest warrant for the guy who fired his gun 3 times at the head of a 37-year old mom who writes poetry and drives an SUV with teddy bears in the glove compartment. In other words I'm not sure this was intentional (on behalf of ICE), and I think they may have to turn this guy over, otherwise someone is getting impeached. The video is too compelling.&quot;</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="Was the ICE murder pre-calculated?" created="Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:52:52 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/08/155252.html">
				<source:outline text="When there's breaking news these days I check Fox News in addition to CNN, MSNOW, BBC, PBS. The best are the last two. But last night night when everyone was fixated on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Killing_of_Renee_Good&quot;&gt;story&lt;/a&gt; of Renee Nicole Good, the woman who was killed in cold blood, on video, by a masked ICE thug, I wondered what Fox was saying. They were showing the actual video over and over like the other networks. Their words were what Trump was saying, but they didn't hide what actually happened, at least as long as it's news." created="Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:40:29 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/08/155252.html#a154029"/>
				<source:outline text="Then I wondered how much this was pre-calculated. It clearly doesn't hurt ICE to signal that they're killing US citizens in the US with impunity. Next time will be soon, and it will be more than one dead, and maybe they'll be kids. What makes me think this was not planned by the higher-ups is that they killed a middle-aged white woman, mother of 3,, who writes poetry. Not a very likely cartel leader or narco-terrorist. There were dolls in the glove compartment of the car." created="Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:54:37 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/08/155252.html#a155437"/>
				<source:outline text="Every indication is that she was just afraid and trying to get out of there as quickly as possible." created="Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:21:39 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/08/155252.html#a172139"/>
				<source:outline text="We also remember that in the aftermath of Jan 6, private texts from the top people at Fox indicated they were scared and appalled like most other relatively sane Americans. What had happened then was unthinkable. Well, what happened yesterday was just as unthinkable. Shocking. Makes you wonder what's next. Get ready, we're going to see a lot of ugliness now, hard to comprehend, hard to accept. We still have a skeletal democracy, and ICE isn't fully staffed yet (they have new billions of dollars to spend)." created="Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:27:48 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/08/155252.html#a172748"/>
				<source:outline text="On Facebook, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dan.conover.714/posts/pfbid035Dzpcd13T73crrWxC85U6GMf1UH2qH148cJuYvEfHMzCUjMDypyha9vbrrMSKEDJl?comment_id=1185132377083238&amp;notif_id=1767891365875871&amp;notif_t=feedback_reaction_generic&amp;ref=notif&quot;&gt;Dan Conover said&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;This is what the collapse of the rules-based order looks like.&quot;" created="Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:15:58 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/08/155252.html#a171558"/>
				<source:outline text="I responded: &quot;Or it's a test of it. The guy wasn't very well disguised, I think he will be identified if he hasn't already been identified. Will he be arrested and tried? If yes, then we just validated the rule-based order. If no, we're fucked." created="Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:28:20 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/08/155252.html#a172820"/>
				<source:outline text="&quot;Or even better the state of Minnesota could go to court and sue ICE to get their officers to wear identifying information, and no masks. For just this reason. And then here's an arrest warrant for the guy who fired his gun 3 times at the head of a 37-year old mom who writes poetry and drives an SUV with teddy bears in the glove compartment. In other words I'm not sure this was intentional (on behalf of ICE), and I think they may have to turn this guy over, otherwise someone is getting impeached. The video is too compelling.&quot;" created="Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:17:30 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/08/155252.html#a171730"/>
				</source:outline>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;img class=&quot;imgRightMargin&quot; src=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/07/mailbox.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;float: right; padding-left: 25px; padding-bottom: 10px; padding-top: 10px; padding-right: 15px;&quot;&gt;Another incredible use-case for ChatGPT. When it first came out &lt;a href=&quot;https://fontawesome.com/&quot;&gt;Font Awesome&lt;/a&gt; was a total godsend. It took something every developer of graphic apps had to struggle with, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yYey8ntlK_E&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; basically &quot;I can do that.&quot; They had a growing set of standard icons, it got better with every version. But some special icons haven't appeared in &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22Font%20Awesome%22&quot;&gt;Font Awesome&lt;/a&gt;. There was a great icon on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/article/designed-with-kare-influential-macintosh-graphics-of-early-apple-computers/&quot;&gt;original Mac&lt;/a&gt;, for a desk accessory, I don't remember which one. It was a flag, like the flag on a mailbox. If you put a piece of mail in the box you raise the flag, that way the postman knows to stop. When they pick up the mail they flip the flag down. On the early Mac it took an app that was wide and short, and made it wide and tall, revealing the ideas and data it kept for you. You can still have the icon, using ChatGPT. Have it generate your own icon using SVG. You get something every bit as good as a Font Awesome icon. So you can be creative in a new way. Whether this is art or not (of course it is) is beside the point. It's progress, evolution -- a way for users to make perfectly specified feature requests.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 20:59:27 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/07.html#a205927</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/07.html#a205927</guid>
			<source:markdown>![](https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/07/mailbox.png)Another incredible use-case for ChatGPT. When it first came out [Font Awesome](https://fontawesome.com/) was a total godsend. It took something every developer of graphic apps had to struggle with, and [said](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yYey8ntlK_E) basically &quot;I can do that.&quot; They had a growing set of standard icons, it got better with every version. But some special icons haven't appeared in [Font Awesome](https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22Font%20Awesome%22). There was a great icon on the [original Mac](https://99percentinvisible.org/article/designed-with-kare-influential-macintosh-graphics-of-early-apple-computers/), for a desk accessory, I don't remember which one. It was a flag, like the flag on a mailbox. If you put a piece of mail in the box you raise the flag, that way the postman knows to stop. When they pick up the mail they flip the flag down. On the early Mac it took an app that was wide and short, and made it wide and tall, revealing the ideas and data it kept for you. You can still have the icon, using ChatGPT. Have it generate your own icon using SVG. You get something every bit as good as a Font Awesome icon. So you can be creative in a new way. Whether this is art or not (of course it is) is beside the point. It's progress, evolution -- a way for users to make perfectly specified feature requests.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="Another incredible use-case for ChatGPT. When it first came out &lt;a href=&quot;https://fontawesome.com/&quot;&gt;Font Awesome&lt;/a&gt; was a total godsend. It took something every developer of graphic apps had to struggle with, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yYey8ntlK_E&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; basically &quot;I can do that.&quot; They had a growing set of standard icons, it got better with every version. But some special icons haven't appeared in &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22Font%20Awesome%22&quot;&gt;Font Awesome&lt;/a&gt;. There was a great icon on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/article/designed-with-kare-influential-macintosh-graphics-of-early-apple-computers/&quot;&gt;original Mac&lt;/a&gt;, for a desk accessory, I don't remember which one. It was a flag, like the flag on a mailbox. If you put a piece of mail in the box you raise the flag, that way the postman knows to stop. When they pick up the mail they flip the flag down. On the early Mac it took an app that was wide and short, and made it wide and tall, revealing the ideas and data it kept for you. You can still have the icon, using ChatGPT. Have it generate your own icon using SVG. You get something every bit as good as a Font Awesome icon. So you can be creative in a new way. Whether this is art or not (of course it is) is beside the point. It's progress, evolution -- a way for users to make perfectly specified feature requests." created="Wed, 07 Jan 2026 20:59:27 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/07/mailbox.png" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/07.html#a205927"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnet.com/culture/facebook-f8-one-graph-to-rule-them-all/&quot;&gt;Remember&lt;/a&gt; when &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Facebook_Platform#Open_Graph_protocol&quot;&gt;OG metadata&lt;/a&gt; was new? 16 years ago. It's one of those things that's widely forgotten, but still widely in use. I just wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/scripting.com/post/3mbtstigya22o&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; on Bluesky that &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/07/bigAppleUgh.png&quot;&gt;demonstrates&lt;/a&gt;. That could be a new feature in WordPress, or the decision whether or not to display it could be up to the reader app (in this case Bluesky). If it were up to the reader we might need a way to signal that to the reader from the CMS. In the new WordLand, we use the image as an icon. It's completely wrong to use it as an OG Metadata image in Bluesky -- realllly embarrassing (&lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/07/bigAppleUgh.png&quot;&gt;screen shot&lt;/a&gt;).</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:52:43 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/07.html#a155243</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/07.html#a155243</guid>
			<source:markdown>[Remember](https://www.cnet.com/culture/facebook-f8-one-graph-to-rule-them-all/) when [OG metadata](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Facebook_Platform#Open_Graph_protocol) was new? 16 years ago. It's one of those things that's widely forgotten, but still widely in use. I just wrote a [post](https://bsky.app/profile/scripting.com/post/3mbtstigya22o) on Bluesky that [demonstrates](https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/07/bigAppleUgh.png). That could be a new feature in WordPress, or the decision whether or not to display it could be up to the reader app (in this case Bluesky). If it were up to the reader we might need a way to signal that to the reader from the CMS. In the new WordLand, we use the image as an icon. It's completely wrong to use it as an OG Metadata image in Bluesky -- realllly embarrassing ([screen shot](https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/07/bigAppleUgh.png)).</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnet.com/culture/facebook-f8-one-graph-to-rule-them-all/&quot;&gt;Remember&lt;/a&gt; when &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Facebook_Platform#Open_Graph_protocol&quot;&gt;OG metadata&lt;/a&gt; was new? 16 years ago. It's one of those things that's widely forgotten, but still widely in use. I just wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/scripting.com/post/3mbtstigya22o&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; on Bluesky that &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/07/bigAppleUgh.png&quot;&gt;demonstrates&lt;/a&gt;. That could be a new feature in WordPress, or the decision whether or not to display it could be up to the reader app (in this case Bluesky). If it were up to the reader we might need a way to signal that to the reader from the CMS. In the new WordLand, we use the image as an icon. It's completely wrong to use it as an OG Metadata image in Bluesky -- realllly embarrassing (&lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/07/bigAppleUgh.png&quot;&gt;screen shot&lt;/a&gt;)." created="Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:52:43 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/07.html#a155243"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;img class=&quot;imgRightMargin&quot; src=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2020/11/26/uncleSam.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;float: right; padding-left: 25px; padding-bottom: 10px; padding-top: 10px; padding-right: 15px;&quot;&gt;I considered my &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22Blogger%20of%20the%20Year%22&quot;&gt;Blogger of the Year&lt;/a&gt; award for 2025 very carefully, and yesterday did a &lt;a href=&quot;https://shownotes.scripting.com/scripting/2026/01/05/bloggerOfTheYear.html&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; about my choice, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Frum&quot;&gt;David Frum&lt;/a&gt;, who is doing an outstanding job of adapting his work to the podcast medium, as it was intended to work. What finally made my decision easy was his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6zzK5K1ig-Y&quot;&gt;last episode of the year&lt;/a&gt;, where along with fellow Atlantic staff writer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/author/charlie-warzel/&quot;&gt;Charlie Warzel&lt;/a&gt;, they considered how podcasting works, and what if anything they should do to conform. The answer is -- &lt;i&gt;don't conform.&lt;/i&gt; It isn't up to any single contributor to turn the tide, instead their only job is to be true to themselves, and learn from others and share what they've learned. Be a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2016/05/31/1296.html&quot;&gt;human-size&lt;/a&gt; blogger. I thought perhaps this represented my opportunity to speak to them, and help understand that there are tech people who want to work with them and enhance their freedom, rather than consume it. But we need &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; help to do it. They've settled on Substack, without realizing they're just hooking up with the same people who screwed them before (ie Twitter, then all the techies who have dinner with Trump). As &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.snopes.com/fact-check/einstein-insanity-quote/&quot;&gt;they&lt;/a&gt; say -- doing the same thing and expecting a different outcome is not particularly smart, and Frum &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; smart. I don't care if he roots for the Red Sox (I'm a Mets fan), right now we're on the same side. We love the United States, and what it has done for us, and for the world, and we are falling apart. It's not time to stay within our communities, it's time to do whatever we can to save the country we love so much, &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22working%20together%22&quot;&gt;working together&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 14:38:37 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/06.html#a143837</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/06.html#a143837</guid>
			<source:markdown>![](https://imgs.scripting.com/2020/11/26/uncleSam.png)I considered my [Blogger of the Year](https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22Blogger%20of%20the%20Year%22) award for 2025 very carefully, and yesterday did a [podcast](https://shownotes.scripting.com/scripting/2026/01/05/bloggerOfTheYear.html) about my choice, [David Frum](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Frum), who is doing an outstanding job of adapting his work to the podcast medium, as it was intended to work. What finally made my decision easy was his [last episode of the year](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6zzK5K1ig-Y), where along with fellow Atlantic staff writer, [Charlie Warzel](https://www.theatlantic.com/author/charlie-warzel/), they considered how podcasting works, and what if anything they should do to conform. The answer is -- _don't conform._ It isn't up to any single contributor to turn the tide, instead their only job is to be true to themselves, and learn from others and share what they've learned. Be a [human-size](http://scripting.com/2016/05/31/1296.html) blogger. I thought perhaps this represented my opportunity to speak to them, and help understand that there are tech people who want to work with them and enhance their freedom, rather than consume it. But we need _their_ help to do it. They've settled on Substack, without realizing they're just hooking up with the same people who screwed them before (ie Twitter, then all the techies who have dinner with Trump). As [they](https://www.snopes.com/fact-check/einstein-insanity-quote/) say -- doing the same thing and expecting a different outcome is not particularly smart, and Frum _is_ smart. I don't care if he roots for the Red Sox (I'm a Mets fan), right now we're on the same side. We love the United States, and what it has done for us, and for the world, and we are falling apart. It's not time to stay within our communities, it's time to do whatever we can to save the country we love so much, [working together](https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22working%20together%22).</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="I considered my &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22Blogger%20of%20the%20Year%22&quot;&gt;Blogger of the Year&lt;/a&gt; award for 2025 very carefully, and yesterday did a &lt;a href=&quot;https://shownotes.scripting.com/scripting/2026/01/05/bloggerOfTheYear.html&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; about my choice, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Frum&quot;&gt;David Frum&lt;/a&gt;, who is doing an outstanding job of adapting his work to the podcast medium, as it was intended to work. What finally made my decision easy was his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6zzK5K1ig-Y&quot;&gt;last episode of the year&lt;/a&gt;, where along with fellow Atlantic staff writer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/author/charlie-warzel/&quot;&gt;Charlie Warzel&lt;/a&gt;, they considered how podcasting works, and what if anything they should do to conform. The answer is -- &lt;i&gt;don't conform.&lt;/i&gt; It isn't up to any single contributor to turn the tide, instead their only job is to be true to themselves, and learn from others and share what they've learned. Be a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2016/05/31/1296.html&quot;&gt;human-size&lt;/a&gt; blogger. I thought perhaps this represented my opportunity to speak to them, and help understand that there are tech people who want to work with them and enhance their freedom, rather than consume it. But we need &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; help to do it. They've settled on Substack, without realizing they're just hooking up with the same people who screwed them before (ie Twitter, then all the techies who have dinner with Trump). As &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.snopes.com/fact-check/einstein-insanity-quote/&quot;&gt;they&lt;/a&gt; say -- doing the same thing and expecting a different outcome is not particularly smart, and Frum &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; smart. I don't care if he roots for the Red Sox (I'm a Mets fan), right now we're on the same side. We love the United States, and what it has done for us, and for the world, and we are falling apart. It's not time to stay within our communities, it's time to do whatever we can to save the country we love so much, &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=%22working%20together%22&quot;&gt;working together&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 06 Jan 2026 14:38:37 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2020/11/26/uncleSam.png" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/06.html#a143837"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Put another way, I don't think they know that there are hippie-type developers who believe in you and your free speech, and build accordingly. The web is the home page for that movement, and it's still there and ready to do the job it was built to do, and not feed your soul into the &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=slurry&quot;&gt;slurry&lt;/a&gt;-making machines.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:27:42 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/06.html#a152742</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/06.html#a152742</guid>
			<source:markdown>Put another way, I don't think they know that there are hippie-type developers who believe in you and your free speech, and build accordingly. The web is the home page for that movement, and it's still there and ready to do the job it was built to do, and not feed your soul into the [slurry](https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=slurry)\-making machines.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="Put another way, I don't think they know that there are hippie-type developers who believe in you and your free speech, and build accordingly. The web is the home page for that movement, and it's still there and ready to do the job it was built to do, and not feed your soul into the &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=slurry&quot;&gt;slurry&lt;/a&gt;-making machines." created="Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:27:42 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/06.html#a152742"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>BTW, I was right about our respective ages. I am five years older, so we are of the same generation, but have taken different paths, but have arrived at basically the same place. And for what it's worth I voted for George W. Bush against Al Gore in 2000, but voted and worked for John Kerry in 2004.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 14:49:30 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/06.html#a144930</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/06.html#a144930</guid>
			<source:markdown>BTW, I was right about our respective ages. I am five years older, so we are of the same generation, but have taken different paths, but have arrived at basically the same place. And for what it's worth I voted for George W. Bush against Al Gore in 2000, but voted and worked for John Kerry in 2004.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="BTW, I was right about our respective ages. I am five years older, so we are of the same generation, but have taken different paths, but have arrived at basically the same place. And for what it's worth I voted for George W. Bush against Al Gore in 2000, but voted and worked for John Kerry in 2004." created="Tue, 06 Jan 2026 14:49:30 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/06.html#a144930"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Another btw, in the early blogosphere we had a motto -- watching them watch us watch them, etc. You aren't blogging if you aren't always considering what you're doing.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:18:02 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/06.html#a151802</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/06.html#a151802</guid>
			<source:markdown>Another btw, in the early blogosphere we had a motto -- watching them watch us watch them, etc. You aren't blogging if you aren't always considering what you're doing.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="Another btw, in the early blogosphere we had a motto -- watching them watch us watch them, etc. You aren't blogging if you aren't always considering what you're doing." created="Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:18:02 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/06.html#a151802"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Must-watch narrated &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CvL4sXhGrYs&amp;t=1s&quot;&gt;bodycam video&lt;/a&gt; from Jan 6 Capitol riot. Maybe the saddest moment in American history, so far.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 14:37:09 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/06.html#a143709</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/06.html#a143709</guid>
			<source:markdown>Must-watch narrated [bodycam video](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CvL4sXhGrYs&amp;t=1s) from Jan 6 Capitol riot. Maybe the saddest moment in American history, so far.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="Must-watch narrated &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CvL4sXhGrYs&amp;t=1s&quot;&gt;bodycam video&lt;/a&gt; from Jan 6 Capitol riot. Maybe the saddest moment in American history, so far." created="Tue, 06 Jan 2026 14:37:09 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/06.html#a143709"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Problem with ChatGPT is that it thinks you always want to know everything about all the options, no matter how convoluted they are, based on incorrect assumptions about what you're doing. You ask a simple question with a simple answer and they write you a four page briefing on everything. At least they do seem to give you the correct answer up front. They ought to work on making these things manageable, and btw for these reasons I believe they must write the most shitty code when they're left to write the whole thing. If they have a different better mode, please let me talk to that one! :-)</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 22:53:01 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/06.html#a225301</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/06.html#a225301</guid>
			<source:markdown>Problem with ChatGPT is that it thinks you always want to know everything about all the options, no matter how convoluted they are, based on incorrect assumptions about what you're doing. You ask a simple question with a simple answer and they write you a four page briefing on everything. At least they do seem to give you the correct answer up front. They ought to work on making these things manageable, and btw for these reasons I believe they must write the most shitty code when they're left to write the whole thing. If they have a different better mode, please let me talk to that one! :-)</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="Problem with ChatGPT is that it thinks you always want to know everything about all the options, no matter how convoluted they are, based on incorrect assumptions about what you're doing. You ask a simple question with a simple answer and they write you a four page briefing on everything. At least they do seem to give you the correct answer up front. They ought to work on making these things manageable, and btw for these reasons I believe they must write the most shitty code when they're left to write the whole thing. If they have a different better mode, please let me talk to that one! :-)" created="Tue, 06 Jan 2026 22:53:01 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/06.html#a225301"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Podcast: &lt;a href=&quot;https://shownotes.scripting.com/scripting/2026/01/05/bloggerOfTheYear.html&quot;&gt;Blogger of the Year&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:19:53 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/05.html#a161953</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/05.html#a161953</guid>
			<source:markdown>Podcast: [Blogger of the Year](https://shownotes.scripting.com/scripting/2026/01/05/bloggerOfTheYear.html).</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="Podcast: &lt;a href=&quot;https://shownotes.scripting.com/scripting/2026/01/05/bloggerOfTheYear.html&quot;&gt;Blogger of the Year&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:19:53 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/05.html#a161953"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>I did a long &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8n6N9wOaGI4&quot;&gt;video demo&lt;/a&gt; yesterday with a narrative about where WordLand is going. The audio quality sucks. And at the beginning I said I wasn't going to narrate, but I couldn't help myself. Turn the volume way up. WordLand has become a new kind of feed reader, it's totally building off FeedLand, I love the idea of apps building on other apps. It's exactly the kind of software we predicted, long before MCP's, with Frontier back in the 80s, 90s and 00s.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:43:19 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/05.html#a134319</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/05.html#a134319</guid>
			<source:markdown>I did a long [video demo](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8n6N9wOaGI4) yesterday with a narrative about where WordLand is going. The audio quality sucks. And at the beginning I said I wasn't going to narrate, but I couldn't help myself. Turn the volume way up. WordLand has become a new kind of feed reader, it's totally building off FeedLand, I love the idea of apps building on other apps. It's exactly the kind of software we predicted, long before MCP's, with Frontier back in the 80s, 90s and 00s.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="I did a long &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8n6N9wOaGI4&quot;&gt;video demo&lt;/a&gt; yesterday with a narrative about where WordLand is going. The audio quality sucks. And at the beginning I said I wasn't going to narrate, but I couldn't help myself. Turn the volume way up. WordLand has become a new kind of feed reader, it's totally building off FeedLand, I love the idea of apps building on other apps. It's exactly the kind of software we predicted, long before MCP's, with Frontier back in the 80s, 90s and 00s." created="Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:43:19 GMT" type="outline" urlVideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8n6N9wOaGI4" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/05.html#a134319"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Just heard an ad on WNYC-FM saying we should share news with them. That's a milestone. First time I've ever heard NPR say our purpose was anything other than giving them money. They could go even further -- support blogs and podcasts that cover the NYC area.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 20:28:59 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/05.html#a202859</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/05.html#a202859</guid>
			<source:markdown>Just heard an ad on WNYC-FM saying we should share news with them. That's a milestone. First time I've ever heard NPR say our purpose was anything other than giving them money. They could go even further -- support blogs and podcasts that cover the NYC area.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="Just heard an ad on WNYC-FM saying we should share news with them. That's a milestone. First time I've ever heard NPR say our purpose was anything other than giving them money. They could go even further -- support blogs and podcasts that cover the NYC area." created="Mon, 05 Jan 2026 20:28:59 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/05.html#a202859"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;img class=&quot;imgRightMargin&quot; src=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/05/peets.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;float: right; padding-left: 25px; padding-bottom: 10px; padding-top: 10px; padding-right: 15px;&quot;&gt;I've tried a lot of different kinds of Keurig pods, but the best -- with the richest taste is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.peets.com/collections/all-coffees&quot;&gt;Peet's&lt;/a&gt;. Just ordered a whole bunch more to try out. And btw, when I looked up Peet's on Google I found that it had been &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/keurig-dr-pepper-peets-acquisition-coffee-904c356a8eb57a6b256b7f45a0f59d8d&quot;&gt;bought by Dr Pepper&lt;/a&gt; for (sit down please) $18 billion. I hope you didn't pass out. I always thought of Peet's as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Peet's+Coffee/@37.8803729,-122.2683059,3a,37.5y,186.58h,82.78t/data=!3m7!1e1!3m5!1sZwBhp-mi6kXN66mVlUTufA!2e0!6shttps:%2F%2Fstreetviewpixels-pa.googleapis.com%2Fv1%2Fthumbnail%3Fcb_client%3Dmaps_sv.tactile%26w%3D900%26h%3D600%26pitch%3D7.217521607956982%26panoid%3DZwBhp-mi6kXN66mVlUTufA%26yaw%3D186.58228587981463!7i16384!8i8192!4m6!3m5!1s0x80857ea12b318d1d:0x1b0fe71cdb63e238!8m2!3d37.8802629!4d-122.2683283!16s%2Fg%2F1yl47h12q?entry=ttu&amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI1MTIwOS4wIKXMDSoKLDEwMDc5MjA3M0gBUAM%3D&quot;&gt;hometown favorite&lt;/a&gt;, the underdog, but my lord so much money. No wonder the coffee is so good.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:29:46 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/05.html#a132946</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/05.html#a132946</guid>
			<source:markdown>![](https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/05/peets.png)I've tried a lot of different kinds of Keurig pods, but the best -- with the richest taste is [Peet's](https://www.peets.com/collections/all-coffees). Just ordered a whole bunch more to try out. And btw, when I looked up Peet's on Google I found that it had been [bought by Dr Pepper](https://apnews.com/article/keurig-dr-pepper-peets-acquisition-coffee-904c356a8eb57a6b256b7f45a0f59d8d) for (sit down please) $18 billion. I hope you didn't pass out. I always thought of Peet's as a [hometown favorite](https://www.google.com/maps/place/Peet's+Coffee/@37.8803729,-122.2683059,3a,37.5y,186.58h,82.78t/data=!3m7!1e1!3m5!1sZwBhp-mi6kXN66mVlUTufA!2e0!6shttps:%2F%2Fstreetviewpixels-pa.googleapis.com%2Fv1%2Fthumbnail%3Fcb_client%3Dmaps_sv.tactile%26w%3D900%26h%3D600%26pitch%3D7.217521607956982%26panoid%3DZwBhp-mi6kXN66mVlUTufA%26yaw%3D186.58228587981463!7i16384!8i8192!4m6!3m5!1s0x80857ea12b318d1d:0x1b0fe71cdb63e238!8m2!3d37.8802629!4d-122.2683283!16s%2Fg%2F1yl47h12q?entry=ttu&amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI1MTIwOS4wIKXMDSoKLDEwMDc5MjA3M0gBUAM%3D), the underdog, but my lord so much money. No wonder the coffee is so good.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="I've tried a lot of different kinds of Keurig pods, but the best -- with the richest taste is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.peets.com/collections/all-coffees&quot;&gt;Peet's&lt;/a&gt;. Just ordered a whole bunch more to try out. And btw, when I looked up Peet's on Google I found that it had been &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/keurig-dr-pepper-peets-acquisition-coffee-904c356a8eb57a6b256b7f45a0f59d8d&quot;&gt;bought by Dr Pepper&lt;/a&gt; for (sit down please) $18 billion. I hope you didn't pass out. I always thought of Peet's as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Peet's+Coffee/@37.8803729,-122.2683059,3a,37.5y,186.58h,82.78t/data=!3m7!1e1!3m5!1sZwBhp-mi6kXN66mVlUTufA!2e0!6shttps:%2F%2Fstreetviewpixels-pa.googleapis.com%2Fv1%2Fthumbnail%3Fcb_client%3Dmaps_sv.tactile%26w%3D900%26h%3D600%26pitch%3D7.217521607956982%26panoid%3DZwBhp-mi6kXN66mVlUTufA%26yaw%3D186.58228587981463!7i16384!8i8192!4m6!3m5!1s0x80857ea12b318d1d:0x1b0fe71cdb63e238!8m2!3d37.8802629!4d-122.2683283!16s%2Fg%2F1yl47h12q?entry=ttu&amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI1MTIwOS4wIKXMDSoKLDEwMDc5MjA3M0gBUAM%3D&quot;&gt;hometown favorite&lt;/a&gt;, the underdog, but my lord so much money. No wonder the coffee is so good." created="Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:29:46 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/05/peets.png" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/05.html#a132946"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>I never was very good with PhotoShop and other bitmap image apps. Now I use ChatGPT, I just tell it what I want, like remove this bit and that bit, and it just freaking does it. This is how computers were meant to work. That's how I did the &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/05/peets.png&quot;&gt;Peet's logo&lt;/a&gt; in the image in the previous post. And btw the people who are down on ChatGPT being used for graphics and videos are full of shit about it not having value. Some of us don't have the skill yet still would like to illustrate our ideas with images and videos. For those of us, the AI apps are a godsend. They're also pretty good I hear at providing medical advice. I've been using it for that pretty extensively. At my age health is not something you can ignore, and it helps to be informed. And with the healthcare system these days in the US being so limited, you don't really get to have a relationship with your doctor as we did in the past, so guess what, I bet ChatGPT is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/11/16/well/ai-chatbot-doctors-health-care-advice.html&quot;&gt;saving some lives&lt;/a&gt;. So if you don't like being seriously wrong about new tech, you should start seeing the advantages, not just the belief that it cancels freedom. If it does, and so far I don't see it, there's a lot of good that that compensates. There are always tradeoffs in evolution.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:52:12 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/05.html#a135212</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/05.html#a135212</guid>
			<source:markdown>I never was very good with PhotoShop and other bitmap image apps. Now I use ChatGPT, I just tell it what I want, like remove this bit and that bit, and it just freaking does it. This is how computers were meant to work. That's how I did the [Peet's logo](https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/05/peets.png) in the image in the previous post. And btw the people who are down on ChatGPT being used for graphics and videos are full of shit about it not having value. Some of us don't have the skill yet still would like to illustrate our ideas with images and videos. For those of us, the AI apps are a godsend. They're also pretty good I hear at providing medical advice. I've been using it for that pretty extensively. At my age health is not something you can ignore, and it helps to be informed. And with the healthcare system these days in the US being so limited, you don't really get to have a relationship with your doctor as we did in the past, so guess what, I bet ChatGPT is [saving some lives](https://www.nytimes.com/2025/11/16/well/ai-chatbot-doctors-health-care-advice.html). So if you don't like being seriously wrong about new tech, you should start seeing the advantages, not just the belief that it cancels freedom. If it does, and so far I don't see it, there's a lot of good that that compensates. There are always tradeoffs in evolution.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="I never was very good with PhotoShop and other bitmap image apps. Now I use ChatGPT, I just tell it what I want, like remove this bit and that bit, and it just freaking does it. This is how computers were meant to work. That's how I did the &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/05/peets.png&quot;&gt;Peet's logo&lt;/a&gt; in the image in the previous post. And btw the people who are down on ChatGPT being used for graphics and videos are full of shit about it not having value. Some of us don't have the skill yet still would like to illustrate our ideas with images and videos. For those of us, the AI apps are a godsend. They're also pretty good I hear at providing medical advice. I've been using it for that pretty extensively. At my age health is not something you can ignore, and it helps to be informed. And with the healthcare system these days in the US being so limited, you don't really get to have a relationship with your doctor as we did in the past, so guess what, I bet ChatGPT is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/11/16/well/ai-chatbot-doctors-health-care-advice.html&quot;&gt;saving some lives&lt;/a&gt;. So if you don't like being seriously wrong about new tech, you should start seeing the advantages, not just the belief that it cancels freedom. If it does, and so far I don't see it, there's a lot of good that that compensates. There are always tradeoffs in evolution." created="Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:52:12 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/05.html#a135212"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.scripting.com/?tab=politics&quot;&gt;political news&lt;/a&gt; on my FeedLand news site.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 01:17:42 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/04.html#a011742</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/04.html#a011742</guid>
			<source:markdown>Follow [political news](https://news.scripting.com/?tab=politics) on my FeedLand news site.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="Follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.scripting.com/?tab=politics&quot;&gt;political news&lt;/a&gt; on my FeedLand news site." created="Mon, 05 Jan 2026 01:17:42 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/04.html#a011742"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Do you feel powerless to communicate online unless it serves the interests of the people who own the networks you post to? Why not own your own means of distribution, managed as a co-op, and only responsible to you, as a member and customer. No VC, no billionaire, no government control.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 01:14:17 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/04.html#a011417</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/04.html#a011417</guid>
			<source:markdown>Do you feel powerless to communicate online unless it serves the interests of the people who own the networks you post to? Why not own your own means of distribution, managed as a co-op, and only responsible to you, as a member and customer. No VC, no billionaire, no government control.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="Do you feel powerless to communicate online unless it serves the interests of the people who own the networks you post to? Why not own your own means of distribution, managed as a co-op, and only responsible to you, as a member and customer. No VC, no billionaire, no government control." created="Mon, 05 Jan 2026 01:14:17 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/04.html#a011417"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bush at war</title>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Bush at the start of the Iraq war when MSNBC called him a visionary. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;He looked pretty lost at the time, I remember -- and we all hoped that wasn't true, we hoped he knew what he was doing.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;divInlineImage&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imgInline&quot; src=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/04/bushAtWar.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/center&gt;We've been here before. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 17:08:49 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/04/170849.html?title=bushAtWar</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/04/170849.html</guid>
			<source:markdown>Bush at the start of the Iraq war when MSNBC called him a visionary.&#10;&#10;He looked pretty lost at the time, I remember -- and we all hoped that wasn't true, we hoped he knew what he was doing.&#10;&#10;![](https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/04/bushAtWar.png)&#10;&#10;We've been here before.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="Bush at war" created="Sun, 04 Jan 2026 17:08:49 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/04/170849.html">
				<source:outline text="Bush at the start of the Iraq war when MSNBC called him a visionary." created="Sun, 04 Jan 2026 17:10:43 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/04/170849.html#a171043"/>
				<source:outline text="He looked pretty lost at the time, I remember -- and we all hoped that wasn't true, we hoped he knew what he was doing." created="Sun, 04 Jan 2026 17:28:16 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/04/170849.html#a172816"/>
				<source:outline text="We've been here before." created="Sun, 04 Jan 2026 17:08:52 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/04/bushAtWar.png" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/04/170849.html#a170852"/>
				</source:outline>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:oety7qbfx7x6exn2ytrwikmr/post/3mbjprtoj4s2d&quot;&gt;On Bluesky&lt;/a&gt;: I can't tell you how &lt;b&gt;tired&lt;/b&gt; I am of copying and pasting the same text into five different silos. When will this ridiculous system that claims to be the web, get its shit together and start acting like the web (ie interop).</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 16:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/03.html#a160700</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/03.html#a160700</guid>
			<source:markdown>[On Bluesky](https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:oety7qbfx7x6exn2ytrwikmr/post/3mbjprtoj4s2d): I can't tell you how **tired** I am of copying and pasting the same text into five different silos. When will this ridiculous system that claims to be the web, get its shit together and start acting like the web (ie interop).</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:oety7qbfx7x6exn2ytrwikmr/post/3mbjprtoj4s2d&quot;&gt;On Bluesky&lt;/a&gt;: I can't tell you how &lt;b&gt;tired&lt;/b&gt; I am of copying and pasting the same text into five different silos. When will this ridiculous system that claims to be the web, get its shit together and start acting like the web (ie interop)." created="Sat, 03 Jan 2026 16:07:00 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/03.html#a160700"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;img class=&quot;imgRightMargin&quot; src=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/03/bushLooksLikeHegseth.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;float: right; padding-left: 25px; padding-bottom: 10px; padding-top: 10px; padding-right: 15px;&quot;&gt;Today feels like the day the war in Iraq began. Wars are easy to start, hard to end. They actually called Bush a &quot;visionary&quot; on MSNBC, they were so in awe of his courage, but that would end soon. And this time, no doubt Trump started the war with the approval of China and Russia, which will be left alone by the US in their conquest of Taiwan and Ukraine. Leaders of smaller countries must be wondering where they can hide from this. A very depressing moment. I've lived through two voluntary wars by the US, first Vietnam, then the post-911 wars in Afghanistan and Iraq, and now this war.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 14:31:52 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/03.html#a143152</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/03.html#a143152</guid>
			<source:markdown>![](https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/03/bushLooksLikeHegseth.png)Today feels like the day the war in Iraq began. Wars are easy to start, hard to end. They actually called Bush a &quot;visionary&quot; on MSNBC, they were so in awe of his courage, but that would end soon. And this time, no doubt Trump started the war with the approval of China and Russia, which will be left alone by the US in their conquest of Taiwan and Ukraine. Leaders of smaller countries must be wondering where they can hide from this. A very depressing moment. I've lived through two voluntary wars by the US, first Vietnam, then the post-911 wars in Afghanistan and Iraq, and now this war.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="Today feels like the day the war in Iraq began. Wars are easy to start, hard to end. They actually called Bush a &quot;visionary&quot; on MSNBC, they were so in awe of his courage, but that would end soon. And this time, no doubt Trump started the war with the approval of China and Russia, which will be left alone by the US in their conquest of Taiwan and Ukraine. Leaders of smaller countries must be wondering where they can hide from this. A very depressing moment. I've lived through two voluntary wars by the US, first Vietnam, then the post-911 wars in Afghanistan and Iraq, and now this war." created="Sat, 03 Jan 2026 14:31:52 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/03/bushLooksLikeHegseth.png" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/03.html#a143152"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>The war in Iraq started in &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2003/03.html&quot;&gt;March 2003&lt;/a&gt;. That was also the month I arrived in Cambridge after driving cross-country from Woodside, CA. Because I did most of my blogging on scripting.com, I still have a good &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2003/03.html&quot;&gt;archive&lt;/a&gt; of how I experienced both those things. It's also the month we got the Harvard weblogs going, but they have not stood up so well. I wouldn't have predicted then that my personal blog would survive the system we started at one of America's great universities.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 14:53:39 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/03.html#a145339</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/03.html#a145339</guid>
			<source:markdown>The war in Iraq started in [March 2003](http://scripting.com/2003/03.html). That was also the month I arrived in Cambridge after driving cross-country from Woodside, CA. Because I did most of my blogging on scripting.com, I still have a good [archive](http://scripting.com/2003/03.html) of how I experienced both those things. It's also the month we got the Harvard weblogs going, but they have not stood up so well. I wouldn't have predicted then that my personal blog would survive the system we started at one of America's great universities.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="The war in Iraq started in &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2003/03.html&quot;&gt;March 2003&lt;/a&gt;. That was also the month I arrived in Cambridge after driving cross-country from Woodside, CA. Because I did most of my blogging on scripting.com, I still have a good &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2003/03.html&quot;&gt;archive&lt;/a&gt; of how I experienced both those things. It's also the month we got the Harvard weblogs going, but they have not stood up so well. I wouldn't have predicted then that my personal blog would survive the system we started at one of America's great universities." created="Sat, 03 Jan 2026 14:53:39 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/03.html#a145339"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;img class=&quot;imgRightMargin&quot; src=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/02/sauerkraut.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;float: right; padding-left: 25px; padding-bottom: 10px; padding-top: 10px; padding-right: 15px;&quot;&gt;BTW, I used to have a tradition in the early days of this blog to write new stuff about an important idea on January 1 each year. At some point I stopped doing that. Now I realized that unintentionally I have just written such a piece, &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/144702.html&quot;&gt;below&lt;/a&gt;. There's a lot of good stuff in that piece and in the places it links to. See the web is still useful. You won't hear these ideas on CNN or MS.NOW or in the NYT, WP, or from any billionaires either. I'm not saying I'm right, I've definitely been wrong before. But I think I'm &lt;i&gt;mostly&lt;/i&gt; right. ;-)</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 15:19:56 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/02.html#a151956</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/02.html#a151956</guid>
			<source:markdown>![](https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/02/sauerkraut.png)BTW, I used to have a tradition in the early days of this blog to write new stuff about an important idea on January 1 each year. At some point I stopped doing that. Now I realized that unintentionally I have just written such a piece, [below](http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/144702.html). There's a lot of good stuff in that piece and in the places it links to. See the web is still useful. You won't hear these ideas on CNN or MS.NOW or in the NYT, WP, or from any billionaires either. I'm not saying I'm right, I've definitely been wrong before. But I think I'm _mostly_ right. ;-)</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="BTW, I used to have a tradition in the early days of this blog to write new stuff about an important idea on January 1 each year. At some point I stopped doing that. Now I realized that unintentionally I have just written such a piece, &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/144702.html&quot;&gt;below&lt;/a&gt;. There's a lot of good stuff in that piece and in the places it links to. See the web is still useful. You won't hear these ideas on CNN or MS.NOW or in the NYT, WP, or from any billionaires either. I'm not saying I'm right, I've definitely been wrong before. But I think I'm &lt;i&gt;mostly&lt;/i&gt; right. ;-)" created="Fri, 02 Jan 2026 15:19:56 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/02/sauerkraut.png" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02.html#a151956"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>The web after AI</title>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imgRightMargin&quot; src=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/02/frankfurterWithSauerkraut.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;float: right; padding-left: 25px; padding-bottom: 10px; padding-top: 10px; padding-right: 15px;&quot;&gt;I still use Google. And I like the AI response they put at the top of the page, even though I get that it's bad for the web. Maybe there's a position for a web-only search engine. One where my writing has a chance of being seen by interested parties, rather than being converted to &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=slurry&quot;&gt;slurry&lt;/a&gt; to be fed to consumers as one would get a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alamy.com/stock-photo/hot-dog-stand-new-york.html?sortBy=relevant&quot;&gt;tasty hot dog&lt;/a&gt; from a NYC street vendor. Another level of processing. If I recall correctly one of the browsers is saying they're not using AI at all. But this would be different, it would be for search, not the browser. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;But Google, if you want to be fair about it, there should be a permalink for the AI-generated answers. This is something none of the AI vendors seem to be able to do. If so, I wonder why? &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;I just tried looking up &quot;Regular Medicare&quot; on Google, I was looking for an official page and ended up using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.medicare.gov/providers-services/original-medicare&quot;&gt;Medicare.gov&lt;/a&gt; one. But I could have decided the Google synopsis was the best. No way that I can see to use that as a link. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Maybe we should all start thinking about how we would like the new post-AI web to work? &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;I am trying to reach the well-known political pundits to tell them we don't have to accept the web the billionaires give us. The costs are very low, their money doesn't help them as much as you might think, because they have different concerns from the ones you (writer) and I (developer) have. I don't care about revenue (disclaimer that doesn't mean everything will be free and there won't be a business model, it just isn't the reason I'm doing the work). This is my way of giving back, the area I have the greatest leverage. I always argued that Bill Gates who kept saying in the 90s he was going to be a scrappy competitor now and give away his wealth when he retired. He &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; doing that btw, but I thought man you're never going to have the leverage you have now. Your money as a way to end famine or fight the climate crisis is nothing compared to the power you had when you had the dominant operating system in a time of great transition. You could, I argued, make the web a breakthrough for self-government, so we could &lt;i&gt;systematically&lt;/i&gt; solve those problems with the resources of the United States, not just the resources of the world's richest man. That possibility really was within reach, I believed then and still do now. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;I made the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2016/05/31/1296.html&quot;&gt;choice&lt;/a&gt; Bill didn't and it worked. We were able to build something amazing, only to see it broken down into that slurry I mentioned at the top of the page. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;I love AI, I don't want to go back. But I also have big plans for human thinkers and developers -- writers, using the technology we never got a chance to develop while we were busy being dominated by Larry and Sergey, Zuckerberg, the Twitter founders, et al. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;As I &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/scripting.com/post/3mbgv3xaah22u&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; on Bluesky today, we're going to insist this time that the political punditry get involved, assuming they are serious about saving what's left of our democracy.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:47:02 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/144702.html?title=theWebAfterAi</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/144702.html</guid>
			<source:markdown>![](https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/02/frankfurterWithSauerkraut.png)I still use Google. And I like the AI response they put at the top of the page, even though I get that it's bad for the web. Maybe there's a position for a web-only search engine. One where my writing has a chance of being seen by interested parties, rather than being converted to [slurry](https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=slurry) to be fed to consumers as one would get a [tasty hot dog](https://www.alamy.com/stock-photo/hot-dog-stand-new-york.html?sortBy=relevant) from a NYC street vendor. Another level of processing. If I recall correctly one of the browsers is saying they're not using AI at all. But this would be different, it would be for search, not the browser.&#10;&#10;But Google, if you want to be fair about it, there should be a permalink for the AI-generated answers. This is something none of the AI vendors seem to be able to do. If so, I wonder why?&#10;&#10;I just tried looking up &quot;Regular Medicare&quot; on Google, I was looking for an official page and ended up using the [Medicare.gov](https://www.medicare.gov/providers-services/original-medicare) one. But I could have decided the Google synopsis was the best. No way that I can see to use that as a link.&#10;&#10;Maybe we should all start thinking about how we would like the new post-AI web to work?&#10;&#10;I am trying to reach the well-known political pundits to tell them we don't have to accept the web the billionaires give us. The costs are very low, their money doesn't help them as much as you might think, because they have different concerns from the ones you (writer) and I (developer) have. I don't care about revenue (disclaimer that doesn't mean everything will be free and there won't be a business model, it just isn't the reason I'm doing the work). This is my way of giving back, the area I have the greatest leverage. I always argued that Bill Gates who kept saying in the 90s he was going to be a scrappy competitor now and give away his wealth when he retired. He _is_ doing that btw, but I thought man you're never going to have the leverage you have now. Your money as a way to end famine or fight the climate crisis is nothing compared to the power you had when you had the dominant operating system in a time of great transition. You could, I argued, make the web a breakthrough for self-government, so we could _systematically_ solve those problems with the resources of the United States, not just the resources of the world's richest man. That possibility really was within reach, I believed then and still do now.&#10;&#10;I made the [choice](http://scripting.com/2016/05/31/1296.html) Bill didn't and it worked. We were able to build something amazing, only to see it broken down into that slurry I mentioned at the top of the page.&#10;&#10;I love AI, I don't want to go back. But I also have big plans for human thinkers and developers -- writers, using the technology we never got a chance to develop while we were busy being dominated by Larry and Sergey, Zuckerberg, the Twitter founders, et al.&#10;&#10;As I [said](https://bsky.app/profile/scripting.com/post/3mbgv3xaah22u) on Bluesky today, we're going to insist this time that the political punditry get involved, assuming they are serious about saving what's left of our democracy.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="The web after AI" created="Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:47:02 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/144702.html">
				<source:outline text="I still use Google. And I like the AI response they put at the top of the page, even though I get that it's bad for the web. Maybe there's a position for a web-only search engine. One where my writing has a chance of being seen by interested parties, rather than being converted to &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=slurry&quot;&gt;slurry&lt;/a&gt; to be fed to consumers as one would get a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alamy.com/stock-photo/hot-dog-stand-new-york.html?sortBy=relevant&quot;&gt;tasty hot dog&lt;/a&gt; from a NYC street vendor. Another level of processing. If I recall correctly one of the browsers is saying they're not using AI at all. But this would be different, it would be for search, not the browser." created="Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:44:45 GMT" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/02/frankfurterWithSauerkraut.png" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/144702.html#a144445"/>
				<source:outline text="But Google, if you want to be fair about it, there should be a permalink for the AI-generated answers. This is something none of the AI vendors seem to be able to do. If so, I wonder why?" created="Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:47:22 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/144702.html#a144722"/>
				<source:outline text="I just tried looking up &quot;Regular Medicare&quot; on Google, I was looking for an official page and ended up using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.medicare.gov/providers-services/original-medicare&quot;&gt;Medicare.gov&lt;/a&gt; one. But I could have decided the Google synopsis was the best. No way that I can see to use that as a link." created="Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:49:43 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/144702.html#a144943"/>
				<source:outline text="Maybe we should all start thinking about how we would like the new post-AI web to work?" created="Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:50:35 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/144702.html#a145035"/>
				<source:outline text="I am trying to reach the well-known political pundits to tell them we don't have to accept the web the billionaires give us. The costs are very low, their money doesn't help them as much as you might think, because they have different concerns from the ones you (writer) and I (developer) have. I don't care about revenue (disclaimer that doesn't mean everything will be free and there won't be a business model, it just isn't the reason I'm doing the work). This is my way of giving back, the area I have the greatest leverage. I always argued that Bill Gates who kept saying in the 90s he was going to be a scrappy competitor now and give away his wealth when he retired. He &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; doing that btw, but I thought man you're never going to have the leverage you have now. Your money as a way to end famine or fight the climate crisis is nothing compared to the power you had when you had the dominant operating system in a time of great transition. You could, I argued, make the web a breakthrough for self-government, so we could &lt;i&gt;systematically&lt;/i&gt; solve those problems with the resources of the United States, not just the resources of the world's richest man. That possibility really was within reach, I believed then and still do now." created="Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:50:53 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/144702.html#a145053"/>
				<source:outline text="I made the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2016/05/31/1296.html&quot;&gt;choice&lt;/a&gt; Bill didn't and it worked. We were able to build something amazing, only to see it broken down into that slurry I mentioned at the top of the page." created="Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:54:02 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/144702.html#a145402"/>
				<source:outline text="I love AI, I don't want to go back. But I also have big plans for human thinkers and developers -- writers, using the technology we never got a chance to develop while we were busy being dominated by Larry and Sergey, Zuckerberg, the Twitter founders, et al." created="Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:54:39 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/144702.html#a145439"/>
				<source:outline text="As I &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/scripting.com/post/3mbgv3xaah22u&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; on Bluesky today, we're going to insist this time that the political punditry get involved, assuming they are serious about saving what's left of our democracy." created="Fri, 02 Jan 2026 15:15:16 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/144702.html#a151516"/>
				</source:outline>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>Good Old Medicare</title>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;This year I switched to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.medicare.gov/providers-services/original-medicare&quot;&gt;Original Medicare&lt;/a&gt; for 2026 after being on super duper insurance industry enhanced Medicare for the first five years. I should've known that it's super duper for them but not so great for the insured person or the taxpayer, that is -- me. They have set it up so they can scam it 18 different ways, Some of the &quot;services&quot; they offer are just ways for them to charge the government more for your care, in return for doing absolutely nothing. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;So today I had my first Regular Medicare experience. I went to renew my prescriptions, and the vendor already knew my insurance info which was impressive use of computers. I was prepared to give it the new info. And in case you're confused, you still have to pay the insurance industry for Regular Medicare, even though that's actually a deal between me and my government. No way to deal them out, though I'm sure it would make total sense for us to do exactly that. Don't believe that when it comes to health care the US has been anything like a democracy.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Where the old plan each prescription cost $0, this time I actually have to pay out of pocket approx $100 for a 90 day supply of five different medications. On the other hand, I'm paying much less for this insurance. I haven't done the math yet, but it feels like I'm not getting ripped off. See how many qualifiers there are.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Oh the great old US of A where you can give your tax money and retirement funds to insurance companies who buy politicians etc and so on. Maybe the only thing to appreciate is that we get some health care for all our tax payments over our careers? &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;And one good thing is now I get to keep most of my Social Security payments instead of it all going to United Healthcare. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:38:24 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/143824.html?title=goodOldMedicare</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/143824.html</guid>
			<source:markdown>This year I switched to [Original Medicare](https://www.medicare.gov/providers-services/original-medicare) for 2026 after being on super duper insurance industry enhanced Medicare for the first five years. I should've known that it's super duper for them but not so great for the insured person or the taxpayer, that is -- me. They have set it up so they can scam it 18 different ways, Some of the &quot;services&quot; they offer are just ways for them to charge the government more for your care, in return for doing absolutely nothing.&#10;&#10;So today I had my first Regular Medicare experience. I went to renew my prescriptions, and the vendor already knew my insurance info which was impressive use of computers. I was prepared to give it the new info. And in case you're confused, you still have to pay the insurance industry for Regular Medicare, even though that's actually a deal between me and my government. No way to deal them out, though I'm sure it would make total sense for us to do exactly that. Don't believe that when it comes to health care the US has been anything like a democracy.&#10;&#10;Where the old plan each prescription cost $0, this time I actually have to pay out of pocket approx $100 for a 90 day supply of five different medications. On the other hand, I'm paying much less for this insurance. I haven't done the math yet, but it feels like I'm not getting ripped off. See how many qualifiers there are.&#10;&#10;Oh the great old US of A where you can give your tax money and retirement funds to insurance companies who buy politicians etc and so on. Maybe the only thing to appreciate is that we get some health care for all our tax payments over our careers?&#10;&#10;And one good thing is now I get to keep most of my Social Security payments instead of it all going to United Healthcare. ;-)</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="Good Old Medicare" created="Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:38:24 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/143824.html">
				<source:outline text="This year I switched to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.medicare.gov/providers-services/original-medicare&quot;&gt;Original Medicare&lt;/a&gt; for 2026 after being on super duper insurance industry enhanced Medicare for the first five years. I should've known that it's super duper for them but not so great for the insured person or the taxpayer, that is -- me. They have set it up so they can scam it 18 different ways, Some of the &quot;services&quot; they offer are just ways for them to charge the government more for your care, in return for doing absolutely nothing." created="Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:40:16 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/143824.html#a144016"/>
				<source:outline text="So today I had my first Regular Medicare experience. I went to renew my prescriptions, and the vendor already knew my insurance info which was impressive use of computers. I was prepared to give it the new info. And in case you're confused, you still have to pay the insurance industry for Regular Medicare, even though that's actually a deal between me and my government. No way to deal them out, though I'm sure it would make total sense for us to do exactly that. Don't believe that when it comes to health care the US has been anything like a democracy." created="Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:41:16 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/143824.html#a144116"/>
				<source:outline text="Where the old plan each prescription cost $0, this time I actually have to pay out of pocket approx $100 for a 90 day supply of five different medications. On the other hand, I'm paying much less for this insurance. I haven't done the math yet, but it feels like I'm not getting ripped off. See how many qualifiers there are." created="Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:43:17 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/143824.html#a144317"/>
				<source:outline text="Oh the great old US of A where you can give your tax money and retirement funds to insurance companies who buy politicians etc and so on. Maybe the only thing to appreciate is that we get some health care for all our tax payments over our careers?" created="Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:43:56 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/143824.html#a144356"/>
				<source:outline text="And one good thing is now I get to keep most of my Social Security payments instead of it all going to United Healthcare. ;-)" created="Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:44:11 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/143824.html#a144411"/>
				</source:outline>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>I’m never too old to make a young developer’s mistake.</title>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;This is one of those times when you pay the price for working past your timeout, like a pitcher pitching too many pitches in one game. There's an item on your checklist, and you'd love to take it off before you start the next session. You copy paste something, get it to work, and close out your session for the day. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;While you're preparing to get up you decide to share a linkblog item, and when it boots up there's something severely broken. It has nothing to do with anything on your list! You roll it up for the day anyway, figuring it'll be easy to find when you start the next session. No sir. You have to work through complicated code you haven't touched in months! Where the fuck is this, and how the fuck did it happen. Drink more coffee. Keep stepping through the code to identify when things went bad. It happens in the most impossible place. You keep digging in. Even more impossible. Unfathomable. But you keep going in, making sure every bit of code does something you think it should and then boom! You left a copy in some DOM code in something you cribbed so now there are two of this thing you hadn't touched or even looked at in months. Delete the mistake, rebuild, click off all the breakpoints. And yup that was it. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;I started work at approx 9AM and it's 11:41AM — wasted the best part of the day, all to learn the lesson that no more &quot;one more feature&quot; before I get up bullshit. If you're tired you make mistakes, and you can't not pay for them. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;p&gt;No doubt I will continue to learn this and other lessons all through what remains of my career. Some things you never learn, like &quot;I can always roll back&quot; — but where should I roll back to? When did I break this mofo? Oy. I'm never willing to go back that way.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 16:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/164500.html?title=imNeverTooOldToMakeAYoungDevelopersMistake</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/164500.html</guid>
			<source:markdown>This is one of those times when you pay the price for working past your timeout, like a pitcher pitching too many pitches in one game. There's an item on your checklist, and you'd love to take it off before you start the next session. You copy paste something, get it to work, and close out your session for the day.&#10;&#10;While you're preparing to get up you decide to share a linkblog item, and when it boots up there's something severely broken. It has nothing to do with anything on your list! You roll it up for the day anyway, figuring it'll be easy to find when you start the next session. No sir. You have to work through complicated code you haven't touched in months! Where the fuck is this, and how the fuck did it happen. Drink more coffee. Keep stepping through the code to identify when things went bad. It happens in the most impossible place. You keep digging in. Even more impossible. Unfathomable. But you keep going in, making sure every bit of code does something you think it should and then boom! You left a copy in some DOM code in something you cribbed so now there are two of this thing you hadn't touched or even looked at in months. Delete the mistake, rebuild, click off all the breakpoints. And yup that was it.&#10;&#10;I started work at approx 9AM and it's 11:41AM — wasted the best part of the day, all to learn the lesson that no more &quot;one more feature&quot; before I get up bullshit. If you're tired you make mistakes, and you can't not pay for them.&#10;&#10;No doubt I will continue to learn this and other lessons all through what remains of my career. Some things you never learn, like &quot;I can always roll back&quot; — but where should I roll back to? When did I break this mofo? Oy. I'm never willing to go back that way.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="I’m never too old to make a young developer’s mistake." created="Fri, 02 Jan 2026 16:45:00 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/164500.html">
				<source:outline text="This is one of those times when you pay the price for working past your timeout, like a pitcher pitching too many pitches in one game. There's an item on your checklist, and you'd love to take it off before you start the next session. You copy paste something, get it to work, and close out your session for the day." created="Fri, 02 Jan 2026 16:45:04 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/164500.html#a164504"/>
				<source:outline text="While you're preparing to get up you decide to share a linkblog item, and when it boots up there's something severely broken. It has nothing to do with anything on your list! You roll it up for the day anyway, figuring it'll be easy to find when you start the next session. No sir. You have to work through complicated code you haven't touched in months! Where the fuck is this, and how the fuck did it happen. Drink more coffee. Keep stepping through the code to identify when things went bad. It happens in the most impossible place. You keep digging in. Even more impossible. Unfathomable. But you keep going in, making sure every bit of code does something you think it should and then boom! You left a copy in some DOM code in something you cribbed so now there are two of this thing you hadn't touched or even looked at in months. Delete the mistake, rebuild, click off all the breakpoints. And yup that was it." created="Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:29:59 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/164500.html#a132959"/>
				<source:outline text="I started work at approx 9AM and it's 11:41AM — wasted the best part of the day, all to learn the lesson that no more &quot;one more feature&quot; before I get up bullshit. If you're tired you make mistakes, and you can't not pay for them." created="Fri, 02 Jan 2026 16:46:32 GMT" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/164500.html#a164632"/>
				<source:outline text="No doubt I will continue to learn this and other lessons all through what remains of my career. Some things you never learn, like &quot;I can always roll back&quot; — but where should I roll back to? When did I break this mofo? Oy. I'm never willing to go back that way." flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/02/164500.html#aNaNNaNNaN"/>
				</source:outline>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://tv.bingeworthy.org/?id=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.metacritic.com%2Ftv%2Fthe-staircase-2022%2F&quot;&gt;Liked&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metacritic.com/tv/the-staircase-2022/critic-reviews/&quot;&gt;The Staircase&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/82166981&quot;&gt;on Netflix&lt;/a&gt;. I had watched it before but had forgotten all the different conflicting stories. It is a bit irritating, but I think that's an important part of the story.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 19:51:32 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/01.html#a195132</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/01.html#a195132</guid>
			<source:markdown>[Liked](https://tv.bingeworthy.org/?id=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.metacritic.com%2Ftv%2Fthe-staircase-2022%2F) [The Staircase](https://www.metacritic.com/tv/the-staircase-2022/critic-reviews/) [on Netflix](https://www.netflix.com/title/82166981). I had watched it before but had forgotten all the different conflicting stories. It is a bit irritating, but I think that's an important part of the story.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://tv.bingeworthy.org/?id=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.metacritic.com%2Ftv%2Fthe-staircase-2022%2F&quot;&gt;Liked&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metacritic.com/tv/the-staircase-2022/critic-reviews/&quot;&gt;The Staircase&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/82166981&quot;&gt;on Netflix&lt;/a&gt;. I had watched it before but had forgotten all the different conflicting stories. It is a bit irritating, but I think that's an important part of the story." created="Thu, 01 Jan 2026 19:51:32 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/01.html#a195132"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Loving my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CW4N8KDQ?ref=ppx_yo2ov_dt_b_fed_asin_title&amp;th=1&quot;&gt;Keurig-style coffee maker&lt;/a&gt;. I've been stocking up on all kinds of pods. Favorite so far is hazelnut -- flavored, not real -- but really tasty. I never thought I'd want to try out all these different kinds of coffee. I wonder if I'm getting an espresso machine next.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 19:33:01 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/01.html#a193301</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/01.html#a193301</guid>
			<source:markdown>Loving my [Keurig-style coffee maker](https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CW4N8KDQ?ref=ppx_yo2ov_dt_b_fed_asin_title&amp;th=1). I've been stocking up on all kinds of pods. Favorite so far is hazelnut -- flavored, not real -- but really tasty. I never thought I'd want to try out all these different kinds of coffee. I wonder if I'm getting an espresso machine next.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="Loving my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CW4N8KDQ?ref=ppx_yo2ov_dt_b_fed_asin_title&amp;th=1&quot;&gt;Keurig-style coffee maker&lt;/a&gt;. I've been stocking up on all kinds of pods. Favorite so far is hazelnut -- flavored, not real -- but really tasty. I never thought I'd want to try out all these different kinds of coffee. I wonder if I'm getting an espresso machine next." created="Thu, 01 Jan 2026 19:33:01 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/01.html#a193301"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;img class=&quot;imgRightMargin&quot; src=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/05/13/modernTimes.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;float: right; padding-left: 25px; padding-bottom: 10px; padding-top: 10px; padding-right: 15px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/tree/master/blog/opml/2025&quot;&gt;All the Scripting News OPML's for 2025 in one GitHub folder&lt;/a&gt;. An example of user-owned storage. The protocol that connects our services won't know or care how we're storing stuff behind the API. A great prototype is imho the WordPress &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=wpcom&quot;&gt;wpcom&lt;/a&gt; API.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 13:52:14 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/01.html#a135214</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/01.html#a135214</guid>
			<source:markdown>![](https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/05/13/modernTimes.png)[All the Scripting News OPML's for 2025 in one GitHub folder](https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/tree/master/blog/opml/2025). An example of user-owned storage. The protocol that connects our services won't know or care how we're storing stuff behind the API. A great prototype is imho the WordPress [wpcom](https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=wpcom) API.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/tree/master/blog/opml/2025&quot;&gt;All the Scripting News OPML's for 2025 in one GitHub folder&lt;/a&gt;. An example of user-owned storage. The protocol that connects our services won't know or care how we're storing stuff behind the API. A great prototype is imho the WordPress &lt;a href=&quot;https://daytona.scripting.com/search?q=wpcom&quot;&gt;wpcom&lt;/a&gt; API." created="Thu, 01 Jan 2026 13:52:14 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/05/13/modernTimes.png" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/01.html#a135214"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>A &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:oety7qbfx7x6exn2ytrwikmr/post/3mbejmnizqc2q&quot;&gt;note&lt;/a&gt; to Josh Marshall, David Frum, Jay Rosen and Heather Cox Richardson, just a few of the political pundits I read. Now you all have seen up close the &quot;move fast and break things&quot; philosophy of Silicon Valley, also known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Department_of_Government_Efficiency&quot;&gt;DOGE&lt;/a&gt;. They do this with investors' money. This was a preview of how they will govern, after Trump, when Silicon Valley is fully running the world. We need to get some tech background in your writing. The history of tech is very much the history of politics as we go forward. We had a merger, and you can and should incorporate our history in your understanding of US history.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 14:05:33 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/01.html#a140533</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/01.html#a140533</guid>
			<source:markdown>A [note](https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:oety7qbfx7x6exn2ytrwikmr/post/3mbejmnizqc2q) to Josh Marshall, David Frum, Jay Rosen and Heather Cox Richardson, just a few of the political pundits I read. Now you all have seen up close the &quot;move fast and break things&quot; philosophy of Silicon Valley, also known as [DOGE](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Department_of_Government_Efficiency). They do this with investors' money. This was a preview of how they will govern, after Trump, when Silicon Valley is fully running the world. We need to get some tech background in your writing. The history of tech is very much the history of politics as we go forward. We had a merger, and you can and should incorporate our history in your understanding of US history.</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="A &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:oety7qbfx7x6exn2ytrwikmr/post/3mbejmnizqc2q&quot;&gt;note&lt;/a&gt; to Josh Marshall, David Frum, Jay Rosen and Heather Cox Richardson, just a few of the political pundits I read. Now you all have seen up close the &quot;move fast and break things&quot; philosophy of Silicon Valley, also known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Department_of_Government_Efficiency&quot;&gt;DOGE&lt;/a&gt;. They do this with investors' money. This was a preview of how they will govern, after Trump, when Silicon Valley is fully running the world. We need to get some tech background in your writing. The history of tech is very much the history of politics as we go forward. We had a merger, and you can and should incorporate our history in your understanding of US history." created="Thu, 01 Jan 2026 14:05:33 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/01.html#a140533"/>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ten years ago today</title>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;divInlineImage&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imgInline&quot; src=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/01/latkes2016.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/center&gt;Wishing you many happy latkes in 2026 too. &lt;span class=&quot;spOldSchoolEmoji&quot;&gt;😄&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 19:22:03 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>http://scripting.com/2026/01/01/192203.html?title=tenYearsAgoToday</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/2026/01/01/192203.html</guid>
			<source:markdown>![](https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/01/latkes2016.png)&#10;&#10;Wishing you many happy latkes in 2026 too. 😄</source:markdown>
			<source:outline text="Ten years ago today" created="Thu, 01 Jan 2026 19:22:03 GMT" type="outline" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/01/192203.html">
				<source:outline text="Wishing you many happy latkes in 2026 too. &lt;span class=&quot;spOldSchoolEmoji&quot;&gt;😄&lt;/span&gt;" created="Thu, 01 Jan 2026 19:22:11 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2026/01/01/latkes2016.png" flInCalendar="true" permalink="http://scripting.com/2026/01/01/192203.html#a192211"/>
				</source:outline>
			</item>
		</channel>
	</rss>
