<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- OPML generated by OPML Editor v10.1b19 on Wed, 22 Dec 2021 15:59:17 GMT -->
<opml version="2.0">
	<head>
		<title>Scripting News</title>
		<dateCreated>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 15:59:14 GMT</dateCreated>
		<dateModified>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 15:59:17 GMT</dateModified>
		<ownerName>Dave Winer</ownerName>
		<ownerId>http://davewiner.com/</ownerId>
		<expansionState>1</expansionState>
		<vertScrollState>1</vertScrollState>
		<windowTop>631</windowTop>
		<windowLeft>1087</windowLeft>
		<windowBottom>831</windowBottom>
		<windowRight>1472</windowRight>
		</head>
	<body>
		<outline text="March 2000" created="Wed, 01 Mar 2000 05:00:02 GMT">
			<outline text="March 31" created="Fri, 31 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;rules&gt;">
					<outline text="&lt;rule&gt;&lt;outlineSpacing&gt;1.5&lt;/outlineSpacing&gt;&lt;/rule&gt;"/>
					<outline text="&lt;/rules&gt;"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Announce: &quot;UserLand&quot; will join &lt;a href=&quot;http://w3.org/&quot;&gt;W3C&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;$5000.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="Further: I will speak at WWW9 on XML-RPC. &lt;i&gt;Priceless.&lt;/i&gt; "/>
				<outline text="ZDNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.com/zdnn/stories/news/0,4586,2495536,00.html&quot;&gt;Dave Winer doesn't believe in software patents&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;What if software developers called a daylong moratorium on coding to protest patents?&quot; "/>
				<outline text="David Carter-Tod: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.listserv.acm.org/archives/wa.cgi?A2=ind0003e&amp;L=chi-web&amp;F=&amp;S=&amp;P=2327&quot;&gt;CHI-WEB&lt;/a&gt; has been discussing web apps and are having a meeting about them April 1-6 in the Hague, Netherlands."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldlink.co.uk/stories/storyReader$23&quot;&gt;Klaus Schwab&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;To conclude, you have in front of you the 1,000 most influential business leaders. What would be your single, most important wish towards them, at this moment?&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://array.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;array&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;kevin drennan of the santa fe institute and i are arranging the first annual meeting of frontier users here in santa fe.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="The &lt;a href=&quot;http://webapps.userland.com/mailList&quot;&gt;Webapps mail list&lt;/a&gt; is starting to get interesting."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.com/zdnn/stories/news/0,4586,2461851,00.html?chkpt=zdnnrla&quot;&gt;Bill Machrone&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;If Amazon wants to fight, let it fight on a thousand fronts. Let it be nibbled to death by ducks.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Jeff Cheney has lots of great links on &lt;a href=&quot;http://ican.editthispage.com/2000/03/31&quot;&gt;editorial integrity&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Can you find the &lt;a href=&quot;http://2020hindsight.editthispage.com/2000/03/31&quot;&gt;black dot&lt;/a&gt;? Warning, it may drive your eyes crazy."/>
				<outline text="On the W3C xml-dist-apps mail list, &lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.w3.org/Archives/Public/xml-dist-app/2000Mar/0084.html&quot;&gt;Jeremy Allaire&lt;/a&gt; gives a status report on WDDX."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/stories/storyReader$501&quot;&gt;46 sites&lt;/a&gt; on Weblogs.Com. I really like the look of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ergonautes.weblogs.com/&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$15833&quot;&gt;Making Zope Zoooom&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Frontier has that wide-open wild-ass thing too, but focusing the functionality for writers was the single best thing that ever happened to Frontier. I suggest the same can and should be done for Zope. In other words, if there were a Manila-compatible mode for Zope that might be the secret sauce that makes Zope zooom.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Real world: &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$520&quot;&gt;Two Way Web White Board&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Wow. Photos of whiteboards are in my space now. As I was posting the picture above, Marc Canter sent me this &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/marcCantersWhiteboards.jpg&quot;&gt;picture&lt;/a&gt; of him in a virtual sea of whiteboards."/>
				<outline text="Since &lt;a href=&quot;http://spicynoodles.com/&quot;&gt;Andre&lt;/a&gt; is returning to Germany tomorrow, I wanted to take some pictures of his workplace, also known as Spicy Noodles West. Andre's been &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$517&quot;&gt;working&lt;/a&gt; pretty much round the clock. But all you have to do to get Andre to wake up is say &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$516&quot;&gt;Wiener Schnitzel&lt;/a&gt;! I tried to sneak up and take a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$518&quot;&gt;picture&lt;/a&gt; of the Frontier source code but Andre says &quot;Not Open Source!&quot; Ironically Andre uses his &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$519&quot;&gt;Mac and BBEdit&lt;/a&gt; to review Dr Watson error logs. &quot;For some reasons it's the only editor that works,&quot; he said."/>
				<outline text="What is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.soda.co.uk/soda/constructor/&quot;&gt;Constructor&lt;/a&gt;?"/>
				<outline text="WSJ: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/389076.asp&quot;&gt;Microsoft enters uncertain era&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Is the company as aggressive as it was two years ago? When asked, Mr. Silverberg, a former Microsoft senior vice president who oversaw Explorer and two versions of Windows, just smiles and asks: 'Have you ever met Steve?'&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Joel Spolsky: &lt;a href=&quot;http://joel.editthispage.com/stories/storyReader$31&quot;&gt;Painless Software Schedules&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.com/zdnn/stories/news/0,4586,2487846,00.html&quot;&gt;ZDNet&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Patents are not just being used as another revenue stream, but as a way to block rivals from competing in the market.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Mike Donnelan, the editor of &lt;a href=&quot;http://blackholebrain.editthispage.com/2000/03/29&quot;&gt;blackholebrain&lt;/a&gt; is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/images/blackholebrain/GRANDCASINOHWY49SMALL.jpg&quot;&gt;sign&lt;/a&gt; designer. That explains a lot (I think) about the colors and style he uses on his sites."/>
				<outline text="Yesterday on a follow-up mail list to the patent meeting at Esther's earlier this month, Tim O'Reilly told us that he's going to Washington next week with Jeff Bezos to meet with legislators about web patents. Esther responded saying she was going to be at the White House the same day for an event that she would tell us about later. I asked the group if any inventors were in the loop here. Not much of a response. I thought to myself, would they pass legislation revolutionizing medicine without involving doctors? Wouldn't that be considered an obvious question? I concluded later that software designers and inventors don't get much respect. They'll find out later how dependent they are on us when the systems *really* stop working. Lawyers controlling software? I'd rather not be their beta testers."/>
				<outline text="BTW, as far as I know Jeff Bezos is not a software designer. Before starting Amazon he managed a hedge fund. He's an investment banker, not one who sweats pixels."/>
				<outline text="I also talked on the phone at length yesterday with Gordon Eubanks of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oblix.com/company/comp_biographies.html&quot;&gt;Oblix&lt;/a&gt;. You may recall that Gordon was my partner in Symantec in the late 80s. We talked about many things, including the Microsoft antitrust situation. Gordon testified in Microsoft's defense in the current trial. My position has shifted, I now favor some action by the DOJ. Not because I dislike Microsoft or are &quot;against&quot; them, but because a one-browser market is not workable. I asked Gordon if the industry could do anything to overcome this situation without help from the government. I asked the same question of &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$472&quot;&gt;Steve Ballmer&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month. He said it's not his problem. I guess so, but in a larger sense, I think it actually &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; his problem. "/>
				<outline text="One of books which I'm reading very slowly and in pieces is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www1.fatbrain.com/asp/bookinfo/bookinfo.asp?theisbn=0071358951&quot;&gt;Fire in the Valley&lt;/a&gt; by Michael Swaine and Paul Freiberger. I'm finishing the part on MITS and Ed Roberts, Bill Gates and Paul Allen; and starting the part about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.maxframe.com/EUBANKS.HTM&quot;&gt;Gary Kildall and Gordon Eubanks&lt;/a&gt;. I sometimes forget that Gordon was one of the very first personal computer software developers. Being in the US Navy and being in Monterey were the common denominators. CP/M was their operating system, in many ways it was the Linux of its day. (In culture, not economics.)"/>
				<outline text="I went poking around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fireinthevalley.com/&quot;&gt;companion website&lt;/a&gt; to Fire in the Valley, and was really disappointed. This is one book that should be on the Web in its entirety, indexed by search engines. It would be easy to do with current technology, and damn, you gotta buy the book if it keeps turning up in my search queries, which it would, probably within a few months. There are so many people-connections in this book. I'd love to get that in XML and browse the network. That would make an interesting BBS. I keep pitching book authors and publishers on this simple idea, and you'd be amazed at how scared they get. But we know, Mr and Ms Web Reader, that the computer screen is no substitute for a reference book and the prices of books these days pale in comparison with the price of our time. Think about it. People are so expensive. Why not buy the book? (Esp if Jeff Bezos would let us 1-Click to buy it, and I'm still boycotting Amazon, so don't even think about me pointing to your stupid friggin site.) "/>
				<outline text="Lance Knobel: &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/stories/storyReader$514&quot;&gt;Put the book on the Web&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Dave, there are a few publishers that have seen the light.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Anyway here's &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; current problem. Yesterday, the store coughed up at least a few hairballs on &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.userland.com/webapps2000&quot;&gt;registrations&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;http://webapps.userland.com/&quot;&gt;WebApps 2000&lt;/a&gt;. If you tried to register yesterday and the system failed, first many apologies, and please try again, and if it doesn't work, send me an email with a phone number and we'll take the registration the old fashioned way. This suggests one topic for discussion. How to test e-commerce web apps. &lt;i&gt;Arrrggh!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="In an email to Ric Ford at &quot;MacInTouch&quot;, cc'd to me, &lt;a href=&quot;http://chuck.weblogs.com/&quot;&gt;Chuck Shotton &lt;/a&gt;says there's a flaw in MSIE5/Mac. It doesn't like to talk to servers running on the same machine as the browser. Chuck says: &quot;The connection can take up to 10 times as long to complete as when using IE4.5 or any version of Netscape.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="I agree with Chuck that this is a serious concern. We just shipped &quot;Pike&quot; last Saturday. It's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1997/09/14/FractionalHorsepowerHTTPSe&quot;&gt;Fractional Horsepower HTTP Server&lt;/a&gt;, among its many other talents. Without a clean fast connection to the local browser, that functionality is pretty useless."/>
				<outline text="Speaking of Pike, last night I was talking with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spicynoodles.com/&quot;&gt;Andre&lt;/a&gt; and asked if he thought people were doing &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$15810&quot;&gt;wildass development&lt;/a&gt; with Pike yet. (It's got a scripting language and object database and website framework and HTTP server.) Andre said he didn't think so. I asked why. He said that I haven't told people that it was OK. Oh. OK, it's OK. &lt;i&gt;Go go go.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="Andre also taught me how to count to ten in Cherman. Eins, svei, drei, fir, fumph, etc."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$15835&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blackholebrain.editthispage.com/picture$152&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 30" created="Thu, 30 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;rules&gt;">
					<outline text="&lt;rule&gt;&lt;outlineSpacing&gt;1.5&lt;/outlineSpacing&gt;&lt;/rule&gt;"/>
					<outline text="&lt;/rules&gt;"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="UserLand is hosting the first &lt;a href=&quot;http://webapps.userland.com/&quot;&gt;WebApps 2000&lt;/a&gt; meeting on Wednesday April 19, in Palo Alto, CA. The meeting opens with a dinner on April 18. It's a full-day event. There will be brief presentations, and lots of time for small group breakouts and one-to-one meetings. &lt;i&gt;US$750.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="Dale Dougherty: &lt;a href=&quot;http://weblogs.oreillynet.com/dale/stories/storyReader$32&quot;&gt;Viola Is a Repository of Prior Art&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Patent 5,838,906 has to do with controlling embedded hypermedia applications inside a browser. A person named Michael Doyle applied for this patent in 1994, and he got the patent in 1999. Now he is suing Microsoft (going after the big fish first) saying that ActiveX controls among other things infringe on his patent. The lawsuit set Microsoft off on a search for prior art and they uncovered Viola.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Pei Wei: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.viola.org/&quot;&gt;Viola Home Page&lt;/a&gt;. A Web browser from 1991. The first to support graphics! And many other things."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ora.com/&quot;&gt;O'Reilly Associates&lt;/a&gt; is a sponsor of WebApps 2000. &lt;i&gt;Thanks!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="WebApps 2000 will be held at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hyatt.com/usa/palo_alto/hotels/hotel_sjcri.html&quot;&gt;Hyatt Rickeys&lt;/a&gt;. Weather in mid-April in Palo Alto is likely to be perfect. Highs in the 70s, possibility of some rain, but not likely. We're going to use the outdoors as much as we possibly can."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$15804&quot;&gt;Jacob Levy found&lt;/a&gt; Netscape 6 Preview Release 1."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://webapps.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$7&quot;&gt;Edd Dumbill&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Where does my personal data actually live? Does it live a place where all the Web Apps I use can get at it?&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$434&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/timbraythumb.gif&quot; height=&quot;36&quot; width=&quot;37&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; vspace=&quot;10&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xml.com/pub/au/Bray_Tim&quot;&gt;Tim Bray&lt;/a&gt; will be at WebApps 2000. Tim, you are one of three editors of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3.org/TR/1998/REC-xml-19980210&quot;&gt;XML 1.0&lt;/a&gt;, which is a key spec for Web App developers. You also have a product in development that's a Web App, so you come to Palo Alto with a practical attitude and an entreprenurial spirit. Since you come from Canada, we are already assured that WebApps 2000 will be an international conference."/>
				<outline text="If Bryan Boyer makes a billion dollars on his Web App &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.deepleap.com/&quot;&gt;startup&lt;/a&gt;, I have a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bryanboyer.com/gifts/list.html?cat=5&amp;num=all&quot;&gt;feeling&lt;/a&gt; he'll know what to do with the money. We hope Bryan will be there. He says that his company's app will be public by then. &lt;i&gt;Curious!&lt;/i&gt; "/>
				<outline text="We're also working on scholarships for deserving Web App entrepreneurs who are cash-strapped. It happens. We want your brain and ideas, even if we can't get your money. Some rich companies will be there. So there are sponsorship opportunities. Feel free to email me with offers or requests."/>
				<outline text="Chip Brookshaw: &lt;a href=&quot;http://live.altavista.com/scripts/editorial.dll?ei=1649817&amp;ern=y&quot;&gt;Sorting Out a Web Spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;I think almost anyone who uses BrainMatter will be amazed at how it looks and acts like a typical spreadsheet, with all the basic calculating, sorting and formatting functions you would expect.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="I'm still filling out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://webapps.userland.com/backgroundReading&quot;&gt;background reading&lt;/a&gt; page on the WebApps 2000 site. I want this to grow huge. Send me links to your apps or articles you think others would find interesting."/>
				<outline text="NY Times: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/library/tech/00/03/biztech/articles/30patents.html&quot;&gt;Federal Agency Rethinks Internet Patents&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/stories/storyReader$501&quot;&gt;This page&lt;/a&gt; counts page reads for Weblogs.Com hosted sites, starting on 3/30/00. The stats are recalced once a night at midnight Pacific.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/stories/storyReader$499&quot;&gt;This page&lt;/a&gt; lists the 20 most recently updated home pages hosted at Weblogs.Com. A change in length of at least 50 characters is required for a page to appear on this list.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="MacInTouch Reader Report: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macintouch.com/msie5.html&quot;&gt;MSIE5 and Outlook Express 5.02&lt;/a&gt; for Macintosh. "/>
				<outline text="InfoWorld: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoworld.com/cgi-bin/deleteframe.pl?story=/articles/ic/xml/00/03/30/000330icnetscape.xml&quot;&gt;Beta of Netscape 6 due April 5&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Web Patents: &lt;a href=&quot;http://patents.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;Heard, by the USPTO&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/stories/storyReader$510&quot;&gt;UserLand as a publisher&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;In my opinion, there's no silver bullet here. He would have a conflict of interest, but all pubs appear to be crossing this line now. Editorialists no longer take an oath of poverty, nor should they, imho.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Matt Neuburg: &lt;a href=&quot;http://drmatt.userland.com/mradvancedstuff/xmlrpc.html&quot;&gt;A Gentle Introduction to XML-RPC&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/2000/02/04/howToMakeMoneyOnTheInternet&quot;&gt;How to Make Money on the Internet&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;[Klaus Schwab] has an interesting way of introducing speakers, one which I've never seen before, that I will try the next time I moderate a panel. He addresses the speaker not the audience. For example he would say &quot;Tony Blair, you are the Prime Minister of Great Britain. In your six years in office you have had many successes in bringing your country into the new global economy. You were a Global Leader of Tomorrow, inducted in 1989. We are very proud of our association with you.&quot;&quot;"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 29" created="Wed, 29 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;rules&gt;">
					<outline text="&lt;rule&gt;&lt;outlineSpacing&gt;1.5&lt;/outlineSpacing&gt;&lt;/rule&gt;"/>
					<outline text="&lt;/rules&gt;"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/2000/03/29/davenetOnHiatus&quot;&gt;DaveNet on Hiatus&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Shift Happens!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="We planned to open registration for the Web Apps conference for April 19, but it got pushed back because of a technical glitch. We'll have the site up tomorrow."/>
				<outline text="W3C: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/03/29-XML-protocol-matrix&quot;&gt;XML Protocol Comparisons&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Milestone.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="USPTO: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uspto.gov/web/offices/com/sol/actionplan.html&quot;&gt;Business Methods Patent Initiative, An Action Plan&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="David Adams' &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stuffeddog.com/speller/&quot;&gt;Speller&lt;/a&gt; web app is an important idea!"/>
				<outline text="O'Reilly: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oreillynet.com/pub/a/network/2000/03/29/jini.html&quot;&gt;Why is the Jini Bottled Up?&lt;/a&gt;"/>
				<outline text="AP: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usatoday.com/life/cyber/tech/cth632.htm&quot;&gt;Judge OKs deep hyperlinking&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="8/12/99: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1999/08/12/infoworldAndDeepLinking&quot;&gt;InfoWorld and Deep Linking&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://mmd.weblogs.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/moshpitman.gif&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Mike Donnelan has been working on a &lt;a href=&quot;http://mmd.weblogs.com/&quot;&gt;new skin&lt;/a&gt; for Weblogs.Com. What do you &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/discuss/msgReader$484&quot;&gt;think&lt;/a&gt;?"/>
				<outline text="After many months of trouble-free operation, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/weLoveOurQube.html&quot;&gt;Qube&lt;/a&gt; finally crashed, leaving this cute &quot;Weblogs.Com&quot; screen &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/qubeQurash.gif&quot;&gt;shot&lt;/a&gt;. It's back up now. "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.cnet.com/news/0-1003-200-1597346.html&quot;&gt;News.Com&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;VA Linux Systems has signed on two new customers that together will buy hundreds of its servers.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://drothgery.editthispage.com/discuss/msgReader$80&quot;&gt;David Rothgery reviews&lt;/a&gt; Pike."/>
				<outline text="Gary Secondino: &lt;a href=&quot;http://iseeisay.editthispage.com/discuss/msgReader$108&quot;&gt;Pike sign survey&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="LA Times: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/business/smbiz/20000329/t000029448.html&quot;&gt;Outlining Brings Meeting to Order&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="AP: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/388275.asp&quot;&gt;Supreme Court limits nude dancing&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Ruling says laws can require pasties, G-strings.&quot; &lt;i&gt;I didn't know that!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1998/05/24/heyPockyWay&quot;&gt;5/24/98&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Then one evening, quite surprisingly, I saw a fat naked woman dancing at an amateur talent show. I had to look. She was good! Her big fat body had the rhythm of the music. Her huge breasts swung to the beat. A big funky happy smile on her face! It made the point. If a big fat naked woman can dance so beautifully in public, what do I have to worry about?&quot;"/>
				<outline text="WSJ: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.com/zdnn/stories/news/0,4586,2487010,00.html&quot;&gt;Patent Office to change its tune&lt;/a&gt;. Via Will Cate via Lawrence Lee via ZDNet. &quot;Syndication,&quot; says Lawrence."/>
				<outline text="Internet.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://ipw.internet.com/development/software_development/954342376.html&quot;&gt;Macromedia Flash SDKs&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Using the code, developers are able to both play Flash files from within their programs, as well as export Flash comptible SWF files.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Larry Yudelson: &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$15764&quot;&gt;It's August in March!&lt;/a&gt; &quot;Remember Byte's August language issues? I remember as a high school kid, wrapping my brain around Pascal and structured programming, Smalltalk and object-orientation, Forth and threading. Reading that issue was an amazing experience -- a whole new paradigm (wrapped within a wonderful cover) for me to struggle with.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.powazek.com/&quot;&gt;Powazek&lt;/a&gt; redesigns his weblog. Much better."/>
				<outline text="Qube Quorner: &lt;a href=&quot;http://weblogs.userland.com/qube/stories/storyReader$396&quot;&gt;Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;. I think it's time for the Scripting News community to give a Big Group Hug to Luke and the Qube Qrowd. I think it sucks that Cobalt points to Slashdot from their site and ignores Qube Quorner. When are those guys going to take a ride on the Cluetrain? "/>
				<outline text="Dan Gillmor wrote a glowing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mercurycenter.com/svtech/columns/gillmor/docs/dg032600.htm&quot;&gt;piece&lt;/a&gt; about Cobalt. He interviewed me for it, I said they're smart, for sure, but they're blowing it with the Qube. A brilliant product, ahead of the time, but they're letting the market catch up with them. Perhaps they can make more money on RAQs, but we will remember them for the Qube. A company with a huge hoard of cash can afford to build a market! Hello. $1000 is a nice pricepoint. The Qube Quounts. Every Mac LAN should have a Qube. &lt;i&gt;Hello Qubetrain!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="Conclusion: All the Linux guys are rushing to grow to compete with Dell. I think Dell will win that one. Zig don't zag."/>
				<outline text="Now a message to Dan Gillmor, who I just heard interviewed on NPR. Dan, we help you, please help us. In this world reciprocity counts. It's not compromising to your editorial integrity to include your experience in the web world in your presence in older media, where they like the credibility that comes from being part of a major news pub. Help Luke help Qube users. Why not? When you talk about revolutionary trends in technology mention the web, and the boom in easy to use authoring tools. Anyone can gush with ease when it comes to gigahertz processors. You lament the lack of innovation in software. Hello Dan!"/>
				<outline text="OTOH, Luke must take some of the responsibility for the lack of support from hardware vendors. He made a big mistake by incorrectly stating my point of view with a rep of VA Linux. Too bad. I'm more interested in getting an easily scriptable version of PHP with the right macros in standard distribution by Cobalt and VA. We should have &lt;i&gt;integration&lt;/i&gt; between Manila and the runtimes on the servers, not necessarily with UserLand software. That's why we did xml-rpc. Luke incorrectly guessed our motive and plan, and made the mistake of telling that to the VA guy w/o checking with me. At the time we already had Manila static rendering working! Oy. The VA guy was was concerned that I'm a random huckster with compromised integrity, even though Doc Searls had already told him otherwise. Luke fed right into his fear and he ran away, that was the last we ever heard from him. So Luke, why don't you tell the story publicly and say what you learned? It will make us all more effective at gathering the support we want."/>
				<outline text="Now a question for everyone. It's The Year 2000. There's a brand name up for grabs. If you believe in the power of web community, what does that make you? It's a puzzle. Figure it out."/>
				<outline text="Hint: Too bad this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.communism.com/&quot;&gt;name&lt;/a&gt; is taken."/>
				<outline text="AP: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/388508.asp&quot;&gt;Reform rabbis back same-sex unions&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Excellent!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$15758&quot;&gt;Will Cate quotes&lt;/a&gt; a report in today's WSJ. &quot;Amid a growing debate over patents that stake out broad claims for basic methods of doing business on the Web, the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office is expected Wednesday to unveil an overhaul of the way it examines applications and awards patents for many online practices.&quot; Happy! We'll watch for this announcement, can't point to the WSJ article, it's behind a for-fee firewall."/>
				<outline text="&quot;jerry&quot;"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 28" created="Tue, 28 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;rules&gt;">
					<outline text="&lt;rule&gt;&lt;outlineSpacing&gt;1.5&lt;/outlineSpacing&gt;&lt;/rule&gt;"/>
					<outline text="&lt;/rules&gt;"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://frontier.userland.com/stories/storyReader$3476&quot;&gt;Frontier 6.2b1&lt;/a&gt; is released. Major  database performance enhancements. This is a beta, deploy with care."/>
				<outline text="Important: UserLand will host an all-day meeting in Palo Alto on Wed Apr 19 for developers of web applications to talk about the market, partnerships, compatibility, standards and whatever else this new industry would like to talk about. Limited participation -- 100 people. Developers only, no press. UserLand will host this meeting, in cooperation with IBM and O'Reilly. We'll have a new website open tomorrow with more information. &lt;i&gt;T-shirt included at no extra cost.&lt;/i&gt; &quot;;-&gt;&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Frontier: &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontier.userland.com/stories/storyReader$3514&quot;&gt;html.refGlossary callback&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Social Ecology: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.socialecology.com/frontier/pikechat.html&quot;&gt;ManilaPalooza Chat Transcript&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://netdyslexia.editthispage.com/2000/03/28&quot;&gt;NetDyslexia&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Most of the NetDyslectics were born in a socialist country: in the G.D.R. (East Germany). So we know what it means to live in a dictatorship.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iisg.nl/exhibitions/chairman/sov33.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/hammerAndSickle.gif&quot; height=&quot;51&quot; width=&quot;40&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; vspace=&quot;10&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://netdyslexia.editthispage.com/2000/03/28&quot;&gt;Vigencia Y Tributo&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I think of you as the Cuba of the Manila bloc because you practice the dogma at a purist level and you provide the soldiers who fight the wars in Africa and the rest of the Third World. I think of Scripting News as the Soviet Union, a corrupt regime with a crumbling foundation with nuclear weapons.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Joel Spolsky: &lt;a href=&quot;http://joel.editthispage.com/stories/storyReader$25&quot;&gt;Software NDAs and contracts that you should never sign&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;I recently signed this clause in a 3 page NDA by a startup company that consisted of exactly two founders, and no employees. So the founders, by putting this clause in the NDA, are doing nothing but guaranteeing that if their business doesn't work out, none of the people they met while working on the business will be able to give them jobs.&quot; "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$15750&quot;&gt;Jim Matthews&lt;/a&gt;: Carbon-compatible  menusharing.c?"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zonealarm.com/&quot;&gt;ZoneAlarm&lt;/a&gt; sounds like the perfect companion to Pike."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://pikebeta.userland.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/images/irights/iLikePike.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; vspace=&quot;10&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I usually don't report on my state of being here on Scripting News. Let me make an exception. Today I am wiped out. More tired than I remember ever being. The outages, the Pike shipment, ManilaPalooza, new business, and some self-centered would-be software architects. Please let up on the redesigns. There's a lot of thought and permutation, blind alleys and retooling that went into Pike. Software design is highly skilled work and doesn't happen quickly. It's OK to poke at Pike, discover how it works, ask questions, but save the redesigns for when you understand more about what you got. We've been working on permutations of this software for two years. I strongly believe this is the one that works best. (Or we wouldn't have shipped it.)"/>
				<outline text="2/9/98: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/98/02/stories/masonHaleOnWorkingWithMe.html&quot;&gt;Mason on Working With Dave&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="I've been saying this for quite a while. The Cluetrain goes in both directions. I must remember to talk with Doc about this. That said, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://pikebeta.userland.com/whatIsThis&quot;&gt;current Pike-button approach&lt;/a&gt; is far from the only configuration Pike will support. But give us a &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$8190&quot;&gt;chance&lt;/a&gt; to rest and regroup! Thanks for listening."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$8213&quot;&gt;Eating tutorial for men, primarily&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;As you're eating, visibly enjoy the food. Get some on your shirt. Laugh. Say thank you 18 times, but not all at once. Save the onions for last. Eat a few, get up from the table, declaring yourself completely satisfied, and go around the back of the house and make digestive noises, outside where they're appreciated more.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="What is &lt;a href=&quot;http://irights.editthispage.com/linkback/whatIsTheLinkbackProgram&quot;&gt;LinkBack&lt;/a&gt;?"/>
				<outline text="Salon: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salon.com/tech/feature/2000/03/28/bookmarks/index.html&quot;&gt;Why leave your marks online?&lt;/a&gt; &quot;A bevy of companies wants you to move your bookmarks from your browser to the Web, but it's not clear how you'd benefit.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://insite.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;InSite&lt;/a&gt; is a free site management tool written in Perl."/>
				<outline text="News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.cnet.com/news/0-1003-200-1592450.html&quot;&gt;Akamai, CacheFlow team for caching speed&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;The deal highlights the increasing number of alliances being struck as companies strive to avoid sluggish or even embarrassingly inaccessible Web sites due to heavy traffic. Companies across the high-tech landscape--including computer makers, network equipment makers, Web site hosting firms and telecommunications firms--are forming partnerships to make sure information is delivered quickly.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="WSJ: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/387697.asp&quot;&gt;Outlook for settling antitrust case dim&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Microsoft Corp. and the government continued working toward a possible settlement, even as a federal judge prepared to rule soon if the effort fails, people close to the case said.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Static rendering was released last night to Frontier developers and system managers. Four pages of docs -- an &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontier.userland.com/manila/staticRendering/&quot;&gt;overview&lt;/a&gt; with instructions for Manila MEs, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontier.userland.com/manila/staticRendering/serverSetup&quot;&gt;howto&lt;/a&gt; for server managers, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontier.userland.com/manila/staticRendering/caseStudy&quot;&gt;case study&lt;/a&gt;, and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontier.userland.com/manila/staticRendering/developersGuide&quot;&gt;guide&lt;/a&gt; for people who want to customize their static renderings. "/>
				<outline text="After much discussion and a demo about static rendering at ManilaPalooza on Saturday, we decided to release it first to Frontier developers so they can have static rendering for their Manila sites. Used in this mode, Manila becomes a multi-user staging server. Very powerful combination. "/>
				<outline text="It's going to be difficult to transition individual ETP sites to static rendering without link breakage. We're going to start with some of the high-flow sites, like Matt Garland's music site. Each site will teach us something. However it's easy for *new* sites. So we may open an all-static hosting server on UserLand.Com. Still puzzling this out."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tidbits.com/tb-issues/TidBITS-523.html#lnk3&quot;&gt;Adam Engst&lt;/a&gt; reviews MSIE5/Mac. "/>
				<outline text="Breakage fixed. In switching to Pike for editing Scripting News we broke the &lt;scriptingNews&gt; xml version. I am assured that it now works. Now I will &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/xml/scriptingnews2.xml&quot;&gt;verify&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Bing.&lt;/i&gt; "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://speedysnail.com/grinding/doktor.html&quot;&gt;Greetinks, vebfolk&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 27" created="Mon, 27 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;rules&gt;">
					<outline text="&lt;rule&gt;&lt;outlineSpacing&gt;1.5&lt;/outlineSpacing&gt;&lt;/rule&gt;"/>
					<outline text="&lt;/rules&gt;"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Pike Beta: &lt;a href=&quot;http://pikebeta.userland.com/stories/storyReader$707&quot;&gt;Browsing your Manila site in Pike&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;A new version of the Pike menu allows you to view your Manila site locally. This should be an eye-opener for people who have never seen what a Manila site looks like behind the scenes.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="New Manila feature: &lt;a href=&quot;http://weblogs.userland.com/manilaNewbies/stories/storyReader$2527&quot;&gt;Linking to archive from the News Day template&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Jason Levine implemented a cool feature that was catching on in the weblog world on his Queso web site, and I said 'This is going to be in Manila' and implemented it on Scripting News, and now it's on EditThisPage.Com, and when Brent is ready to distribute it, it'll be on all other Manila sites.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Pics from ManilaPalooza: &lt;a href=&quot;http://2020Hindsight.editthispage.com/manilapalooza&quot;&gt;Susan Kitchens&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://jake.editthispage.com/manilaPaloozaPictures&quot;&gt;Jake Savin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://ican.editthispage.com/stories/storyReader$748&quot;&gt;Jeff Cheney&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="NY Times: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/library/tech/00/03/biztech/articles/28soft.html&quot;&gt;Talks in Microsoft Case Continue as Judge's Decision Looms&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="I'm busting with pride over &lt;a href=&quot;http://weblogs.oreillynet.com/dale/&quot;&gt;this site&lt;/a&gt;. I've been working with Dale since last summer and the seed planted then is popping through the earth now. We have a very ambitious project in the works with O'Reilly. I think it's going to work. Happy! &quot;;-&gt;&quot;"/>
				<outline text="One thing remains constant across source code systems, net outages, and the patent system, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dictionary.com/cgi-bin/dict.pl?term=murphy%27s%20law&quot;&gt;Murphy's Law&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;"/>
				<outline text="But sometimes things work that you don't think will. For example, I tried typing this &lt;a href=&quot;http://weblogs.oreillynet.com/tim/&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/a&gt; into my browser, and hot damn, it &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/timOreillysManilaSite.gif&quot;&gt;worked&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://weblogs.oreillynet.com/edd/&quot;&gt;Edd Dumbill&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;And you never tried /edd/?&quot; &quot;;-&gt;&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/2000/01/29/twoDaysAtDavos&quot;&gt;1/29/00&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;At dinner last night I told the story of my company and likened the last year to jumping out of a plane with no parachute. One of my dinner friends said that's crazy. So I said OK, you have a parachute. Later I thought about it and realized that there is no parachute. Not only do you have to create the parachute while you're in free-fall, you also have to invent the damned thing!&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Followup to yesterday's escalation through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weforum.org/&quot;&gt;WEF&lt;/a&gt; to management at PacBell. Lance Knobel contacted the exec in charge of worldwide operations of SBC, the parent company of PacBell. We use routers in the human world too! I forwarded Lance's email to the NOC mailbox at Conxion, asking them to get ready to work with SBC. "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://2020hindsight.editthispage.com/2000/03/27&quot;&gt;Susan Kitchens&lt;/a&gt; on new slogans she learned at ManilaPalooza, including Biermania, which will be the name of Bierman's new weblog, starting sooon, we hope. Too bad Susan doesn't want to share her mother's secret slogan that gets people to laugh when she's taking their picture."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://surveys.userland.com/surveys/run/dave@userland.com/howDoesMsKitchensDoIt&quot;&gt;Survey&lt;/a&gt;: Should I reveal Mrs. Kitchens' secret slogan? &lt;i&gt;100 yes votes required.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="I was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?q=smiley+face+picture&amp;num=10&quot;&gt;searching&lt;/a&gt; for a smiley face collection on Google and to my surprise one of the top hits was a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.turtleprod.com/groovy/smileys&quot;&gt;Manila site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Excellent!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="OK, we got the hundred votes, thanks everyone, so here's the &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/mrsKitchensSecret.gif&quot;&gt;secret slogan&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="Press release: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.microsoft.com/presspass/press/2000/Mar00/IE5ma.asp&quot;&gt;MSIE5/Mac&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="WSJ: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/387243.asp&quot;&gt;An ex-reporter tackles the future of Net media&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;In the mid-1970s, Jonathan Sacks was a reporter at the tiny St. Cloud Times in Minnesota. Today, he’s got an audience of 22 million at one of the most powerful media companies. His title is senior vice president and general manager of America Online Inc.’s Interactive Services. That means he is in charge of programming and commerce for the giant AOL online service, the Aol.com Web site and the AOL Instant Messenger tool for chatting online.&quot; I know Jon Sacks. I saw the video of his speech. He was arrogant back in the 80s, but tolerable. Today he's unleashed!"/>
				<outline text="MacWEEK: &lt;a href=&quot;http://macweek.zdnet.com/2000/03/19/0324ie5.html&quot;&gt; Internet Explorer 5 ships&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://ryan.editthispage.com/2000/03/27&quot;&gt;Ryan Szekeres&lt;/a&gt; has screen shots of MSIE5/Mac. "/>
				<outline text="Tom Clifton sent a &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/xmlMSIE5Mac.gif&quot;&gt;screen shot&lt;/a&gt; of XML in MSIE5/Mac."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/news/business/0,1367,35206,00.html&quot;&gt;Wired&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Microsoft's 11th-hour stab at settling its antitrust case is going nowhere fast.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="On Friday, NPR's &lt;a href=&quot;http://search.npr.org/cf/cmn/cmnpd01fm.cfm?PrgDate=03/24/2000&amp;PrgID=5&quot;&gt;Talk of the Nation&lt;/a&gt; covered software patents. According to William Krzysko, who heard the broadcast, &quot;Q. Todd Dickenson, Assistant Secretary of Commerce and Commissioner of Patents and Trademarks was on the show, discussing technology patents. When asked about the Amazon 1-Click patent, he suggested that people request a re-examination of the merits of the patent, which could result in its cancellation.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Wow, listening to it now. They think that baseball's double play could be patented if it wasn't already being done. Geez Louise."/>
				<outline text="Let's hope Wired nukes the &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/yuckyWiredRedesign.gif&quot;&gt;latest redesign&lt;/a&gt; soon. I can't read articles this way. My mind doesn't work this way. I wonder if they're trying to kill their pub?"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$15723&quot;&gt;David Humphreys&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;We've been using weblogs at Organic to try to start a community diary around a given project. It's a new program -- a week or two old -- but we're definitely going there.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.villa-bosch.de/eml/english/research/optimem/optimem.html&quot;&gt;Optimem&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Scientists from the European Media Laboratory in Heidelberg, working together with the Institute of Computer Science at the University of Mannheim, have demonstrated that 10 gigabytes of data can be stored on a roll of conventional adhesive tape&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/387262.asp&quot;&gt;WSJ&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Microsoft Corp.’s offer to settle federal antitrust charges frees computer makers to embed competitors’ software into Microsoft’s Windows, one of several major concessions that could form a basis for resolving the case, people close to the settlement discussions said. Under the proposal, personal-computer and software makers would be allowed to modify the secret “source code” underlying Windows to add rival products such as Internet browsers or media players.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://unreason.editthispage.com/2000/03/27&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/images/netdyslexia/d2kpi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://netdyslexia.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;Netdyslexia&lt;/a&gt;, the Cuba of the Manila bloc, takes on Kottke. &quot;Stolen? Mr. Kottke should know that there is a difference between interface-design and website-design.&quot; BTW, I apologize for correcting the punctuation and capitalization in the ND post. I haven't yet fully conformed to &lt;a href=&quot;http://netdyslexia.editthispage.com/dogma2000&quot;&gt;Dogma 200&lt;/a&gt;, more or less. &lt;i&gt;Still diggin!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="Dack.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dack.com/web/bullshit.html&quot;&gt;web economy bullshit generator&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Blogger gets &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogger.com/permanent_link.pyra&quot;&gt;permanent links&lt;/a&gt;. "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://espn.go.com/gen/news/2000/0326/447248.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/implodingKingdome.gif&quot; height=&quot;33&quot; width=&quot;75&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; vspace=&quot;10&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://espn.go.com/gen/news/2000/0326/447248.html&quot;&gt;ESPN&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The Kingdome, which went from engineering marvel to anachronistic eyesore in just 24 years, was demolished in a controlled implosion Sunday to make room for a new, more expensive stadium.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1995/07/20/seattletripreport&quot;&gt;2/20/95&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The Department of Justice is powerful. They're part of the US Government, which has a huge army, navy, air force, and nuclear weapons. How will this faceoff be resolved?&quot; I guess we found out. They blew up the Kingdome. &lt;i&gt;Ooops!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/library/tech/00/03/biztech/articles/27pola.html&quot;&gt;NY Times&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Since digital photography is essentially an electronic form of instant pictures, Polaroid is either in a unique position to move into this field -- or uniquely suited to be rendered obsolete by it.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Michael Rose explains &lt;a href=&quot;http://pikebeta.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$665&quot;&gt;how he got Pike to work&lt;/a&gt; with his Frontier server."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/stats/findinweblogs?q=pikebeta&quot;&gt;Weblogs&lt;/a&gt; that point to &lt;a href=&quot;http://pikebeta.userland.com/&quot;&gt;PikeBeta&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://spicynoodles.com/2000/03/25&quot;&gt;Andre Radke&lt;/a&gt; on ManilaPalooza: &quot;For me, probably the most interesting part of the event was to discuss the possibilities of embedding Python in Frontier with Frederik Lundh of Pythonware.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/library/tech/00/03/biztech/articles/27digi.html&quot;&gt;Denise Caruso&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;For the last couple of months, Doerr, the venture capitalist, has been redefining success from an even broader perspective. In public forums, he has been encouraging a shift in focus from mercenary to missionary, asking executives to think about starting companies and building products that they believe will change the world, rather than merely amassing wealth.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://inessential.com/2000/03/26.html&quot;&gt;According to Brent&lt;/a&gt; the word of the day at UserLand is Wiener Schnitzel, and yesterday was Brent's 32nd birthday! Happy birthday Brent and &lt;i&gt;pass the Schnitz.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fahs.org/schnitzel.htm&quot;&gt;Wiener Schnitzel&lt;/a&gt;, the national dish of Austria."/>
				<outline text="With over 300 restaurants, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wienerschnitzel.com/&quot;&gt;Wienerschnitzel&lt;/a&gt; is the largest hot dog fast food chain in the world."/>
				<outline text="Salon: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salon.com/people/feature/2000/03/27/webjournals/index.html?CP=USE&amp;DN=310&quot;&gt;Keep a Web journal, get fired.. or worse&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://tirade.weblogs.com/tirades/how_to_blog&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog blog."/>
				<outline text="&lt;i&gt;The word &quot;blog&quot; makes me want to blog.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://array.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/images/array/lemon3b.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 26" created="Sun, 26 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;rules&gt;">
					<outline text="&lt;rule&gt;&lt;outlineSpacing&gt;1.5&lt;/outlineSpacing&gt;&lt;/rule&gt;"/>
					<outline text="&lt;/rules&gt;"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="To ManilaPalooza People: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www1.bluemountain.com/cards/box5668c/ffr6sztmfghauhx.htm&quot;&gt;You're Totally Awesome&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Thanks!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$15707&quot;&gt;David Weinberger&lt;/a&gt;, one of the Cluetrain authors, is looking for examples of people who use weblogs in business. &quot;I'm trying to illustrate the point that the Web is changing the old rules about the presumption of secrecy.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Dan Gillmor: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mercurycenter.com/svtech/columns/gillmor/docs/dg032600.htm&quot;&gt;Cobalt Networks is emblematic of valley evolution&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="This was a week of outage and escalation. One very big one, lots of aftershocks. Now I've gotten used to the Ten Minute Outage. One happened in Cupertino, just before my demo. Luckily the line stayed up through ManilaPalooza. And now, we've bonded with the Conxion people, and this week I learned more about escalation, watching Steve Martin waste huge amounts of time looping. PacBell is not taking responsibility. In the ISP world, when that happens, you escalate. But Conxion can only go so high up the hierarchy at PacBell. I said &quot;It's a shame they're not really part of our industry, because I can usually find a way to get through to the CEOs of high-tech companies.&quot; Then I realized that I &lt;i&gt;could&lt;/i&gt; escalate to the PacBell CEO through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldeconomicforum.com/&quot;&gt;Davos&lt;/a&gt;. So this is a public note to Lance Knobel at WEF. Lance, how would we go about contacting PacBell? They have a serious issue, and could take leadership in a very important area for world economic growth. How can we network to the right person at PacBell?"/>
				<outline text="BTW, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.davosnewbies.com/&quot;&gt;DavosNewbies&lt;/a&gt; is served on our Seattle LAN, so it did not go out when PacBell started heaving our packets. In a way (a small one!) it's unfortunate that this site was not served through PacBell, because then the CEO would instantly care if he looks bad. Imagine a Davos site behind all that michegas in the PacBell cloud!"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://march25.editthispage.com/discuss/msgReader$296&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/kenDowThumb.gif&quot; height=&quot;36&quot; width=&quot;35&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; vspace=&quot;10&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Lots of great feedback yesterday. We will deploy static rendering for EditThisPage sites, probably next week. We'll also host media objects like movies and wavs. We'll create a SlashDot-mode for Manila weblogs, individually editable objects by mutliple editors on a home page. We will convene a design workshop, where we meet to design features. Everyone is invited to post their thoughts on the March 25 site. "/>
				<outline text="To &lt;a href=&quot;http://wmf.editthispage.com/2000/03/25&quot;&gt;Wes Felter's&lt;/a&gt; question -- we're not there yet with all the features you asked for. What more can I say? Our focus in 1999 was on ease of use and writing tools. We've delivered, now we're in refinement mode on those things, and lookin for the next holes to dig. We're going to hire more engineers soon. And partnerships are a distinct possibility. No company can do everything, right??"/>
				<outline text="BTW, to Wes, we sent a Frontier T-shirt to Austin for you with Craig Jensen. And thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bump.net/&quot;&gt;Robert Occhialini&lt;/a&gt; for the wonderful shirts! And we gave out Frontier 1.0 manuals. There's still a palette of those in my garage, so I don't think they'll become collector's items any time sooon."/>
				<outline text="Ideas for Manila plug-ins: Presentation bullet charts, Blue Mountain Arts. "/>
				<outline text="And we met Fredrik Lundh, I'm sorry I didn't get a chance to introduce him. Fredrik was instrumental in the adoption of xml-rpc, after we released the Frontier implementation, he made it work in Python. He &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10726&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Writing the first version of Python's xmlrpclib took me about 20 minutes.&quot; Looking back, with the benefit of hindsight, this was one of the most powerful 20 minutes in history. Lundh's implementation bonded us to the Python community, and it precipitated all the other xml-rpc implementations."/>
				<outline text="Danny O'Brien from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ntk.net/&quot;&gt;NTK&lt;/a&gt; was there too. I explained what &quot;It's even worse than it appears&quot; means in the context of ETP. I realized immediately that I had stepped in it. "/>
				<outline text="Other regrets, I gave a hint to the cluelessness of VA Linux. We offered to make them kings of our world, but they'd rather be whores to the corporate bosses. Not great profit margins there. We're not hucksters folks, we just want to help you make the products we want. Thanks for listening."/>
				<outline text="Keynote Systems: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keynote.com/freeappraisal2.html&quot;&gt;Free Performance Appraisal of Your Web Site&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Are you losing customers or revenue because your web site is too slow or slower than your competitors?&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://bradpettit.editthispage.com/2000/03/24&quot;&gt;Psssst&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 25" created="Sat, 25 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;rules&gt;">
					<outline text="&lt;rule&gt;&lt;outlineSpacing&gt;1.5&lt;/outlineSpacing&gt;&lt;/rule&gt;"/>
					<outline text="&lt;/rules&gt;"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://pikebeta.userland.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/pikeBeta.gif&quot; width=&quot;402&quot; height=&quot;109&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;"/>
				<outline text="ManilaPalooza 1.0 is over! Great time see you on the web tomorrow."/>
				<outline text="Here's the ManilaPalooza &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gilbert.org/.biapchat&quot;&gt;chatroom&lt;/a&gt;!"/>
				<outline text="And the &lt;a href=&quot;http://64.14.1.90/webcast2&quot;&gt;webcast&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://pikebeta.userland.com/whatIsThis&quot;&gt;What is Pike?&lt;/a&gt; &quot;Pike is an outliner that's been custom-fitted to plug into Manila sites. You can create and edit stories with Pike. You can use it to edit your home page. And you can also use it to edit the myriad of templates that define how a Manila site is rendered. It's both a writing and design tool.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Of course there's a Pike-Beta &lt;a href=&quot;http://pikebeta.userland.com/mail&quot;&gt;mail list&lt;/a&gt;. "/>
				<outline text="Basic things about Pike. &lt;b&gt;1.&lt;/b&gt;You must have a Manila site you can write for. Without a site, Pike is useless. It *only* works over the net. &lt;b&gt;2. &lt;/b&gt;Pike is a free public beta. No need to grovel. Everyone gets one. (This list will be added to.)"/>
				<outline text="Screen shots of Pike being used to edit a &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/pikeEditingScriptingNews.gif&quot;&gt;weblog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/pikeEditingATemplate.gif&quot;&gt;template&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/pikeEditingAStory.gif&quot;&gt;story&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/pikeEditingXml.gif&quot;&gt;XML&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/pikeHomePageEditing.gif&quot;&gt;home page&lt;/a&gt; of the Pike-beta site."/>
				<outline text="This &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/pikeEditingAStory.gif&quot;&gt;screen shot&lt;/a&gt; would probably mean the most to MORE and ThinkTank users."/>
				<outline text="Yes yes yes we're going to &lt;a href=&quot;http://march25.editthispage.com/stories/storyReader$290&quot;&gt;webcast&lt;/a&gt; ManilaPalooza."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://march25.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;ManilaPalooza&lt;/a&gt; began for me last night. While Brent and Andre fixed bugs, did a security checkout and got the downloads and license agreement ready, Sheila and I went for a walk, and then did a little web work, and then drove to Palo Alto to get Spicy Noodles takeout (a first!) we talked about weblogs, community, outages. "/>
				<outline text="I had some comments here about design vs cheese, but based on email I think I'll wait till next week to explore this stuff. "/>
				<outline text="IP Law: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lawnewsnetwork.com/practice/iplaw/news/A19011-2000Mar17.html&quot;&gt;Bar Reacts To Bezos Patent Reform Plan&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="New channel: &lt;a href=&quot;http://my.userland.com/viewChannel$1802&quot;&gt;Exploring XML&lt;/a&gt; from Webreference.Com."/>
				<outline text="The NY Times &lt;a href=&quot;http://search.nytimes.com/books/00/03/26/reviews/000326.26walkert.html&quot;&gt;reviews&lt;/a&gt; Cluetrain. &quot;A manifesto should be full of hyperbole, and while this one often strains credulity in the particulars, the general thrust is on the mark.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Letters from readers on Doc's &lt;a href=&quot;http://weblogs.userland.com/cluetrain/&quot;&gt;weblog&lt;/a&gt;. "/>
				<outline text="Nick Petreley: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linuxworld.com/linuxworld/lw-2000-03/f_lw-03-penguin_6.html&quot;&gt;The dope on Zope&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="I didn't know that there's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sarrchasm.com/cgi-bin/yashmoo/amazon.pl&quot;&gt;Netdyslexia book&lt;/a&gt;. Written by E. Norma Cheese!"/>
				<outline text="Tom Clifton's &lt;a href=&quot;http://209.233.29.192/plugins/stories/storyReader$4&quot;&gt;webScheduler&lt;/a&gt; Manila plug-in. &lt;i&gt;Bing!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="Mr. T has &lt;a href=&quot;http://penn.netroedge.com/~mrt/cgi-bin/t.cgi?field=scripting.com&quot;&gt;something to say&lt;/a&gt; about all this weblog stufff."/>
				<outline text="Today is a day of celebration. Whether the demo goes well or not, today is a day when writing for the web becomes easier than it's ever been. There will be many more of these days. "/>
				<outline text="I want to change the tagline for Pike from &lt;i&gt;The first Web outliner&lt;/i&gt; to &lt;i&gt;The Web's first outliner.&lt;/i&gt; Subtle but important difference. We are part of the web, our success is the web's success. When we win the web wins. That's part of the Ask Not philosophy."/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 24" created="Fri, 24 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;rules&gt;">
					<outline text="&lt;rule&gt;&lt;outlineSpacing&gt;1.5&lt;/outlineSpacing&gt;&lt;/rule&gt;"/>
					<outline text="&lt;/rules&gt;"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://march25.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;Tomorrow&lt;/a&gt; is a very big day for me. I'm so psyched! My imagination has run wild. I think of Matt Neuburg racing north on his BMW motorcycle. And Susan Kitchens humming tunes driving up 101. Ken Dow flying in from Ottawa and Eric Soroos from Seattle. Zoom zoom. People from Organic and Macromedia sipping lattes and thinking about the stock market. So this is what Silicon Valley looks like? Jacob Levy getting ready to say &quot;Let's see Pike already!&quot; Oooh ooh ooooh. Who will be the most surprising?? And how many digital cameras will there be? And will the webcast work? And perhaps the most vexing question of them all.. "/>
				<outline text="Survey: &lt;a href=&quot;http://surveys.userland.com/surveys/run/dave@userland.com/aSongForManilapalooza&quot;&gt;What's the song&lt;/a&gt;?"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inessential.com/sheila/&quot;&gt;Sheeela Simmons&lt;/a&gt; is sitting next to me and I'm interviewing her. Sheila. What will be your next issue after they &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.controlled-demolition.com/&quot;&gt;implode&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metrokc.gov/stadium/&quot;&gt;Kingdome&lt;/a&gt; on Sunday? I don't know. Would you like a suggestion? Sure. Well, you could always blow up the &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/spaceNeedle.gif&quot;&gt;Space Needle&lt;/a&gt;! No way, can't be done. &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/wavs/fargo5.wav&quot;&gt;Ohhhhhh&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="XML.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xml.com/pub/2000/03/22/psi/index.html&quot;&gt;Portable Site Information&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;XML can be used to model the actual structure of a web site.&quot; &lt;i&gt;True.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macopinion.com/columns/megabyte/00/03/23/index.html&quot;&gt;Erik Barzeski&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Many people believe that CodeWarrior will be dead by the summer of 2001.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="InfoWorld: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoworld.com/articles/ec/xml/00/03/24/000324ecperl.xml&quot;&gt;Perl 6 to debut in August&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Perl 6 is a ground-up rewrite using the object-oriented C++ language.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/library/politics/032400wh-email.html&quot;&gt;NY Times&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The Justice Department has begun a criminal investigation into whether White House officials illegally suppressed large numbers of e-mail messages subpoenaed in investigations of Clinton administration campaign fund-raising and other activities.&quot; "/>
				<outline text="Now, you already know I'm working in an outliner. As Jerry said, what a long strange trip it's been. A few years ago I did all my Scripting News writing in an outliner. Then I had to master writing for the web in a browser. That's how we figured out how to do Manila. Now that that works, I can use an outliner again to edit this site. One advantage of using the outliner is that I can quickly edit and re-order the items. It's faster than the web browser, it reduces three steps to two. Edit-Change-Post becomes Change-Save. However there's more I can do, and probably will, to use more than one level of the outline. The key is in adjusting the rules so that it renders in a sensible way."/>
				<outline text="Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/pikeEditingScriptingNews.gif&quot;&gt;screen shot&lt;/a&gt; of today's editing environment, with the Pike File menu pulled down. Speaking of strange trips, this is the new File menu I was &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1999/05/24/editThisPage&quot;&gt;speaking&lt;/a&gt; of in May of last year."/>
				<outline text="BTW, now that you have seen the new File menu, I expect complaints about the What is This? command. What does it do? It opens a page in your browser that explains what it is. We figured this would be the place to put the uber-help command, that this would be the place where confusion would expect a quick answer. (And there is no New command in the menu, which is what usually appears in that slot. The menu looked wrong with Close as the first item.)"/>
				<outline text="The day after ManilaPalooza, Seattle will &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/385562.asp&quot;&gt;blow up&lt;/a&gt; the Kingdome in celebration. Make sense to me. They ought to blow up the other stadium too."/>
				<outline text="News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.cnet.com/news/0-1005-200-1583951.html&quot;&gt;Former Beatle's publishing house sues MP3.com&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$15694&quot;&gt;Andrew Wooldridge wonders&lt;/a&gt; if Pike could be used to edit XUL. My answer is basically &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$15695&quot;&gt;yes&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Outliners are good design tools for all hierarchic languages and data structures.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://march25.editthispage.com/discuss/msgReader$278&quot;&gt;Tom Clifton volunteers&lt;/a&gt;  to plan tomorrow's dinner. &lt;i&gt;Thanks!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://jim.roepcke.com/2000/03/24&quot;&gt;Jim Roepcke reports&lt;/a&gt; a new email virus."/>
				<outline text="OK, &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.cnet.com/news/0-1008-200-1583066.html?tag=st.ne.1002.thed.1008-200-1583066&quot;&gt;B2B&lt;/a&gt; is hot, somehow we missed that boat, so let's start another one. W2R. What does that mean? Writers To Readers. The next big growth area!"/>
				<outline text="Update. The next growth area after B2B and W2R will be F2F, or Face-To-Face. So today's hot stock market tip, invest in companies that run conferences that make it easy for people who meet in cyberspace to meet in person."/>
				<outline text="Joe Clark: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.electricseed.com/joeclark/epinions.html&quot;&gt;Usability at epinions.com&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="BTW, the Joe Clark link was added using Manila Express connecting to &quot;Pike&quot;. Since epinions is for writers, they could support the same interface as Manila and then Pike would be able to submit stories to epinions, and of course everything that's compatible with Pike would work too. (So far there are no Pike-compatibles, but anything that is will get a big fat link on Scripting News.) This is how non-dominant web apps companies can work together to empower users and make the Web more powerful."/>
				<outline text="Like Brent, I am editing my home page in an outline! This is even cooler than email."/>
				<outline text="Now Brent is working on making &quot;Manila Express&quot; work with Pike. I'm getting ready to use it! "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/business/20000323/t000027480.html&quot;&gt;LA Times&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;[Microsoft has] identified seven key categories that will represent the core components of the emerging system, known as Next Generation Windows Services. These categories--billing, publishing, relationship management, directory, communications, personalization and storage--will require intense problem-solving to make the transactions and communications over the Internet work among different computing systems.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://march25.editthispage.com/discuss/msgReader$265&quot;&gt;Ianus Keller&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Is it coincidence or a global weblog feeling, but those Dutch Weblogs that have already been mentioned on Scripting.com have decided to get together for a virtual 'instuif' (gettogether) as well?&quot;"/>
				<outline text="It is a global gettogether &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/stories/storyReader$193&quot;&gt;feeling&lt;/a&gt;! The Netherlands is my second home. I miss you guys. See you in May!"/>
				<outline text="Can you tell I'm using an outliner? (I can.)"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 23" created="Thu, 23 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Survey: &lt;a href=&quot;http://surveys.userland.com/surveys/run/dave@userland.com/willYouBeAtManilapalooza&quot;&gt;Will you be at ManilaPalooza?&lt;/a&gt;"/>
				<outline text="We made some changes to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xmlrpc.com/stories/storyReader$769&quot;&gt;Manila-RPC spec&lt;/a&gt; as we zero in on the first beta of Pike."/>
				<outline text="BTW, we will also release Frontier 6.2b1 on Saturday, Murphy and PacBell-willing. &lt;i&gt;Your humble servant.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="I have a wish list item for people who like to play with PhotoShop. Remember those THINK signs that IBM used to give to all its employees. I want one of those, but for the web. It was one of the things I liked best about IBM (I was an IBM kid, my dad worked in Armonk. Did I say that before?) Any company that sent that message to all their employees had something good going, Dave The Kid used to think. &lt;i&gt;There's that word again!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="One of my best products ever was called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.outliners.com/thinkTank2Pc.html&quot;&gt;ThinkTank&lt;/a&gt;. Pike of course, is very much like ThinkTank, but it's for networked writing. We used to &quot;hack culture&quot; as Doc says Chris Locke does. I wanted an IBM-style sign back then too, but instead of saying &quot;think&quot; it would have said &quot;tank&quot;. "/>
				<outline text="My ad guy for ThinkTank was Dave Carlick, who went on to do Netscape's first website, and founded the now notorious DoubleClick. His slogan for ThinkTank was Cogitank Ergo Sum, loosely translated to &quot;I ThinkTank therefore I am.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://march25.editthispage.com/discuss/msgReader$264&quot;&gt;Eric Soroos&lt;/a&gt; is coming down from Seattle. This will be the gathering of the millennium. Can you believe I've already forgotten how to spell millennium??"/>
				<outline text="Making up for lost time on the Pike beta release. Working on taglines. Four so far:"/>
				<outline text="&lt;ul&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;li&gt;Free for everyone."/>
				<outline text="&lt;li&gt;Works with Manila."/>
				<outline text="&lt;li&gt;Windows/Mac."/>
				<outline text="&lt;li&gt;The 1st Web outliner."/>
				<outline text="&lt;/ul&gt;"/>
				<outline text="Here's how it all comes together (at least in my mind):"/>
				<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/pikeBeta.gif&quot; height=&quot;109&quot; width=&quot;402&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;&gt;"/>
				<outline text="When was the last time you listened to a song that used to be a favorite 25 years ago? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xs4all.nl/~maroen/engels/lyrics/meetinga.htm&quot;&gt;Meeting Across the River&lt;/a&gt;, from Bruce Springsteen's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cdnow.com/cgi-bin/mserver/redirect/leaf=switch/from=sr-2211456/target=buyweb_purchase/ddcn=SD-7464+33795+2&quot;&gt;Born To Run&lt;/a&gt; album, just gave me the chills, like a time capsule. It used to define, in a way, what it meant for me to be a man, or more accurately, a developing man. Living at the edge of the law (if we blow this one they ain't gonn be lookin for just me this time) he has time to express his love for his brother (Change your shirt, cause tonight we got style)."/>
				<outline text="&quot;But Eddie, man, she don't understand, there's two grand practically sitting here in my pocket.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://inessential.com/2000/03/23.html&quot;&gt;BrentNut&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Hey -- I'm editing this page in an outliner!&quot; &lt;i&gt;No doubt the first of many such exclamations.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="Also note the weird URL on Brent's page. How did that happen??"/>
				<outline text="&quot;picard&quot; &quot;jerry&quot;"/>
				<outline text="We like to stay current on what Microsoft is doing in network systems, web user interfaces, XML, distributed computing, standards, OSes. For the last six months or so, we have been in the wrong PR flow, getting briefed on consumer stuff, MSN, Radio Shack, etc and not being briefed or included in important (to us) rollouts in XML, operating systems and browsers. Any Microsoft marketing/PR people tuned in? I have tried every other means to get this corrected. I'm sure it's just an administrative thing."/>
				<outline text="O'Reilly's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oreillynet.com/pub/a/rss/2000/03/17/about_meerkat.html&quot;&gt;Meerkat&lt;/a&gt; is an &quot;open wire service&quot;. It's kind of hard to find the actual Meerkat &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oreillynet.com/meerkat/&quot;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt; on O'Reilly. Comparable to &quot;My.UserLand&quot;, they wrote their own aggregator that reads (a subset of?) the same files My.UserLand reads."/>
				<outline text="Reuters: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dailynews.yahoo.com/h/nm/20000323/bs/tech_cisco_2.html&quot;&gt;Cisco Briefly Tops Microsoft in Value&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="7/9/96: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1996/07/09/ciscosystems&quot;&gt;Cisco Systems&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;The two companies are like Amtraks on a collision course. Why? Simple. Cisco makes software for networking, and wants to make tools for content. Microsoft makes tools for content and wants to make software for networking.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/discuss/msgReader$469&quot;&gt;New features&lt;/a&gt; in changes.xml on Weblogs.Com."/>
				<outline text="Peter Miller: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xmlrpc.com/discuss/msgReader$765&quot;&gt; Representing Tables in XML-RPC&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Two new weblogs: &lt;a href=&quot;http://digitalfoto.weblogs.com/&quot;&gt;Digital Photography&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://justapplescript.weblogs.com/&quot;&gt;AppleScript&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;i&gt;&quot;Gee it's great to be back home!&quot;&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://2020hindsight.editthispage.com/2000/03/23&quot;&gt;Susan Kitchens&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Glad the network is fixed!&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://array.editthispage.com/2000/03/23&quot;&gt;Garret Vreeland&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Hey, we're alive again!&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://ican.editthispage.com/2000/03/23&quot;&gt;Jeff Cheney&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Wow! I didn't really know how much I love EditThisPage until I had to live without it for a day.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Three mini-outages this morning, 10, 20 and 30 minutes, during which there were no hits on the servers, and I couldn't get out. They're like aftershocks of earthquakes. I totally don't have my sea-legs now. "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$483&quot;&gt;Linux1 and the Honkers&lt;/a&gt;: The California LAN gets bigger. Now there's a Linux machine in the cluster, and the new 700 Mhz Subhonker1 is added to the mix, along with a MacUser Eddy award for Frontier 2.0."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/stories/storyReader$493&quot;&gt;Outage Images&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;While we were cooling our heels waiting for the Internet Gods at PacBell to give us juice, I played with pictures on my laptop, reviewing unpublished pics, and coming up with this random selection which I call Outage Images.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Press release: &lt;a href=&quot;http://biz.yahoo.com/prnews/000323/ca_cobalt__1.html&quot;&gt;Cobalt to Acquire Chili!Soft&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Chili!Soft enables developers to use Microsoft tools to create dynamic Web pages.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://liberte.aful.org/pipermail/patents/2000-March/000377.html&quot;&gt;According to Jean-Paul Smets&lt;/a&gt;, the European Patent Office has granted Amazon a patent for 1-Click."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$486&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/steveMartinSmall.gif&quot; height=&quot;56&quot; width=&quot;50&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;One of our longest and most frustrating outages is over. Our link through Conxion went down, the outside world couldn't access any of the servers that are on our California LAN, including EditThisPage.Com and Weblogs.Com. The outage was in PacBell, and you gotta know this, Conxion came through in unbelievable form. At times I couldn't believe the resources that were applied to getting us back on the air. We're going to send flowers to Conxion today for performance above and beyond the call of duty, particularly Steve Martin, who outlasted all of us, he arrived at 5:30AM yesterday, and he was still here when Bierman and I left at about 10PM. Brent stayed up with Steve, and explains the &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$15671&quot;&gt;resolution&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="The outage also meant that we couldn't get out, and it couldn't have come at a worse time, because everyone was here for our onsite in preparation for the ManilaPalooza meeting on Saturday. Or maybe it was for the best. Instead of working at a breakneck pace, we had to slow down. Both Brent and Andre were able to get development done, although it was difficult to do without a net connection, it was possible."/>
				<outline text="As noted below, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$471&quot;&gt;hardware&lt;/a&gt; upgrade for EditThisPage.Com went smoothly, it took 38 minutes, and while the upgrade was happening Murphy tripped the wire at PacBell and knocked us off the air. We took the unusual outage as an opportunity to do software upgrades on most of our servers, and to add 256MB of RAM to Subhonker2, the machine that runs Weblogs.Com, so it should be faster now too. I'm looking for signs of problems related to all the upgrading that happened yesterday, and there may be a problem with static pictures on ETP, but otherwise all looks good. Still probing."/>
				<outline text="From the I Learned Something New Department. Yesterday Steve Martin was talking about &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pla-netx.com/linebackn/news/bsod.html&quot;&gt;Blue Screens of Death&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; on Windows NT. I told him that in three years of running as many as five NT systems I had seen only one blue screen. He told me that that was quite good, he sees lots more of them. Bierman then explained that Microsoft's server software, Back Office, SQL Server, Active Server Pages, etc, tends to use undocumented system calls to get closer to the hardware, and that's why NT gets the rep for bluescreening. My servers don't do this because Frontier plays by the rules, and when there are problems it doesn't bring the OS down.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;"/>
				<outline text="This makes the Cobalt acquisition of Chili!Soft that much more interesting. I assume that their ASP-compatible runtime doesn't do the BSOD thing. Is that true? Luke?"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 21" created="Tue, 21 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;font color=&quot;red&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Network problems that started Monday evening have now turned into an outage, our main LAN is disconnected, you can access Scripting News because it is at Exodus, not on our LAN.  The EditThisPage.Com upgrade was completed in 38 minutes at 6:08pm Pacific yesterday.  We're awaiting word from PacBell and Conxion on when the outage will be fixed.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/font&gt;"/>
				<outline text="EditThisPage.Com will get a hardware upgrade this evening, going from 500Mhz to 700Mhz. There will be an outage, hopefully no more than one hour, while we do the hardware switchover."/>
				<outline text="I had a phone talk with Brian Biles, VP-Marketing at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.valinux.com/&quot;&gt;VA Linux&lt;/a&gt;. I'm not sure he understood what I was asking for in the way of a relationship with a server vendor. It's basically the same relationship we offered to Cobalt. Help us form a sub-community of VA users, so we can study the product, understand where they're going and see if it makes sense to go there together. It's such a fluid market, and ultimately marketing through the Web, through all its channels, is how the market will segment. Imho of course."/>
				<outline text="What I want to do with a server vendor is what I talked about in &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/2000/02/04/howToMakeMoneyOnTheInternet&quot;&gt;How to Make Money on the Internet&lt;/a&gt;. Form a community around the product, learn from the people, and create products to make them ecstatic. "/>
				<outline text="In the server market, there is no single outstanding vendor. By this time we should have a single default choice, one company that makes the best servers, who responds when there are problems, and has deep roots in the user community. No such vendor exists, but we're offering to try to help one of them become that. "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.cnet.com/news/0-1006-200-1579573.html&quot;&gt;Interestingly&lt;/a&gt;, Palm was able to do a stunning IPO and then attract a top-level management team, exploding yet another Silicon Valley belief that you have to form your full management team before raising public money."/>
				<outline text="Upside: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.upside.com/Ebiz/38d28df10.html&quot;&gt;A call for universal registration&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;For example, if you are shopping online and decide that you'll buy a few things from Gap.com, BattersChoice.com, Amazon.com and 800.com, and you are not a registered customer for each one, you can spend the better part of an hour in dial-up mode just registering yourself. And even if you have registered, all of these sites have different shopping cart implementations, different checkouts, and, sometimes, an assigned user identification moniker different from your real name.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Do you doubt that user interface standards are coming?&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="Today we begin a two-week onsite meeting at UserLand. Andre is here, Brent is flying down from Seattle this morning. On Saturday we'll be at the March 25 ManilaPalooza gathering. Then we will have a full week to incorporate what we learned into our development plan for the next few months."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://march25.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;The March 25 meeting&lt;/a&gt; is free and open to the public. Even if you have a casual interest in our sites and services, you're welcome at the meeting. It's a function of the whole UserLand.Com and Scripting News community. We're there to listen and we'll also speak frankly and openly about our plans to grow our part of the Web. Even if you compete, you are welcome on &lt;a href=&quot;http://march25.editthispage.com/whoWhatWhere&quot;&gt;Saturday&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="What we will demo: First and foremost, we will demo Pike. We will have a website ready by Saturday so Manila users all over the world, even those who are not in Cupertino, will be able to download and use the software. It will be a free public beta. "/>
				<outline text="What is Pike? It is an outliner that's been custom-fitted to plug into Manila sites. You can create and edit stories with Pike. You can use it to edit your home page. And you can also use it to edit the myriad of templates that define how a Manila site is rendered. It's both a writing and design tool. "/>
				<outline text="Pike is as easy to use as a web browser but has the common features that web writers and designers need. Undo, Find and Replace, etc. And if you've never used an outliner, a bunch of surprises. Did you know that text has structure? That's the basic premise of an outliner."/>
				<outline text="Further, Pike is also a Web server. And an object database. And a programming platform. It's basically a limited version of Frontier with a carefully crafted user interface designed to hide the details, but if you know how to poke it, it's a full scripting, database, and server environment. "/>
				<outline text="Even further, Pike is a homecoming, in so many ways. For me, it's the final step in a loop that began for me 22 years ago when I started working on outliners. To me they were always about groupware. Now, with all the pieces in place, a strong rendering engine and storage system, networking, and hypertext, we're ready to put the cap on the mountain. When Pike is successfully deployed, my lifetime work, from a software point of view, will be done. All that remains is getting the whole world to use it! &lt;i&gt;Not a small thing.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="For people who still use Frontier 5, the last free version, this could also be a homecoming. Pike is built from the same codebase as Frontier 6.1, and it will track the development of Frontier. We will release new versions of Pike as we release new versions of Frontier. Pike is for Mac and Windows, there is no difference between the two versions. Pike may also satisfy the ever-present request for &quot;Frontier Runtime&quot;. Pike will be free, at least in the first release, so it's a chance for everyone who stayed with the free version of Frontier to graduate to all the new stuff. However, if you want to deploy a real server that lots of people can use, you must license Frontier for US$899."/>
				<outline text="What else will we demo? Well, that's still up for grabs. We're basically done with static rendering of Manila sites, which, if you choose to use it, will turn Manila into an editorial system, and offload serving of your site to server software such as Apache, IIS and WebSTAR. I'd also like to demo the connection between a Manila plug-in and a Pike plug-in, showing how Frontier developers can create custom editorial systems with very high-level interfaces. We can't possibly demo all this stuff, and still leave lots of room for the community to speak and organize. So we will focus on things that are best demo'd face-to-face."/>
				<outline text="And face-to-face is what the meeting is all about. When an online community gets together in a room sparks will fly. Hopefully everyone will be in good cheer! If there are any issues you need to raise that might not be in good cheer, I hope we get a heads-up on them *before* the meeting on Saturday. Thanks."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://march25.editthispage.com/discuss/msgReader$229&quot;&gt;Jacob Levy&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I'll be there, but not the whole day. Could we have an agenda so I can plan which part of the day to attend.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://march25.editthispage.com/discuss/msgReader$230&quot;&gt;My answer&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Jacob, it's not a whole-day meeting, it's 1PM to 5PM with an informal no-host dinner at a local restaurant afterwards.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.deanza.fhda.edu/map/directions.shtml&quot;&gt;Thanks to De Anza College&lt;/a&gt; for hosting the March 25 meeting. What a great place, with all that personal computing history, to host the first ManilaPalooza community arts festival!"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 20" created="Mon, 20 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="DaveNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/2000/03/17/wasJfkAHippie&quot;&gt;Was JFK a Hippie?&lt;/a&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://foz.editthispage.com/stories/storyReader$8&quot;&gt;John Foster&lt;/a&gt; on prior art for Amazon's 1-Click patent. &quot;I walk up to a soda machine, put in 50 cents, push one button and get a drink.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$15641&quot;&gt;Chuck Shotton discusses&lt;/a&gt; turning MacBird into an XML-based UI design tool."/>
				<outline text="News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.cnet.com/news/0-1003-200-1577598.html&quot;&gt;Hewlett-Packard spends big to woo start-ups&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Traditional companies such as Sun, HP and IBM are eager to trot out start-up partners to demonstrate that they understand the Internet economy and deserve a place in it.&quot; &lt;i&gt;HP is spending $1.5 billion on startups.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="FYI, we contacted VA Linux for a discount on a new Linux server for Scripting News, but got the blowoff. Eventually we will cover servers here, as we have with the Qube, but the manufacturers haven't been helping much. "/>
				<outline text="Jakob Nielsen: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.useit.com/alertbox/20000319.html&quot;&gt;Test With 5 Users&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Chris Locke: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edventure.com/release1/0200text.html&quot;&gt;Winning through worst practices&lt;/a&gt;. I spent a couple of hours on the phone this weekend with Chris. Along with Doc, he's one of the Cluetrain guys. Very interesting conversation."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://iseeisay.editthispage.com/2000/03/20&quot;&gt;Gary Secondino has&lt;/a&gt; a trio of old tomatoes in living color, wrinkles and all."/>
				<outline text="News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.cnet.com/news/0-1005-200-1576572.html&quot;&gt;Netscape to release browser update next month&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="David Strom: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.egroups.com/group/webinformant/45.html?&quot;&gt;The hidden privacy hazards of HTML Email&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Hidden inside those fancy, fun-with-fonts and link-filled messages are some sly ways of keeping track of who you are and what you do with this information.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="WSJ: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/384456.asp&quot;&gt;Shockwave.com signs host of deals to produce exclusive Web animations&lt;/a&gt;. The site is owned by Macromedia, and headed by Macromedia CEO Rob Burgess. They hired Joe Shields, who's well-known in the Director world, and made a deal with James Brooks, who produced The Simpsons. Signing up 80,000 new members a day. "/>
				<outline text="NY Times: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/library/tech/00/03/biztech/articles/20aol.html&quot;&gt;Netscape Browser Faces a Changed World&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;After saying little about Netscape over the last year, America Online is now talking up its benefits largely to combat the impression in Silicon Valley, reported in a number of published accounts, that Netscape is in disarray and a shell of its former self.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Does &lt;a href=&quot;http://wmf.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;Wes&lt;/a&gt; have a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bradlands.com/sxsw2000/d2p11.html&quot;&gt;girlfriend&lt;/a&gt;? (She's a cutie for sure!)"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bradlands.com/sxsw2000/d4Bp5.html&quot;&gt;Wes says&lt;/a&gt; that Sarah is not his girlfriend and he's still lookin. Girls, this is quite a geek. A nice guy who knows his stuff."/>
				<outline text="Salon: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salon.com/tech/log/2000/03/20/imac_attack/index.html&quot;&gt;Don't shoot that iMac!&lt;/a&gt; &quot;Online reviewers convince Epinions not to run a TV ad featuring a Mac being blown to smithereens by a PC lover.&quot;"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 19" created="Sun, 19 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/stories/storyReader$421&quot;&gt;Big change&lt;/a&gt; on Weblogs.Com. &quot;We've had an internal project for about two weeks to redesign Weblogs.Com and to add a key new feature to the site, the ability to create your own Weblogs.Com site.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Thanks to Garret Vreeland and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mmd.weblogs.com/&quot;&gt;Mike Donnelan&lt;/a&gt; who are helping us figure out how to use this stuff. It's confusing, I admit it. But it's always confusing when you first jump out of the plane with no parachute. Scripting.Com regulars will remember our longtime slogan, still diggin, which might be amended now with &quot;still haven't figured out how the parachute works.&quot; &quot;;-&gt;&quot;"/>
				<outline text="OK, so you want to get started customizing but don't know where to begin. Here's a kick out of the airplane, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/weblogsCom/misc/clueForWebloggers.html&quot;&gt;source listing&lt;/a&gt; of the Weblogs.Com home page. What are those funny things in curly braces? They're called macros, and when the page is rendered they invoke magic bits of Frontier code called scripts. (That's why this site is called &lt;i&gt;Scripting&lt;/i&gt; News.) Those scripts poke around in the invisible object database that makes Manila work and gets things and turns them into HTML which web browsers know how to display. If you do exactly what this page does on your home page, you'll get a home page exactly like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/&quot;&gt;ours&lt;/a&gt;. If you change the formatting, your home page will contain the same info as ours but it will look different. This is called &quot;customization&quot;."/>
				<outline text="Andre chust arrived from Chermanee. Ve might go out for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spicynoodles.com/&quot;&gt;Spicy Noodles&lt;/a&gt; dinner. Andre groans. &quot;Not so soon!&quot;. &quot;Why not?&quot; I asked. &lt;i&gt;It's even worse than it appears.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.patents.ibm.com/details?pn=US06025810__&quot;&gt;US6025810&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;...thereby creating an input and output port; and generating a communications signal into the input and output port, thereby sending the signal at a speed faster than light.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mercurycenter.com/svtech/news/indepth/docs/dp031900.htm&quot;&gt;SJ Merc&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;If a site's not constantly under reconstruction, it's just one click short of becoming another 404 error on the cyberspacial roadside.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Another &lt;a href=&quot;http://dmoz.org/cgi-bin/add.cgi?where=Computers/Internet/WWW/Web_Logs&quot;&gt;place&lt;/a&gt; to register your weblog."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xmlrpc.com/discuss/msgReader$762&quot;&gt;Jon Arney&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I'm working on an XML-RPC implementation in C++ using the Xerces-C XML library from Apache.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Wow, they put a redirect on the original &lt;a href=&quot;http://info.cern.ch/&quot;&gt;home page&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cern.ch/Public/ACHIEVEMENTS/web.html&quot;&gt;Web&lt;/a&gt;, the site built by Tim Berners-Lee at CERN. From this page he pointed to the new sites as they came online. Unfortunately this site wasn't archived, wouldn't it be great if it were? It would be like the Bible for the Web. &lt;i&gt;In the beginning..&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://webservices.web.cern.ch/webservices/General/people.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/cernGeek.gif&quot; height=&quot;77&quot; width=&quot;75&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; vspace=&quot;10&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Looks like CERN wants to use the flow to create a &lt;a href=&quot;http://webservices.web.cern.ch/WebServices/&quot;&gt;portal&lt;/a&gt; of Web resources. Wait a minute, it's even heavier. They're doing something like Manila! Excellent. Tried to create a site but I'm not a member. Sad. Hey the &lt;a href=&quot;http://webservices.web.cern.ch/webservices/General/people.htm&quot;&gt;people&lt;/a&gt; look pretty cool. &lt;i&gt;New friends?&lt;/i&gt; "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/articles/A38122-2000Mar18.html&quot;&gt;Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;This is the goose, it laid the golden egg,&quot; says Lessig of the system of shared ideas that created the Internet. Left to themselves, corporate lawyers will try to patent the goose and build a legal fence around it--and then wonder what happened to the eggs.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sjmercury.com/svtech/columns/gillmor/docs/dg031900.htm&quot;&gt;Dan Gillmor&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Picture the jaded technology watcher, contemplating a slew of announcements in recent days.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="This morning one DaveNet member threatened another, a newbie, who did something understandable, but not usual. (I had already sent him a private email gently explaining how it works.) The complainer wanted me to punish the person who offended him, and also rewrite the DaveNet software, and change the culture (visible To: header) because he got one piece of email he considered spam. Oy. I took him off the list with no regrets. If you send me Old Tomatoes, you're off the list, immediately. If you want to give me your pain, look in the mirror instead, and say it to yourself. You'll find a more sympathetic ear, for sure."/>
				<outline text="I did a search for Old Tomatoes, thinking I'd find dozens of pages explaining what they are, but I found none. So here's the definitive graph on the subject. &quot;Old Tomato&quot; is a cute mis-pronunciation for &quot;ultimatum&quot;. They don't work and they're easy to avoid. Write down your old tomato. Put it in your wallet. Read it two days from now. You'll very likely find you don't care anymore. "/>
				<outline text="Given this data, it's not surprising that &lt;a href=&quot;http://whois.userland.com/default$oldtomatoes.com&quot;&gt;oldtomatoes.com&lt;/a&gt; is not taken and neither is &lt;a href=&quot;http://whois.userland.com/default$oldtomato.com&quot;&gt;oldtomato.com&lt;/a&gt;. "/>
				<outline text="However, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.whatatomato.com/&quot;&gt;whatatomato.com&lt;/a&gt; is taken."/>
				<outline text="If you like tomatoes (I don't) you'll probably like this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nald.ca/clr/meals/lunchpic.htm&quot;&gt;picture&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Jeff Cheney: &lt;a href=&quot;http://loganalysis.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;Log Analysis for Manila Sites&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adcritic.com/content/budweiser-true-wazzup.html&quot;&gt;If I watched more TV&lt;/a&gt; I would know wazzup. &lt;i&gt;True.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="NY Times: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/library/tech/00/03/biztech/articles/19eraider.html&quot;&gt;A New Activist Fund Will Test Web's Clout&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;We are as close to the Weathermen as you're going to get in the financial world.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://antecedent.editthispage.com/2000/03/19&quot;&gt;Electric Dirt Farmer&lt;/a&gt; reviews Zaplets."/>
				<outline text="&quot;jerry&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;i&gt;&quot;It's even worse than it appears.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 18" created="Sat, 18 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://members.cruzio.com/~keeper/P0.html&quot;&gt;Before&lt;/a&gt; each night is done, their plan will be unfurled, by the dawning of the sun, they'll take over the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wso.williams.edu/~mgarland/sounds/Pinky2.WAV&quot;&gt;world&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Here's a very cool Java applet that allows the user to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.martinidesign.com/kingdome/implode.htm&quot;&gt;implode&lt;/a&gt; the Seattle KingDome. Well worth the 500K download. Try blowing up some of the neighborhood for fun!"/>
				<outline text="DevX: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.devx.com/upload/free/features/vcdj/2000/04apr00/dm0400/dm0400-1.asp&quot;&gt;Distributed Computing With SOAP&lt;/a&gt;. "/>
				<outline text="David Dodd: &lt;a href=&quot;http://arts.ucsc.edu/gdead/agdl/index.html&quot;&gt;The Annotated Grateful Dead Lyrics&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Edd Dumbill: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xml.com/pub/2000/03/15/xul/index.html&quot;&gt;Fooling with XUL&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Jason Levine: &lt;a href=&quot;http://q.queso.com/discuss/msgReader$306&quot;&gt;Manila and Daily Links&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for the inspiration! I added the same feature on Scripting News, that's what the little page symbols on each day do, they take you to the archived version of the page. So instead of pointing to the Scripting News home page, now it's easy to point to the archived version. This was a good idea for a UI standard and we're glad to support it on SN and we will support it in Manila as well."/>
				<outline text="Good news, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://avantgo.userland.com/&quot;&gt;palmtop version&lt;/a&gt; of Scripting News is working once again. Still diggin!"/>
				<outline text="I played with Firedrop's &lt;a href=&quot;http://zaplet.zaplet.com/index.jsp&quot;&gt;Zaplets&lt;/a&gt; last night, but I swear there isn't an interesting application in sight. I also received a threatening email from their VC, who I thought was a friend. He said that the little guy needs protection. Little guy? Hello? I think we have a bad connection. "/>
				<outline text="According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://zaplet.zaplet.com/about/investors.jsp&quot;&gt;Firedrop&lt;/a&gt;, Kleiner has started companies that are worth &lt;i&gt;$80 billion.&lt;/i&gt; I wonder how big they think UserLand is! I also wondered if they would fight us legally, based on a &lt;a href=&quot;http://zaplet.zaplet.com/about/technology.jsp&quot;&gt;suite of over a dozen patents&lt;/a&gt; that might be issued someday, or fight me in the market, which would be be very good for everyone and totally cool. Regardless, I tried to get enthusiastic about competing with them, and haven't managed to muster the juice. Zaplets are boring. Back to the drawing board."/>
				<outline text="However: When a company advertises unissued patents, they're advertising vulnerability. The plan goes like this. Compete. Get publicity and users. Then the patents are issued. Wait for the demand letter. Tell your users &quot;Sorry, we just got shut down.&quot; Give them the URL of the government-sanctioned monopoly. See if the monopolist can make them happy. (Doubtful.)"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://foz.editthispage.com/stories/storyReader$6&quot;&gt;John Foster&lt;/a&gt; on Zaplets: &quot;I looked into Zaplets after scripting.com made mention of them and gosh, gee, there's it is, another feature from 10 years ago QuickMail from CE Software. We called them 'QM Forms' and they worked two different ways. One was you could use them to send data to a 'collector' account. Useful for gathering name, address, telephone, whatever else information... We got a 'big deal' reaction from customers for these features. Sure they were cool, they made good demos, but nobody used them.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Prior Art.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="Hunting around the web I think I found the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.musicats.com/aypcow.wav&quot;&gt;genesis&lt;/a&gt; of the Zaplet strategy."/>
				<outline text="Press release: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ibm.com/Press/prnews.nsf/jan/0E8FBD7E6AC8D12E85256863005A3D4C&quot;&gt;IBM Leads In U.S. Patents for Seventh Consecutive Year&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="While all this patent michegas is brewing, a relationship is blooming between UserLand and IBM. It's actually been blooming longer than I knew, key engineers in their Internet development group have been reading Scripting News and following our advice re XML-RPC. Well what do you know! It turns out they like weblogs too. Oy yoy yoy. Now, IBM, with over $1 billion per year in patent revenues becomes friends with Dave The Hippie who wants to make his users happy and return reasonable value to his shareholders. This is going to be an interesting conversation!"/>
				<outline text="Made even more interesting by my long history with IBM. I was an IBM kid, my father worked in Armonk when I was growing up. Later, when I ran a PC software company I made many &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1997/02/14/Toasters&quot;&gt;trips&lt;/a&gt; to Boca Raton, to visit the headquarters of the technology world. Yes, that's where it was in the early-mid 80s! (Hard to believe now, eh?) We shipped the first app for OS/2. I met with Bill Gates at the PS/2 rollout in Miami. Everyone shook their head at the lock-in. And we all headed to the Mac. &lt;i&gt;&quot;I will survive.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="Lock-in kills companies. Just ask IBM."/>
				<outline text="&lt;i&gt;&quot;It's even worse than it appears.&quot; -- Jerry Garcia.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="Alta Vista has a great picture browser that links into the Corbis database. I just spent 15 minutes browsing their Jerry Garcia &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.altavista.com/cgi-bin/query?pg=q&amp;imgset=1&amp;stype=simage&amp;q=jerry+garcia&amp;iclr=1&amp;ibw=1&amp;iexc=1&amp;mmW=1&amp;micat=0&quot;&gt;collection&lt;/a&gt;. Some great photos in there!"/>
				<outline text="About hippies and software. Long tradition there. It took a lot of imagination to be into software in the 70s and 80s. Until the Mac really took hold, software was thought to be a very unimaginative thing. Meanwhile all the really good stuff was created by people with long hair, beards, loud laughs, they listened to Grateful Dead music, and stayed pretty quiet while the suits took the credit and most of the money."/>
				<outline text="&quot;jerry&quot;"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 17" created="Fri, 17 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Reuters: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dailynews.yahoo.com/h/nm/20000317/wr/amazon_propel_1.html&quot;&gt;New Internet Start-Up Offers 'Amazon in a Box'&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Apparently due to hitting a random milestone, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ntk.net/&quot;&gt;NTK&lt;/a&gt; must now move to California. Although it pains me greatly to say this, this is somewhat &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/cooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooool.gif&quot;&gt;cool&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="NY Times: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/library/tech/00/03/biztech/articles/18net.html&quot;&gt;From Geek Improvisers, a $99 Personal Computer&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inessential.com/sheila/2000/03/17&quot;&gt;Sheila Simmons is counting&lt;/a&gt; the days until the implosion of the Kingdome in Seattle. A little over 8, as of today."/>
				<outline text="Another idea for demonstrating resistence to the rule of patent. A programmer's strike. No code, no support, perhaps we even we shut down our servers, for 24 hours, in demonstration of our opposition to patents rewriting the rules of the software business. Instead of trying to convince the suits that this is wrong, let's show them how dependent they are on us. What do you think?"/>
				<outline text="BTW, in all but the most offensive patent-owning companies, such a demonstration would probably have the support of management and ownership. I believe most companies think the current situation is unworkable, at least if you take their comments at face-value."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://farsideofmymind.editthispage.com/2000/03/17&quot;&gt;Oliver Breidenbach&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;A man comes into a park where he meets a girl with a beautiful dog sitting on a park bench.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/forbes/00/0320/6507052a.htm&quot;&gt;Forbes&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Sun Microsystems' lawsuit claims that Kingston's primary product, add-on computer memory modules, is infringing on a Sun patent. Kingston, with sales last year of $1.4 billion, is the world's largest maker of the after-market modules, which are used to expand memory in computers.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oreillynet.com/pub/a/network/2000/03/10/mozilla.html&quot;&gt;O'Reilly Network interviews&lt;/a&gt; Mozilla's Brendan Eich and Mitchell Baker."/>
				<outline text="Tim O'Reilly says patents are OK, he's just against stupid patents. In the spirit of Touch of Grey, Tim man, patents are lock-in of the worst kind. There's no way to route around them. "/>
				<outline text="Consider this paragraph from yesterday's &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/2000/03/16/thanksEsther&quot;&gt;DaveNet&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;I believe we must take extra steps to guarantee that there's no customer lock-in. It's even more important in the age of the Web when the user might not even have a copy of their own data. One of the cardinal requirements of this market, even before we try to get the UIs compatible, is an export function that leaves un-rendered text and data on the user's hard disk in a format readable by software that's available at a reasonable or no cost.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Tim, give it some thought. I'm sure you agree with the paragraph above. But any patent, stupid or not, will create an environment of certain customer lock-in, not just probable lock-in."/>
				<outline text="The only choice, imho, is to watch the Internet revolution wither and die while customers want features and fixes and are told about patents. "/>
				<outline text="To paraphrase &lt;a href=&quot;http://weblogs.userland.com/cluetrain/&quot;&gt;Doc&lt;/a&gt;, this will not be a very happy conversation. The kids will ask what we did during the war. Is it worth going to jail for, as Professor Lessig warns? The day before they put me in jail, &lt;i&gt;for writing software,&lt;/i&gt; I'll write one hell of a DaveNet. "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blackholebrain.editthispage.com/2000/03/17&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/images/blackholebrain/davejerry001.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; vspace=&quot;10&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I was struck by the characterization of Tim and myself as hippies in the Salon &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salon.com/tech/feature/2000/03/16/patent/index1.html&quot;&gt;piece&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;If the guys in the button-down shirts say the system doesn't work for us, it would be hard for Congress not to listen,&quot; Samuelson says. &quot;They have the clout; they don't look like a bunch of ragtag Internet hippies trying to get out from under the strictures of the patent system, which is exactly how the anti-patent crowd has been portrayed.&quot; Yeah I am a hippie. And I make software. And I have users who like it. Some of them are hippies, and some of them are very powerful people too."/>
				<outline text="To me, being a hippie means having a mind and a heart, and remembering to dance when you get the chance."/>
				<outline text="***Was JFK a hippie?"/>
				<outline text="Hey, if he had lived, would JFK have been a hippie?"/>
				<outline text="&quot;jfk&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;i&gt;&quot;And so my fellow Americans, ask not what your country can do for you, ask what you can do for your country.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="BTW, one of the things I can do for my country is &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$303&quot;&gt;put on a button-down shirt&lt;/a&gt;. It's not that big a deal."/>
				<outline text="Thanks to Mike Jamieson for a full &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mediacentre.com/mike/grey.mp3&quot;&gt;MP3 scan&lt;/a&gt; of Touch of Grey. What a gorgeous song. Tears running down my face and I'm laughing. &quot;The ABC's we all must face, try to keep a little grace. I know the rent is in arrears. The dog has not been fed in years. &lt;i&gt;It's even worse than it appears.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="Great email from Deadheads. From Keith Hurwitz, &quot;I started the internal distribution list, deadheads at Microsoft, "/>
				<outline text="in 92. I think I still have an extra &quot;deadheads at Microsoft&quot; t-shirt - on the back it has a cool steal your face skull with Windows logo in the center and billg glasses!  I'd be honored to send you one if you are interested!&quot; The Dead was a culture that permeated everything in my generation."/>
				<outline text="What's wrong with this picture? &lt;a href=&quot;http://quote.yahoo.com/q?s=COMS&amp;d=t&quot;&gt;3COM&lt;/a&gt;, which owns 95 percent of Palm, has a market capitalization of $22 billion, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://quote.yahoo.com/q?s=palm&amp;d=t&quot;&gt;Palm&lt;/a&gt; has a market cap of $31 billion. In the Old Economy, this would be immediately adjusted, stock traders would do the math and see that 3COM was totally undervalued, it's just math. But one plus one doesn't equal two anymore. Toto, I don't think we're in Kansas anymore."/>
				<outline text="I found a RealAudio interview with Jerry and Phil. Great quote about taxes. &quot;The first problem we couldn't deal with by completely ignoring it.&quot; Probably not the last! &quot;;-&gt;&quot;"/>
				<outline text="This is a test for my friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://weblogs.userland.com/fod/picture$8&quot;&gt;Dave Jacobs&lt;/a&gt;, a vice-president at Macromedia."/>
				<outline text="&quot;dorothy&quot;"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 16" created="Thu, 16 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="DaveNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/2000/03/16/thanksEsther&quot;&gt;Touch of Grey&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="First MacWorld, now &lt;a href=&quot;http://jim.roepcke.com/2000/03/16&quot;&gt;Jim Roepcke&lt;/a&gt;, have dug out quotes from old DaveNets about Apple. Now let me return the favor. Here's what Steve Jobs said in &lt;a href=&quot;http://library.northernlight.com/SG19990714100000645.html?cb=13&amp;sc=0#doc&quot;&gt;Fortune&lt;/a&gt; in 1996. &quot;If I were running Apple, I would milk the Macintosh for all it's worth--and get busy on the next great thing. The PC wars are over. Done. Microsoft won a long time ago.&quot; "/>
				<outline text="WSJ: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/383357.asp&quot;&gt;Success of King’s e-book sparks old-line vs. online controversy&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Simon &amp; Schuster said it didn’t include Fatbrain on the list of vendors for Mr. King’s book because Fatbrain’s encryption systems, which allow readers to download the material twice, wasn’t suitable.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="NY Times: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/library/tech/00/03/biztech/articles/17blue.html&quot;&gt;IBM Makes Breakthrough in Memory for Computers&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Susan Kitchens started a &lt;a href=&quot;http://march25.editthispage.com/discuss/msgReader$179&quot;&gt;roll call page&lt;/a&gt; on the March 25 site."/>
				<outline text="Linux Newbies: &lt;a href=&quot;http://linuxnewbies.editthispage.com/tips/20000316&quot;&gt;More On Installing Software&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Grateful Dead: &lt;a href=&quot;http://members.aol.com/Oxym0r0n99/grateful.html&quot;&gt;Touch Of Grey&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="8/21/95 Time: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.time.com/time/magazine/archive/1995/950821/950821.showbusiness.html&quot;&gt;Jerry Garcia dies at 53&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;The flags were at half staff in San Francisco, and on one, a riot of colors replaced the traditional red, white and blue. It was the first tie-dyed flag to fly in front of city hall.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="4/21/97: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1997/04/21/CanAppleSurvive&quot;&gt;Can Apple Survive?&lt;/a&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.mpr.org/programs/futuretense/daily_rafiles/20000310.ram&quot;&gt;Minnesota Public Radio interviews&lt;/a&gt; Jesse James Garrett on weblogs. &lt;i&gt;RealAudio.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.cnet.com/news/0-1003-201-1559726-0.html?tag=st.ne.1002.bgif?st.ne.fd.gif.l&quot;&gt;News.Com&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The way Jini has been handled is a classic example of the product-marketing cycles that drive much of today's high-tech industry. To satisfy the relentless demands of competition and Wall Street, companies often hype their products far before a market for them has been created--and sometimes with little knowledge about how their technology will ultimately be used, if at all.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://weblog.mercurycenter.com/ejournal/2000/03/16&quot;&gt;Dan Gillmor&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;For the first time in years, the installation of a new operating system went without a hitch. With Windows 2000, Microsoft put a lot of effort into this part of the product, and it shows.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$15601&quot;&gt;Steve Yost&lt;/a&gt; would like to apply collaborative filtering technology to My.UserLand and Weblogs.Com."/>
				<outline text="What is &lt;a href=&quot;http://everydevel.com/&quot;&gt;Everything&lt;/a&gt;?"/>
				<outline text="Synchronicity. A few minutes ago I sent a follow-up email to John Patrick of IBM, saying that I saw how Sash, their JavaScript UI widgets, could fit into our &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/2000/03/02/theTwowayweb&quot;&gt;Two-Way-Web vision&lt;/a&gt;, and at the same time, Andrew Wooldridge, editor of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://webapps.editthispage.com/2000/03/16&quot;&gt;Web Apps site&lt;/a&gt;, was pointing to &lt;a href=&quot;http://sash.alphaworks.ibm.com/&quot;&gt;Sash&lt;/a&gt;, saying &quot;This is truly interesting.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="To Manila designers -- I'm sure there's a temptation to regard my &lt;a href=&quot;http://march25.editthispage.com/discuss/msgReader$145&quot;&gt;call for templates&lt;/a&gt; as a greedy request by a huge corporation to get its users to work for free. I've even seen this POV on the web. Or you could view it as a way of giving future Manila users the benefit of your experience, knowing that this will mean they will have more fun, and will get to know you as the design inspiration for their site. We're going to open a new hosting service in the next few days. Right now all we have is the plain It Worked template that's getting kind of stale. We could offer money for the winning design. If we did, would that get you off your butts and coming up with new starter designs?"/>
				<outline text="Tim Bray: &lt;a href=&quot;http://xml.org/archives/xml-dev/msg01263.html&quot;&gt;Patent your DTDs&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;It's interesting to note that the DTD is ambiguous and hence technically not XML - I'm sure the USPTO will detect this.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://danbricklin.com/log/&quot;&gt;Dan Bricklin&lt;/a&gt; has some great pictures from Esther's, including me, smiling. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;"/>
				<outline text="One of my best lines ever. At the Web Apps panel on Tuesday, we're talking about building on each others' tools, Evan Williams volunteers that they've already prototyped an XML-RPC connection between Blogger and Manila. &quot;Excuse me while I fall off my chair.&quot; It was that kind of session. Good humor, lots of laughs, awe at some of the demos (particularly ThinkFree), and hunger for success. "/>
				<outline text="NetDyslexia: &lt;a href=&quot;http://netdyslexia.editthispage.com/euroblogs/&quot;&gt;Euroblogs&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.free-conversant.com/&quot;&gt;Conversant&lt;/a&gt; is a Frontier-based web app. I created a Conversant site late last week, but only had a few minutes to play with it. I'm interested in starting a discussion on how Conversant and Manila might be integrated, along the lines of the discussion we had in Phoenix (which I haven't written up yet!) about connecting various content servers with editorial tools. Perhaps someone with a Manila site can create a Conversant site for exploring the possible connections between the products."/>
				<outline text="Also this is a milestone for the Frontier development community. This product is at least as competitive with Manila as Blogger is. (As if competitiveness could be measured on a scale of 1 to 10.) Finding a method for co-existence is going to be a bit of a challenge. The two lead developers of Conversant, Seth Dillingham and Brian Andresen, are highly regarded in the community as experts in getting Frontier to do amazing feats and working around its flaws. I bet Conversant works really well. They've been working on the service for many months. Their work deserves a careful review by people who use Manila and Frontier."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.egroups.com/group/xml-rpc/738.html?&quot;&gt;XML-RPC mail list&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I am working on a business to business portal, which allows members to put up Items to buy/sell on the exchange.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Chris Nolan: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salon.com/tech/feature/2000/03/14/dotcom_journalist/index.html&quot;&gt;Why I'm still scribbling for a living&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Silicon Valley is now well on its way to becoming an affluent, fast-paced urban environment, stretching from San Francisco to San Jose. It is sophisticated, it is cutthroat and it is one of the most amazing places on Earth right now.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Reuters: &lt;a href=&quot;http://biz.yahoo.com/rf/000315/bd1.html&quot;&gt;Life imitates art in Web confession sites&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;This year's South by Southwest Interactive Festival featured an impressive array of Webcam and Weblog site proprietors who are committed to making people see that the Internet as a medium can be more than just an online mall.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Tim O'Reilly talks with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oreillynet.com/pub/a/patents/2000/03/09/stallman.html&quot;&gt;Richard Stallman&lt;/a&gt; on patents. &quot;If only the nontrivial new ideas are off limits for 20 years, that will be enough to keep us 20 years behind the times.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&quot;gandhi&quot;"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 15" created="Wed, 15 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="On Tuesday, Steve Ballmer of Microsoft announced a deal with RealNames, but was this a slip of the tongue? They also did a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/382637.asp?0m=T15N&quot;&gt;deal&lt;/a&gt; with RealNetworks on the same day. (Great quote: &quot;Microsoft is just one of the colors on the globe (in this space),&quot; Doherty said. &quot;Real is still the mapmaker.&quot;)"/>
				<outline text="In fact they did do a &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.excite.com/news/r/000314/12/net-microsoft-realnames&quot;&gt;deal with RealNames&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;The pact will let Microsoft expand its use of RealNames' technology that lets Web surfers find Web sites by typing keywords like &lt;i&gt;ford explorer&lt;/i&gt; in a browser, rather than by using lengthy addresses packed with dots and slashes.&quot; The domain name system just took another hit. Will there be an outcry this time? There wasn't the &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1998/07/20/netscapeAndGenericNames&quot;&gt;last time&lt;/a&gt; it happened."/>
				<outline text="Paranoid vision from yesterday's patent discussion. DOJ negotiates a settlement with MS. Major limitations on what they can do, with real teeth, unlike the last consent decree. A few months pass. Microsoft starts exercising their &lt;i&gt;legal&lt;/i&gt; monopolies through their 1000+ patents. Sorry I don't remember who raised this scenario. It's cute. I'm not sure if they would play this tough. I kind of hope not. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&quot;dorothy&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Xml.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://xml.com/pub/2000/02/xtech/xul.html&quot;&gt;Cool XUL Provides Cross-Platform UI&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Brett Glass: &lt;a href=&quot;http://boardwatch.internet.com/mag/99/dec/bwm62.html&quot;&gt;Twinkle, twinkle little prime&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;The patent on the RSA public key cryptography algorithm is due to expire shortly.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="People I bonded with in Phoenix (this list will grow): Brian Behlendorf of Apache, David Ellington of NetNoir, Fred Davis and Colette McMullen of Lumeria, Dan Lynch (founder of many net-things), Tim O'Reilly of O'Reilly Associates, John Patrick of IBM, Evan Williams of Pyra, Ken Rhie of ThinkFree, Lawrence Lessig of Harvard, Tara Lamay of EFF, Doc Searls (who needs no introduction here), Michael Shrage of MIT Media Lab."/>
				<outline text="And get this -- I spent ten minutes with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tu-berlin.de/~gruhlke/forum/whoopi/&quot;&gt;Whoopi Goldberg&lt;/a&gt;! We talked about growing up in NY, getting older (we're both 44), her fear of flying (she travels in a bus), and of course I mentioned the problem with patents. I liked talking with her. It gave me a buzz."/>
				<outline text="***Good morning from Day 3 of PC Forum"/>
				<outline text="The Web Apps discussion yesterday was great fun. Lots of different approaches, the room was packed, humor, insights, in a way, the first meeting of members of a new market. "/>
				<outline text="Last night an interesting session on patents. As one would expect, two extreme views, one that patents are needed to protect small companies from larger predators, the other that monopolies are not cool, even under the guise of patents. "/>
				<outline text="An intermediate viewpoint, that the furor over patents is like Y2K, an imagined crisis, and an idea that the Frontier community could test the law by picking one highly visible yet thin company and meet them in the market, see how they respond. "/>
				<outline text="One idea we've been interested in for quite some time is HTML email, so perhaps Firedrop would make a good test case. As you know Manila sends HTML email to subscribers that request it. I know their VCs well, and they know me. From what I've seen it wouldn't take long to build a server app that does what Firedrop does. How would they respond? Well, it's pretty clear that their patents have yet to be issued. Maybe they would just welcome the competition, as a way of helping them refine their relationship with their market."/>
				<outline text="These are just some thoughts from the field. I'm writing this out on the patio, it's a very pretty day, hard to be inside, but it's time to go back in! More news tomorrow, for sure."/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 14" created="Tue, 14 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="AP: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dailynews.yahoo.com/h/ap/20000314/hl/britain_cloned_pigs_2.html&quot;&gt;Dolly Creators Claim Cloning Pigs&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Doc Searls: &lt;a href=&quot;http://weblogs.userland.com/cluetrain/stories/storyReader$115&quot;&gt;Patent Death Pending&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="The 3COM wireless connection is flaky and batteries don't last very long. So updates may or may not be very frequent."/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 13" created="Mon, 13 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://zaplet.zaplet.com/about/technology.jsp&quot;&gt;About FireDrop&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The Zaplet Communications Platform required significant technology breakthroughs to leverage the convergence of the web, email, and instant messaging. Breakthroughs that centered around server-based asynchronous communications, and innovations in cross-email platform technology, which are part of the FireDrop suite of over a dozen patents.&quot; "/>
				<outline text="BYTE: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.byte.com/column/BYT20000301S0001&quot;&gt;Internet Patents Are Changing The Rules&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="NY Times: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/library/tech/00/03/biztech/articles/13joy.html&quot;&gt;Technologist Gives His Peers a Dark Warning&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.firedrop.com/&quot;&gt;Firedrop&lt;/a&gt; is dropping now. They have lots of patents. &quot;An entirely new communication platform. Email, the web, instant messaging.&quot; Their product is called Zaplet.  "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.onepage.com/&quot;&gt;OnePage&lt;/a&gt;. Blah blah blah. Because blah new inefficiences, it's a hassle visiting all the websites, to drill down, daily basis, at the end of the day. Bookmarks. It's only getting worse. more necessary, not less. Smaller. It sucks. The internet sucks. At the end of the day fifteen years ago. Today schools register online, blah blah ok blah blah. You lose. They lose."/>
				<outline text="The guy from Time-Warner says &quot;at the end of the day&quot; a lot. Now I am too."/>
				<outline text="Good morning and welcome to Phoenix. Thanks to 3COM I have a wireless LAN connection that I can update from the hall at PC Forum. "/>
				<outline text="It's pretty cool to be able to check my email and write for the web while in a conference. It's sort of a very high fidelity webcast. I deliberately sat in the back of the room so the screen would look as small as possible."/>
				<outline text="The CEO of Google is very impressive. I talked with him briefly last night. He's on stage right now with Carl Malamud of Invisible Worlds, and Eric Schmidt of Novell."/>
				<outline text="I've gotten three emails, all not for publication, from Microsoft people saying that they &lt;i&gt;do not&lt;/i&gt; have a patent on XML-RPC technology."/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 12" created="Sun, 12 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="DaveNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/2000/03/12/whatIsAWebApplication&quot;&gt;What is a Web Application?&lt;/a&gt;"/>
				<outline text="If I don't respond to your emails or postings it's because I'm on my way to Phoenix. Have a great day, see y'all tomorrow!"/>
				<outline text="Last night I put together the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www9.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;schedule&lt;/a&gt; for the Distributed Computing Track on Developer's Day at WWW9 in Amsterdam, May 19, 2000. That's quite a mouthful! It was also way late. Sorry to the WWW9 people. Glad it's done now."/>
				<outline text="I like Esther because she gets &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$122&quot;&gt;silly&lt;/a&gt;. She thought I should wear jeans to the soiree in Davos. I didn't. But I will wear jeans at Esther's. The official national dress of the Internet. Yaya."/>
				<outline text="Great to see the NY Times in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/timesMagazineShot.gif&quot;&gt;leadership position&lt;/a&gt; covering the patent crisis. At least we can document the Internet boom de-constructing. Let's give the candidates something to talk about, leave a trail for historians to follow."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/wavs/overTheRainbow.wav&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/dorothy.gif&quot; height=&quot;57&quot; width=&quot;40&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; vspace=&quot;10&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;All over the weblogs this morning I'm seeing notes about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sxsw.com/inter/index.shtml&quot;&gt;SXSW&lt;/a&gt; show. I'm sad I'm not there. The energy seems so beautiful! All those digital cameras. A whos-who of the Weblog World. Instead I'm going to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edventure.com/pcforum/pcforum.html&quot;&gt;Esther's&lt;/a&gt;. This is the first one I've been to in close to ten years. I haven't been counting. I stopped going because the group of people I grew up with had become just like the older people we used to hate. To the people at SXSW, who are young, some as young as 21, cherish this experience! And do better than my generation did, keep the optimism, and don't accept the bullshit."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.women.com/tech/spotlight/carusoTrans.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/minidenise.gif&quot; height=&quot;52&quot; width=&quot;31&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; vspace=&quot;10&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1996/10/24/QueSeraSera&quot;&gt;essay&lt;/a&gt; I wrote after the last Stewart's I attended. (Same crowd as Esther's.) It was a good goodbye. I sang with Denise Caruso, one of the keynotes at SXSW. &quot;On Tuesday night, in the main lobby of the Phoenician Hotel, about twenty people sang a chorus of Que Sera Sera. Over and over. It was beautiful. No fear. Ye-hi!&quot; "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fortune.com/fortune/technology/daily/0,3467,617000223,00.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/minijodi.gif&quot; height=&quot;28&quot; width=&quot;25&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; vspace=&quot;10&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Another friend, Jodi Mardesich, will also be speaking at SXSW. I worked with Jodi when she was at the SJ Merc, on the story of the Steve Jobs' coup that toppled Gil Amelio. Jodi just &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fortune.com/fortune/technology/daily/0,3467,617000223,00.html&quot;&gt;left Fortune&lt;/a&gt; to become part of an Internet startup. &lt;i&gt;Go Jodi!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="My love to everyone in Austin. I'm jealous! Have fun!! &lt;i&gt;Be young.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="***Other stuff"/>
				<outline text="David Burdett: &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.develop.com/archives/wa.exe?A2=ind0003&amp;L=soap&amp;F=&amp;S=&amp;P=23514&quot;&gt;What is XML Messaging?&lt;/a&gt;"/>
				<outline text="Internet Analysis on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theinternetanalyst.com/min-tia/individual/000224sections/zeroin.html&quot;&gt;Allaire&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theinternetanalyst.com/min-tia/individual/000224sections/spotlight.html&quot;&gt;Vignette&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&quot;JFK&quot;"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 11" created="Sat, 11 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="DaveNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/2000/03/11/nyTimesOnThePatentCrisis&quot;&gt;James Gleick on the Patent Crisis&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Weblogs.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/membersWithFavorites&quot;&gt;Members with Favorites&lt;/a&gt;. You can also include your favorites, or someone else's, or a collection of them, in any web page, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/favoritesInJavascript&quot;&gt;using&lt;/a&gt; a &amp;lt;script&gt; tag, of course. "/>
				<outline text="There's also an &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/weblogMonitor/favorites.xml&quot;&gt;XML version&lt;/a&gt; of the favorites structure, it's updated every hour, after the hourly scan, as are the other Weblogs.Com XML &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/xmldev&quot;&gt;files&lt;/a&gt;. With this info, other developers can do six-degrees type browsers that should be quite interesting. It's open, have fun!"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/wavs/asknot.wav&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/jfk.gif&quot; height=&quot;69&quot; width=&quot;52&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Press release: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thebrain.com/company/Press/press_march7_2000.html&quot;&gt;TheBrain.com Receives Patent on Graphical Interface for Linked Information&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;In recognition of the innovative and unique nature of TheBrain, the U.S. Patent Office awarded Patent No. 6,031,537.  The patent is the first issued of several filed by TheBrain.com.  Its issuance creates a significant barrier to entry for companies considering developing similar technology and solidifies TheBrain.com’s position as the leading provider of visual information environments.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://jim.roepcke.com/whybrainwhy&quot;&gt;Jim Roepcke&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I have been a customer of Natrificial for a couple of years now. I use The Brain just about every day. I am very disappointed that you intend to use your patents as a barrier to entry for other people who might create competing products.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Jim's comments are interesting, since he's a weblogger, I'm wondering if it would make sense to have an index relating weblogs to products they cover. I didn't know that Jim used The Brain. It would be interesting to get that bit of information recorded in a usable way in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/categories/Products%20I%20Use&quot;&gt;Category Browser&lt;/a&gt; in Weblogs.Com."/>
				<outline text="It might also be interesting to have a weblog that &quot;shadows&quot; each company that is active in patents. This would allow someone who wants the full story on the company to get it. The press release was three levels off the home page on the Natrificial site. Neither Amazon or Geoworks are advertising that Amazon is part-owner of Geoworks. On a shadow site this information would be easy to locate. "/>
				<outline text="There's more we can do than sign petitions and send emails. Information is key. Until this morning I thought that The Brain was a friendly product. "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://slashdot.org/askslashdot/98/10/24/1749257.shtml&quot;&gt;Ask Slashdot&lt;/a&gt;, 10/24/99: &quot;I am writing a Linux and PalmPilot clone of a Windows program (The Brain by Natrificial - www.thebrain.com). It has come to my attention that there are patents pending on 'all fundamental aspects of The Brain.' What exactly does this mean for me?&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inspiration.com/&quot;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://trumpet.sdsu.edu/semnet.html&quot;&gt;SemNet&lt;/a&gt; may be prior art for The Brain."/>
				<outline text="Newsweek: &lt;a href=&quot;http://newsweek.com/nw-srv/issue/11_00a/focus/ty/foty0211_1.htm&quot;&gt;The Great Amazon Patent Debate&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Yes, the law, as well as the prevailing corporate ethic, may be on the side of Jeff Bezos and his current course. But Amazon.com has become a globally known brand valued at $21 billion not because of exclusive technology but by its vision, its aggressive focus on customer service... and its embrace of the Internet, which offers an alternative ethic of sharing technology. Who better to break the mold of predatory patent litigation than its celebrated founder?&quot;"/>
				<outline text="In the true spirit of the Internet, Andrew Wooldridge proposes a short list of truly significant &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$15539&quot;&gt;web apps&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digpokemon.com/&quot;&gt;Pokemon League&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Toy's R Us in San Mateo joins the website today. They play on Saturdays from 9:30am to 11:30am.&quot; This site is being run by UserLand's Bob Bierman and his son Alex."/>
				<outline text="Blogger! Blogger! One of the new features the Blogger &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogger.com/images/mtb.gif&quot;&gt;folk&lt;/a&gt; have in the pipe is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogger.com/remote_editing.pyra&quot;&gt;Remote Editing&lt;/a&gt;. I'm not quite sure what it is, but after some more coffee I'll give it a whirl on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geocities.com/davewiner/&quot;&gt;my Blogger site&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="And, congrats to the Blogger team, esp designer Derek Powazek, for a great redesign of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogger.com/home.pyra&quot;&gt;Blogger site&lt;/a&gt;. They've raised the bar on sites for managing Weblogs. As always, an inspiration!"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/stats/findinweblogs?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.blogger.com%2Fremote_editing.pyra&quot;&gt;Weblogs pointing&lt;/a&gt; to the new remote editing page on Blogger."/>
				<outline text="Late last night I did a &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/asknot.gif&quot;&gt;redesign&lt;/a&gt; myself. James T. Kirk &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/wavs/spaceTheFinalFrontier.wav&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; once again, &quot;To boldly go where no man has gone before.&quot; Jeff Bezos's eyes loom over the landscape. Dorothy is nearby &lt;a href=&quot;http://lynx.neu.edu/home/httpd/j/jforman/oz/toto.wav&quot;&gt;saying&lt;/a&gt; &quot;Toto, I have a feeling we're not in Kansas anymore.&quot; My heroes, Mr Ed, Mahatma Gandhi and the Spicy Noodles get ready to defend the honor of the Internet. The Zeldman icons assemble. Mark Cuban reclines, in faux relaxation, not knowing what to do with himself after sucking billions out of the Internet. And Stewart Alsop grins, beneath the shadow of George Bush the Elder, on behalf of all the VCs who seek non-volatile competitive advantages through the legal system."/>
				<outline text="NY Times: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/library/tech/00/03/biztech/articles/11patent.html&quot;&gt;Chairman of Amazon Urges Reduction of Patent Terms&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;At the least, Mr. Zittrain said, Mr. Bezos is trying to make the best of a possible image problem. 'He took a P.R. problem and turned it into a P.R. opportunity,' he said.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://weblogs.userland.com/qube/2000/03/11&quot;&gt;Luke Tymowski&lt;/a&gt; says it very well. &quot;If [Amazon] really respected what Tim had to say, they would say they're not enforcing their patents, apologise for taking advantage of a wacked out PTO, and work publicly to get rid of software patents. Instead they blame the PTO for the mess, and refuse to let go of their half-witted patents.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Like many others I am watching &lt;a href=&quot;http://watchthisspace.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;this space&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://stewart.weblogger.com/&quot;&gt;Stewart Himself&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I say 'shouting in the dark' on my banner because I’m not sure there is anybody out there listening. So right now that’s what this site is like. But hopefully if I just keep shouting into the darkness, some passersby will stop, maybe even have similar interests and wish to join the discussion — join the shouting.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Press release: &lt;a href=&quot;http://biz.yahoo.com/bw/000310/ct_netmark_1.html&quot;&gt;Netmarket Group Inc. Issued U.S. Patent for Hagglezone E-Commerce System&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Hosts start off the bidding process close to the manufacturer's suggested retail price, but the consumer can offer any price they want. The Host instantly responds to their offer with a new price -- sometimes the Hosts accept the first low-ball offer. Shoppers can always get better deals by honing their haggle skills through repeat visits.&quot;"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 10" created="Fri, 10 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="DaveNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/2000/03/10/speakingOfTheCluetrain&quot;&gt;Speaking of the Cluetrain&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Doc Searls: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.linuxjournal.com/articles/misc/014.html&quot;&gt;Talking Patents&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;I hate them, but we all have to start talking about them, because our world is being mined at an accelerating pace.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/stories/storyReader$457&quot;&gt;Where we're at with patents&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;The not yet published innovations we developed in 1999 and 2000 are as unobvious as outlining was in the early 80s. They are quite patentable, imho, and they will be valuable patents.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="PC Week: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.com/pcweek/stories/news/0,4153,2459280,00.html&quot;&gt;Hype aside, WAP has worries&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;The Geoworks issue seems to have the WAP Forum worried. One new member said a recent forum meeting in Rome was crowded with lawyers who whispered to forum executives every time the conversation got contentious.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="2/16/99: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geoworks.com/corporate/news/pr_amazon.html&quot;&gt;Amazon.Com Purchases Minority Stake in Geoworks&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Amazon.com has invested $5 million in Geoworks common stock, representing approximately a seven percent interest in the company.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mp3.com/news/159.html&quot;&gt;SightSound.Com&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The royalty rate for the License is one percent of the total price charged to customers per transaction for the download sale of music or other audio recordings.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="3/31-4/1 in Boston: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geekpride.org/about/index.html&quot;&gt;Geek Pride Festival&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Go figure. Go geek!&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Steve Yost wants to start a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.halfbakery.com/idea/Charity_20Banner_20Portal&quot;&gt;Charity Banner Portal&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$15504&quot;&gt;Jacob Levy&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;In a previous life, I was part of a team that was trying to get VC money to do a start-up. The VCs made a big deal about having a 'non-volatile competitive&amp;nbsp;advantage' in what we were doing, to assure that we would have the prospective market to ourselves.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Yesterday Mike Murry had &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vkamedia.com/amazon.jpg&quot;&gt;trouble&lt;/a&gt; reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.remarq.com/amazon/transcript.asp?g=discuss%2Eamazon%2Ehelp%2Eus%2Ebuild%2Ethis%2Eservice&amp;tn=656&amp;sh=0145dfffc1891b43&amp;idx=-1&quot;&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt; in response to Jeff Bezos's open letter. &lt;i&gt;Me too, works now.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="NPR's &lt;a href=&quot;http://search.npr.org/cf/cmn/cmnps05fm.cfm?SegID=71224&quot;&gt;Elaine Korry reports&lt;/a&gt; that the &quot;online retailer Amazon.com recently received a patent on sales links between webpages. If enforced, Amazon would be able collect royalties from online companies that refer sales from one website to another.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mercurycenter.com/svtech/columns/gillmor/docs/dg031000.htm&quot;&gt;Dan Gillmor&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Later Thursday, in a phone interview, [Bezos] defended Amazon's actions and amplified on his patent aims.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inessential.com/sheila/2000/03/10&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/spaceNeedle.gif&quot; height=&quot;57&quot; width=&quot;27&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Inc: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inc.com/articles/details/0,3532,ART16854_CNT53,00.html&quot;&gt;What Business Is Amazon.com Really In?&lt;/a&gt; &quot;It's unprofitable, of course, but that's just the superficial answer. The tsunami of red ink, founder and CEO Jeff Bezos has long maintained, is part of the plan. On to the deeper question, then: What on earth is the plan?&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Irish Times: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ireland.com/newspaper/finance/2000/0303/seven9.htm&quot;&gt;Loss-making Amazon turns to bullying&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;As the Web grows almost grotesquely commercial, harking back to the community-mindedness that built the Web is at the very least, quixotically admirable. But don't underestimate the power of community.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="I found out about the Irish Times editorial from its author &lt;a href=&quot;http://indigo.ie/~karlin/kjbio.htm&quot;&gt;Karlin Lillington&lt;/a&gt; who sent me a response she received from Amazon PR, which explains a lot. Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/billCurryToKarlinLilington.gif&quot;&gt;screen shot&lt;/a&gt; of the email."/>
				<outline text="This email has lessons for lots of people. First to the PR guy at Amazon, Bill Curry, this is not a positive way to deal with the press! Second, to Tim O'Reilly who is cited as supporting Amazon, please consider what you're supporting. "/>
				<outline text="And to all of us who are subject to criticism, even ridicule, myself included, it comes with the territory. As Jean-Louis Gassee used to say, maybe he still does, &quot;As the monkey climbs the tree, more people can see his bottom.&quot; "/>
				<outline text="Late in the day, apologies from &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/apologyFromBezos.gif&quot;&gt;Jeff Bezos&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/apologyFromCurry.gif&quot;&gt;Bill Curry&lt;/a&gt; to Karlin Lillington."/>
				<outline text="Representing the other school of thought, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.topica.com/lists/egr/read/message.html?mid=2000766728&amp;sort=d&amp;start=30&quot;&gt;Christopher Locke&lt;/a&gt;, one of the Cluetrain authors, mentions the Bezos-O'Reilly public posts as evidence of their clued-in-ness. But Chris, how would you feel if the art you practiced were subject to the kinds of nonsense rules the USPTO is trying to foist on software developers? Could you have published Cluetrain if Tom Peters had the patent on books that help businesses use technology?"/>
				<outline text="Here's where the Cluetrain guys can get a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rhinotechnologies.com/fun/clue.html&quot;&gt;clue&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.katiesoft.com/111599rel.html&quot;&gt;Katiesoft&lt;/a&gt; &quot;provides partners and portals a super sticky Internet opportunity, backed by patent protected features no one can imitate.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;i&gt;To Scripting News readers, please send me pointers to companies who openly use patents to limit competition.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="Another thing to worry about. There's a two year gestation for patents. A harrowing question raised by the Sun people I met with on Wednesday, has Microsoft filed a patent application on XML-RPC technology? Since Microsoft cites me as a supporter of their work, I must find a way to ask this question without provoking the &quot;You Don't Love Us&quot; response from Microsoft."/>
				<outline text="&lt;i&gt;11:20PM: It's been a remarkable and exhausting day. We did actually ship some new technology today, but I'll wait to explain that until tomorrow. &lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&quot;brain&quot;"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 9" created="Thu, 09 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="DaveNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/2000/03/09/nextWeekAtEsthers&quot;&gt;Next week at Esther's&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="UserLand.Com members: &lt;a href=&quot;http://surveys.userland.com/surveys/run/dave@userland.com/howHighIsTheSky003&quot;&gt;Will you buy from Amazon?&lt;/a&gt;"/>
				<outline text="Amazon.com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/subst/misc/patents.html/103-2339245-5500629&quot;&gt;An Open Letter from Jeff Bezos&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;I also strongly doubt whether our giving up our patents would really, in the end, provide much of a stepping stone to solving the bigger problem.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.cnet.com/news/0-1007-200-1568486.html&quot;&gt;Amazon CEO calls for patent reform&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Amazon's patents have raised the ire of Net advocates because the features the patents would protect have been widely adopted by other companies. Many advocates argue that the features are not only obvious, but Amazon's enforcement of patents for them could harm Net commerce.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="AP: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usatoday.com/life/cyber/tech/cth529.htm&quot;&gt;Amazon moves to stem patent uproar&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oreilly.com/ask_tim/patent_reform_0300.html&quot;&gt;Tim O'Reilly comments&lt;/a&gt; on the Bezos letter. &quot;One thing about a call for action in Washington is that it could be seen as just a way of shifting the focus away from Amazon and onto the PTO.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/stories/storyReader$455&quot;&gt;An open letter&lt;/a&gt; to Doc Searls."/>
				<outline text="I got positive emails from Doc and Tim on the Tuesday night patent discussion at Esther's, so I sent an email to Kevin saying let's go ahead. If you're going to be in Phoenix next week, let's get together and talk. I probably will ask the question at the Web Applications panel as well. &quot;Do any of you guys have patents we should know about?&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://brdbrain.editthispage.com/2000/03/09&quot;&gt;Kate Adams&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I sent Amazon a brief e-mail this morning saying I'm staying away until I either believe in the patent or some other positive outcome is reached.&quot; "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/stats/findinweblogs?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2Fexec%2Fobidos%2Fsubst%2Fmisc%2Fpatents.html&quot;&gt;Weblogs&lt;/a&gt; that point to the Bezos essay."/>
				<outline text="Steve Yost: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.takeitoffline.com/xmlrpc.html&quot;&gt;Take It Offline XML-RPC Interface&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Take It Offline is written in Perl and lives on a Solaris box. Connected XML-RPC clients include one in San Francisco using VBScript on NT, and another in Paris using Perl on Linux.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Today's new feature for &quot;Weblogs.Com&quot; is the Recently Updated Weblogs panel on the home page. It shows your favorite weblogs in the order they were last udpated. To add a log to your favorites, click on its checkbox, then click on the Favorite button. &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/weblogsComFavoritesFeature.gif&quot;&gt;Screen shot&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/news/politics/0,1283,34830,00.html&quot;&gt;Wired&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Arizona's online voting experiment may have started smoothly, but it's becoming a bumpy ride.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="My.UserLand.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://my.userland.com/viewChannel$1765&quot;&gt;Iraqi News Update&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="USA Today: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usatoday.com/money/bcovthu.htm&quot;&gt;Could Linux outdo Windows?&lt;/a&gt; &quot;What makes Linux different is that it's part of the Internet culture. It's essentially being built by a community,&quot; says Irving Wladawsky-Berger, a general manager at IBM, who is heading the Linux movement there."/>
				<outline text="March 25: &lt;a href=&quot;http://march25.editthispage.com/discuss/msgReader$145&quot;&gt;Call for templates&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;We're getting ready to open another server for free Manila hosting. In reviewing the site, I was asked if there was anything I wanted to change in the initial starter site we create.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="MSNBC: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/379409.asp&quot;&gt;The rise and fall of Netscape&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;If there’s a cautionary tale here, it is that you can’t take a dying project, sprinkle it with the magic pixie dust of 'open source,' and have everything magically work out,&quot; Zawinski wrote. &quot;Software is hard. The issues aren’t that simple.&quot; "/>
				<outline text="Ken MacLeod: &lt;a href=&quot;http://LWProtocols.org/DWhite.html&quot;&gt;Distributed Whiteboard API&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oreilly.com/ask_tim/&quot;&gt;Tim O'Reilly responds&lt;/a&gt; to Amazon patent questions."/>
				<outline text="Yesterday at a meeting at Sun I heard a harrowing tale about the Microsoft CSS patent, and a patent that IBM owns for calendars displayed on computer screens. For now, it seems that patents are tools that big companies use to squeeze millions of dollars out of other big companies. But big companies use their weight to crush little companies too. Some users ask why they should care. Well, do you want to get all your software (web apps too) from big companies like Microsoft, Sun and IBM? If you do, stay ambivalent about patents. You'll eventually get your wish."/>
				<outline text="Another thing big companies do is tell harrowing tales to CEOs of small companies. I'm well-practiced at receiving these stories. I tell them my story about buying a sailboat and cruising the Mediterranean, perhaps stopping off to work on pottery every once in a while. "/>
				<outline text="More data from the Sun meeting. Unbeknownst to me, part of Sun has embraced &quot;XML-RPC&quot;. Unless corporate FUD kicks in, there will be a new server that will make some Frontier users quite happy! (And some Sun users too.)"/>
				<outline text="Attention please: &lt;a href=&quot;http://home.att.net/~cecw/lastpage.htm&quot;&gt;The Last Page of the Internet&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&quot;james kirk&quot; "/>
				<outline text="&lt;i&gt;&quot;Enjoy the rest of your life.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 8" created="Wed, 08 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theregister.co.uk/000308-000005.html&quot;&gt;The Register&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Could it be that we are seeing a new facet of Microsoft, that there is the realisation that if you have the expertise, you do not have to use the dirty tricks?&quot; "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://bitsko.slc.ut.us/~ken/xml-rpc/&quot;&gt;Ken MacLeod&lt;/a&gt; has an experimental implementation of SOAP for Perl. The readme is &lt;a href=&quot;http://bitsko.slc.ut.us/~ken/xml-rpc/SOAP-RPC-0.00.readme&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.megnut.com/&quot;&gt;Megnut&lt;/a&gt; says she may leave California. And then &lt;a href=&quot;http://array.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;Garret&lt;/a&gt; says they're bringing cheap DSL to Santa Fe. Then I had this idea, let's start a Web commune in Santa Fe, great air, beautiful country, skiing, it's cheap, and they don't have stupid people who want to prevent other people from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?file=/chronicle/archive/2000/03/08/MN12290.DTL&amp;type=election&quot;&gt;marrying&lt;/a&gt; each other. How childish."/>
				<outline text="There are &lt;a href=&quot;http://array.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;Frontier&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.santafe.edu/&quot;&gt;developers&lt;/a&gt; in Santa Fe. Should we have a bootcamp, Web Commune, Manilapalooza in Santa Fe this summer?"/>
				<outline text="In response to user feedback we have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.editthispage.com/stories/storyReader$56&quot;&gt;revised&lt;/a&gt; the last paragraph of the agreement for EditThisPage.Com members."/>
				<outline text="E&amp;P: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mediainfo.com/ephome/news/newshtm/stop/st030800.htm&quot;&gt;Weblogs, From Underground to Mainstream&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Slow corporatization of the concept will probably be fine with many of the thousands of independent Webloggers who pioneered the concept. Romenesko says as Weblogging becomes more widespread among corporations, there's likely to be some resentment from the pioneers who see it as an anti-corporate concept.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="FWIW, I think he's got it backwards. Weblogs may become corporate tools, but they're also Trojan Horses. Once a corporation becomes weblog-aware, it stops behaving so much like a corporation and more like part of the Web, where ideas are shared and linked to, even (perish the thought) across corporate boundaries. "/>
				<outline text="New feature on &quot;Weblogs.Com&quot; this morning. Now there are Yahoo-style checkboxes on each item and buttons that do stuff with the checked items. Not everything is wired in yet. Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/checkboxesWeblogsCom.gif&quot;&gt;graphic&lt;/a&gt; that explains what's going on."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flashforward2000.com/html/HTML/about.html&quot;&gt;flashforward2000&lt;/a&gt; conference, March 27-29 in SF."/>
				<outline text="New site: &lt;a href=&quot;http://patents.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;Patents.EditThisPage.Com&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="The XML-DEV list is not working properly. Most of my posts yesterday are not in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://xml.org/archives/xml-dev/date1.html&quot;&gt;archive&lt;/a&gt;. They didn't come in email either. If you're on the list and wondering where my posts have been going, I have been wondering about that too. "/>
				<outline text="There are lots of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.topica.com/create/&quot;&gt;free&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.egroups.com/&quot;&gt;reliable&lt;/a&gt; listserves. They're fast too, eGroups takes less than a minute to distribute an email, which makes a difference in how much work you can do in a day. "/>
				<outline text="WSJ: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/379283.asp&quot;&gt;Simon &amp; Schuster to release story by Stephen King on the Web only&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;The book, a 66-page ghost story titled 'Riding the Bullet,' is one of the first examples of a best-selling author creating a work purely for electronic download. Consumers will be able to buy the book for $2.50 through Web sites run by e-book manufacturers as well as online booksellers such as Amazon.com.&quot; Of course I'll buy this, but I won't buy it at Amazon, unless they &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/asknot.gif&quot;&gt;wise up&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="NY Times editorial: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/yr/mo/day/editorial/08wed1.html&quot;&gt;A Decisive Day for Front-Runners&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;When he was attacked unfairly by the religious right in South Carolina, Mr. McCain returned the fire. That decision to counterattack now looks like a costly tactical mistake that damaged the aura of his campaign, revived old worries about his temperament and unsettled many mainstream Republicans.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="I created thumbs of our two presidential candidates, but decided that the &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/presidentialCandidate1.gif&quot;&gt;pictures&lt;/a&gt; without their &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/presidentialCandidate2.gif&quot;&gt;faces&lt;/a&gt; were more interesting."/>
				<outline text="What got me interested in the candidates' pictures was this &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/goreGrimace.jpg&quot;&gt;picture&lt;/a&gt; on the home page of MSNBC showing Gore making a sincere grimace, which looks like an imitation of the sincere grimace that Bill Clinton uses. I'd love to get a peek behind the scenes, how did they teach Gore to do this? The American people are going to love it. Did it require surgery?"/>
				<outline text="Of course it did not require surgery to get George W. Bush to look like his &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/georgeBush1.gif&quot;&gt;father&lt;/a&gt;, but that may not be good tactics! Will they call him &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tarpley.net/bush5.htm&quot;&gt;Poppy&lt;/a&gt; too??"/>
				<outline text="Survey: &lt;a href=&quot;http://surveys.userland.com/surveys/run/dave@userland.com/isBushDisgusting&quot;&gt;Is Bush disgusting?&lt;/a&gt;"/>
				<outline text="NetDyslexia: &lt;a href=&quot;http://netdyslexia.editthispage.com/stories/storyReader$372&quot;&gt;Same Horse, Another Photo&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$439&quot;&gt;Asparagus&lt;/a&gt; in spicy garlic sauce. &lt;i&gt;(Hot!)&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 7" created="Tue, 07 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="NY Times: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/library/politics/camp/030800wh-elect.html&quot;&gt;A Sweep by Gore Assures Nomination; Big Lead for Bush in G.O.P. Delegates&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Al Gore crushed Bill Bradley in state after state tonight, assuring the vice president the Democratic presidential nomination, while Gov. George W. Bush piled up far more Republican delegates than Senator John McCain.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Salon: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salon.com/health/feature/2000/03/07/genetic_test/index.html&quot;&gt;Who Owns Your DNA?&lt;/a&gt; &quot;Genetic research that can save lives is often stymied by biotech companies' greedy patent claims.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Some people may consider this bug a feature. I have not been able to post to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://xml.org/archives/xml-dev/&quot;&gt;XML-DEV&lt;/a&gt; list today, I've tried twice, but haven't gotten through. Here's what I &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/stories/storyReader$451&quot;&gt;wanted to say&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$15439&quot;&gt;Nick Sweeney raised&lt;/a&gt; the issue of Amazon's patents with Amazon's president on CNBC today."/>
				<outline text="The UK now has a free Manila &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qwe.as/&quot;&gt;hosting service&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xmlmag.com/upload/free/features/xml/2000/02spr00/evspr00/ev1spr00.asp&quot;&gt;XML Magazine interviews&lt;/a&gt; Microsoft's John Montgomery on SOAP. &quot;There's nothing hidden here; there are no tricks. But judging by that reaction, Sun was scared. They're realizing that once you have standard XML on the wire, their lock-in that they're trying to get with Java goes away.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="I just realized something about Microsoft. To most people, including people at Microsoft, you're either anti-Microsoft or pro-Microsoft. Then thinking about it some more, this isn't just true of Microsoft. It's also true of Apple. And it's also true of Linux. And Open Source. And it's not just about computers either. It's pretty much everywhere. And it's total bullshit."/>
				<outline text="I re-ran the log &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/logAnalysis/subhonker1/experiment2/domains.html&quot;&gt;analyzer&lt;/a&gt; on yesterday's traffic on Subhonker1. 95550 page reads, of which 74320 were non-members."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://blackholebrain.editthispage.com/stories/storyReader$135&quot;&gt;blackholebrain&lt;/a&gt; says about people watching this site, &quot;We are all like greasy mechanics standing around a humming, hot-rodded v-8 engine: hood up and breathing in the fumes saying WOW! YEAH! COOL! And hey, that is cool! But to the non-mechanic we are engine geeks! Crazed and emphatic engine geeks.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="This is so true. I've been trying to figure out what the Scripting News for Manila users will be. I'm not the author of that site. Already running at 80,000 miles per hour. If possible, I want to slow down. The real rumbling engine is over on EditThisPage.Com. I figure the next step is teamwork, mergers between logs, or new logs that are edited by groups of authors. We want to make the technology to support this activity, and that's what Scripting News must stay focused on, the technology."/>
				<outline text="There's now a &lt;a href=&quot;http://winerlog.editthispage.com/stories/storyReader$12&quot;&gt;Scripting News Drinking Game&lt;/a&gt; for people going to SXSW. I wonder if Dan Gillmor is going? Did you know that Dan has a Manila &lt;a href=&quot;http://weblog.mercurycenter.com/ejournal/&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt;? Hey check this &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$422&quot;&gt;out&lt;/a&gt;. Yesterday I heard that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.accel.com/team/mkapor.html&quot;&gt;Mitch Kapor&lt;/a&gt; is on the board of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eazel.com/&quot;&gt;Eazel&lt;/a&gt;, the company started by Mike Boich and Andy Hertzfeld. They're doing Open Source software. &lt;i&gt;Excellent!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.evhead.com/&quot;&gt;Evan Williams&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;If you or anyone you know has office space in SF you'd like to rent/share with a few Pyradicals, even short term, please let me know. Thanks&quot;"/>
				<outline text="News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.cnet.com/news/0-1005-200-1565468.html&quot;&gt;Researchers work to eradicate broken hyperlinks&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;If a document's URL changes, a search engine could be employed to automatically locate the missing page.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="MSNBC: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/378107.asp&quot;&gt;Bradley, McCain hope for upsets&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Voters from Maine to California are casting their ballots in a decisive day for presidential campaigns. More than half the delegates needed to win the Republican and Democratic nominations will be decided, and polls show Democrat Al Gore and Republican George W. Bush far ahead in nearly every race.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="My.UserLand.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://my.userland.com/viewChannel$1754&quot;&gt;The FreeBSD Diary&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$437&quot;&gt;Beef&lt;/a&gt;, pork, seafood, poultry, rice or spicy noodles?"/>
				<outline text="There are now four sites in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/categories/Dogma2000/&quot;&gt;Dogma 2000&lt;/a&gt; category on Weblogs.Com. Even so, there are ten sites in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/categories/general&quot;&gt;General&lt;/a&gt; category."/>
				<outline text="Reuters: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dailynews.yahoo.com/h/nm/20000307/wr/tech_networksolutions_2.html&quot;&gt;VeriSign to Buy Network Solutions for $21 Billion&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Network Solutions, or NSI, is the company that operates the master directory for the Internet. When a piece of software, like your web browser, wants to find out where given machine is, it sends over a string like &quot;www.news.com&quot; and it returns back an address, like &quot;204.162.80.142&quot;. VeriSign makes software that authenticates documents, making sure you know who created it and when it was last modified. This is an important bit of technology if you want to do legal transactions using the Internet. I want to be able to prove that you signed a contract, and exactly what the contract said when you signed it, without having to print it on paper."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$15437&quot;&gt;Jacob Levy&lt;/a&gt; is having a problem with NSI."/>
				<outline text="PC Week: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.com/pcweek/stories/news/0,4153,2456140,00.html&quot;&gt;AMD first to ship 1GHz processor&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.circleoflearning.com/col/aboutcol.asp&quot;&gt;Circle of Learning&lt;/a&gt; is a &quot;free, online, open-source university, a center of story-telling, a community of people over the age of 50 learning, communicating, writing about their passions and sharing their opinions with an equal passion.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://montananewsdaily.editthispage.com/2000/03/07&quot;&gt;Montana News Daily&lt;/a&gt; reports on a cat wreaking havoc with dogs and birds in downtown Bozeman, including a picture of the cat."/>
				<outline text="Jon Udell: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.byte.com/column/BYT20000302S0010&quot;&gt;The Future Of The Programmable Browser&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;In principle, XUL looks like a good approach to enabling regular HTML-literate folks (rather than GUI programmers) to create more powerful Web-top interfaces.&quot;"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 6" created="Mon, 06 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Steve Litt: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.troubleshooters.com/tpromag/199911/199911.htm&quot;&gt;Outlines, The Do Everything Tool&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Don Box: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xmlrpc.com/discuss/msgReader$744&quot;&gt;XML-RPC to SOAP Translator&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Woo-Hoo!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="I just found out that there's an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xmlrpc.com/discuss/msgReader$743&quot;&gt;Apache module&lt;/a&gt; for XML-RPC. How is it being used?"/>
				<outline text="More data from log analysis. Last Friday 73,025 out 95,009 page reads on Subhonker1 were not members of the site they were reading. This means they were reading, not writing. "/>
				<outline text="George W. Bush has something he'd like to &lt;a href=&quot;http://brunching.com/cgi/gwb-gif.cgi?saying=If%20you%20want%20me%20to%20like%20you%20buy%20my%20pizza!&quot;&gt;say to you&lt;/a&gt; this evening."/>
				<outline text="RCFoC: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.compaq.com/rcfoc/20000306.html&quot;&gt;Our Wireless, Wireless World&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Fortune: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fortune.com/fortune/2000/03/20/eth.html&quot;&gt;New Ethics, or No Ethics?&lt;/a&gt;"/>
				<outline text="WebReference: &lt;a href=&quot;http://webreference.com/xml/column7/&quot;&gt;RSS Viewer Applet&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="osOpinion: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.osopinion.com/Opinions/Guy/Guy1.html&quot;&gt;Microsoft Owns the Web&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Netscape's poorly-implemented, non-standard features lost out to Microsoft's poorly-implemented, non-standard features.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://march25.editthispage.com/discuss/msgReader$80&quot;&gt;March 25&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I want to be able to use elements from community sites in my site. I'd like to be able to connect to the shortcuts table in any site, grab a bit of HTML and have it included in my page. Like NetDyslexia's horse. Or the Zeldman icons. Or James Kirk, the newest addition to the global shortcuts.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Important: I want to &lt;a href=&quot;http://march25.editthispage.com/discuss/msgReader$95&quot;&gt;audio webcast&lt;/a&gt; the March 25 meeting."/>
				<outline text="My.UserLand.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://my.userland.com/viewChannel$1752&quot;&gt;JavaScript Tip of the Day&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Meeting with Jeff Cheney on Saturday was a good thing! I learned that he thought that Pike would not run on the Mac. Not true. Pike will run on the Mac, and will have all the features of Pike for Windows. We punted on browser integration in 1.0. It's difficult for C programs on Windows to do in-app HTML rendering. There's no sample code, and we're running out of time for 1.0. Sorry, I wish it weren't so, because when it happens it will be a killer feature. You'll feel like you're in a browser, but it actually will be an editing and scripting environment with a built-in HTTP server. In 1.0, you'll get all the functionality, but no illusion of being in a browser. There will be a layer switch on both platforms. "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.userfriendly.org/cartoons/archives/00mar/20000305.html&quot;&gt;User Friendly offers&lt;/a&gt; &quot;tough love&quot; for Amazon. &lt;i&gt;Hi Jeff!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="More &quot;tough love&quot; for Jeff Bezos from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.com/pcweek/filters/kattstrip/&quot;&gt;Spencer F. Katt&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fortune.com/fortune/technology/alsop/1999/04/26/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/alsop.gif&quot; height=&quot;52&quot; width=&quot;39&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;5&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fortune.com/fortune/technology/alsop/1999/04/26/index.html&quot;&gt;Stewart Alsop&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I proposed that if we believe that we citizens of the U.S. can't control or regulate Microsoft's behavior as a monopoly, then let's withdraw government protection of the intellectual property making that monopoly possible.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Yesterday's Manila feature addition, &lt;a href=&quot;http://weblogs.userland.com/manilaNewbies/discuss/msgReader$2333&quot;&gt;easy entering&lt;/a&gt; of relative paths, is just the tip of the iceberg of the next Thrilla. The pipe is filling up again! Here we go."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://newsweek.com/nw-srv/issue/17_99b/printed/us/na/chap2_9_1.htm&quot;&gt;Newsweek&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Muhammad Ali says his greatest bout was the Thrilla in Manila. But his whole life has been one great fight.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://inessential.com/&quot;&gt;Brent Simmons&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;We're working on something very cool right now. Grown men will faint. Women will weep. Children will look up from their TV sets. Cats will talk. Squirrels will ride motorcycles. Dogs will invent a new calculus. Roller coasters will run in reverse. Stars will move in closer to the Earth.&quot; "/>
				<outline text="&quot;James Kirk&quot;"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 5" created="Sun, 05 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Manila's new &lt;a href=&quot;http://weblogs.userland.com/manilaNewbies/discuss/msgReader$2333&quot;&gt;Set Relative Path&lt;/a&gt; feature allows you to set the site structure path from the Admin box that appears at the bottom of discussion group pages."/>
				<outline text="Jakob Nielsen: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.useit.com/alertbox/20000305.html&quot;&gt;Profit Maximization vs. User Loyalty&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://march25.editthispage.com/discuss/msgReader$66&quot;&gt;My experience with open source&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I wanted to shake him. Listen to my words dude, I did it, and you can't even hear me.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="NetDyslexia &lt;a href=&quot;http://netdyslexia.editthispage.com/stories/storyReader$345&quot;&gt;explains&lt;/a&gt; why their horse can't talk. Why would he want to? &lt;i&gt;No one listens!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://march25.editthispage.com/discuss/msgReader$70&quot;&gt;Eric Kidd offers&lt;/a&gt; &quot;tough love&quot; for MacBird."/>
				<outline text="I updated the &quot;MacBird&quot; home page in response to private feedback from Eric. Now it better explains why it's unique, and how I feel about it and what it can do for non-Mac platforms. "/>
				<outline text="Also note that Steve Zellers has &lt;a href=&quot;http://macbird.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$44&quot;&gt;checked in the source&lt;/a&gt; to a CVS, &lt;a href=&quot;http://sourceforge.net/cvs/?group_id=1101&quot;&gt;SourceForge&lt;/a&gt;, and has asked us a fair question that we will respond to."/>
				<outline text="Log analysis for Subhonker1 for Friday. Two reports, one ranking &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/logAnalysis/subhonker1/experiment/browsers.html&quot;&gt;browsers&lt;/a&gt;, another ranking &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/logAnalysis/subhonker1/experiment/domains.html&quot;&gt;domains&lt;/a&gt;. Subhonker1 hosts Manila sites only, EditThisPage.Com and others. 95,000 page reads. "/>
				<outline text="On the Weblogs mail list, Jorn Barger &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.egroups.com/group/weblogs/1230.html?&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;"/>
				<outline text="US culture for men is very much about pretending to be a football-fan kind of guy, and if you get caught in a more tender-hearted enthusiasm you may never hear the end of it.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="That &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1998/01/01/menStaySilent&quot;&gt;reminds&lt;/a&gt; me: &quot;A lot of men, including me, don't feel as if we have permission to speak our truth, to say what we see. The barriers seem to be everywhere.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/wavs/misterEd.wav&quot; title=&quot;Hello! I am Mister Ed.&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/misterEd.gif&quot; height=&quot;74&quot; width=&quot;45&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;5&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/stories/storyReader$448&quot;&gt;Cafe Boronne&lt;/a&gt; in Menlo Park is a European type hangout place smack in the middle of Silicon Valley. Next door to one of our best bookstores, Kepler's. A block away from Be's headquarters."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ci.menlo-park.ca.us/history.htm&quot;&gt;History of Menlo Park&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;When the railroad came through in 1863, this station had no name, it was just the end of the line, but it needed a designation.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.egroups.com/group/xml-rpc/696.html?&quot;&gt;Cross-post&lt;/a&gt; on the SOAP and XML-RPC mail lists. &quot;Then the picture all of a sudden becomes clear. Oooops. We got left behind somehow.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$15405&quot;&gt;The idled workaholic&lt;/a&gt; discussion. What if you had been working all your life to get rich, and then you were? What would you do?"/>
				<outline text="Michael Swaine: &lt;a href=&quot;http://webreview.com/pub/2000/03/03/frames/index.html&quot;&gt;More Patent Nonsense&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Since I benefit from that program, I have a moral dilemma to face, or at least I will if Amazon starts suing people over the affiliates patent. I hate moral dilemmas. Sigh.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Get over it.&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/library/magazine/home/20000305mag-workaholic.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/marcCubanThumb.gif&quot; height=&quot;36&quot; width=&quot;32&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Money must be in the air today. On the March 25 site, &lt;a href=&quot;http://march25.editthispage.com/discuss/msgReader$65&quot;&gt;Fredrik Lundh asks&lt;/a&gt; &quot;Is it just me, or does this 'we're making lots of money so you gotta give us your stuff for free' argument feel a little strange?&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Jacob Savin sent me a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.unc.edu/~davemc/Pic/Escher/puddle.jpg&quot;&gt;pointer&lt;/a&gt; to an Escher print that's like my sky in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$429&quot;&gt;puddle&lt;/a&gt; picture."/>
				<outline text="Another sky in the puddle &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$441&quot;&gt;picture&lt;/a&gt;, only it's the light of my camera's flash reflecting off fat in Won Ton Soup. It looks like there's something fibrous on the surface of the soup. I had to look twice to figure out what I was seeing."/>
				<outline text="&quot;spicy noodles&quot;"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 4" created="Sat, 04 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/stories/storyReader$445&quot;&gt;It's a spicy&lt;/a&gt; noodles kind of day."/>
				<outline text="April 6 in SF: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mozilla.org/party/2000/flyer.html&quot;&gt;mozilla.party&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://dave.editthispage.com/linksForW3CIETF&quot;&gt;Links for W3C and IETF people&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I promised to put together a page of links of background information on what we're doing at UserLand to build the Two-Way-Web, for people in W3C and IETF who are getting to know us.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Sun's Michael Condry will host a &lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.w3.org/Archives/Public/xml-dist-app/2000Mar/0000.html&quot;&gt;B2BXML BOF&lt;/a&gt; at IETF in Adelaide. &lt;i&gt;5 acronyms&lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1997/06/17/ILoveAcronyms&quot;&gt;!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://lwprotocols.org/&quot;&gt;LWProtocols.org&lt;/a&gt; is a &quot;clearinghouse for information about distributed computing architectures that are more structured than telnet command protocols or CGIs but less complex or heavy than CORBA or DCOM.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Dan Gillmor: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mercurycenter.com/premium/business/docs/gillmor04.htm&quot;&gt;President gives online privacy some perspective&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Wow. I'm totally glad that former Suck guy &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.suck.com/fish/contributors/knauss/bio.html&quot;&gt;Greg Knauss&lt;/a&gt; has an EditThisPage.Com &lt;a href=&quot;http://winerlog.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Sarcastic!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.suck.com/daily/96/01/12/daily.html&quot;&gt;Suck&lt;/a&gt; parody of &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1996/01/08/gottabearetha&quot;&gt;DaveNet&lt;/a&gt; from January 1996."/>
				<outline text="Eric Soroos: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wiredfool.com/stories/storyReader$93&quot;&gt;Amazon's Net Patents&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Amazon.com has lots of minority shareholders, and their stock has been falling. In today's legal climate, there's a significant possibly that they will have to defend against minority shareholder lawsuits.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=00/03/04/0910226&quot;&gt;Slashdot discusses&lt;/a&gt; last night's O'Reilly post."/>
				<outline text="Two other angles on the Amazon patent situation. First, a common theme, since Amazon loses money on every sale, boycotting them helps them. (Somehow I think that's too linear for today's economy.) A second angle. If you think standardized Web user interfaces are coming, as I do, Amazon may be digging themselves into a hole. Notice that the other booksellers are reverting to the shopping basket metaphor. Unless the market wholly coalesces around Amazon, they may end up switching to shopping baskets themselves at some point, if the Web is like computers, and if UI standardization catches on as it did with the Mac in the early-mid 80s."/>
				<outline text="The benefit of UI standardization was that users could use more than one app, a concept that, when translated to the Web, means a user can use more than one Web site. Today's Web has more in common with Hypercard stacks than it does with desktop apps, but the idea of Web applications is still pretty new."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$432&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/simonStLaurent.gif&quot; height=&quot;27&quot; width=&quot;30&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Pictures from XTech on Thursday. &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$433&quot;&gt;Peter Murray-Rust&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$432&quot;&gt;Simon St Laurent&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$434&quot;&gt;Tim Bray&lt;/a&gt;. Familiar names to people who follow the xml-dev list, xml.com and xmlhack.com. As usual, meeting the people face to face makes all the difference. Peter is very cheerful fellow. Simon is young! (Who knew?) And Tim is pulling back from W3C, encouraging us to work with Apache.Org (no problem) and getting ready to launch his new web application, which of course uses XML, and will do something interesting with weblogs. &lt;i&gt;Excellent!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="Blogger pulling ahead of the pack on the Weblogs &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/hotList&quot;&gt;hotlist&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$431&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/greenGreenGreenThumb.gif&quot; height=&quot;56&quot; width=&quot;75&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Out for a walk yesterday, it was so bright, when I saw this &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$429&quot;&gt;puddle&lt;/a&gt; I asked &quot;Can the camera can see the sky in it?&quot; Yes it can. &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$430&quot;&gt;Live oaks&lt;/a&gt; have gnarly limbs. Soon they will all have leaves. The structure is visible, for now. You like green? We got &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$431&quot;&gt;green&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.cnet.com/news/0-1006-200-1564327.html&quot;&gt;News.Com&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;AMD will try to trump Intel by releasing a 1-GHz Athlon processor on Monday, sources said today, although it's a good bet that Intel will try to move up the release of their one-gig chip to the beginning of the week as well.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="NY Times: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/library/magazine/home/20000305mag-workaholic.html&quot;&gt;The Idled Workaholic&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;His plan to get rich had never included a plan to be rich. He held a title at Yahoo, but it was mostly just a title, not like the jobs he had before. At the age of 41, he faced the question, What would he do?&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.throbbing.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/mrHanky.gif&quot; height=&quot;22&quot; width=&quot;40&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://marcsvoice.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;Marc Canter&lt;/a&gt; for helping Dave Jacobs get his &lt;a href=&quot;http://bigdavesstuff.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;Manila site&lt;/a&gt; going. "/>
				<outline text="&quot;bill gates&quot;"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 3" created="Fri, 03 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="I sent this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.egroups.com/group/xml-rpc/688.html?&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.develop.com/soap.html&quot;&gt;SOAP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.egroups.com/group/xml-rpc/info.html&quot;&gt;XML-RPC&lt;/a&gt; mail lists. We have an understanding. I think this will please everyone who's interested in distributed computing based on XML and HTTP. Everyone gets what they want. Some time to soup up SOAP, and we can go forward building apps using XML-RPC, knowing that when the next-level SOAP is ready, our apps will be compatible. "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1996/05/23/embraceextend&quot;&gt;5/23/96&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Embrace &amp; Extend means that Microsoft Word reads WordPerfect files. Excel runs Lotus spreadsheets. It means that Windows runs DOS applications. And Microsoft Internet Explorer emulates Netscape where ever possible.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Tim O'Reilly: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oreilly.com/ask_tim/bezos_0300.html&quot;&gt;My Conversation with Jeff Bezos&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/stories/storyReader$427&quot;&gt;Talk to us on the Web&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;O'Reilly made a very strong point in his initial essay. Amazon and all of us have been the beneficiaries of a mountain of free ideas. Amazon's improvements to the Web, while useful and innovative, are tiny little bumps on the mountain, yet they they stand in the way of its growth. That is what Bezos must respond to.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Andrew Wooldridge: &lt;a href=&quot;http://anthem.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;Anthem Jr big update&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;I have something really cool in store for you today.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="WebMonkey: &lt;a href=&quot;http://hotwired.lycos.com/webmonkey/00/09/index2a_page8.html&quot;&gt;Adding Search to Your Site&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.com/zdnn/stories/comment/0,5859,2455272,00.html&quot;&gt;Matthew Rothenberg&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Apple is going to have a tough sell to Macolytes who've stuck with the platform largely thanks to their comfort level with its GUI.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Faisal Jawdat: &lt;a href=&quot;http://faisal.editthispage.com/stories/storyReader$44&quot;&gt;Follow the Money&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Red Herring: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.herring.com/companies/2000/0302/com-bigfish030200.html&quot;&gt;Eazel, the comeback tour&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salon.com/tech/feature/2000/03/03/patent/index.html&quot;&gt;Salon&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;When Priceline sued Mircrosoft's Expedia travel site for patent infringement in October 1999, the Net quaked. Suddenly, patents had teeth, and everyone wanted them. Intellectual property lawyers morphed into patent attorneys.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/2000/02/04/howToMakeMoneyOnTheInternet#11&quot;&gt;2/4/00&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Jay Walker, the founder of Priceline.Com, has 60 full-time people working in teams to do nothing more than generate patents. No engineering, no scaling issues, no customer satisfaction requirements (although Walker's company appears to be good at this too), they just a file a claim at various patent offices, and wait for the engineering of the Internet to catch up.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Lance Knobel: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.davosnewbies.com/stories/storyReader$428&quot;&gt;Tony Blair in Davos&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Problems on Subhonker1 today, there was about a 1 hour outage while I save-copied the big databases. It's back on the air now. Should be no data loss."/>
				<outline text="Hey I got an email from TBL re yesterday's &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/2000/03/02/theTwowayweb&quot;&gt;piece&lt;/a&gt;. He took me up on my offer to buy him dinner. Looks like I'm going to Boston."/>
				<outline text="More namedropping. At the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilfornaio.com/restaurant_detail.asp?id=27&quot;&gt;lunch&lt;/a&gt; where Tim O'Reilly got the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$413&quot;&gt;call&lt;/a&gt; from Jeff Bezos, I talked with &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$414&quot;&gt;Dale Dougherty&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oreillynet.com/&quot;&gt;The O'Reilly Network&lt;/a&gt;. I wondered then, and still do, if we can join up with O'Reilly, adding our network of sites to theirs, and vice versa. How would you all feel about being part of what O'Reilly is doing? I think some of our sites would be a natural fit, like &quot;Zope Newbies&quot;, &quot;Qube Quorner&quot; and &quot;Linux Newbies&quot;, as examples. "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thewebtoday.com/bloat/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/sallyTenPenny.gif&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; vspace=&quot;10&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Hey I made #1 on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thewebtoday.com/bloat/&quot;&gt;Bloat&lt;/a&gt; this week, sharing it with Jorn, which is quite an honor. To truthfully answer the question that's raised there, secretly I do indeed feel that Time could have made a better choice for Man of the Year."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://surveys.userland.com/surveys/results/dave@userland.com/howHighIsTheSky003&quot;&gt;Survey Results&lt;/a&gt;: 73 percent of UserLand.Com members will only buy from Amazon competitors, not Amazon."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://cfnews.weblogger.com/&quot;&gt;Cold Fusion News&lt;/a&gt; is a Manila site."/>
				<outline text="Best wishes to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.evhead.com/&quot;&gt;Evan Williams&lt;/a&gt; for a speedy recovery from dental surgery. Do I have any advice to offer? Well, this particular thing can only happen once in a lifetime. If his life is anything like mine (Bloat predicts it will) you'll spend many days programming like hell to get ready for some event or another. In the long-term all the marathon programming binges will melt into one, but you'll probably remember the pain of wisdom teeth forever. I sure do. (I still have two teeth that need extraction, and I've been putting it off for 10 years!)"/>
				<outline text="Charles Moore on Apple's Acqua: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.applelinks.com/articles/2000/03/20000302202926.shtml&quot;&gt;I Just Want To Get My Work Done&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;After playing with it for an hour, he concluded that this new OS is a completely new operating system. 'Nothing that you have learned using a previous Mac OS will be of any use to you whatsoever. It doesn't look like a Mac, it doesn't feel like a Mac, and it certainly doesn't work like a Mac.'&quot; &lt;i&gt;But it does run Mac apps, doesn't it??&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.virtualchina.com/infotech/news/stories/101899-microblow-tech1.html&quot;&gt;Virtual China&lt;/a&gt; on Bill Gates: &quot;He is a God without personal charm. A genius capitalist. One of his friends said 'Bill can conquer the world but he can't move anybody's heart.'&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&quot;turkey&quot; &quot;mister ed&quot; &quot;curly&quot; &quot;brain&quot; "/>
				<outline text="&quot;gandhi&quot; &quot;the pope&quot;"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 2" created="Thu, 02 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="DaveNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/2000/03/02/theTwowayweb&quot;&gt;The Two-Way-Web&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://nondata.editthispage.com/2000/03/02&quot;&gt;Mary Mack&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Now Dave wants a patents weblog editor. I should do this. But can I? I've been enamored of the tools Dave's provided, but I'm clumsy in using them. Voice programming is so much easier.&quot; Mary asks for help from a Manila expert. "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xmlrpc.com/discuss/msgReader$732&quot;&gt;Tim Lundeen&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Making XML-RPC 1.0 a W3C standard would give more support and emphasis to what is already an incredibly useful standard!&quot;"/>
				<outline text="The Minneapolis Star-Tribune has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startribune.com/viewers/qview/cgi/qfolder.cgi?template=column_weblog_f&amp;folder=1400&quot;&gt;weblog&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="XML.com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xml.com/pub/2000/02/xtech/xul.html&quot;&gt;Cool XUL Provides Cross-Platform UI&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fool.com/research/2000/features000302.htm&quot;&gt;Motley Fool&lt;/a&gt; interviews Steve Wozniak."/>
				<outline text="Wes Felter: &lt;a href=&quot;http://wmf.editthispage.com/stories/storyReader$203&quot;&gt;Why it's a good idea to go to class&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Jeremy Bowers: &lt;a href=&quot;http://irights.editthispage.com/stories/storyReader$115&quot;&gt;Weblog Communities&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://netdyslexia.editthispage.com/surveys/run/arf@sexyjazz.de/doYouWantToSeeTheOriginalHorse&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/images/netdyslexia/Pferdy.gif&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://netdyslexia.editthispage.com/2000/03/02&quot;&gt;NetDyslexia&lt;/a&gt; is willing to show us the full picture of their horse if they get 25 votes telling them to do that. I voted in favor of full disclosure."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geocities.com/comradedane/rahdogma.html&quot;&gt;Another convert&lt;/a&gt; to NetDyslexia's Dogma 2000?"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://cabinet.editthispage.com/2000/03/01&quot;&gt;Cabinet&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;My dad writes software and since this weekend he's been hopping mad about something you did with patting. He keeps saying amazon and there frigging patting!&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.monkeyfist.com/?id=293&quot;&gt;Ken MacLeod&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Dave Winer is also a principal developer of and a major proponent of XML-RPC.&quot; I have the same relationship to SOAP."/>
				<outline text="&quot;brain&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Wish: A lively weblog covering patents on &quot;EditThisPage.Com&quot;. "/>
				<outline text="We're working with &quot;Moreover.Com&quot; to get an updated news box as a Manila macro containing stories that cover web patents. This will be a sidebar on the patents site. We need an editor, someone who has background either in software or legal issues, preferably both. There's a time committment, you have to be willing to update the site daily, at least when patents are a hot issue."/>
				<outline text="I've also been thinking about what to do when someone makes a good start at a weblog in an important area, but drops off. Two such areas are &lt;a href=&quot;http://wap.editthispage.com./&quot;&gt;WAP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://svgnewbies.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;SVG&lt;/a&gt;. Both areas require coverage, there are new developments in each every day. I suggest if you are interested in these areas, send an email to the webmaster and ask if they'd be willing to make you a Managing Editor. "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fieldguide.com/Boys/Employed/geek.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/fieldGuideBird.gif&quot; height=&quot;36&quot; width=&quot;30&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;And be sure your site is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/member/signup&quot;&gt;registered&lt;/a&gt; at Weblogs.Com, I depend on it to know when sites I follow change, as many other people who run weblogs seem to. (That was the reason for starting the service.)"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://foz.editthispage.com/stories/storyReader$5&quot;&gt;John Foster&lt;/a&gt; has a lot of nice things to say about Mac OS X, Developer Release 3."/>
				<outline text="Press release: &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/stories/storyReader$424&quot;&gt;Earthport claims prior art in Amazon patent&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Wired: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/news/business/0,1367,34670,00.html&quot;&gt;Another Amazon Patent Furor&lt;/a&gt;. "/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$413&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/timOreillyPhoneThumb.gif&quot; height=&quot;48&quot; width=&quot;50&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; vspace=&quot;10&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Wired sucks. We didn't get a pointer or a &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/2000/02/28/noMorePesosForSenorBezos&quot;&gt;quote&lt;/a&gt; in their story. How did they find Danny Goodman's &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/stories/storyReader$410&quot;&gt;position&lt;/a&gt; re Amazon's patents? Maybe Danny called them. It could have happened. And they say Slashdot is working on this, that's great, but we've been doing a better job covering the Amazon patents than Slashdot. They tuned in late. It's OK, eventually they'll want to work with us. I used to be a fan of Wired! Hey I used to work for them. Sheez. My feelings are hurt. I will not give them permission to run the Forrest Gump-like &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$413&quot;&gt;picture&lt;/a&gt; of Tim O'Reilly talking with Jeff Bezos. "/>
				<outline text="Welcome to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://surprise.editthispage.com/zengarden&quot;&gt;Manila Zen-garden&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="WSJ: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/376822.asp&quot;&gt;Start-up stirred a media frenzy&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Today, Mr. Bowlin’s company has quietly closed. Its demise illustrates the burden of overnight success, and offers a reminder that Web start-ups don’t, after all, defy the laws of gravity.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="I can't tell if &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kottke.org/&quot;&gt;kottke&lt;/a&gt; is being sarcastic: &quot;More Web theft! Dave's worked hard over the years on a design for Scripting News, and now all these folks (here, here, here, here, here, here, and here, among others...) have gone and stolen it from him. Frankly, I'm appalled.&quot; The sites he points to are Manila sites. The default template for Manila sites looks a lot like Scripting News. I think he's joking, but sarcasm is hard to pick up in text."/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="March 1" created="Wed, 01 Mar 2000 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="DaveNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/2000/03/01/march25InCupertino&quot;&gt;March 25 in Cupertino&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="I had an interesting day today at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gca.org/attend/2000_conferences/xtech_2000/&quot;&gt;XTech&lt;/a&gt; in San Jose. Went to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://xmlhack.com/read.php?item=306&quot;&gt;BOF meeting&lt;/a&gt; held by W3C to talk about distributed computing protocols. It looks like Microsoft wants to turn SOAP over to W3C, and it also appears that W3C wants to re-work the whole thing! Wow. Here we go again. Tomorrow I'm giving the morning keynote. I think I'm going to ask for support for &quot;XML-RPC&quot; and ask that whatever W3C et al come up with be backward-compatible. I have some thinking to do tonight."/>
				<outline text="I also had lunch with Tim O'Reilly and &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$414&quot;&gt;Dale Dougherty&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilfornaio.com/restaurant_detail.asp?id=27&quot;&gt;Il Fornaio&lt;/a&gt; in San Jose. While we were having lunch Tim got a phone call from Jeff Bezos! They had a long talk. Afterwards Tim said he now understands why Amazon is doing what they're doing. I said I'm looking forward to reading his report. "/>
				<outline text="BTW, I got a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$413&quot;&gt;picture&lt;/a&gt; of Tim O'Reilly talking with Jeff Bezos. "/>
				<outline text="I met &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/pictures/viewer$421&quot;&gt;Edd Dumbill&lt;/a&gt;, who works at XML.COM, does the &lt;a href=&quot;http://xmlhack.com/&quot;&gt;xmlhack&lt;/a&gt; weblog."/>
				<outline text="Here's the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/stories/storyReader$423&quot;&gt;full set of pics&lt;/a&gt; from XTech, including three pictures of Don Box, the Microsoft SOAP guys and Eric Prud'hommeaux of W3C."/>
				<outline text="Web Techniques: &lt;a href=&quot;http://webtechniques.com/archives/2000/03/xml/&quot;&gt;Blowing XML Bubbles&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.cnet.com/news/0-1003-200-1561701.html&quot;&gt;Microsoft takes aim at Linux with reworked system&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Intel today said it will use Microsoft's reworked operating system--now called Windows for Express Networks--in a server appliance aimed at helping small businesses network their computers.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dailynews.yahoo.com/h/cn/20000301/tc/20000301043.html&quot;&gt;Palm division hit with patent suit&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.op.net/~pbd/amazon-1click.html&quot;&gt;Paul Barton-Davis&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;As one of the founding programmers at Amazon.com, I was very dismayed to learn of the company's legal attempts to enforce its 1-Click patent.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/stories/storyReader$410&quot;&gt;Danny Goodman&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I want to make very clear that I am not an affiliate with Amazon or any other bookseller. In the book info areas on my Web site, there are links to the pages of several booksellers directly to my titles. None of those links include those 'buried' affiliate codes in the URL.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Interesting! It's possible to use a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/cm/member-glance/-/A2SU6CA6HSK85I/002-3621611-8433826&quot;&gt;member profile&lt;/a&gt; page on Amazon to state your position on Web patents. I took a &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.userland.com/misc/snImages/amazonMemberProfile.gif&quot;&gt;screen shot&lt;/a&gt; of the page in case Amazon changes its mind."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/cm/member-glance/-/A2KEKKJ9CAC2KC/002-3621611-8433826&quot;&gt;Jeff Bezos&lt;/a&gt; has a member page and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/wishlist/BUWBWH9K2H77/002-3621611-8433826&quot;&gt;wish list&lt;/a&gt;. Let's buy him something nice when he swears off patent abuse."/>
				<outline text="Even more interesting.. There are lots of comments about patent abuse on the Amazon &lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.remarq.com/amazon/threads.asp?g=discuss.amazon.help.us.build.this.service&quot;&gt;discussion board&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;The Web Speaks!&lt;/i&gt;"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://march25.editthispage.com/&quot;&gt;On March 25&lt;/a&gt; we'll have a meeting of people who use Manila, or who develop with Frontier, and their friends, and other people who participate in UserLand.Com."/>
				<outline text="Manila Newbies: &lt;a href=&quot;http://weblogs.userland.com/manilaNewbies/discuss/msgReader$2273&quot;&gt;The Manila Tip Sheet&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.editthispage.com/stories/storyReader$48&quot;&gt;Last night&lt;/a&gt; we installed two optimizations on the server that's running EditThisPage.Com."/>
				<outline text="Linux Newbies: &lt;a href=&quot;http://linuxnewbies.editthispage.com/tips/20000301&quot;&gt;Understanding the RPM&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="Luca Bolognese: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.genoavalley.org/lb/XMLRPCClient.htm&quot;&gt;XML as a bridge between client and server&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				<outline text="IBM: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www-4.ibm.com/software/developer/library/xml-perl/&quot;&gt;XML and Scripting&lt;/a&gt; in Perl."/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblogs.com/discuss/msgReader$329&quot;&gt;Weblogs.Com&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I'm looking for ideas for taglines.&quot;"/>
				<outline text="Jodi Mardesich: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fortune.com/fortune/technology/daily/0,3467,617000223,00.html&quot;&gt;Why I'm Joining a Startup&lt;/a&gt;."/>
				</outline>
			</outline>
		</body>
	</opml>
