<?xml version="1.0"?>
<opml version="2.0">
	<head>
		<title>Scripting News</title>
		<dateCreated>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 15:51:38 GMT</dateCreated>
		<urlPublic>http://scripting.com/publicfolder/scripting/blog.opml</urlPublic>
		<flPublic>true</flPublic>
		<ownerEmail>dave.winer@gmail.com</ownerEmail>
		<ownerId>dave.winer@gmail.com</ownerId>
		<urlUpdateSocket>wss://drummer.land/</urlUpdateSocket>
		<dateModified>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:48:19 GMT</dateModified>
		<expansionState></expansionState>
		<lastCursor>0</lastCursor>
		</head>
	<body>
		<outline text="December 2023" created="Fri, 01 Dec 2023 14:53:44 GMT" name="december2023" type="calendarMonth">
			<outline text="December 31" created="Sun, 31 Dec 2023 18:12:40 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="31">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/andrewhickey.bsky.social&quot;&gt;Andrew Hickey&lt;/a&gt; is this year's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+Blogger+of+the+Year&quot;&gt;Blogger of the Year&lt;/a&gt;. He's a prototypical blogger, exactly the kind of person I hoped would &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2022/04/13/165056.html?title=sourcesGoDirectExplained&quot;&gt;create&lt;/a&gt; their own media having profound positive impact on people's lives. People like me. His &lt;a href=&quot;https://500songs.com/podcast/&quot;&gt;500 Songs&lt;/a&gt; podcast, which I've written about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+500+songs&quot;&gt;many times&lt;/a&gt;, focuses on a song in every episode and tells you how the pieces came together to create it. When a new episode comes out I greedily savor it, like a great &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+bagel&quot;&gt;bagel&lt;/a&gt; from Zabar's or a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quentin_Tarantino#Filmography&quot;&gt;Tarantino&lt;/a&gt; movie. Two recent episodes, one about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://500songs.com/podcast/episode-165-dark-star-by-the-grateful-dead/&quot;&gt;Grateful Dead&lt;/a&gt; and the other about &lt;a href=&quot;https://500songs.com/podcast/episode-171-hey-jude-by-the-beatles/&quot;&gt;Hey Jude&lt;/a&gt;, changed my views of each of the groups, in the first case confirming an intuition, and in the other showing me how naive my idea of how a song comes together. I am envious of how the musicians work together, it may be a cuthroat industry, but it seems incredibly collaborative compared to how tech works, where we all pretty much ignore each other. Hickey isn't just a podcaster, he's also a blogger, and he does it in an unusual place, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/andrewhickey.bsky.social&quot;&gt;on Bluesky&lt;/a&gt;. He has things to say and that's of course what &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2009/11/24/naturalbornBlogger.html&quot;&gt;NBB's&lt;/a&gt; are all about. You may not care for their opinions, but you will know what they are. Anyway, if you like the Beatles, I highly recommend the &lt;a href=&quot;https://500songs.com/podcast/episode-171-hey-jude-by-the-beatles/&quot;&gt;latest episode&lt;/a&gt;, and if you like popular music, &lt;a href=&quot;https://500songs.com/feed/podcast/&quot;&gt;subscribe&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?river=https%3A%2F%2F500songs.com%2Ffeed%2Fpodcast%2F&quot;&gt;500 Songs&lt;/a&gt;. And if you know of any podcasts like this, please let me know. I always want to add to my podcast reading list. " created="Sun, 31 Dec 2023 18:22:19 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2022/04/15/theEggman.png"/>
				<outline text="Hickey was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/podcast-dept/a-music-podcast-unlike-any-other&quot;&gt;profiled&lt;/a&gt; in the New Yorker in July." created="Sun, 31 Dec 2023 18:35:33 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="A quiet end for 2023. It was not a fantastic year, work-wise. I spent almost all my time working away from my interests. First project was completely replacing the identity system in the two apps I'm maintaining -- &quot;Drummer&quot; and &quot;FeedLand&quot;, and letting the others end. No one ever says thanks for this kind of work, but it's as basic as converting a house from oil heat to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heat_pump&quot;&gt;heat pump&lt;/a&gt;. Some of the ducts still work, but things break in hard to find ways. I also converted FeedLand from a simple app that runs on a virtual server, to a scalable and durable app (we hope) that runs in a big cloud. This part was good, but again the work is far from where my expertise and interests lie. So at the beginning of a new year, I'm going to remind myself that I'm too old and not paid well enough (I'm not paid at all, heh) to do another year of this kind of work. I should be making writing and reading tools work better on the web. That's my mission. If it isn't related to that, please understand when I don't give it a high priority. Just one person here. Surprisingly resilient, but also quite tired. " created="Sun, 31 Dec 2023 18:12:41 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/04/24/cheshireCat.png"/>
				<outline text="Sometimes I wonder if dying is like waking from from a dream, hopefully with friends and loved ones waiting for you, like going to a diner after seeing a movie together and you all talk about how you liked it, and if you want to see it again." created="Mon, 01 Jan 2024 03:27:23 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 30" created="Sat, 30 Dec 2023 14:46:54 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="30">
				<outline text="Here's the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/code/newsproducthome/newsscriptingcom.json&quot;&gt;JSON spec&lt;/a&gt; for news.scripting.com. Not done yet, still more stuff to add, and possibly change, but I think it looks pretty good so far. The previous version depended on OPML, and I wanted to move to JSON because OPML already has plenty to do in our world. :smile:" created="Sat, 30 Dec 2023 16:21:28 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2023/09/18/slugger.png"/>
				<outline text="When I say &quot;textcasting&quot; is &quot;applying the philosophy of podcasting to text&quot; -- what I mean in practical terms is that my flow of ideas is available &quot;where ever you get your text.&quot; Choice in subscribing has to be that fluid, commonsense, and choice is something people feel entitled to, as they do with podcasts. I've been told people would never understand the philosophy of podcasting, but they do, they understand they're entitled to choice in how to listen and thus producers are free to choose where to publish. Somehow text, which is so much easier to transmit than audio, is far less flexible. That's a mistake I want to undo, but I can't do it alone. I need to work with other people who have writing and reading tools, and people who have something to say and want all the features of writing to be at their disposal, and for it to be easy, inexpensive but not free of charge, and not owned by the titans of tech. Another &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U7dBMYUyRAQ&quot;&gt;song&lt;/a&gt; comes to mind. &quot;You can get it if you really want.&quot;" created="Sat, 30 Dec 2023 16:26:40 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Yesterday I wrote that &lt;i&gt;working together&lt;/i&gt; is the challenge for open tech developers. If you're waiting for a big company to work with you, and we all are, the answer is you'll probably wait a long time, and you probably won't get there. It's not impossible, but it is improbable. So while you're waiting, why not work with a peer on solving a problem you both have in somewhat different ways, but make what you do compatible. That's what working together is about. It's not just that the people did it, but you created something that lives on that works together. There's even a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HH3ruuml-R4&quot;&gt;song&lt;/a&gt; that goes with this. &quot;If you can't be with the one you love, love the one you're with.&quot;   " created="Sat, 30 Dec 2023 16:04:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="There's been a bit of trouble on my servers the last couple of days, and as a result a couple of domains are not working for everyone, or are behaving in mysterious ways. I moved &lt;a href=&quot;https://textcasting.org/&quot;&gt;textcasting.org&lt;/a&gt; to a server that has a copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/pagePark/issues/25&quot;&gt;Caddy&lt;/a&gt; installed, and therefore supports HTTPS. I am able to see the domain on my local machines, but not on my phone, and I'm getting reports that other people are getting empty pages. And theoretically there should be no way that people should get a non-HTTPS version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;news.scripting.com&lt;/a&gt;, but I'm seeing hits for the HTTP version in my log. Very weird. If you can shed any light on the problems from your end, please post a note &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/285#issuecomment-1872208109&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks! What a way to end a year. Oy. " created="Sat, 30 Dec 2023 14:46:55 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/10/02/debbieDowner.png"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 29" created="Fri, 29 Dec 2023 16:23:29 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="29">
				<outline text="At the end of another year, network writing is still &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2023/12/28.html#a171709&quot;&gt;broken&lt;/a&gt; and the bigger problem is we don't work together. And we've gotten out of the habit of trying out new ideas with our networks. And we're building systems that depend on the kindness of our peers and big companies, and keep learning that this is not a kind world. All this is why we've been spinning our wheels for 17 years, and unless we start working together, for real, we'll just keep spinning.  " created="Fri, 29 Dec 2023 16:23:30 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2019/11/20/offWithTheirHeads.png"/>
				<outline text="The new version of &quot;news.scripting.com&quot; has been running for a couple of days, and seems to be working well. But I'm not sure everyone is seeing the new version. In the new version there are &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/29/newsScriptingScreenShot.png&quot;&gt;icons&lt;/a&gt; on each tab. If you're seeing the icons, all is good, if not, try clearing your DNS cache? The domain should point to 143.198.165.199. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/285#issuecomment-1872208109&quot;&gt;place to comment&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Fri, 29 Dec 2023 16:28:25 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 28" created="Thu, 28 Dec 2023 16:24:46 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="28">
				<outline text="The state of networked writing at the end of 2023 -- broken, in many cases, no doubt, deliberately, to keep networks from interoperating. One system allows multiple tags per item, another limits it to one. One has a limit of 280 chars, another 500, but if you pay 10,000. There is no interop, we all write in silos. The basic feature of the web, linking, is especially broken. These are all incredibly simple features requiring practically no resources., This must be deliberate, because the problem is so easily solved. Most people can't see the potential of the open internet as a fantastic writing environment, but it can be one, but only if we want it.  " created="Thu, 28 Dec 2023 17:17:09 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2019/12/12/silo.png"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 27" created="Wed, 27 Dec 2023 14:23:33 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="27">
				<outline text="The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2023/12/27/business/media/new-york-times-open-ai-microsoft-lawsuit.html?unlocked_article_code=1.JE0.CZ2w.6HmYzKZ-ps8y&amp;smid=url-share&quot;&gt;NYT is suing ChatGPT&lt;/a&gt; for ingesting their archive. I understand why they would sue now, for legal reasons, but before they had their own service up, assuming they are developing one, it's kind of selfish of them to keep the Times content out of the mix. We're failing at a number of big challenges (climate, guns, abortion, democracy, racial hate, wars), with everyone's future at stake. They could grant ChatGPT a license until at least they had their own product up. That would send the right message, our journalism is an aid to our survival, and we wanted to be sure you had access to the paper of record, now and in the future. Instead they want to take their data out of the mix, and who knows if they ever plan to get it back in. This is a far cry from the NYT that helped get our news systems on the web established in the 90s and 00s. " created="Wed, 27 Dec 2023 14:34:51 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/09/25/ezpass.png"/>
				<outline text="I'm going to write rebuttals to important Wikipedia pages that get the story wrong. In the past this was pointless, because search engines ranked them so high, but now I find that ChatGPT figures out the real story somehow, almost always, even if Wikipedia is wildly wrong. I figure our blogging helps.  " created="Wed, 27 Dec 2023 14:23:34 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="news.scripting.com" created="Wed, 27 Dec 2023 15:18:06 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Okay the new version of &quot;news.scripting.com&quot; is up. " created="Wed, 27 Dec 2023 15:18:14 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Here's what's new." created="Wed, 27 Dec 2023 15:18:23 GMT" flBulletedSubs="true">
						<outline text="When you click on a tab, we change the URL in the address bar to point to the tab, the same way we do on the Scripting News home page. If you bookmark that link, you'll go to that tab." created="Wed, 27 Dec 2023 15:18:30 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Click the white-on-orange XML icon to get an OPML subscription list for the feeds with the category of the current selected tab. " created="Wed, 27 Dec 2023 15:19:59 GMT"/>
						<outline text="The four buttons below each item now work. " created="Sun, 24 Dec 2023 18:34:13 GMT"/>
						<outline text="It should work reasonably well on phones and tablets." created="Wed, 27 Dec 2023 16:01:47 GMT"/>
						<outline text="It's served with HTTPS because in upcoming versions you'll be able to log in. " created="Wed, 27 Dec 2023 16:04:12 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="And that's about it, in terms of visible features. Behind the scenes there's a new tab manager. I figured since all my apps use tabs these days, I should make the investment of having a single tab manager that has all the bells and whistles, invoked by setting an option." created="Wed, 27 Dec 2023 15:22:01 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The customary &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/27/newsScripting.png?nodialog&quot;&gt;screen shot&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Wed, 27 Dec 2023 16:05:59 GMT"/>
					<outline text="A &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/285&quot;&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt; for any questions." created="Wed, 27 Dec 2023 15:24:41 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 26" created="Tue, 26 Dec 2023 15:55:35 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="26">
				<outline text="So much of the history isn't covered on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS&quot;&gt;Wikipedia page on RSS&lt;/a&gt;, for example, the apps that got the ball rolling in the spring of 1999: my.netscape and my.userland and the four pioneering web pubs: Salon, Wired, Motley Fool and Red Herring. We immediately put new feed support into Manila and the early versions of Radio and were followed by Blogger, Movable Type and basically the whole blogging world (WordPress was still a few years in the future). It was all that adoption in a short period of time that made RSS a big thing. Professional and amateur writers in one space. When you went to see what's new, the web did the surfing for you. For me it was the continuation of a story that goes back to the San Francisco &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/davenet/1994/11/07/davesautomatedwebster.html&quot;&gt;newspaper strike&lt;/a&gt; in 1994. And it's still happening today on Twitter, Threads, Bluesky, Mastodon. It's a continuing story. Not over by a lot. " created="Tue, 26 Dec 2023 18:10:38 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/26/rssShirt.png"/>
				<outline text="In the early 80s, my main development machine was an Apple II, believe it or not. Sometimes the machine would just refuse to boot, so I'd get on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/dir/Menlo+Park,+California/1324+S+Mary+Ave,+Sunnyvale,+CA+94087/@37.4029173,-122.15649,13z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m14!4m13!1m5!1m1!1s0x808fa6b1117280ff:0xebbf998e5df289ab!2m2!1d-122.1817252!2d37.4529598!1m5!1m1!1s0x808fb682d5a368c7:0x5af2a581c038f222!2m2!1d-122.0494523!2d37.3512373!3e2?entry=ttu&quot;&gt;El Camino&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/1324+S+Mary+Ave,+Sunnyvale,+CA+94087/@37.3512373,-122.0494523,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m6!3m5!1s0x808fb682d5a368c7:0x5af2a581c038f222!8m2!3d37.3512373!4d-122.0494523!16s%2Fg%2F11c37grvdp?entry=ttu&quot;&gt;Computer Plus&lt;/a&gt; in Sunnyvale, which was the main developer store in the Valley, owned by Dick and Lucy Applebaum and &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/26/wozniakComputerPlus.png&quot;&gt;Mark Wozniak&lt;/a&gt;. Very often when I got to the store and plugged the machine in, it would start right up. That became a superstition, if your computer won't launch take it for a ride in the car. Anyway, this morning, in 2023, my web app, the new version of &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;news.scripting.com&lt;/a&gt; that I'm working on was in a state that was really depressing. I was working on making it mobile-friendly and nothing I did would make the timeline fit into the alotted space. I was at my wits end, thinking maybe I'd have to revert my changes and try another approach. So I went out for a walk, it's a nice day, kind of warm, and the air is clear, no rain, and there are even some trees in bloom which is weird considering that it's &lt;i&gt;the day after Christmas&lt;/i&gt; for crying out loud. But it was a good thing to do, when I got back I had a plan for how to go forward. My brain was now clear. I got myself a nice bowl of fruit salad and a glass of water, and sat down and rolled up my sleeves, and I bet by now dear reader you've figured out the punchline. It worked. I did nothing. Every bit showed up in the right place, more or less (modulo some tweaking). Back with Apple II in the 80s it wasn't really magic. The chips weren't soldered into the motherboard on the machine, and they would get pretty hot, and when you'd turn the computer off and on, it would go hot and cold, which meant the pins on the chips would expand and contract and in doing so, over months, one could unseat. A trip in the car might just jog it back into its socket. The same way, forty years later, if you get up from the computer and go for a walk, when you come back, cached requests have now aged-out and the files that weren't getting refreshed are now up to date, and it turns out I wasn't crazy or incompetent, and it probably wasn't some kind of act of god, it's just the internet being the internet." created="Tue, 26 Dec 2023 17:47:45 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/26/appleII.png"/>
				<outline text="I believe that, with yesterday's &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2023/12/25.html#a153447&quot;&gt;change&lt;/a&gt;, images are now loading &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/283&quot;&gt;properly&lt;/a&gt; in emails transmitted over GMail. " created="Wed, 27 Dec 2023 01:57:23 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 25" created="Mon, 25 Dec 2023 14:54:15 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="25">
				<outline text="Happy Christmas everyone who celebrates. I have a little business to do here on &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/&quot;&gt;my blog&lt;/a&gt; today, then the regular holiday schedule will begin starting tomorrow and probably go through the first week of January." created="Mon, 25 Dec 2023 14:54:16 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2022/12/01/santa.png"/>
				<outline text="This period is often a time of innovation in the world of blogs, podcasting and feeds. For me this year, I'm using the time to do more work on CSS and basic user interface stuff for &quot;FeedLand&quot; and for news products like &quot;news.scripting.com&quot;, which has been surprisingly popular. The new stuff will start showing up first in that site, pretty soon. The goal is to build on its popularity, to bootstrap a new platform. " created="Mon, 25 Dec 2023 14:55:30 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I also want to write a bit more about RSS support in Bluesky, what it means, and ideas for next steps. BTW, here's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/25/emailToJayAtBluesky.png&quot;&gt;screen shot&lt;/a&gt; of the email I sent to Jay Graber, the CEO of Bluesky, on Dec 12, asking for &quot;RSS 2.0&quot; support, which was released publicly ten days later on &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2023/12/22.html&quot;&gt;Dec 22&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Mon, 25 Dec 2023 14:59:23 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I made a change to how images are served from this blog, to see if the images are still blocked by GMail. Previously we redirected to an &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/scripting.com/images/2022/12/01/santa.png&quot;&gt;S3 file&lt;/a&gt;, so we could use HTTPS and but not have to have the bits flow through one of my Digital Ocean servers, which after this change, they now do. For most of you this will be blah blah whatever blah blah zzzz, but some people may find it interesting." created="Mon, 25 Dec 2023 15:34:47 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, there is only one &lt;a href=&quot;https://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html&quot;&gt;RSS 2.0 spec&lt;/a&gt;.  :smile: " created="Mon, 25 Dec 2023 20:05:48 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 24" created="Sun, 24 Dec 2023 16:22:52 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="24">
				<outline text="Christmas Eve 2023" created="Mon, 25 Dec 2023 03:37:49 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Ho ho ho! :smile:" created="Sun, 24 Dec 2023 16:22:53 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/24/santa.png"/>
					<outline text="Draw me a picture of a fat bearded old man in red pajamas in a flying sled powered by reindeer flying in the night sky over NYC." created="Mon, 25 Dec 2023 03:38:08 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/24/fatOldManFlyingOverNYC.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 23" created="Sat, 23 Dec 2023 14:19:38 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="23">
				<outline text="FeedLand and Bluesky feeds" created="Sat, 23 Dec 2023 14:19:39 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="We can now subscribe to Bluesky feeds in &quot;FeedLand&quot; --" created="Sat, 23 Dec 2023 14:20:39 GMT" flBulletedSubs="true">
						<outline text="In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/23/subscribeScreenShot.png&quot;&gt;Subscribe sub-menu&lt;/a&gt;, choose &lt;i&gt;To one feed.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Sat, 23 Dec 2023 14:20:58 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Enter the URL of a Bluesky profile page. For example, here's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/neilhimself.neilgaiman.com&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; to Neil Gaiman's profile. " created="Sat, 23 Dec 2023 14:21:58 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Click OK." created="Sat, 23 Dec 2023 14:22:53 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="When this feature came out &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2023/12/22.html#a193746&quot;&gt;yesterday&lt;/a&gt; it didn't work with FeedLand because we were looking for full URLs pointing to a feed in their feed discovery link and they provided a relative URL." created="Sat, 23 Dec 2023 14:23:33 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The fix was in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/reallysimple/tree/main/demos/feedhunter&quot;&gt;feedHunter package&lt;/a&gt;, it now looks for relative URLs and makes them full before trying to find the feed. " created="Sat, 23 Dec 2023 14:23:14 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I think I understand why they used a relative URL, they're getting ready to federate and it's probably simpler for them to just specify a relative URL." created="Sat, 23 Dec 2023 14:24:51 GMT"/>
					<outline text="On the other hand, I think this is going to be a problem -- in the world of feeds, software usually expects full URLs. " created="Sat, 23 Dec 2023 14:26:04 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PS: This is what a Bluesky feed &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?river=https%3A%2F%2Fbsky.app%2Fprofile%2Fdid%3Aplc%3Apn5qdowybxjewkcq6zzenvtq%2Frss&quot;&gt;looks&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/23/blueskyfeedinfeedlandscreenshot.png&quot;&gt;like&lt;/a&gt; in FeedLand on Day 1." created="Sat, 23 Dec 2023 16:27:37 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 22" created="Fri, 22 Dec 2023 14:53:32 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="22">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/bsky.app/post/3kh5rjl6bgu2i&quot;&gt;Bluesky has RSS 2.0 feeds&lt;/a&gt; for every user, &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/22/blueskyAnnouncement.png&quot;&gt;built-in&lt;/a&gt;. Now we have a basis for interop between Mastodon and Bluesky. Important milestone. What can we build with this? Start thinking, building." created="Fri, 22 Dec 2023 19:37:46 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="This is &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:oety7qbfx7x6exn2ytrwikmr/rss&quot;&gt;my Bluesky feed&lt;/a&gt;. Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/284&quot;&gt;place&lt;/a&gt; for questions or comments. " created="Fri, 22 Dec 2023 21:46:21 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/22/blueskyAnnouncement.png"/>
				<outline text="Is there an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/smart-home-devices/b?ie=UTF8&amp;node=9818047011&quot;&gt;Amazon Echo&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/JBL-Waterproof-Portable-Bluetooth-Speaker/dp/B07QK2SPP7/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?hvadid=267942939791&amp;hvdev=c&amp;hvlocphy=9004747&amp;hvnetw=g&amp;hvqmt=e&amp;hvrand=16161778895412864090&amp;hvtargid=kwd-375689607825&amp;hydadcr=15108_9828339&amp;keywords=jbl+bluetooth+speaker+system&amp;qid=1703269785&amp;sr=8-1-spons&amp;ufe=app_do:amzn1.fos.18630bbb-fcbb-42f8-9767-857e17e03685&amp;sp_csd=d2lkZ2V0TmFtZT1zcF9hdGY&amp;th=1&quot;&gt;form factor&lt;/a&gt; of a battery operated wifi speaker? Such an obvious product. Everyone would get one." created="Fri, 22 Dec 2023 18:58:10 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="In the reporting on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/trump-insurrection-14th-amendment-2024-colorado-d16dd8f354eeaf450558378c65fd79a2&quot;&gt;Colorado Supreme Court&lt;/a&gt; and the 14th Amendment, I've not heard the most basic reason why Trump can't be President. Here's why. He took an &lt;a href=&quot;https://constitution.congress.gov/browse/essay/artII-S1-C8-1/ALDE_00001126/&quot;&gt;oath&lt;/a&gt; to preserve, protect and defend the Constitution. He did the opposite, he attacked the Constitution. So how can we ask him to take the same oath again, the one that he violated the last time he took it. The Constitution is very wise, it's what &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maya_Angelou&quot;&gt;Maya Angelou&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brainyquote.com/quotes/maya_angelou_383371&quot;&gt;taught&lt;/a&gt; -- when someone shows you who they are, believe them the first time. That's why he can't be president again. He can't be believed when he takes the oath, and if he can't take the oath he can't be President. " created="Sat, 23 Dec 2023 01:17:22 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Wordle" created="Fri, 22 Dec 2023 22:25:52 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I've been playing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/games/wordle/index.html&quot;&gt;Wordle&lt;/a&gt; again for the last two months. I'm much better at it this go-around than the last time. Generally I can get it done in three or four moves. If it takes five it's because I made a mistake or took a gamble on the second move that didn't work out. These days I don't even try for the second move, but this morning, on the first move I got four out of the five letters, and got the correct position of two of the four. It took a couple of seconds to see that there was really only one answer, so I decided to risk it, and there was this moment we yearn for when the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SbK1SM_Qomg&quot;&gt;letters reveal&lt;/a&gt; one at a time, all green, a final correct move, in two. First time I've ever gotten that result. I wasn't even sure it was possible. Well there it is. Almost &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/22/9999.png&quot;&gt;perfect&lt;/a&gt;. Nothing more to say than Yay Me! " created="Fri, 22 Dec 2023 14:53:33 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/22/wordleWin.png"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Conversation vs publishing" created="Fri, 22 Dec 2023 15:41:33 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Conversation has a place, but I think we've explored that pretty well, and now I want to create better publishing and reading systems, that are as fast as social web systems, but place less emphasis on replies that can be seen by everyone, because that often is not really conversation, it's spam. " created="Fri, 22 Dec 2023 15:28:45 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="I think ultimately we'll be disappointed with federation for all the reasons we're frustrated with earlier social web systems. People trying to get attention for their ideas, which often are spam or trolling. I also think this means RSS will be more valuable going forward because it's great at publishing, checking all the &quot;textcasting&quot; boxes. " created="Fri, 22 Dec 2023 15:44:54 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I plan to build with and around WordPress. I think of WordPress as a basic platform the way I saw Twitter between 2006 and 2022. Now the question is what are the steps to use WordPress as the back-end of a social communication system. Behind the scenes, its database has all the capabilities we need to provide the tools writers need. And it has excellent RSS support. It all runs at scale and has a mature yet simple API.  That is all we need to form a hub." created="Fri, 22 Dec 2023 15:36:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 21" created="Thu, 21 Dec 2023 17:54:02 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="21">
				<outline text="This is the time of year every day feels like Saturday." created="Thu, 21 Dec 2023 19:01:11 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="ChatGPT is my CSS advisor" created="Thu, 21 Dec 2023 17:56:50 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="People who don't program must not have any idea how much of a boon ChatGPT is to us programmers. " created="Thu, 21 Dec 2023 17:57:28 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I am doing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3schools.com/css/&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/a&gt; coding far in advance of my previous capability. When I know something is possible, but I haven't the slightest idea how to specify it, I just ask, in my own words. " created="Thu, 21 Dec 2023 17:57:50 GMT"/>
					<outline text="For example, a very common thing to want to do is to put a : after the text in the first column every row of a table. " created="Thu, 21 Dec 2023 17:58:19 GMT"/>
					<outline text="So I &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/b19c1c8d-3e19-4039-86aa-803eb7cf46d6&quot;&gt;asked ChatGPT&lt;/a&gt; how to do it, in English, as I did above. This is what it came up with:" created="Thu, 21 Dec 2023 17:54:03 GMT" type="outline">
						<outline text="&lt;code&gt;tr td:first-child::after {content: &quot;:&quot;;}&lt;/code&gt;" created="Thu, 21 Dec 2023 17:55:57 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="When you see it like that you can almost figure out what's going on if you squint and close one eye. " created="Thu, 21 Dec 2023 17:58:45 GMT"/>
					<outline text="And it works. I literally shrieked when it did. " created="Thu, 21 Dec 2023 17:58:57 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Now I am the boss of CSS.. " created="Thu, 21 Dec 2023 17:59:09 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Nice." created="Thu, 21 Dec 2023 17:59:21 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="If FeedLand were from Disney" created="Thu, 21 Dec 2023 18:33:30 GMT" type="outline" metaImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/21/feedland.png">
					<outline text="A beautiful and weird visualization of FeedLand." created="Thu, 21 Dec 2023 18:33:39 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/21/feedLandFromDisneyOoooops.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 20" created="Wed, 20 Dec 2023 13:53:40 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="20">
				<outline text="If we had met in the late 80s and early 90s and we were talking about where technology should go next, I would have talked endlessly about creating apps out of apps. It means being able to write scripts that use an application as a scriptable toolbox, going behind the user interface. I was developing a product around that idea called Frontier. It all happened, and played a big role in making the Mac the ideal development platform for the web when it came along, in the early-late 90s. Unfortunately &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Jobs&quot;&gt;Apple's top people&lt;/a&gt; didn't get this, and wiped out the whole developer community in one press conference. The ideas were still useful and we're using them every day, but not really aware of it. End of speech." created="Wed, 20 Dec 2023 15:02:30 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2003/10/20/siteScriptedWithFrontier.gif"/>
				<outline text="I asked ChatGPT for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/8df0889c-4475-4634-ab2c-9f5b0c3785bb&quot;&gt;list of Motown songs&lt;/a&gt; with a strong fast beat good for dancing. Now I want to play the list in Amazon music. Is there a way to do this? " created="Wed, 20 Dec 2023 15:07:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Technical note: I've observed that GMail is refusing to show the images on my nightly emails, when &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/20/brokenImage.png&quot;&gt;viewed&lt;/a&gt; on my iPad, both in the Safari browser and in the iOS GMail app. I'd like to know if this is happening for other people, and then run an experiment to see if we can figure out what it is they don't like about the images. Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/283&quot;&gt;place&lt;/a&gt; to comment. " created="Wed, 20 Dec 2023 14:10:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="After all the disappointments in our country's response to Homegrown Hitler from Queens, a personality I recognize from the neighborhood I grew up in which is just &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/dir/29-31+170th+Street,+Queens,+NY/85-15+Wareham+Pl,+Queens,+NY+11432/@40.7433231,-73.8089171,14z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m14!4m13!1m5!1m1!1s0x89c28a8078136589:0xcdf1c8651455269a!2m2!1d-73.7948746!2d40.7696367!1m5!1m1!1s0x89c2611ad4d2c6a5:0xfe60c1b9262c3e04!2m2!1d-73.7858208!2d40.7170272!3e2?entry=ttu&quot; title=&quot;via Utopia Parkway&quot;&gt;four miles&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/85-15_Wareham_Place&quot;&gt;where&lt;/a&gt; Trump grew up, what a nice unexpected surprise that one holiday season Tuesday night, I'd turn on the news on MSNBC at the exact moment the host says &quot;Hold on, breaking news&quot; (I sighed, no it's not) only to learn yes, it was. The state of Colorado had decided to use one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wapo.st/3TBQQw3&quot;&gt;guardrail&lt;/a&gt; buttons to extinguish the candidacy of HH, just like that. This morning I woke with a smile on my face and thought, hey it could happen, it &lt;i&gt;should&lt;/i&gt; happen. If the Supreme Court doesn't want to become the &lt;a href=&quot;https://theprint.in/opinion/how-judiciary-helped-hitler-and-stalin-in-destroying-political-opposition/285057/&quot;&gt;Nazi-style&lt;/a&gt; ratifier of a holocaust, this is their moment to act. It's possible they'll decide that the Constitution applies to every officer of the United States government except the president and vice-president, I'd love to hear the reason, and if they do, we'll know that we've already lost. " created="Wed, 20 Dec 2023 13:53:41 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2020/11/26/uncleSam.png"/>
				<outline text="If journalism wants to help inform the populace of the stakes, I'd like them to stop using the term neo-Nazi. There's nothing new about being a Nazi. It adds a tiny bit of confusion at exactly the point where you want zero confusion. It took journalism a long time to use the term insurrection about the January 6 events, that hurt us too. Understand where the path we're on leads, and don't give people a reason to hope that it's not as serious as it is. " created="Wed, 20 Dec 2023 14:05:29 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="They're letting us have RSS" created="Wed, 20 Dec 2023 15:21:27 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Assume that FB doesn't really want to interop, so that's why there's a year timeline on developing AP functionality. No rush. Let's keep growing and later on we can have an app store that only lets certain sites into our world, subject to our turning them off at any time. " created="Wed, 20 Dec 2023 15:21:34 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Assuming this is true, RSS is their worst nightmare. It's implemented in a week, if you're really careful and there are good toolkits for every platform, and lots of developers know what to do with it, and even worse, there already is a huge installed base of such apps and they all have &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/vociferous&quot;&gt;vociferous&lt;/a&gt; users who would be thrilled to be heard, because they largely feel like they're pissing in the wind. I am doing CSS coding far in advance of my previous capability, when I know something is possible, but I haven't the slightest idea how to specify it. " created="Wed, 20 Dec 2023 23:11:27 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Remember they said RSS is Dead. I always felt that was aimed at me, but it was aimed at them too, even more so." created="Wed, 20 Dec 2023 23:11:34 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The thing to do, build -- intelligently, slowly, showing interop at every step. Watch out for people who take stuff out with out putting back. " created="Wed, 20 Dec 2023 15:21:52 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 19" created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:05:06 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="19">
				<outline text="A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.threads.net/@davew/post/C1CnzSqALTu&quot;&gt;suggestion&lt;/a&gt; to ActivityPub enthusiasts -- a very simple, highly factored toolkit for posting via ActivityPub might unleash a flood of compatible software, depending on how many obstacles can be removed. I've tried to evangelize the idea, but it didn't happen. In the end I punted, and used Mastodon's API, and thus &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/textcasting&quot;&gt;my software&lt;/a&gt; only works with services that implement their API.  " created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 16:16:53 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2020/11/27/duck.png"/>
				<outline text="There's actual news tonight" created="Wed, 20 Dec 2023 01:11:24 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I've been watching the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.memeorandum.com/231219/p55#a231219p55&quot;&gt;news&lt;/a&gt; tonight, when there's some &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/trump-insurrection-14th-amendment-2024-colorado-d16dd8f354eeaf450558378c65fd79a2&quot;&gt;actual&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/live/2023/12/19/us/trump-colorado-ballot-news#trump-colorado-ballot-14th-amendment&quot;&gt;news&lt;/a&gt;, and it's &lt;i&gt;good&lt;/i&gt; news. " created="Wed, 20 Dec 2023 01:11:32 GMT"/>
					<outline text="What they're not saying is that the US has the tools to defend itself from enemies like Trump, and finally we're starting to use them. Not impotent tools, like congressional hearings or impeachment, but the actual guardrail meant to serve as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://constitution.findlaw.com/amendment14/annotation15.html&quot;&gt;last resort&lt;/a&gt; to keep a nightmare out of the government.  An insurrectionist should be dealt with a lot more swiftly than Trump has and the penalty should be harsh to warn off other would-be coup plotters. But -- better late than never. " created="Wed, 20 Dec 2023 01:11:53 GMT" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2020/11/26/uncleSam.png"/>
					<outline text="And if they want to have a civil war, okay -- better to do it when the military is under constitutional control, at least theoretically. Tell the Republicans to try again, now before any primary votes have been cast. This candidate is prohibited from being president, as if he were born outside the United States. Not qualified. " created="Wed, 20 Dec 2023 01:12:54 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="A funny ChatGPT story" created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 18:07:33 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I wanted a simple chicken soup recipe, so I entered." created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 18:07:41 GMT">
						<outline text="Simple chicken soup " created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 18:07:56 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="And hit Return." created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 18:08:08 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It started drawing a picture. " created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 18:08:11 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I was fascinated, wondering what will it draw?" created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 18:08:24 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Here is an image of a cozy, homestyle bowl of chicken soup." created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 18:08:35 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/19/chickenSoup.png"/>
					<outline text="The caption was written by the AI." created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 18:36:48 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Very different from previous cartoonish pictures." created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 18:13:27 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I asked for the ingredients and got the &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/b94400e9-8aaf-4ec0-a247-f1407df036b4&quot;&gt;recipe&lt;/a&gt; I sought." created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 18:10:05 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Facebook offers AI participation a private group" created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 17:08:01 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I have a private group on Facebook, and just got &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/19/metaAiInvite.png&quot;&gt;this notice&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 17:08:05 GMT">
						<outline text="&quot;Join the waitlist for Meta AI in your group! Meta AI can save you time and spark conversations by answering questions posted in your group, linking people to the posts they find most helpful, and more. Sign up your group to be the first to get access when it becomes available in your region.&quot;" created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 17:14:49 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="When I clicked on the &lt;i&gt;Learn More&lt;/i&gt; button, this is what came back." created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 17:09:35 GMT">
						<outline text="A new way to get questions answered" created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 17:09:58 GMT">
							<outline text="Meta AI will comment on questions that haven't gotten an answer after one hour" created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 17:10:01 GMT"/>
							</outline>
						<outline text="Keep members engaged">
							<outline text="Meta AI's answers will summarize earlier group discussions and share past posts from the group, helping to build community and spark discussion" created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 17:10:03 GMT"/>
							</outline>
						<outline text="Stay in control">
							<outline text="You'll be able to delete any of Meta AI's comments, turn it off anytime, and customize it for your group" created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 17:10:04 GMT"/>
							</outline>
						</outline>
					<outline text="A thought -- this kind of feature could not have been offered a year ago. The online world and journalism would never have accepted it from Facebook. But now they're called Meta and that seems to matter. ChatGPT has created a new opening. Not sure I'm going to like it, esp since this is mostly a one-way group. It's not for discussions. But it's the only group they offered to, and I love this stuff and want to know more." created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 17:10:11 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I haven't told the members of the group that I've requested this. Am I obligated to do that?  " created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 17:11:19 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Also in private groups where people reveal personal info (not the purpose of this group) I could see where this would be very controversial." created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 17:12:29 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Music at The Colony" created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:16:48 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I went to my first since-pandemic live show, at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.colonywoodstock.com/&quot;&gt;The Colony&lt;/a&gt; in Woodstock. It's small venue that &lt;a href=&quot;https://buildingsofnewengland.com/2022/09/11/the-colony-hotel-1927/&quot;&gt;goes way back&lt;/a&gt;. It's basically a bar, with a stage and a small seating area which can hold about 50 people, seated at tables. Very comfortable space. Woodstock as you might imagine is a great place for live music, one of the reasons I moved here, the other being that it's a magnet for creative people, like a lot of the other places I've lived (New Orleans, Cambridge, Berkeley, Madison, Seattle, New York). But the pandemic squashed that, now maybe we're starting to come back. " created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:05:07 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="The Levin Brothers band at The Colony, Sunday night. " created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:33:44 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/19/levinBrothers.png"/>
					<outline text="I decided to risk it because a friend was playing last night, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tony_Levin&quot;&gt;Tony Levin&lt;/a&gt;, who I know through his wife, Andi. When I first met Tony, at a birthday dinner last year, I thought he was a banker. He's tall, an impressive-looking person, like the people who rose to be an executive at companies like IBM in the 80s. Just shows how deceiving appearances can be. He's an accomplished musician, and a very sweet, quiet person. Probably about as far from an IBM exec or banker as you can get. Until Sunday I had never seen him perform.  " created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:29:05 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The group I was with arrived early, and Tony was at the front door, greeting people as we entered, and immediately he made a very different impression. He seemed soft, hippieish, relaxed, smiling. Later I realized this may have been the first time I'd seen him in his element. And the show, a four-piece jazz band, with his brother &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pete_Levin&quot;&gt;Pete Levin&lt;/a&gt; on piano, started off playing (to my uneducated ear) pretty plain improvisational jazz. But as the show went on, I could see that this music had been composed, and had all kinds of themes running through it. It seemed to me the music had been cultivated over many years? " created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:09:36 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The Levins and friends, are roughly my age. I imagined they had been playing together as long as I have been making software. And I felt certain what I was seeing here were two very talented brothers, who have been performing together their whole lives, and there was something I had been trying to understand about myself, how I feel about my art, almost fifty years after I started. There is an important difference in how I do it at 68 vs how I did it when I was 22. Exactly how it is different, I'm probably too close to it to really understand, but seeing what I imagined to being something similar in two people I kind of know, that was thought-provoking." created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:21:14 GMT"/>
					<outline text="To me, music is as software probably is to most people who use it. I love it, but I don't have much of an idea of how it's made. The last few years I've been reintroduced to it in a new way, &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/12/01/144612.html?title=theBeatlesWereAnInvention&quot;&gt;thanks&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2022/01/25/144824.html?title=imABeatleshead&quot;&gt;the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.disneyplus.com/series/the-beatles-get-back/7DcWEeWVqrkE&quot;&gt;Get Back documentary&lt;/a&gt;, which gave us a view into the Beatles' creative process, something I wish I could have seen when I was much younger. The Beatles were the music my generation grew up with, but I never really even understood that there was a difference between a John song and a Paul song. " created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:13:46 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The second great influence has been Andrew Hickey's &lt;a href=&quot;https://500songs.com/&quot;&gt;500 songs&lt;/a&gt; podcast. Now I have so many more stories to go with the music that my life was formed by. And I have a feeling that attending this event on Sunday will turn out to be a similar influence. " created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:31:19 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Now, what music should I go see next? :boom:" created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:26:09 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PS: The concert was &lt;a href=&quot;https://nippertown.com/2023/12/18/concert-review-the-levin-brothers-the-linda-12-16-2023/&quot;&gt;reviewed&lt;/a&gt; by a professional." created="Tue, 19 Dec 2023 17:37:10 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 18" created="Mon, 18 Dec 2023 14:52:05 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="18">
				<outline text="We're easing into the holiday period now, just had my last meeting in 2023. I want to thank the people at &lt;a href=&quot;https://automattic.com/&quot;&gt;Automattic&lt;/a&gt; who helped get us over the top with FeedLand running in their fantastic cloud. The software is &lt;s&gt;finished&lt;/s&gt; running now, modulo bug fixes, docs, examples, developer tools, user evangelism, and working with other developers to make feeds live up to the enormous potential, which imho has been laying dormant for far too many years. Specifically thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/christie-j-wright/&quot;&gt;Christie Wright&lt;/a&gt; for taking this project under her wing. I can't believe how fast the software runs in its &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/&quot;&gt;new home&lt;/a&gt;. We're set up for a great 2024. :boom:" created="Mon, 18 Dec 2023 22:12:43 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/11/24/santaSecure.png"/>
				<outline text="Here's an &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/publicfolder/feedland/subscriptionLists/bluesky.opml&quot;&gt;OPML subscription list&lt;/a&gt; of the people I follow on Bluesky. " created="Mon, 18 Dec 2023 14:52:06 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 17" created="Sun, 17 Dec 2023 18:06:49 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="17">
				<outline text="I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://inessential.com/2023/12/17/on_mastodon_support_in_netnewswire&quot;&gt;Brent's piece&lt;/a&gt; on Mastodon and NetNewsWire, holding my breath hoping he'd arrive at the same answer I did, and he did. &quot;RSS&quot; is perfect for Mastodon, it supports RSS, as does NNW (of course), and that's imho exactly the right way to connect the two. That's how we're doing it in &quot;FeedLand&quot;. And in case Brent reads this, the same approach works for Bluesky, which has excellent RSS 2.0 support thanks to the work done by John Spurlock. The RSS 2.0 support there has more features than Mastodon's RSS feeds, but so far is not part of the Bluesky platform (I am urging them to adopt it). Here's the &lt;a href=&quot;https://rss.firesky.tv/?filter=from:brentsimmons.bsky.social&quot;&gt;feed&lt;/a&gt; for Brent's account on Bluesky, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://rss.firesky.tv/?filter=from:scripting.com&quot;&gt;mine&lt;/a&gt;. RSS is a perfect format for open non-silo'd social web apps. It gives us the most interop, most quickly. They should all be getting on board the RSS bandwagon, asap, imho. It's too good an opportunity to pass up. " created="Mon, 18 Dec 2023 03:40:45 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2019/01/10/loveRss.png"/>
				<outline text="One interesting way to make our feed readers smarter about working with Mastodon and Bluesky is to do the same kind of mapping from account to feed we do with sites that support &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2011/12/17/rssAutodiscovery.html&quot;&gt;feed discovery&lt;/a&gt;. When we see the user is trying to subscribe to a Mastodon account, we know where its feed is, so subscribe to that. Same for Bluesky. I expect we'll do that for FeedLand via the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/reallysimple/tree/main/demos/feedhunter&quot;&gt;FeedHunter package&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Mon, 18 Dec 2023 03:55:20 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The last episodes of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+%22the+crown%22&quot;&gt;The Crown&lt;/a&gt; were absolute garbage. It's so bad that you notice the music and how dramatic it is for absolutely no drama on screen. I'm surprised the actors were willing to go along with it. The only good part was where the Queen does standup near the end of the last episode. Something like 80 hours of TV behind them, and all of a sudden this stoic character, with no sense of humor whatsoever, who can't even cry, is bringing down the house. Oh please. I had to stick around to see how bad it can get, now you don't. If I had to give it a rating it would be &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/17/ohthehumanity.png&quot;&gt;Oh The Humanity&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 17 Dec 2023 18:24:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Picked a movie, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Last_Duel_(2021_film)&quot;&gt;The Last Duel&lt;/a&gt;, more or less at random, based largely on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Last_Duel_(2021_film)#Cast&quot;&gt;who&lt;/a&gt; was in it, and the fact that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/10/13/movies/the-last-duel-review.html?unlocked_article_code=1.Gk0.YAJS.AGdcc4Vz9G0C&amp;hpgrp=k-abar&amp;smid=url-share&quot;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt; gave it a critic's pick rating. It was good. But this isn't a movie review, it's a review of the user interface for choosing movies on streaming services. Why can't we integrate a site like &lt;a href=&quot;http://metacritic.com/&quot;&gt;Metacritic&lt;/a&gt; with Hulu, Netflix, Amazon, Max, AppleTV, et al. Just let me know what Metacritic says, and make it clickable, so I can see what the individual pubs had to say if I want more info. Don't make me look it up. People joke about how we spend our time scrolling around not watching anything. But it's true, I do it. Most of them are not worth the time, I suspect. But when you find one that's good, almost at random and even so had to do a lot of work to determine if it was worth a chance, and this has been going on for a decade, why doesn't one of these services just buy Metacritic and integrate it and make your users sing your praises everywhere online. How much could Metacritic cost? (They seem to be in trouble, a lot of the links generated by their CMS are broken.)" created="Sun, 17 Dec 2023 18:06:50 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/17/lastDuel.png"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 16" created="Sat, 16 Dec 2023 15:49:21 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="16">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com/search?q=howard+weaver+site%3Ascripting.com&quot;&gt;Howard Weaver&lt;/a&gt;, who was a giant &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sacbee.com/news/local/obituaries/article283114898.html&quot;&gt;both&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adn.com/alaska-news/2023/12/15/howard-weaver-editor-who-led-anchorage-daily-news-through-transformative-years-dies-at-73/&quot;&gt;journalism&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://editor.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;blogging&lt;/a&gt;, has &lt;a href=&quot;https://mediagazer.com/231215/p16#a231215p16&quot;&gt;died&lt;/a&gt;. A bunch of my pieces really pissed him off, &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2009/01/11/howInvestigativeResearchHa.html&quot;&gt;like this one&lt;/a&gt;. You didn't have to guess where you stood with him. And he listened when you told him he was all fucked up and full of it and didn't understand the first thing about what you said. He was from Alaska and I am from the east and west coasts. We were friends. I'lll miss his caustic and broad dismissals. I knew then and now that his heart was in it, and it is a good heart. &lt;span style=&quot;opacity: 0.4&quot;&gt;:heart:&lt;/span&gt;" created="Sat, 16 Dec 2023 18:18:15 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I listened to a podcast &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wnycstudios.org/podcasts/otm/episodes/celebrating-norman-lear-on-the-media&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norman_Lear&quot;&gt;Norman Lear&lt;/a&gt;. He's a great talker and story-teller and philosopher, and a great human being. I had never heard him interviewed before, or read anything written by him, but I watched all his TV shows in the 70s. The people in them were people from my neighborhood, but funnier. Why should it be surprising that the stories this man told in real life were the same ones he told in his scripts. Now I want to find more interviews with him. Great stuff.  " created="Sat, 16 Dec 2023 17:15:18 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2012/01/21/maude.jpg"/>
				<outline text="No matter how hard we try, no matter how much we want to make a difference, for most of us, all the difference we make happens when we're alive, there is no lasting value to our existence after we're gone. Most people know that, but some people (like me) struggle against it. " created="Sat, 16 Dec 2023 20:46:57 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I'm starting to scope out if it would be possible to create an Electron version of FeedLand. I had a &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/e825efea-c271-4c24-8594-01a03c21f3af&quot;&gt;conversation&lt;/a&gt; with ChatGPT about that. We did not arrive at a plan. FeedLand uses MySQL, I can't convert to another SQL, we have to use the same codebase in all versions. If, after reading the chat, you have ideas, please post a note &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/282&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  " created="Sat, 16 Dec 2023 15:49:22 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, here's the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedlandInstall&quot;&gt;feedlandInstall&lt;/a&gt; repo. It has full &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/feedlandInstall/blob/main/docs/setup.md&quot;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt; for setting up your own FeedLand instance. " created="Sat, 16 Dec 2023 15:57:25 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Disneyland on the internet" created="Sat, 16 Dec 2023 18:32:10 GMT" type="outline" metaImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/16/disneyLand.png">
					<outline text="I posted &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@davew/111591319022264255&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; on Mastodon." created="Sat, 16 Dec 2023 18:34:02 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Trying to wrap my head around the idea of Facebook in the Fediverse. This is a company that strives to deliver Disneyland on the internet. " created="Sat, 16 Dec 2023 18:32:16 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Who cares if a node blocks them, what's really going to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eVF4kebiks4&amp;t=50s&quot;&gt;bake your noodle&lt;/a&gt; is when they run access to the fediverse like Apple manages their App Store. " created="Sat, 16 Dec 2023 18:32:34 GMT"/>
					<outline text="And that is how it's going to work."/>
					<outline text="They're also going to implement Facebook-only APIs, and you're going to want to support them, because they give you access to many millions of people." created="Sat, 16 Dec 2023 18:32:53 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It might be better for the Fediverse if they're just bluffing, but don't be so sure you're going to like the way it works once they're fully in (if they ever are)." created="Sat, 16 Dec 2023 18:32:53 GMT"/>
					<outline text="How ChatGPT visualized Threads as I described it. " created="Sat, 16 Dec 2023 18:46:14 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/16/threads.png"/>
					<outline text="PS: &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2023/12/07/140505.html&quot;&gt;Bluesky&lt;/a&gt;, I'm beggin you -- get those RSS 2.0 feeds in there asap, and hook up with Mastodon now. Let's go. It'll be so much fun and give people all they want without putting Facebook in the middle. " created="Sat, 16 Dec 2023 18:41:08 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 15" created="Fri, 15 Dec 2023 15:51:27 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="15">
				<outline text="I think now, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/scripting.com/post/3kgmjvmt3ok24&quot;&gt;if Bluesky announced&lt;/a&gt; outbound RSS 2.0 support, really good RSS support, they'd blow the whole thing up." created="Fri, 15 Dec 2023 22:32:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="You're supposed to know" created="Fri, 15 Dec 2023 15:55:58 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Not sure if you all know, I was a math major in college. " created="Fri, 15 Dec 2023 15:51:28 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It was the weirdest choice for me because, until my first semester of college, not been interested in math. I thought it was boring. " created="Fri, 15 Dec 2023 16:04:54 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Turns out math &lt;i&gt;wasn't&lt;/i&gt; boring, the teachers were boring. " created="Fri, 15 Dec 2023 16:05:12 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I had a math professor in freshman year, at Lehman College, in the Bronx, who showed me first that I could do it, and then led me to the discovery that hey this is amazing. So I majored in it. " created="Fri, 15 Dec 2023 16:05:22 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I didn't do great, B-minus average. But there was one class I got an A in, a summer class (in New Orleans), and it was the only class I took. I think that made a big difference, I could just focus on this one subject. My mind has always been like that, I like to zoom in on things. " created="Fri, 15 Dec 2023 16:05:43 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Anyway, I remember one day, almost 50 years ago, the professor was standing in front of the class, fuming, angry. We had all turned in proofs that didn't work and that included grad students, he pointed out (I was an undergrad). " created="Fri, 15 Dec 2023 15:59:49 GMT"/>
					<outline text="He said this: &quot;You're supposed to know when you've proven it.&quot; " created="Fri, 15 Dec 2023 16:00:15 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Might be the most important thing I learned from all the math. " created="Fri, 15 Dec 2023 16:00:19 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It's not math if your proof doesn't work. " created="Fri, 15 Dec 2023 16:00:24 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;b&gt;Next story&lt;/b&gt;" created="Fri, 15 Dec 2023 16:00:27 GMT"/>
					<outline text="A few years later I'm a grad student in Computer Science, and a teaching assistant for a class in assembly language. First semester I was learning it along with the students, although I had already had a class in assembly, you don't really learn it until you teach it. " created="Fri, 15 Dec 2023 16:00:34 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Anyway, I promised to post example code on the door of my office for students to copy if they needed help on an assignment. I did. When I got back, one of my office mates, whose name I remember to this day, was, like my math prof at Tulane, fuming, this time at me. " created="Fri, 15 Dec 2023 16:09:05 GMT"/>
					<outline text="She said this -- you have to run your code before you post it. " created="Fri, 15 Dec 2023 16:03:13 GMT"/>
					<outline text="There was fire coming out of her eyes. " created="Fri, 15 Dec 2023 16:03:19 GMT"/>
					<outline text="She was right. I was shamed. And obviously never forgot it." created="Fri, 15 Dec 2023 16:03:25 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Same story really. A proof that doesn't work isn't math. And code that doesn't run isn't software.  " created="Fri, 15 Dec 2023 16:04:25 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 14" created="Thu, 14 Dec 2023 14:40:08 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="14">
				<outline text="Not a lotta yadda yadda. Heard in a commercial and I had to write it down. We now return to our regularly scheduled program." created="Fri, 15 Dec 2023 02:57:49 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="So, with the &quot;Bloggers&quot; category not yet ready for prime time, I've replaced it with my &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?river=true&amp;screenname=davewiner&amp;catname=all&quot;&gt;All category&lt;/a&gt; from FeedLand, changing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/14/newstab.png&quot;&gt;title to News&lt;/a&gt;. I know it's confusing. I think there's going to be a fair amount of this kind of shuffling in the weeks and months ahead, as we try to fit news and blogs together in interesting ways. You can read the Bloggers category on &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;news.scripting.com&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 14 Dec 2023 22:02:46 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, even with &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;News&lt;/a&gt; no longer on the home page of scripting.com, it still gets more hits than the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/&quot;&gt;home page&lt;/a&gt;. There's something there to look at. I want to do more to integrate the blog and the news. To make some kind of new publication that has a bunch of voices, yet doesn't spin out of control. " created="Thu, 14 Dec 2023 21:05:51 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://forms.gle/wNEiUxkuAijRBY4L7&quot;&gt;Braintrust query&lt;/a&gt;: What if I asked you for a list of your favorite blogs? It could be a podcast, or a tech news site. Something you think every Scripting News reader should see when there's something new? Just curious to know what news sources people think are the most interesting, valuable. " created="Thu, 14 Dec 2023 20:35:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I've been re-bingeing the whole &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Crown_(TV_series)&quot;&gt;Crown series&lt;/a&gt;, anticipating that there was going to be a new and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metacritic.com/tv/the-crown/season-6/&quot;&gt;final series&lt;/a&gt; of episodes, out today. I started watching the new one, and all of a sudden the two princes, William and Harry, are actual people. I have a lot of trouble with that, because of course I remember when they were born. However I'm pretty sure I'll go all the way through. There are a lot of hours of entertainment in The Crown and a few scenes that are truly spectacular (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rBwQICiGRmw&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/a&gt;). I remember the really good ones of course, but there's an awful lot of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/schlock&quot;&gt;schlock&lt;/a&gt;. One scene I had not remembered was a pretty good illustration of how fucked up people can be. Princess Diana had just gone on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vqe-SuyAyWI&quot;&gt;tour of NYC&lt;/a&gt;, her first international tour on her own, and it was (surprising to her) a huge success. Another British invasion. The people of NYC loved Diana (at least in the show, I don't remember this, I was living in California at the time). So she comes home, and the royal family, instead of cheering her, were angry with her for being so charming. Go figure. Her husband, Prince Charles is yelling at her and he asks her if she ever considered how &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Queen_Camilla&quot;&gt;Camilla&lt;/a&gt;, Charles' one true love, would feel about Diana being so popular. Diana is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/gobsmacked&quot;&gt;gobsmacked&lt;/a&gt; (as am I). Why would she think of that. How totally fucked up is that. Why should anyone, being themselves, being happy, worry about how anyone else might feel about their happiness? I've been in Diana's position a few times, achieving success, much deserved, and was reminded that this upset people who (apparently) didn't want me to succeed? I have even been asked that question. If you ever feel that way, that someone else's happiness is meant to make you feel bad, remember Carl Sagan's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wupToqz1e2g&quot;&gt;Pale Blue Dot&lt;/a&gt; video. Really, &lt;i&gt;no one cares&lt;/i&gt; if you are offended by someone else's happiness. Remember, none of this stuff amounts to anything in the big picture. We're very small, all of us put together, in the grand scheme of things. So if you're happy, good for you! And one other question -- is re-bingeing actually a word?? &lt;span style=&quot;opacity: 0.6&quot;&gt;:smile:&lt;/span&gt;" created="Thu, 14 Dec 2023 14:40:09 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2019/12/24/santa.png"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2023/12/13.html#a140021&quot;&gt;Yesterday&lt;/a&gt; I addressed the How Do I Write question, now let me address Why I Write. I write at least partially because I know there are good people who love my writing. Anyway, I love to write because there are people who love to read. And I feel connected to them. My mother was the prototype. We weren't very close in actual life, but she was a devoted reader of my blog. It gave us a connection. And I assume all daily or nightly readers of this blog have that kind of connection, whether I hear from them or not. And sometimes you do &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tanyaweiman/status/1735267625691701440&quot;&gt;hear from them&lt;/a&gt;, and that's especially lovely." created="Thu, 14 Dec 2023 21:58:03 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The tech industry, to the extent that they remember me, resents me. I get that. It's sad, because I do care, I am one of them, as Diana was one of the royals (see above). " created="Thu, 14 Dec 2023 21:58:18 GMT" type="outline" isComment="true"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 13" created="Wed, 13 Dec 2023 13:52:17 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="13">
				<outline text="I'm pretty sure federation in social media is the wrong bet. We have to think more broadly. What are the benefits we want from interop in social media. Federation isn't itself a benefit. It's an idea hatched by techies who aren't thinking about how people actually use these systems and which features are valued and which are problematic. Imho, what's valued is the ability to publish something quickly, and without much fuss, and follow others, again easily without having to have a deep understanding of how these things are architected. No one but us programming plumbers cares. I think the idea of &lt;i&gt;conversation&lt;/i&gt; not only is overrated, but it's where all the problems are, where all the abuse happens. If we focus on the benefits, quick dissemination of news, and the power of the individual to choose their sources and share them with others -- that's where the juice is. Imho of course, ymmv, praise Murphy, I am not a lawyer and my mother loved me, even though at times it was hard to tell. &lt;span style=&quot;opacity: 0.4&quot;&gt;:heart:&lt;/span&gt;" created="Wed, 13 Dec 2023 13:52:18 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/13/frozenOrangeJuiceFromHannafords.png"/>
				<outline text="I had a long chat yesterday with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+%22Guy+Kawasaki%22&quot;&gt;Guy Kawasaki&lt;/a&gt;. Along the way he wondered how I find something to write every day. The answer -- I don't find things to write, it doesn't work that way. I don't sit down in the morning and say OK now I have to write 1000 words and it doesn't matter what it's about. If I have something to say I say it. And as you can tell, I usually do have something to say, because I'm always thinking and planning, trying to figure out what I want, or if I already know, how to get other people to help me get there. A lot of trial and error, let's see if this way of putting it works, or that one, etc. There's a slogan for this -- &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2009/08/09/narrateYourWork.html&quot;&gt;Narrate Your Work&lt;/a&gt; -- and my work is narratable and creates its own record because I do my work right &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2023/12/13.html#a140021&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, because much of my work involves other people. Actually all of it. And if I can get the people I need to listen to me, ie read my blog, then we can work together (a recurring theme) to make great communication systems out of the web and avoid flushing our future down the toilet, which we always seem to be doing. " created="Wed, 13 Dec 2023 14:00:21 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2019/12/24/searsCatalog.png"/>
				<outline text="Another time I blog about is when I figure something out that I've been trying to understand for a long time, in some cases my whole life. That still happens. The other day I found myself talking with a friend about love, why when someone says &quot;I love you&quot; it doesn't mean what it seems to. Love comes from understanding someone well enough that you know what they desire, what they ache to have, and you to try to help them get it. See all the qualifications in that. Try. Help. Them. In other words, you can love someone when you know them. And you don't give them what they want, you help them get it. You can't love someone who your whole idea of is based on a dream you have about them. That's different. Anyway, lots more to say about all this. It's a recurring topic. It might be the &lt;i&gt;only&lt;/i&gt; topic. Someday they'll invent an AI that can analyze my writing and tell me if I've ever written for any other purpose than being worthy of love. " created="Wed, 13 Dec 2023 14:25:03 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I miss &quot;Frontier&quot; so much. Debugging its database was several orders of magnitude less work than the Node+SQL setup where the runtime and the database are very far apart. In Frontier the database and the language are the same thing. And because Frontier did the rational thing with synchronization, it was handled in the kernel, the code you write doesn't have to worry about it, you can write reasonably readable code. In Node it's a real chore to come back to some code you worked on last a while back. Makes my mind tired, but I do it, because it's where I work now. " created="Wed, 13 Dec 2023 16:15:29 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2019/12/26/frontier.png"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 12" created="Tue, 12 Dec 2023 14:44:30 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="12">
				<outline text="If &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.threads.net/@davew/post/C0xvallMmgn&quot;&gt;Threads&lt;/a&gt; supported outbound RSS 2.0 feeds we could avoid the dominance Twitter had over news for so long. There's nothing hard or magical about it, the technology of RSS is simple, and well understood by thousands of developers." created="Wed, 13 Dec 2023 02:56:24 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="My idea of a friend is someone who laughs at my jokes." created="Tue, 12 Dec 2023 17:56:36 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Chuck did a &lt;a href=&quot;https://arc.net/boost/B3857C94-AA7F-4FC3-9FE2-98104E93DE1E&quot;&gt;Dark Mode for FeedLand&lt;/a&gt; &quot;boost&quot; for the Arc browser." created="Tue, 12 Dec 2023 14:44:31 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Working my way through loose-ends. The feed-only &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?myfeed&quot;&gt;editor&lt;/a&gt; built into FeedLand has now been &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/12/feedOnlyEditorScreenShot.png&quot;&gt;converted to mobile&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Tue, 12 Dec 2023 16:18:22 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 11" created="Mon, 11 Dec 2023 13:37:55 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="11">
				<outline text="Do you have a feed-only blog?" created="Mon, 11 Dec 2023 20:58:09 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Obviously, at some point Musk will sell Twitter to Zuckerberg." created="Mon, 11 Dec 2023 14:58:17 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Something that should make you cry. So many of our friends on the web are happy to let Facebook run the new Twitter. What is wrong with you. I don't know any better way to put it. Quitting Twitter is pointless, meaningless, powerless. But not building Threads for Facebook is not meaningless. For once can people look out for the future, keep the window open for independence for writers and developers, and let us try out some new ideas that might not be something Zuckerberg would love? Come on already. This is the saddest moment, when there's so much possibility, and you all are ready to just throw it away. (And no, I don't believe for a minute they're going to do anything that helps the Fediverse. I know the playbook. Saying you'll be open is what you do until you dominate, then it's just business. Truth is it's always just business, and saying you're going to be open at this stage of network development &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; good for business.)" created="Mon, 11 Dec 2023 14:27:47 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2021/12/24/dontLookUp.png"/>
				<outline text="Starting in September or so I start thinking about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+boty&quot;&gt;Blogger of the Year&lt;/a&gt;, a thing I do at the end of most years. Not too many people care, but it's a good thing for me to do -- to review what makes a blog the most interesting and valuable of the year, to me -- obviously. We all should name a BOTY, or give out any award we feel is deserved. People think &quot;well it's just me and I don't matter&quot; -- which is totally true, and is why you might as well pick someone. At least &lt;i&gt;they'll&lt;/i&gt; know you appreciate them. And it gets you to think about what you value, which builds over time to a better understanding of everything. Last year I &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2023/01/01.html#a032915&quot;&gt;chose&lt;/a&gt; Heather Cox Richardson, whose &lt;a href=&quot;https://heathercoxrichardson.substack.com/&quot;&gt;Substack site&lt;/a&gt; is a constant read for me. Every night an email arrives, at different times, and if I'm up and in the mood, I'll spend a few minutes with HCR and it's always illuminating. She was my choice last year because her writing re-kindled my interest in American history, and I started reading books on most slavery, something that was seriously missing from my NYC education, and is so important to who we are as a country. " created="Mon, 11 Dec 2023 13:47:10 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Before moving on to this year's BOTY, I thought HCR could help figure out how we could move past merely reporting on Trump's danger to democracy, something that was clear going back to 2015, the news could start reporting on The Resistance, what we're doing to prevent the end of democracy. And in order for that to happen, we have to do newsworthy things for them to write about! We're not doing that. It started out well, with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2017_Women%27s_March#:~:text=The%20Women's%20March%20was%20a,to%20the%20rights%20of%20women.&quot;&gt;Woman's March on January 20, 2017&lt;/a&gt;, but that was it. We can and must keep showing up, and I'm not advocating huge marches, I want to see neighborhood-level marching. Once a month, rain or shine, we all walk (if possible) or drive to our voting places, where there will be music, food, people with ideas, dancing, whatever you like. Making civic participation a regular thing. You go because you want to be there. Not against something but &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; all of us. All we have to do is figure out how this works, how to beat the drum, to get the ball rolling. The idea is that if we got close to 100 percent voter participation, our democracy would be in the best shape it's been in probably since inception. I had another idea that's worth considering. We should all wear the same button, just a picture, no slogans, an idea of what we stand for as Americans. It could be an American flag, or it could be a photo of &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2016/12/30/theMlkButtonsArrived.html&quot;&gt;Martin Luther King&lt;/a&gt;. The latter was my choice. People love the button, but it didn't catch on. If we all did, it's omission would be noticed, and we'd know there's someone we should talk with about America and offer them a free button, nicely, if they'll put it on right now. Anyway, I'm putting this out there again, and I'll keep doing it. " created="Mon, 11 Dec 2023 13:59:26 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2020/06/17/mlkButton.png"/>
				<outline text="There's an interesting recent development in the world of feeds and blogs -- blogs that are only feeds. Designed to be read in feed readers of all sizes and shapes. I have a few of these myself. My &lt;a href=&quot;http://data.feedland.org/feeds/davewiner.xml&quot;&gt;linkblog&lt;/a&gt; for example. Also, FeedLand provides an outbound &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?myfeed&quot;&gt;feed to every user&lt;/a&gt;, which meets all the qualifications of a feed-only blog. " created="Mon, 11 Dec 2023 13:37:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Working together for writers" created="Mon, 11 Dec 2023 14:18:11 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I want to say this as loudly and clearly as I can. If we want independent writing on the web to flourish, we need our own search engine, to help us find each other, and build associations of writers, so we can influence each other, and help developers create new tools for all writers. Or simply to find something I wrote about 15 years ago, so I can refer back to it. I really don't have a good way yet to find stuff I've written. It's all there on the web, for crying out loud. " created="Mon, 11 Dec 2023 14:18:17 GMT" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2020/06/29/alice.png"/>
					<outline text="More important, we need to learn to work together, we do very very little of that. It's amazingly difficult to get a new idea heard by other developers. This is a huge problem, it's why we've always been dominated by big companies who don't care about what we do. " created="Mon, 11 Dec 2023 14:18:49 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Start with a search engine for bloggers. I'll help. And let's do lots of them, so no one can stand in the way of trying out new ideas. " created="Mon, 11 Dec 2023 14:18:50 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="General note" created="Mon, 11 Dec 2023 14:20:16 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="If you develop one of the ideas I write about here, tell me about it!" created="Mon, 11 Dec 2023 14:20:22 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Let me try it out. Lately there have been people doing this, but for some reason I don't find out about the work until it's too late." created="Mon, 11 Dec 2023 14:20:33 GMT"/>
					<outline text="What are people thinking? If I ask for something, there's a reason -- I want to learn from it." created="Mon, 11 Dec 2023 14:20:54 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I think programmers are shy. You need to stop doing that. :smile:" created="Mon, 11 Dec 2023 14:23:23 GMT"/>
					<outline text="And of course I'll share what I learn here on my blog, of course." created="Mon, 11 Dec 2023 14:21:15 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="A lighter note" created="Tue, 12 Dec 2023 02:34:02 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Former House Speaker Kevin McCarthy has officially pledged his fealty to former President Donald Trump in the 2024 presidential election  despite some concerns about Trumps messaging." created="Tue, 12 Dec 2023 02:34:18 GMT"/>
					<outline text="A meeting of minds." created="Tue, 12 Dec 2023 02:34:29 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/11/aMeetingOfMinds.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 10" created="Sun, 10 Dec 2023 13:09:07 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="10">
				<outline text="How we got here" created="Sun, 10 Dec 2023 14:03:53 GMT" type="outline" description="The idea of FeedLand is to see what would happen if instead of building something complicated around conversations, we limited ourselves to what feeds could do and then see where we could go with that. ">
					<outline text="First an apology. To all the people who clicked on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?river=true&amp;screenname=davewiner&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; to a FeedLand page on a phone in the past, I am sorry to have put you through that. Now that it works on phones, I can see how nice it is to be able to skim the news while you're out and about. " created="Sun, 10 Dec 2023 14:03:57 GMT"/>
					<outline text="When you're working alone on a huge product like this, you have to keep your head down and focus on the problem of the moment. There have been some huge ones this year. The product's identity system had to be replaced, while people were using it, because Twitter was getting ready to explode their API. Then the move from a Digital Ocean server to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.wpvip.com/technical-references/node-js/&quot;&gt;Automattic VIP server&lt;/a&gt; required fairly large pieces of the software to be rewritten, again, in-place, while feedland.org continued to run. There's a huge change between writing software for a server where the runtime environment doesn't include local storage. Everything has to be stored in a database. " created="Sun, 10 Dec 2023 14:13:04 GMT"/>
					<outline text="All the pieces were rewritten, one by one, until we discovered another that needed to be rewritten. And then at almost the last minute I &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2023/10/09/135922.html&quot;&gt;decided&lt;/a&gt; we had to have &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2023/10/21/143159.html&quot;&gt;reading lists&lt;/a&gt;, because of the kind of feed network I wanted to build with this product. And one more thing, let's get this mofo working on mobile devices as it was meant to, which turned out to be not as hard as I imagined, and very nice to have. " created="Sun, 10 Dec 2023 14:14:01 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The new version of the software with all the new code turned on is at &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/&quot;&gt;feedland.com&lt;/a&gt;. That's the version that's running on Automattic's servers, and should be able to scale to far more users. The docs aren't converted yet, but the software is basically the same. You should read the &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.feedland.org/firstThings.opml&quot;&gt;first page&lt;/a&gt; of the docs, at least, so you aren't surprised to find out that your subscriptions are public. This is not the usual kind of feed product, it's more of a community of news users. Just like a social network, you can see what other people are reading. The idea of FeedLand is to see what would happen if instead of building something complicated around conversations, we limited ourselves to what feeds could do and then see where we could go with that. That's what FeedLand is. " created="Sun, 10 Dec 2023 14:09:35 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PS: I can't believe how fast Automattic's system is. I don't understand how it does all that work in so little time. " created="Sun, 10 Dec 2023 14:23:48 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PPS: The menus are different on the mobile version, by necessity. I included the Bookmarks menu, it's really important to have the news you want to read available one click away in mobile. I imagine doing setup on your home computer, with links you'll use when you're using the mobile version. " created="Sun, 10 Dec 2023 14:25:46 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The mobile-ready &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/&quot;&gt;FeedLand&lt;/a&gt; is ready to use.  " created="Sun, 10 Dec 2023 13:53:34 GMT" type="outline" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/10/feedlandScreen1.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 9" created="Sat, 09 Dec 2023 13:08:02 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="09">
				<outline text="I've been working all week on the mobile version of &quot;FeedLand&quot;. It's the best mobile version of anything I've done. I finally figured out how this works, I think. So if you're using FeedLand on a phone, sometime in the next 24-48 hours you may see a significant improvement. I will of course write a blog post about it with screen shots when it does become available. " created="Sat, 09 Dec 2023 13:38:24 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2022/12/01/santa.png"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/281&quot;&gt;Braintrust query&lt;/a&gt;: Yesterday there was a meeting with people from Meta about their plans to support ActivityPub in Threads. A bunch of people I follow went there saying they'd report on what transpired. I haven't seen one yet. Pointers appreciated." created="Sat, 09 Dec 2023 15:05:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="After listening to Thursday's &lt;a href=&quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/il/podcast/ive-got-bidens-daisy-ad-and-trump-is-disqualified-12-7-23/id1633301179?i=1000637762872&quot;&gt;Countdown podcast&lt;/a&gt; I'd like to read a short book about the presidency after the Lincoln assassination, leading to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Impeachment_of_Andrew_Johnson&quot;&gt;impeachment&lt;/a&gt; and trial of his successor, Andrew Johnson. This is where the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fourteenth_Amendment_to_the_United_States_Constitution&quot;&gt;14th Amendment&lt;/a&gt; came from. Some days Olbermann really nails it, this was one of those episodes, left me wanting more. This may be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Impeached-President-Andrew-Johnson-Lincolns/dp/1416547509&quot;&gt;the book&lt;/a&gt;, I'm still looking for suggestions. I am not a history scholar, just an interested citizen. " created="Sat, 09 Dec 2023 13:56:13 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="How I know Twitter was great. When something was going on anywhere, any kind of thing, I'd go to Twitter and it happened there 14 minutes ago. It was the pulse of the news. And somehow they couldn't figure out how to make a business of that! Amazing." created="Sat, 09 Dec 2023 16:19:25 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Heard on ski lift: &quot;I'm not particular, I'll work with anyone as long as the goal is to keep one company from controlling something worthwhile.&quot;" created="Sun, 10 Dec 2023 02:19:33 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="An alert to readers who remember how great it was to have Twitter be the meeting place for news people and their stories prior to the Musk takeover. I think Facebook's new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.threads.net/&quot;&gt;Threads service&lt;/a&gt; is poised to replace Twitter in this role, once they add an API that allows pubs to post links to their stories on their service. We will, in a few weeks or months, wish we had proactively formed a non-Facebook news service, a place where by convention we know we can get links to the hot stories as they become available. I think Bluesky is the perfect place to go for this now, but it would require the company behind the service to work with news orgs and independent software developers to quickly build the network. It's possible. They already have the API, we just need to do a little marketing. It's even possible without the help of Bluesky itself, if a few leaders from the news industry got involved, either individuals like Jay Rosen, Emily Bell or Jeff Jarvis, or Richard Gingras who leads news at Google (who thankfully doesn't have a horse in this race) or a big news org or two, acting proactively against turning this valuable space over to a much untrusted big tech company like Facebook. (I don't call them Meta, I think that was a con to give them cover for exactly a move like this, who would ever trust Facebook with such power after what happened in the 2016 election, but &lt;i&gt;Meta&lt;/i&gt; is just confusing enough.)" created="Sat, 09 Dec 2023 13:18:27 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/09/cuteCat.png" imageLink="http://scripting.com/2023/12/09/134017.html"/>
				<outline text="Follow-up on &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2023/12/08.html#a140102&quot;&gt;yesterday's&lt;/a&gt; bits about The Atlantic. 1. It is available on newsstands, I did a search and found I could pick it up at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://stores.barnesandnoble.com/store/3405&quot;&gt;Barnes &amp; Noble&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/1200+Ulster+Ave,+Kingston,+NY+12401/@41.9651793,-74.0275494,13z/data=!4m6!3m5!1s0x89dd0f2c78ed7179:0xe5adbff00343979c!8m2!3d41.9651793!4d-73.9889256!16s%2Fg%2F11bw442113?entry=ttu&quot;&gt;in Kingston&lt;/a&gt;, a 1/2 hour drive from where I live. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/the-atlantic-magazine/1104733038?ean=2940000280874&quot;&gt;$2.20 per issue&lt;/a&gt;. A fair price imho. I advertised I'd be willing to pay $5 to read all the articles in the special issue about the second Trump presidency. Driving one hour round trip raises the price considerably. 2. A couple of readers wrote to say that the full text of the Atlantic is available in their RSS 2.0 feed. I knew that, but that isn't the issue. It's very generous of The Atlantic to offer their publication that way, but I'm not looking for a free ride, just a fair deal. I might want to subscribe to The Atlantic, what better way to offer it than on a piece-price basis. I might end up paying more than the subscription price. If I was doing that regularly you bet I'd subscribe. 3. I really dislike the term &quot;micropayments.&quot; It's disrespectful of the customer's money, and businesses that do that don't deserve our patronage. When you add up the per-article expense of great pubs like The New Yorker or The Atlantic there would be nothing micro about the money I'd spend. It's the commitment I want to avoid. Magazines are notoriously difficult to unsub from. I'd rather pay more and stay anonymous to them. Anyway, as always thanks to my readers who always offer up good food for thought! :smile:" created="Sat, 09 Dec 2023 13:08:03 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/08/atlanticCover.png"/>
				<outline text="Grandma and the cat" created="Sat, 09 Dec 2023 13:40:17 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="&quot;I'd like a drawing of a sewing room with a perplexed grandma looking at a cat who was playing with balls of yarn and spools of threads, all unwound. The grandma is tangled up in the threads. The cat is smiling, mischievously as if she planned to entangle grandma like this!&quot;" created="Sat, 09 Dec 2023 13:41:26 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Margaret the cat and grandma in the sewing room." created="Sat, 09 Dec 2023 13:40:24 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/09/grandmaAndTheCat.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 8" created="Fri, 08 Dec 2023 14:01:01 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="08">
				<outline text="Where is the Resistance?" created="Fri, 08 Dec 2023 15:40:19 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="We know journalists are not The Resistance, which begs the question -- who is and why aren't journalists searching for them?" created="Fri, 08 Dec 2023 15:02:59 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I heard &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeffrey_Goldberg&quot;&gt;Jeffrey Goldberg&lt;/a&gt;, the Editor in Chief of The Atlantic, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2023/12/08/1218100652/writers-at-the-atlantic-examine-what-trumps-second-term-could-look-like&quot;&gt;on NPR&lt;/a&gt; this morning talking about their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2024/01/donald-trump-second-term-policies/676176/&quot;&gt;special edition&lt;/a&gt; about what a second Trump presidency would be like. I'd love to read it but I am not a subscriber. I'd like to hear Goldberg interviewed on what happened to buying an issue of a magazine just because I want to read it. I think it's actually a bigger story, because realistically, it's probably good journalism but won't do anything to prevent a second Trump term, where hearing him explain why they have such a bizarre economic model might help them try another approach and thus provide greater service, and very likely increase their revenue because it would give readers a way to ease into subscribing." created="Fri, 08 Dec 2023 14:01:02 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/08/atlanticCover.png"/>
				<outline text="Goldberg said they are not &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/797774d7-4770-46b8-863d-b7c62da4261c&quot;&gt;The Resistance&lt;/a&gt;, they're journalists. Well then my question is what good are you exactly and why are you using up all the airtime? Why is NPR even bothering to interview you. He said it clearly, he was just trying to save his conscience for after the Nazis came to power in the US. We have bigger issues than Jeffrey Goldberg's conscience. Why doesn't NPR and The Atlantic go out and find The Freaking Resistance and introduce us to them. My grandfather said something to me when I was a little boy, with such clarity, I can never forget it. He said David, when the Nazis come (he was sure they would) you need to go up on the roof with a gun, and shoot them. He knew. He didn't say &quot;David, run&quot; or &quot;David, write an article in The Atlantic so you have a clear conscience.&quot; He said I should fight. With guns. That was the lesson he learned from his experience. So where is our Resistance? What the F are we waiting for?  " created="Fri, 08 Dec 2023 14:39:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&quot;Wait and see what happens&quot; is a losing strategy. By the time you figured out what happened, if you ever do, it's too late." created="Fri, 08 Dec 2023 16:24:28 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Using Threads is giving up" created="Fri, 08 Dec 2023 15:33:39 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Cross-posted &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.threads.net/@davew/post/C0mLHffsbNK&quot;&gt;from Threads&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Fri, 08 Dec 2023 15:35:20 GMT">
						<outline text="I have a lot of trouble calling Facebook some other name." created="Fri, 08 Dec 2023 15:33:47 GMT"/>
						<outline text="I feel like I'm being used." created="Fri, 08 Dec 2023 15:33:56 GMT"/>
						<outline text="The company is still the same company it was when they locked up Facebook and fed us to the enemy during the 2016 election. I haven't forgotten." created="Fri, 08 Dec 2023 15:33:59 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Why are we letting them build our new online home if that's what this is supposed to be?" created="Fri, 08 Dec 2023 15:34:12 GMT"/>
						<outline text="This is part of recognizing the stakes in the next election folks, this is something you can do about it." created="Fri, 08 Dec 2023 15:34:16 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Using Threads is as dangerous as voting for Trump." created="Fri, 08 Dec 2023 15:34:21 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 7" created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 13:24:58 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="07">
				<outline text="Twitter poisoned our minds with the idea that by taking away the basic features of writing on the web they were encouraging people to write shorter, better, more to-the-point posts and that would make communication on the web like poetry. It was a very zen-like mystical idea, and imho totally wrong. And it's still repeated as if it were gospel -- it's a typical response when I beg for a standard that is more realistic, that incorporates the &lt;a href=&quot;http://textcasting.org/&quot;&gt;basic features of web writing&lt;/a&gt;: simple styles, links, optional titles, enclosures, the ability to edit and unlimited length. The fallacy of this response is that you are free to write however you want, if you feel your ideas are better communicated in short messages, go ahead. I want to use all the tools in my writing. And if you don't want to read all that I write or any of it, there are tools that make that easy. So everyone wins, and you don't have to try to impose your ideas of religiously pure writing on anyone but yourself. " created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 13:24:59 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2019/12/24/santa.png"/>
				<outline text="A &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corollary&quot;&gt;corrollary&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://textcasting.org/&quot;&gt;textcasting&lt;/a&gt; philosophy is that I should be able to use any writing tool I like to post to the web, and have it flow where ever I want. The idea of being forced to use a teeny little edit box to write my wonderful prose is as silly as bunding a word processor with a printer, and forcing you to use that editor if you want to print it with that printer. If I sent you a document written for my Brand X printer but you had Brand Y, sorry -- you can't read it. I'm at the point in my life where I have to explain to young folk how great things were when I was their age, but it's true in this case, when I was in my 20s and 30s, there were simple standards for text, and you could print documents produced by any writing tool on any printer. And as a result a wide variety of writing tools and editors were available, and there was lots of innovation in a very short period of time because everyone had competition they could learn from and had to keep up with. Now there's no reason for Twitter, Facebook, Threads, Instagram, Bluesky, Mastodon or whatever to improve their editors because after all you don't have any choice. That's another important facet of textcasting that we borrow from podcasting -- lots of ways to create and lots of ways to listen mean things &lt;i&gt;can&lt;/i&gt; get better. With lock-in, they can't. " created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 13:38:32 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Why we want feeds in Bluesky" created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 14:05:05 GMT" type="outline" description="Feeds should be the baseline of compatibility between social media platforms.">
					<outline text="My old friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+%22chuck+shotton%22&quot;&gt;Chuck Shotton&lt;/a&gt; just &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/mrwheat.bsky.social&quot;&gt;showed up&lt;/a&gt; on Bluesky. " created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 14:05:13 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I love Chuck. We've been through a lot together over a long time. " created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 14:05:28 GMT"/>
					<outline text="We had a ton of fun in the early days of the web on the Mac. Chuck wrote the HTTP server we all used. And he loved Frontier, so we made our products work incredibly well together. " created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 14:05:40 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Those were the days! :smile:" created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 14:14:37 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Anyway, of course I immediately followed Chuck in Bluesky, but then I realize, I can also follow him &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?feedurl=https%3A%2F%2Frss.firesky.tv%2F%3Ffilter%3Dfrom%3Amrwheat.bsky.social&quot;&gt;in FeedLand&lt;/a&gt; because thanks to John Spurlock, &lt;a href=&quot;https://rss.firesky.tv/?filter=from:mrwheat.bsky.social&quot;&gt;we have feeds&lt;/a&gt; for every freaking Bluesky user. " created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 14:06:13 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+spurlock&quot;&gt;Spurlock&lt;/a&gt; is a gifted programmer, like Chuck, who thinks creatively and doesn't mind priming the pump of a bootstrap, something Chuck and I have done many times in the past. (Chuck is an largely uncredited contributor to the bootstraps of RSS, XML-RPC, podcasting, object databases, content management systems, hey pretty much everything I've worked on since 1994 or so.)" created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 16:09:19 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Okay, now I get to the point. " created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 14:08:11 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I want to build with confidence on the feed connection with Bluesky. Today I know the ability to &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?feedurl=https%3A%2F%2Frss.firesky.tv%2F%3Ffilter%3Dfrom%3Ascripting.com&quot;&gt;subscribe&lt;/a&gt; to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://rss.firesky.tv/?filter=from:scripting.com&quot;&gt;Bluesky RSS 2.0 feed&lt;/a&gt; is there, but will it be there in the future? I would feel better if the feed support were built-into Bluesky, part of its basic feature set. Another very simple API that gets ideas out of Bluesky and anywhere feeds go, which is, as you know, everywhere. " created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 14:08:21 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Feeds should be the baseline of compatibility between social media platforms. " created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 14:09:34 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Working with Spurlock, we have given Bluesky a huge headstart, a lead in what I hope will be a race to feed support in all the social media apps, to hook them up to the worldwide feed bus. It's a way to get interop without having to concede that any comprehensive API is the winner. Think of RSS 2.0 support at the TCP of social networking, offering a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lowest_common_denominator&quot;&gt;LCD&lt;/a&gt; compatibility to a world that desperately needs one. " created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 14:09:59 GMT"/>
					<outline text="And then after we have that, we can talk about the format of the data we're sending over this network. We have some work to do there too, but luckily the capabilities and limits of RSS 2.0 are a perfect match here. " created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 14:11:19 GMT"/>
					<outline text="In summary, the reason we want it is so we can do more with confidence with Bluesky, integrate it into more systems. " created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 14:12:03 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The reason the Bluesky people should want it is that it offers a way to interop with all social nets, that will take almost no effort on their part, and there's no guesswork, we already know how to make feeds that will work pretty much everywhere, and it lets them take the lead in what will be an important way to communicate on the net. " created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 14:12:24 GMT"/>
					<outline text="And the reason it's good for all of us is we can start viewing the web once again as a fully supported writing environment, and let the writers of the world get to work on solving all our problems (of which we have many) and get the freaking technology out of their way. " created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 14:13:19 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Think of it as the feed-iverse, it's easier and more low-level than the fed-iverse, and can be implemented in a weekend. And it's fun! " created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 14:16:55 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Grandma on a snowy winter day" created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 20:50:26 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Moose the cat sits in Grandma's lap while Lionel the dog keeps her feet warm." created="Thu, 07 Dec 2023 20:50:43 GMT" inlineImage="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/07/grandmaMooseAndBarnabyOnAColdDayInTheMountains.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 6" created="Wed, 06 Dec 2023 15:02:47 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="06">
				<outline text="We could make this election a literary expo. Get the great apocalypse scifi and poliscifi authors to write a daily installment of what President Trump and his governing mafia will be doing on 1/20/25 on 1/20/24. Every day a new atrocity in serial form. A textcast. Finally something worth writing about. " created="Wed, 06 Dec 2023 16:48:51 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Recreating Twitter is boring. One of these ventures that's trying to do that should blow the doors off the whole thing, and get rid of every limit. Just support writing and reading and &lt;a href=&quot;http://textcasting.org/&quot;&gt;get on with it&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Wed, 06 Dec 2023 15:02:48 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 5" created="Tue, 05 Dec 2023 20:11:09 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="05">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?river=true&amp;screenname=davewiner&quot;&gt;This is how I read my news&lt;/a&gt;. In FeedLand most pages are public. " created="Tue, 05 Dec 2023 20:11:10 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="If you've been reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;news.scripting.com&lt;/a&gt; and only want one panel (as some people do), you can bookmark just that panel. For example, this is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?river=true&amp;screenname=davewiner&amp;catname=tech&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; for my Tech news category. Or the Bloggers tab on Scripting News can be accessed directly in FeedLand &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?river=true&amp;screenname=davewiner&amp;catname=bloggers&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;By category&quot; is just one way FeedLand can display a timeline of news. " created="Tue, 05 Dec 2023 20:49:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, we care when an item changes, so if we see the text has changed, or a link has been added, or an image enclosure, we update the database and update the rendering on-screen. " created="Tue, 05 Dec 2023 20:57:48 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="We're thinking about different ways to render art. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?river=true&amp;screenname=davewiner&amp;catname=art&quot;&gt;this is news&lt;/a&gt; from my Art category. I could see this kind of timeline feeding another kind of image viewer app, maybe something running on a kiosk or in a store window.  " created="Tue, 05 Dec 2023 21:00:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 4" created="Mon, 04 Dec 2023 13:28:48 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="04">
				<outline text="I'm back in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/games/wordle/&quot;&gt;Wordle&lt;/a&gt; groove, having done the last 42 puzzles without missing one. I think I understand the game much better now. I do sometimes make mistakes, and always pay for them. The thing that keeps me coming back is the feeling when you press Return to see the result of your first guess. It's like opening a present, only better. If you get two green tiles, you can bask in the glow of being extremely lucky. If you guess well you usually can solve the puzzle in three or at most four moves. I've never gotten it in two, and I don't usually try, and when I do it's usually a mistake, I would have done better to stick with the plan of eliminating a bunch of letters and confirming others, and then go for solution in the third round. But the thing that keeps me coming back is the feeling of getting a really good present, and that feeling of fortune and a bit of love, self-love, when you see the answer, decide to go for it, and see five green tiles open up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SbK1SM_Qomg&quot;&gt;one at a time&lt;/a&gt;. That's the feeling that keeps me coming back day after day. " created="Mon, 04 Dec 2023 13:28:49 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/04/wordle.png"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 3" created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 16:41:29 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="03">
				<outline text="&quot;Wait and see what happens&quot; is a losing strategy. By the time you figured out what happened, if you ever do, it's too late.  " created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 16:41:30 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Whatever verse you like" created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 20:36:33 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I wrote this as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://social.masto.land/@dave/111517322418415422&quot;&gt;Mastodon post&lt;/a&gt; to a bunch of people who somehow I got cc'd to. I figured I should share it here too. " created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 20:38:10 GMT" flBulletedSubs="true">
						<outline text="Let's start with feeds and build as much of a Mastodon as we can, without inventing anything new and see what we come up with." created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 20:36:48 GMT"/>
						<outline text="That way we know at every step we're standing on a solid foundation of interop." created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 20:37:15 GMT"/>
						<outline text="At the same time invest in the feed support of every contender, no matter what &quot;verse&quot; its part of. " created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 20:37:20 GMT"/>
						<outline text="John Spurlock has done an exemplary implementation of RSS 2.0 feeds for Bluesky. That &lt;a href=&quot;https://rss.firesky.tv/?filter=from:scripting.com&quot;&gt;format&lt;/a&gt; should be copied everywhere. He did it in about a week in July and it's great. We're building all kinds of stuff on it. Wish it were in Mastodon, and wish Bluesky would bake it in." created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 20:37:25 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Forget about clubs, what we want is interop, maximally as widely as possible to force the silos to get on board. They won't unless they have to." created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 20:37:59 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					</outline>
				<outline text="What about the Fediverse?" created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 21:25:37 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="&quot;Fediverse&quot; is another kind of silo." created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 21:25:47 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Our social media apps should be rising up out of feeds to interop with each other now, not sometime in the future."/>
					<outline text="By then Facebook (or Meta or Threads) will own us as much as Twitter did. " created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 21:30:03 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Doc &amp; FeedLand &amp; artcasting" created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 19:28:21 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I pinged Doc the other day saying he should do an artcasting feed. " created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 19:28:29 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Doc is in addition to being a prodigious blogger, also is a photo taker and story teller, so he is perfect for artcasting." created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 19:28:46 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I was then going to think about what would be the easiest way to get him going, and quickly realized the fastest way is Bluesky because &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+spurlock&quot;&gt;John Spurlock&lt;/a&gt; did it right and his feeds coming out of Bluesky are totally artcasting-compatible. Just like that. (Artcasting is one of those cases where almost everyone was doing it the right way. Absolutely no one invented it, it was just obvious how it should work, obvious to enough people.)" created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 19:29:06 GMT" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2017/07/29/doc.png"/>
					<outline text="But I wanted to talk about it with A8C people first, because it's also an opportunity to support it in WordPress, or to create a small app that interfaces to WordPress, so it can lead here too. But Doc beat me to it, he posted a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/dsearls.bsky.social/post/3kfnwb6dbf72b&quot;&gt;beautiful picture&lt;/a&gt; of a building site his new hometown to Bluesky, and it appeared in &lt;a href=&quot;https://rss.firesky.tv/?filter=from:dsearls.bsky.social&quot;&gt;his RSS 2.0 feed&lt;/a&gt;, and of course it &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?river=https%3A%2F%2Frss.firesky.tv%2F%3Ffilter%3Dfrom%3Adsearls.bsky.social&quot;&gt;showed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?item=594431&quot;&gt;up&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?feedurl=https%3A%2F%2Frss.firesky.tv%2F%3Ffilter%3Dfrom%3Adsearls.bsky.social&quot;&gt;in FeedLand&lt;/a&gt; when I subscribed to his feed. " created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 19:30:05 GMT"/>
					<outline text="So I added it to my collection of artcasting feeds, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.feedcorps.org/artshow.opml&quot;&gt;new version&lt;/a&gt; is now &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?readinglist=https%3A%2F%2Flists.feedcorps.org%2Fartshow.opml&quot;&gt;available&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?feedcorps=true&quot;&gt;FeedCorps&lt;/a&gt; and his name shows up in the list in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://artshow2.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;artshow app&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 19:31:28 GMT"/>
					<outline text="This is how we do it, keep turning the wheel." created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 19:32:06 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Interop my friends. " created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 19:37:17 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Feed Info for phones" created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 22:13:20 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I've been working on the mobile version of FeedLand. " created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 22:13:35 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/03/mobileScreenShot1.png&quot;&gt;" created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 22:14:00 GMT"/>
					<outline text="This is very much a snapshot in time. Lots more tweaking coming. ;-) " created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 22:14:46 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I want to do some more reduction on the menubar at the top. " created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 22:15:08 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/03/timelinescreen.png&quot;&gt;Timelines&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/03/feedlistscreen.png&quot;&gt;feed lists&lt;/a&gt; have been converted. " created="Sun, 03 Dec 2023 22:15:19 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 2" created="Sat, 02 Dec 2023 15:32:24 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="02">
				<outline text="Today's song: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Hg-ILjqbKT4&quot;&gt;Rockin' Chair&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sat, 02 Dec 2023 19:14:58 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2023/12/02/whatIsElonMuskDoing.m4a&quot;&gt;Podcast&lt;/a&gt;: What is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=elon+musk+shut+the+fuck+up&quot;&gt;Elon Musk&lt;/a&gt; doing? There's value in Twitter that goes beyond the balance sheet and share price. I saw the opportunity in &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2017/01/14/whatIfTwtrIsBoughtByARepub.html&quot;&gt;January 2017&lt;/a&gt;, a few days before Trump was &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inauguration_of_Donald_Trump&quot;&gt;inaugurated&lt;/a&gt;. Twitter had just elected a president. What is the dollar value of that? In the hands of someone who knows how to squeeze money from the US government, as Musk surely does (and Trump had no idea) -- it could be worth many more billions than he paid for Twitter." created="Sat, 02 Dec 2023 16:50:38 GMT" type="outline" enclosure="http://scripting.com/2023/12/02/whatIsElonMuskDoing.m4a" enclosureType="audio/mpeg" enclosureLength="3080321" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/02/whiteRabbitFromAliceInWonderland.png"/>
				<outline text="You can live in places where people do awful disgusting things, I know, I've lived in New Orleans, Berkeley and NYC. Twitter is so huge, this idea that it could disband just like that, well it isn't happening. Maybe it's time for us to say clearly what we expect of a social network and try to influence how they run them. We have these great tools for organizing, one of these days we're going to use them for good, in a serious way. And at this point the users have a lot of power relative to what we've had in the past. " created="Sat, 02 Dec 2023 16:00:59 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I'm cleaning up some loose-ends in the Scripting News redesign, esp in the phone version. After that, I'm going to start applying the same techniques to FeedLand on phones. Our timelines look fine in that context, here's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/02/scriptingMobileScreenshot.png&quot;&gt;screen shot&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sat, 02 Dec 2023 16:03:49 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I also updated the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/?tab=about&quot;&gt;About tab&lt;/a&gt;, to be a bit more current. " created="Sat, 02 Dec 2023 16:56:00 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="This is the stupidest thing ever. We've had a bit of trouble with the implementation of &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/opmlHowto/dave/rssCloud/walkthrough/publisher.html&quot;&gt;rssCloud&lt;/a&gt; on the new Automattic-hosted server, the pings to coming from one server in particular. We did finally get to the bottom of it and all of a sudden it's working. Except for &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/rss.xml&quot;&gt;Scripting News&lt;/a&gt;. I added debugging code, stared at server logs, and scratched my head, until I decided to check if I was subscribed to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?feedurl=http%3A%2F%2Fscripting.com%2Frss.xml&quot;&gt;freaking feed&lt;/a&gt;. I wasn't. Once I fixed that little oversight, it's all &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/12/02/itworked.png&quot;&gt;working&lt;/a&gt;, nice and fast. Sometimes the bug is in your brain not in the software. :smile:" created="Sat, 02 Dec 2023 18:52:32 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2023/11/30/curly.png"/>
				<outline text="BTW, this is what &quot;Scripting News&quot; looks like &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?river=http%3A%2F%2Fscripting.com%2Frss.xml#&quot;&gt;in FeedLand&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sat, 02 Dec 2023 19:00:40 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="If I could devote myself fulltime to AI development, first thing I'd do is teach a bot how to generate CSS with high level commands from me. After 15 years of wrangling CSS, I still create messes that are impossible to unravel, the only way to fix it is to start over, and then that gets out of control, and on and on. It would take some patience to establish some basic design patterns, but once designed I could say things like &quot;a little less margin on top of the tabs&quot; and boom that would happen. " created="Sat, 02 Dec 2023 15:32:25 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 1" created="Fri, 01 Dec 2023 14:53:45 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="01">
				<outline text="WordPress.org has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/photos/&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; where people share Creative Commons licensed photos. We asked them to support image enclosures (aka artcasting) in &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?feedurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwordpress.org%2Fphotos%2Ffeed%2F&quot;&gt;their feed&lt;/a&gt;. They just did. And as a result their flow &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?river=https%3A%2F%2Fwordpress.org%2Fphotos%2Ffeed%2F&quot;&gt;looks outstanding&lt;/a&gt; on FeedLand, which totally supports this format. This is a bell-ringer event, this is what we're about -- building up and out from where we are in the land of feeds. We can do a lot if we work together. " created="Fri, 01 Dec 2023 17:08:40 GMT" type="outline" image="https://imgs.scripting.com/2020/08/12/indianaJones.png"/>
				<outline text="A bit of a mindbomb. &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?readinglistnews=https%3A%2F%2Fdiggingthedigital.com%2Fblogroll.opml&quot;&gt;All&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?readinglist=https%3A%2F%2Fdiggingthedigital.com%2Fblogroll.opml&quot;&gt;different&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedland.com/?subscriptionlist=https%3A%2F%2Fdiggingthedigital.com%2Fblogroll.opml&quot;&gt;ways&lt;/a&gt; to view Frank Meeuwsen's &lt;a href=&quot;https://diggingthedigital.com/blogroll.opml&quot;&gt;blogroll&lt;/a&gt; in FeedLand. " created="Fri, 01 Dec 2023 18:03:40 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Remember &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/786af3a9-c35c-499f-8e97-f4b7017415ab&quot;&gt;Bingeworthy&lt;/a&gt;? It fell off the air when Twitter blew up their API. I keep wanting it back, because I keep watching shows that should be in its database. I miss it. Then I realized it's not that different from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://defaults.rknight.me/&quot;&gt;group of explorers&lt;/a&gt; who are putting their app choices into feeds. The Bingeworthy database is people, shows and ratings. The simplest relational database possible. It would be easy to represent each user as a feed, where each item is a rating. The link for each item would be a pointer to the Metacritic page. And then give each feed a category of &lt;i&gt;bingeworthy. &lt;/i&gt;From there, we explore.  BTW, this is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/scripting/a5b3ac43939954c4af6759a9ce27989f&quot;&gt;SQL code&lt;/a&gt; that creates the BW database. " created="Fri, 01 Dec 2023 14:56:10 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Another month past, archive created. Clean slate. " created="Fri, 01 Dec 2023 14:53:46 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			</outline>
		</body>
	</opml>
