<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- OPML generated by OPML Editor v10.1b19 on Thu, 23 Dec 2021 14:28:33 GMT -->
<opml version="2.0">
	<head>
		<title>Scripting News</title>
		<dateCreated>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 14:28:27 GMT</dateCreated>
		<dateModified>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 14:28:33 GMT</dateModified>
		<ownerName>Dave Winer</ownerName>
		<ownerId>http://davewiner.com/</ownerId>
		<expansionState>1</expansionState>
		<vertScrollState>1</vertScrollState>
		<windowTop>631</windowTop>
		<windowLeft>1087</windowLeft>
		<windowBottom>831</windowBottom>
		<windowRight>1472</windowRight>
		</head>
	<body>
		<outline text="August 1999" created="Sun, 01 Aug 1999 05:00:02 GMT">
			<outline text="August 31" created="Tue, 31 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10333&quot;&gt;Frontier 6.1b1&lt;/a&gt; is now running on Nirvana." created="Tue, 31 Aug 1999 05:01:56 GMT" name="aHrefhttpdiscussuserlandcommsgreader10333frontier61b1aIsNowRunningOnNirvana" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Arnold Lesikar: &lt;a href=&quot;http://einstein.stcloudstate.edu/libGd/&quot;&gt;LibGD 1.0b3&lt;/a&gt; uses RLE compression only and does not infringe the Unisys patent." created="Tue, 31 Aug 1999 05:02:24 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Nick Denton: &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10335&quot;&gt;130 RSS News Feeds&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Moreover.com is an Internet service which scrapes headline links from about 1,500 sources on the web, and across more than 150 categories of news.&quot; This raises an interesting issue, the next one after deep linking. Can others scrape your site for links to stories and repurpose them as XML?" created="Tue, 31 Aug 1999 05:03:23 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Newsweek: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newsweek.com/nw-srv/printed/int/wb/ov3010_1.htm&quot;&gt;Europe's Got Net Fever&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Nick Denton didn't plan to leave his perfectly good job as technology correspondent for the Financial Times when he moved to California.&quot;" created="Tue, 31 Aug 1999 05:04:03 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10352&quot;&gt;Ian Davis&lt;/a&gt; of Internet Alchemy adds his thoughts to the XML-scraping thread. &quot;Dave said he would be unhappy if someone scraped his site. I'm not sure why. Dave gains nothing in monetary terms for driving customers to Scripting News but gains a whole lot in mindshare and exposure for Frontier, Userland and whatever he's working on at that point in time.&quot; &lt;i&gt;A disturbing comment. I'm right here, I wish he would ask instead of telling me why I have the wrong opinion, about *my* content. Thanks for listening.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Tue, 31 Aug 1999 05:05:21 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://cnn.com/TECH/computing/9908/31/link.suits.idg/index.html&quot;&gt;CNN is running&lt;/a&gt; Dylan Tweney's InfoWorld column, with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://cnn.com/POLL/results/194021.html&quot;&gt;survey&lt;/a&gt; that asks how you feel about Deep Linking." created="Tue, 31 Aug 1999 05:06:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="MacWEEK: &lt;a href=&quot;http://macweek.zdnet.com/1999/08/29/jobskey.html&quot;&gt;Apple introduces new desktops, flat-panel display&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 31 Aug 1999 05:07:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10304&quot;&gt;This morning's&lt;/a&gt; Scripting News Challenge&amp;trade;." created="Tue, 31 Aug 1999 05:08:09 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="My bet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10306&quot;&gt;Open Source AppleScript&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 31 Aug 1999 05:09:11 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10327&quot;&gt;Jeremy Bowers wins&lt;/a&gt; a minor Honorable Mention for predicting the Steve Jobs Reality Distortion Field&amp;trade;, but no one bet on a G4 (and I doubt if we would have given the prize anyway, it wasn't a very exciting announcement, unless you think varying the colors is a major deal)." created="Tue, 31 Aug 1999 05:10:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="SlashDot.Org: &lt;a href=&quot;http://slashdot.org/articles/99/08/31/0143246.shtml&quot;&gt;Unisys not suing all webmasters&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 31 Aug 1999 05:11:17 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Simon St. Laurent: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.simonstl.com/articles/civilw3c.htm&quot;&gt;A Civilian's Guide to W3C&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Tue, 31 Aug 1999 05:12:51 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Sun's newly acquired StarOffice is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sun.com:/products/staroffice/get.html&quot;&gt;available for download&lt;/a&gt;. It's not clear from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sun.com:/dot-com/staroffice.html&quot;&gt;marketing page&lt;/a&gt; whether StarOffice is written in Java. This used to matter to Sun, does it not matter now?" created="Tue, 31 Aug 1999 05:13:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 30" created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10246&quot;&gt;This is the DG interface&lt;/a&gt; that Simone Bettini and Paolo Valdemarin are working on. They're using the XML-RPC DG &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xmlrpc.com/discuss/msgReader$181&quot;&gt;interface&lt;/a&gt; released last week. &lt;i&gt;Hint to Paolo and Macromedia, it would be great if the editor produced Flash text.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:01:21 GMT" name="aHrefhttpdiscussuserlandcommsgreader10246thisIsTheDgInterfaceaThatSimoneBettiniAndPaoloValdemarinAreWorkingOnTheyreUsingTheXmlrpcDgAHrefhttpwwwxmlrpccomdiscussmsgreader181interfaceaReleasedLastWeekIhintToPaoloAndMacromediaItWouldBeGreatIfTheEditorProducedFlashTexti" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="New channel: &lt;a href=&quot;http://my.userland.com/viewChannel$1252&quot;&gt;Jon Udell&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:02:42 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="New tours: &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontier.userland.com/stories/storyReader$1006&quot;&gt;Website framework&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontier.userland.com/stories/storyReader$1008&quot;&gt;Workgroup web server&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontier.userland.com/stories/storyReader$1191&quot;&gt;Case studies&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:03:29 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Buried treasure: &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontier.userland.com/stories/storyReader$101&quot;&gt;How to Write an XML-RPC Handler&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:04:19 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="More buried treasure: &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontier.userland.com/stories/storyReader$1075&quot;&gt;Matt Neuburg explains XML-RPC&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:05:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://linux.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$55&quot;&gt;Here's a neat application&lt;/a&gt; of the XML-RPC to DG interface. Eric Kidd, who works at UserLand, has connected his CVS to his DG, so we can watch the changes as he checks them in. &lt;i&gt;Zzzzip!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:06:12 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Wired: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/news/news/business/story/21501.html&quot;&gt;A startup for startups&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:07:31 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I got five emails in three minutes about a &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10230&quot;&gt;backdoor&lt;/a&gt; in Microsoft's HotMail server that allows anyone to read anyone else's mail without a password. " created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:08:48 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnn.com/TECH/computing/9908/30/hotmail.hack.01/&quot;&gt;CNN&lt;/a&gt; on the HotMail security hole. &quot;Millions of free Internet e-mail accounts provided by Microsoft's Hotmail service were susceptible to a major security breach that allowed access Monday to users' accounts.&quot;" created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:09:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10251&quot;&gt;Tim Bray on the HotMail Hole&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The thing that's really startling is that the HotMail system was left on the air for a substantial number of hours after the one line of HTML necessary to open the door had been posted on dozens of public web sites.&quot;" created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:10:30 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10228&quot;&gt;Progress report&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I saw how the Frontier site could be like Scripting News, but better. That I could have fun with it, and that it could become a discussion group like this one, *and* that it could have a functional hierarchy.&quot;" created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:11:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="InfoWorld: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoworld.com/cgi-bin/displayStory.pl?990830.pisunncs.htm&quot;&gt;Sun to mount desktop attack&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:12:58 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Jon Udell: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.byte.com/column/threads/BYT19990824S0013&quot;&gt;Exploring Zope&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Zope is a 100 percent scripted long-running HTTP daemon, which maps HTTP requests directly into scripted method calls.&quot;" created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:13:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Jacob Levy: &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10209&quot;&gt;Programming ideas and time to mature&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Dave's recent ruminations on Algol-60 and its relation to UserTalk reminded me of an urban legend about software: some pundits believe that it takes about 20-30 years for novel approaches in programming languages to become mainstream.&quot;" created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:14:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10222&quot;&gt;And sometimes&lt;/a&gt;, when the timing is just right, adoption happens very quickly. Examples include spreadsheets and HTML." created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:15:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Press release: &lt;a href=&quot;http://biz.yahoo.com/prnews/990830/ca_macrome_2.html&quot;&gt;Macromedia Flash-enables Illustrator&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:16:26 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10219&quot;&gt;David Carter-Tod wishes&lt;/a&gt; to revise his wishes for achieving the M10K threshold. &quot;I wish for a good job with stock options so I can retire in 10 years time.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Seems do-able.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:17:53 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10221&quot;&gt;The next M10K challenge&lt;/a&gt;. Be the first to have a DG message that you posted achieve more than 10,000 reads. (Honorable mentions achieve more than 5,000 reads.)" created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:18:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Evolt.Org: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.evolt.org/index.cfm?menu=8&amp;cid=389&amp;catid=25&quot;&gt;Don't Panic About GIFs&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;OK.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:19:57 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Wired: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/news/news/technology/story/21482.html&quot;&gt;Apple, Adobe show at Seybold&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;The hottest buzz surrounds Apple, which is widely rumored to be unveiling a new professional machine featuring a new, hotly anticipated PowerPC chip from Motorola that dramatically speeds multimedia performance.&quot;" created="Mon, 30 Aug 1999 05:20:21 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 29" created="Sun, 29 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Digging up background for the tours for the Frontier site, I came across this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.monash.edu.au/~lloyd/tildeProgLang/Algol60/RRA60.info&quot;&gt;specification&lt;/a&gt;, written in 1960, that describes what was then a new programming language called Algol 60. It's the basic design for many current programming languages, including C, Pascal, Java, JavaScript, and UserTalk, the language built into Frontier. &lt;i&gt;I was five years old when this spec came out.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Sun, 29 Aug 1999 05:01:38 GMT" name="diggingUpBackgroundForTheToursForTheFrontierSiteICameAcrossThisAHrefhttpwwwcsmonasheduaulloydtildeproglangalgol60rra60infospecificationaWrittenIn1960ThatDescribesWhatWasThenANewProgrammingLanguageCalledAlgol60ItsTheBasicDesignForManyCurrentProgrammingLanguagesIncludingCPascalJavaJavascriptAndUsertalkTheLanguageBuiltIntoFrontierIiWasFiveYearsOldWhenThisSpecCameOuti" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Except for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acm.org/classics/oct95/&quot;&gt;GOTO statement&lt;/a&gt; and keywords appearing in 'single quotes', the design of Algol-60 is the way all block structured languages work today. Was it the first language to be specified by a BNF grammar? I'm not sure. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www8.informatik.uni-erlangen.de/html/lisp/histlit1.html&quot;&gt;Lisp&lt;/a&gt; may have been first with a formal definition. Most earlier languages were designed in an ad hoc way, and could not be formally specified." created="Sun, 29 Aug 1999 05:02:35 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xmlrpc.com/discuss/msgReader$216&quot;&gt;James Spahr&lt;/a&gt; has DreamWeaver/Mac integrated with our CMS using the AppleScript XML-RPC connector. &lt;i&gt;Bravo!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Sun, 29 Aug 1999 05:03:02 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I believe &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xmlrpc.com/discuss/msgReader$229&quot;&gt;we nailed the problem&lt;/a&gt; in the XML-RPC DG interface, thanks to patience and intelligence from Ben Griffiths." created="Sun, 29 Aug 1999 05:04:35 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://linuxtoday.com/stories/9312.html&quot;&gt;According to LinuxToday&lt;/a&gt;, mySql is now open source. &lt;i&gt;Coool!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Sun, 29 Aug 1999 05:06:00 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10103&quot;&gt;Eric Kidd&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The Cathedral and the Bazaar wasn't written to compare proprietary software with open source software. Instead, it was written to compare two ways of building open source software.&quot; &lt;i&gt;I didn't know that.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Sun, 29 Aug 1999 05:06:03 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="On the XML-DEV list, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lists.ic.ac.uk/hypermail/xml-dev/xml-dev-Aug-1999/0378.html&quot;&gt;Tim Bray takes issue&lt;/a&gt; with multiple namespaces in the XHTML spec. It's over my head, but if Tim says it won't work, I believe him." created="Sun, 29 Aug 1999 05:07:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I'm working on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontier.userland.com/&quot;&gt;Frontier website&lt;/a&gt; this morning, building a series of tours to link into the pages hanging off the home page. Finally it's all making sense to me, the What is Frontier? stuff, which everyone likes, is the table of contents for the site. I'm just hotting up the bold items and linking them to pages that take you on a tour of the features." created="Sun, 29 Aug 1999 05:08:54 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Along the way I'm discovering some gems. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontier.userland.com/stories/storyReader$151&quot;&gt;this story&lt;/a&gt; explains outlining in Frontier. With the recent renewed interest in outliners this has become an interesting page in a new way. Note that we describe outlining in Frontier in the context of script editing. In Frontier 6 the outliner became more generally useful for writing, and the docs don't reflect that yet." created="Sun, 29 Aug 1999 05:09:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="If you are an expert Frontier user you can help out and write a tour or two. It's quite easy, and I even wrote &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontier.userland.com/stories/storyReader$1120&quot;&gt;a spec&lt;/a&gt; that explains how to do it." created="Sun, 29 Aug 1999 05:10:58 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="New tours: &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontier.userland.com/stories/storyReader$1119&quot;&gt;Scripting in Frontier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontier.userland.com/stories/storyReader$1132&quot;&gt;Frontier's object database&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 29 Aug 1999 05:11:04 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 28" created="Sat, 28 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xmlrpc.com/discuss/msgReader$192&quot;&gt;XML-RPC DG Status&lt;/a&gt;: We've had some reports of problems, but messages have been posted thru Perl and AppleScript, so we know the interface is working at least from those two languages. Stay tuned. " created="Sat, 28 Aug 1999 05:01:21 GMT" name="aHrefhttpwwwxmlrpccomdiscussmsgreader192xmlrpcDgStatusaWeveHadSomeReportsOfProblemsButMessagesHaveBeenPostedThruPerlAndApplescriptSoWeKnowTheInterfaceIsWorkingAtLeastFromThoseTwoLanguagesStayTuned" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoworld.com/cgi-bin/displayIcommerce.pl?/prophet.htm&quot;&gt;InfoWorld's Dylan Tweney&lt;/a&gt; on Deep Linking. &quot;InfoWorld until recently had a restrictive linking policy, although it was essentially toothless. According to this policy, people who wanted to link to stories within InfoWorld's Web site were supposed to request permission first. The policy was widely ignored, as search engines and a host of other Web sites regularly linked to InfoWorld articles.&quot;" created="Sat, 28 Aug 1999 05:02:46 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="c't: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ix.de/ct/99/18/064/&quot;&gt;Multiskript-Hypertexter&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Wem die händische Erstellung seiner wachsenden Webpräsenz über den Kopf wächst, sucht früher oder später nach einer automatisierten Lösung seiner Probleme. Unter MacOS und Windows findet die objektorientierte Datenbank Frontier daher immer mehr Freunde. In der Version 6 lässt sich das skriptgesteuerte Programm sogar durch Browser-Aufrufe steuern.&quot;" created="Sat, 28 Aug 1999 05:03:15 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10174&quot;&gt;Don Hopkins&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;In my big book of karma, Bill Joy has a lot of penance to pay, to make up for the psychic and aesthetic discordances he inflicted on the world by writing VI and CSH. He can have all the credit for those he wants.&quot;" created="Sat, 28 Aug 1999 05:04:03 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10176&quot;&gt;Oliver Wrede&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I think Generator is far to expensive. They demand a licence at $3000 bucks for each processor on the webserver and $500 per developer using the developers suite.&quot;" created="Sat, 28 Aug 1999 05:05:48 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10183&quot;&gt;Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Personally, here's what I'd like to see. A cheap Flash-based word processor with very basic formatting commands. That way I could write some text, see what it spits out, and learn how the Flash format works.&quot;" created="Sat, 28 Aug 1999 05:06:36 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pbs.org/cringely/pulpit/pulpit19990826.html&quot;&gt;Cringely&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;..a bad experience in the company's very first acquisition, when it bought Powerpoint. Even though this late-80s purchase was of a company with fewer than 50 employees, both Bill Gates and then-CEO Jon Shirley told me the experience was horrific for Microsoft. It was a problem of trying to merge corporate cultures that were very different. And the lesson learned was not to even try for such a merger. For the sake of Microsoft, the new model says that the corporate culture of the company being bought has to die.&quot;" created="Sat, 28 Aug 1999 05:07:31 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="From the It Could Have Been Me Department. Before Bill Gates and Jon Shirley decided to acquire PowerPoint, they had a Letter of Intent to acquire my company, Living Videotext. We lost the deal in a meeting with Shirley over exactly this issue. Shirley said that they'd offer everyone at LVT jobs, but that we'd become a product team and nothing more. &quot;Oh the waste!&quot; I thought. We had put so much effort into integrating the support and management functions of the company. Everyone was a MORE user, and on a career path to be part of the product team. I objected. They bought Forethought instead, the company that made PowerPoint. Don't worry, it was still hell trying to integrate LVT with Symantec." created="Sat, 28 Aug 1999 05:08:46 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 27" created="Fri, 27 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="New spec: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xmlrpc.com/discuss/msgReader$181&quot;&gt;How to access UserLand's DGs thru XML-RPC&lt;/a&gt;. If this gains traction it will become an important standard for including user-written text in a content management system, directly connecting to user-oriented desktop text editing tools. This is how we factor the limited text editors in web browsers, by making the editors we love more intimate with HTTP (thru XML-RPC of course). Support is welcome from HTML editors (eg Word, Golive, Dreamweaver) and user-oriented databases (eg FileMaker, Access) as well as programmer editors such as BBEdit and Emacs. It's an open protocol, we also welcome competition on the server side, and in fact we plan to provide an excellent outliner to hook in on the workstation side. If you're interested in the future of writing for the web at a plumbing level, please check this out. &lt;i&gt;Thanks!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 27 Aug 1999 05:01:18 GMT" name="newSpecAHrefhttpwwwxmlrpccomdiscussmsgreader181howToAccessUserlandsDgsThruXmlrpcaIfThisGainsTractionItWillBecomeAnImportantStandardForIncludingUserwrittenTextInAContentManagementSystemDirectlyConnectingToUserorientedDesktopTextEditingToolsThisIsHowWeFactorTheLimitedTextEditorsInWebBrowsersByMakingTheEditorsWeLoveMoreIntimateWithHttpThruXmlrpcOfCourseSupportIsWelcomeFromHtmlEditorsEgWordGoliveDreamweaverAndUserorientedDatabasesEgFilemakerAccessAsWellAsProgrammerEditorsSuchAsBbeditAndEmacsItsAnOpenProtocolWeAlsoWelcomeCompetitionOnTheServerSideAndInFactWePlanToProvideAnExcellentOutlinerToHookInOnTheWorkstationSideIfYoureInterestedInTheFutureOfWritingForTheWebAtAPlumbingLevelPleaseCheckThisOutIthanksi" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Eric Folley: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nomadder.com/frontier/autowebedit&quot;&gt;suites.autoWebEdit&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;This suite is designed to make using WebEdit easier: when you open a webpage, this suite automatically checks it out for you; close the page, it's automatically checked in.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Good idea!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 27 Aug 1999 05:02:05 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoworld.com/cgi-bin/displayStory.pl?990827.hnomg.htm&quot;&gt;InfoWorld&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The long-sought ability to run applications on different servers in far-flung places over the Internet without an army of high-end developers came a step closer this week as the Object Management Group (OMG) adopted the CORBA Component Model.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Why wait? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xmlrpc.com/&quot;&gt;XML-RPC&lt;/a&gt; is doing this right now, not in the next millenium!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 27 Aug 1999 05:03:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Once again I get good links from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ntk.net/index.cgi?back=archive99/now0827.txt&quot;&gt;ntk.net&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;If we had Xanadu you'd realise how out of context all these quotes are.&quot; Hey they follow the DG here. &lt;i&gt;Thanks!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 27 Aug 1999 05:04:23 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.news.com/News/Item/0,4,41027,00.html?st.ne.fd.mdh.ni&quot;&gt;Web breathes new life into Macromedia&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 27 Aug 1999 05:05:29 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Hey &lt;a href=&quot;http://quote.yahoo.com/q?s=MACR&amp;d=t&quot;&gt;Macromedia&lt;/a&gt; has two new products! Here are some pictures and screen shots. &lt;a href=&quot;http://206.204.24.3/snimages/macromediaannounce/generatorArchitecture.gif&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://206.204.24.3/snimages/macromediaannounce/generatorAuthoring.gif&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://206.204.24.3/snimages/macromediaannounce/generatorOnline.gif&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://206.204.24.3/snimages/macromediaannounce/generatorOutput.gif&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;. Here's the scoop on the two products. One is an improved version of their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macromedia.com/software/generator/productinfo/&quot;&gt;Generator&lt;/a&gt; server-side engine, and the other is an add-on that allows Adobe Illustrator users to generate Flash-compatible content. Not earth-shaking, evolutionary. That's always a good idea. (I'm looking for the press releases now. If you find them send me a pointer.)" created="Fri, 27 Aug 1999 05:06:23 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="InfoWorld: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoworld.com/cgi-bin/displayStory.pl?990827.iinetprint.htm&quot;&gt;Microsoft and HP spec Over-the-Internet Printing&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;IPP allows print jobs to be sent to any printer connected to the Internet.&quot;" created="Fri, 27 Aug 1999 05:07:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10085&quot;&gt;On this page&lt;/a&gt; I outline my vision for RSS and invite everyone who has an opinion to express it. &lt;i&gt;Thanks!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 27 Aug 1999 05:08:39 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://soa.granitecanyon.com/&quot;&gt;Granite Canyon&lt;/a&gt; provides a free public DNS." created="Fri, 27 Aug 1999 05:09:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10091&quot;&gt;I got emails&lt;/a&gt; this morning from vice-presidents of Microsoft and Compaq in response to yesterday's piece." created="Fri, 27 Aug 1999 05:10:02 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="MSNBC: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/304546.asp&quot;&gt;Teachers take the Web to Class&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Thousands of teachers nationwide are returning to their classrooms this year with a few new technological tools under their belts.&quot;" created="Fri, 27 Aug 1999 05:11:13 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.outliners.com/msgReader$255&quot;&gt;Nick Lowe defends&lt;/a&gt; Word-as-Outliner." created="Fri, 27 Aug 1999 05:12:38 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10068&quot;&gt;Jason Levine had&lt;/a&gt; a happy Dell experience." created="Fri, 27 Aug 1999 05:13:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/$1999/08/26&quot;&gt;Yesterday&lt;/a&gt; was a stunning day on Discuss.UserLand.Com. We're really zooooming. What a community. What good spirits. No flames and we're tackling tough issues. &lt;i&gt;Excellent!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 27 Aug 1999 05:14:23 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Yesterday was &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10000&quot;&gt;M10K Day&lt;/a&gt;. David Carter-Tod, the lucky creator of message 10K, gets a wish! &lt;i&gt;Use it wisely.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 27 Aug 1999 05:15:03 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Reuters/ZDNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.com/zdnn/stories/news/0,4586,2322302,00.html&quot;&gt;A good geek is hard to find&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;The men here are every mother's dream. They're stable and well-educated, and they are wealthy. Some of them have millions and millions of dollars and no one to spend it on.&quot; " created="Fri, 27 Aug 1999 05:16:02 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 26" created="Thu, 26 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="DaveNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1999/08/26/compaqDoaMicrosoftNtSetupCruelAndUnusualPunishment&quot;&gt;Compaq DOA, Microsoft NT setup cruel and unusual punishment&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;A long title today!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Thu, 26 Aug 1999 05:01:12 GMT" name="davenetAHrefhttpdavenetuserlandcom19990826compaqdoamicrosoftntsetupcruelandunusualpunishmentcompaqDoaMicrosoftNtSetupCruelAndUnusualPunishmentaIaLongTitleTodayi" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10008&quot;&gt;The Compaq Saga continues&lt;/a&gt;. I resign as a customer. They continue to play hard-ass. I flip it around. In case anyone from Compaq is tuning in, I included my customer number. Dell asks if there's any way they can win me back. I have terms." created="Thu, 26 Aug 1999 05:02:23 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="While I was on the phone with Compaq we crossed a milestone on Discuss.UserLand.Com. David Carter-Tod posted the &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$10000&quot;&gt;10,000th message&lt;/a&gt;. David has been a frequent contributor to the Frontier community and to Scripting News. I couldn't think of anyone I'd like to honor more. &lt;i&gt;Excellent!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Thu, 26 Aug 1999 05:03:05 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.news.com/News/Item/0,4,40965,00.html?st.ne.fd.tohhed.ni&quot;&gt;More Compaq Layoffs Expected&lt;/a&gt;." created="Thu, 26 Aug 1999 05:04:06 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="TJ Rooney, a Pennsylvania legislator, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pahouse.com/rooney/pr/133081999.htm&quot;&gt;proposes&lt;/a&gt; a computer lemon law. &quot;Rooney was joined by two Pennsylvania consumers who purchased defective computers and are battling the manufacturers over ineffective repairs covered under warranty.&quot;" created="Thu, 26 Aug 1999 05:05:10 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9928&quot;&gt;Richard Blumberg recommends&lt;/a&gt; Debco Electronics, a clone maker in Cincinnati. Phil Suh recommends &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9963&quot;&gt;Virtual Micro&lt;/a&gt; in Milpitas, CA. (That's closer!) Ron McCoy recommends &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tesys.com/&quot;&gt;Telenet Systems&lt;/a&gt;, and says they make the servers for Yahoo and About.Com." created="Thu, 26 Aug 1999 05:06:31 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="SJ Merc: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sjmercury.com/breaking/headline1/022810.htm&quot;&gt;George W. Bush says Give Creationism a Chance&lt;/a&gt;. I think he needs a whack over the head with a computer disk. &lt;i&gt;This is so embarassing for the US!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Thu, 26 Aug 1999 05:07:54 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="MSNBC: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/304203.asp&quot;&gt;Bands of Angels Get Organized&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Angel investors — wealthy individuals — now inject an estimated $50 billion into young companies every year.&quot;" created="Thu, 26 Aug 1999 05:08:57 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoworld.com/cgi-bin/displayTC.pl?/990823analysis.htm&quot;&gt;InfoWorld on virtual meetings&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Collaborative real-time conferencing solutions, a subset of the ever-expanding Web-based collaboration market, is bringing employees, customers, and corporate partners together via the Web, minimizing the effort and time required by all.&quot;" created="Thu, 26 Aug 1999 05:09:53 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.outliners.com/msgReader$226&quot;&gt;Richard Hoefer&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;When I asked top-flight web design firms in San Francisco what they used for web flowcharting, some mentioned Visio -- while most used no form of intelligent flowcharting at all.&quot;" created="Thu, 26 Aug 1999 05:10:12 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.outliners.com/msgReader$225&quot;&gt;David Sherman explains&lt;/a&gt; how cloning makes lawyers more powerful." created="Thu, 26 Aug 1999 05:11:57 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9902&quot;&gt;Doc Searls&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Phil's beliefs are ones that Business Week, The Wall Street Journal, the San Jose Mercury News, the Los Angeles Times and most of the publishing world agrees with.&quot;" created="Thu, 26 Aug 1999 05:12:37 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9916&quot;&gt;Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;As you know, I am not an open source zealot, but I am a zealot when I think I'm being lied to.&quot;" created="Thu, 26 Aug 1999 05:13:45 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9922&quot;&gt;Reuven Lerner&lt;/a&gt;, a columnist at Linux Journal, says they have a liberal policy, allowing authors to publish articles elsewhere, upon publication, as long as they include the phrase &quot;Reprinted from Linux Journal.&quot;" created="Thu, 26 Aug 1999 05:14:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Jacob Levy with today's Quote of the Day: &quot;No! You're supposed to love FAT32. What! You don't love it? Let me whack you over the head with this computer disk.. Wham! There, now you feel better, surely!&quot;" created="Thu, 26 Aug 1999 05:15:30 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 25" created="Wed, 25 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="The Compaq Saga that started last week &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9880&quot;&gt;continues&lt;/a&gt;, with the arrival of the machine, DOA. And I finally wrote down, so I won't forget, why NT setup is such a uniquely humbling experience." created="Wed, 25 Aug 1999 05:01:20 GMT" name="theCompaqSagaThatStartedLastWeekAHrefhttpdiscussuserlandcommsgreader9880continuesaWithTheArrivalOfTheMachineDoaAndIFinallyWroteDownSoIWontForgetWhyNtSetupIsSuchAUniquelyHumblingExperience" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Today's song, &lt;a href=&quot;http://alexia.lis.uiuc.edu/~slterry/lyrics.htm&quot;&gt;Galileo&lt;/a&gt; by the Indigo Girls." created="Wed, 25 Aug 1999 05:02:22 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bricklin.com/history/dmrletter.htm&quot;&gt;An email&lt;/a&gt; from Dennis Ritchie to Dan Bricklin explaining how he got permission to release the early version of the original C compiler." created="Wed, 25 Aug 1999 05:03:31 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9883&quot;&gt;Dori Smith&lt;/a&gt; on the difference between coding and writing." created="Wed, 25 Aug 1999 05:04:23 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Wired: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/news/news/technology/story/21430.html&quot;&gt;Programmer Reaches his Xanadu&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 25 Aug 1999 05:05:02 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9840&quot;&gt;A question to start the day&lt;/a&gt;. If open source is so good for software, why isn't it equally good for books and magazines?" created="Wed, 25 Aug 1999 05:06:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oreilly.com/ask_tim/orabooks_os.html&quot;&gt;Tim O'Reilly&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I feel that it's immoral to try to compel someone else to give you something they've created without compensating them in some way. That is, when software is freed, it is a gift, not the result of an obligation.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Excellent!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Wed, 25 Aug 1999 05:07:22 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.livebiz.com/jice/&quot;&gt;Jice&lt;/a&gt; &quot;enables companies to easily construct syndicated publishing networks, Web superstores, and online reseller channels by establishing Web-site-to-Web-site information networks.&quot;" created="Wed, 25 Aug 1999 05:08:35 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="InternetNews.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.internetnews.com/prod-news/article/0,1087,9_188461,00.html&quot;&gt;The Worst Security Hole&lt;/a&gt;? &quot;IE5 users can protect themselves by going into security tab of the browser's Internet Options menu, and disabling ActiveX controls or plug-ins.&quot;" created="Wed, 25 Aug 1999 05:09:52 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Apparently the Udanax site has exceeded its transfer limit. Luckily there's a mirror site &lt;a href=&quot;http://udanax.xanadu.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;" created="Wed, 25 Aug 1999 05:10:04 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 24" created="Tue, 24 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="DaveNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1999/08/24/tedNelsonReturns&quot;&gt;Ted Nelson Returns&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Now, twenty years later, and ten years after all work on the system had ceased, Nelson and his band of believers have released the source code to the Xanadu system.&quot;" created="Tue, 24 Aug 1999 05:01:57 GMT" name="davenetAHrefhttpdavenetuserlandcom19990824tednelsonreturnstedNelsonReturnsaNowTwentyYearsLaterAndTenYearsAfterAllWorkOnTheSystemHadCeasedNelsonAndHisBandOfBelieversHaveReleasedTheSourceCodeToTheXanaduSystem" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.byte.com/nntp/joncon?comment_id=1701&quot;&gt;Jon Udell&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Last night, at the O'Reilly Open Source conference in Monterey, Ted" created="Tue, 24 Aug 1999 05:02:26 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Nelson and his team demonstrated and shipped Xanadu, the fabled hypertext system that inspired the World Wide Web. It was a remarkable" created="Tue, 24 Aug 1999 05:03:18 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="and strange moment.&quot;" created="Tue, 24 Aug 1999 05:04:51 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.udanax.com/&quot;&gt;Xanadu Secrets Become Open-Source&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;In celebration of the success and vast human benefit of the Open Source movement, we are proud at last to be able to present to the world the technical ideas and methods on which we worked so hard for so long.&quot;" created="Tue, 24 Aug 1999 05:05:30 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I downloaded the &quot;Green&quot; release of Xanadu and put it into a &lt;a href=&quot;http://linux2.userland.com/users/admin/static/misc/xanaduGreen/aug22rel/&quot;&gt;folder on my server&lt;/a&gt; so I can read it thru the web. &lt;i&gt;You can too!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Tue, 24 Aug 1999 05:06:25 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1995/06/19/thehypertextman&quot;&gt;Gary Wolf&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Ted Nelson's Xanadu project was supposed to be the universal, democratic hypertext library that would help human life evolve into an entirely new form.&quot; " created="Tue, 24 Aug 1999 05:07:18 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Ted Nelson's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sfc.keio.ac.jp/~ted/&quot;&gt;home page&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 24 Aug 1999 05:08:03 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Lots of Ted Nelson and Doug Engelbart links in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/1998/01/24&quot;&gt;archive&lt;/a&gt; from 1/24/98." created="Tue, 24 Aug 1999 05:09:38 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;i&gt;Is Xanadu a software antique? I think so!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Tue, 24 Aug 1999 05:10:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Prosthetic Monkey: &lt;a href=&quot;http://prosthetic-monkey.com/RHWM/&quot;&gt;Red Hat Wealth Monitor&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 24 Aug 1999 05:11:32 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Matt Neuburg: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tidbits.com/tb-issues/TidBITS-494.html#lnk2&quot;&gt;Long Day's Journey into Night of the Living Dead Software&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Excellent!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Tue, 24 Aug 1999 05:12:15 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Upside: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.upside.com/texis/mvm/story?id=37bdd1270&quot;&gt;Percolating Java&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 24 Aug 1999 05:13:12 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.outliners.com/msgReader$208&quot;&gt;Here's what happens&lt;/a&gt; when an outliner discovers cloning." created="Tue, 24 Aug 1999 05:14:40 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://forums.infoworld.com/threads/get.cgi?130370&quot;&gt;Nicholas Petreley&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;If you're going to bet your company on Windows 2000, I've assembled 10 responses you should memorize to be fully prepared for the consequences.&quot;" created="Tue, 24 Aug 1999 05:15:39 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.windows2000test.com/default.asp&quot;&gt;The guestbook&lt;/a&gt; on Microsoft's Windows 2000 test site is interesting. Lots of Linux people there. Why are they so interested in Windows 2000?" created="Tue, 24 Aug 1999 05:16:31 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Another Jon Udell piece: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.byte.com/column/threads/BYT19990818S0003&quot;&gt;From Virtual Memory to Object Storage&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Tue, 24 Aug 1999 05:17:19 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 23" created="Mon, 23 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Jakob Nielsen: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.useit.com/alertbox/990822.html&quot;&gt;Do user interface standards stifle creativity&lt;/a&gt;? &quot;Despite the strong consistency in all Mac software do you think Excel looks like MacWrite? Or that there was no design creativity involved in making MORE (a popular outliner)? It's clearly not the case that all GUI software is the same even though most software has pretty strong compliance with the platform design standards these days.&quot; &lt;i&gt;I absolutely agree. The Mac UI guidelines of the day covered a small part of the functionality of any app. Yet developers resist standardization, I did too.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 23 Aug 1999 05:01:14 GMT" name="jakobNielsenAHrefhttpwwwuseitcomalertbox990822htmldoUserInterfaceStandardsStifleCreativityaDespiteTheStrongConsistencyInAllMacSoftwareDoYouThinkExcelLooksLikeMacwriteOrThatThereWasNoDesignCreativityInvolvedInMakingMoreAPopularOutlinerItsClearlyNotTheCaseThatAllGuiSoftwareIsTheSameEvenThoughMostSoftwareHasPrettyStrongComplianceWithThePlatformDesignStandardsTheseDaysIiAbsolutelyAgreeTheMacUiGuidelinesOfTheDayCoveredASmallPartOfTheFunctionalityOfAnyAppYetDevelopersResistStandardizationIDidTooi" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogger.com/&quot;&gt;Blogger&lt;/a&gt; is an automated weblog publishing tool. &lt;i&gt;Excellent!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 23 Aug 1999 05:02:54 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.news.com/News/Item/0,4,40830,00.html?st.ne.fd.mdh.ni&quot;&gt;Sun Decapitates Java OS&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Oooops!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 23 Aug 1999 05:03:26 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Heads-up -- Scripting News will not be updated frequently until Wednesday morning. I'm in Monterey at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://conferences.oreilly.com/&quot;&gt;O'Reilly Open Source Convention&lt;/a&gt;. I'm on a panel at 2PM (tomorrow!) with Paul Everitt, Guido Van Rossum and Eric S. Raymond. There was a scheduling screwup so I'm relaxing and learning a little about Perl and Python. I just watched the Perl Bowl. It was funny. Also it's funny that I can update the home page from the computer room. Even though there are 50 people in the room, it's silent. All you can hear is clicking of keys. Lots of clicking of lots of keys. Hey I could get used to this." created="Mon, 23 Aug 1999 05:04:49 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="On second thought I miss my laptop, even though its keyboard doesn't work well. This system is running Netscape on Linux. The clipboard doesn't work right. It refreshes pages when I go back and forward, wiping out what I typed. And it looks cheezy! I miss Windows! I'm going to say that on stage tomorrow. (Probably not.)" created="Mon, 23 Aug 1999 05:05:03 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="PS: I figured out how to use the clipboard." created="Mon, 23 Aug 1999 05:06:15 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 22" created="Sun, 22 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="DaveNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1999/08/22/readerProfiles&quot;&gt;Who Reads DaveNet&lt;/a&gt;? Thanks to Jakob Nielsen, Dan Gillmor, Craig Cline, Brent Schlender, Pam Edstrom, Bill Gates, Jim Gable, Rick LeFaivre, Jesse Berst, Douglas Adams, Kevin Fong, Andrew Anker, Dan Shafer, Adam Curry and John Perry Barlow for participating." created="Sun, 22 Aug 1999 05:01:23 GMT" name="davenetAHrefhttpdavenetuserlandcom19990822readerprofileswhoReadsDavenetaThanksToJakobNielsenDanGillmorCraigClineBrentSchlenderPamEdstromBillGatesJimGableRickLefaivreJesseBerstDouglasAdamsKevinFongAndrewAnkerDanShaferAdamCurryAndJohnPerryBarlowForParticipating" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9774&quot;&gt;Frontier 6.1d16&lt;/a&gt; is now running. This should increase performance on MailToTheFuture and the main DG, as examples. We're also hot on the trail of a crashing bug. &lt;i&gt;Excellent!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Sun, 22 Aug 1999 05:02:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techweek.com/articles/8-23-99/needle.htm&quot;&gt;TechWeek's David Needle&lt;/a&gt; on me. &quot;User interface design has become a lost art. In the early day of PCs, prior to the Mac, every program had its own UI. The Web is now in that position, where every site has a different UI. The next big thing is going to be a standard UI for the Web, so we have to decide what the basic features are a site needs. If we do it right, it will be better for users.&quot;" created="Sun, 22 Aug 1999 05:03:28 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="There's a lot of confusion in the Needle piece. Some important things were dropped in the editing process, I guess. Here's my &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9783&quot;&gt;response&lt;/a&gt;. After reading Needle's piece and responding to it, I read the Microsoft pages on the review sites for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/davenet/97/review/microsoft.html&quot;&gt;1997&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/davenet/98/review/microsoft.html&quot;&gt;1998&lt;/a&gt;. I think I've been pretty consistent, preaching peace and love, and trying to understand Microsoft, playing dumb and taking them at face value, and then pointing out where the contradictions are. This is all in the hope of pointing the way, getting them back on course, so they don't try to hold back progress, in fact, I want Microsoft to  *help* the new software world shape itself around the Internet. I've always believed since the Bill Gates vs The Internet piece in 1994, that Microsoft had to adapt to a world where they didn't set the standards. I believe that even more today." created="Sun, 22 Aug 1999 05:04:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sjmercury.com/svtech/columns/gillmor/docs/dg082299.htm&quot;&gt;Dan Gillmor&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;My ability to get nearly instant responses to my e-mail query from so many smart people feels close to miraculous. It's just a hint of what's to come.&quot;" created="Sun, 22 Aug 1999 05:05:11 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/library/tech/99/08/biztech/articles/22pape.html&quot;&gt;NY Times&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The conventional wisdom of the new economy says newspapers ought to be on their last legs. In this view, it will not be long before the Internet eats the newspapers' lunch by siphoning off readers and advertising to Web sites.&quot;" created="Sun, 22 Aug 1999 05:06:10 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.herald.com/herald/content/archive/living/barry/1999/docs/aug15.htm&quot;&gt;Dave Barry&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Nowadays all of the hip modern newspapers spend millions of dollars operating Web sites where we give away the entire newspaper for free. Sometimes we run advertisements in the regular newspaper urging our remaining paying customers to go to our Web sites instead. &lt;i&gt;Stop giving us money!&lt;/i&gt; is the shrewd marketing thrust of these ads.&quot;" created="Sun, 22 Aug 1999 05:07:21 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://cnn.com/US/9908/22/sagan.mairjuana.ap/&quot;&gt;CNN&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The late astronomer and author Carl Sagan was a secret but avid marijuana smoker, crediting it with inspiring essays and scientific insight, according to Sagan's biographer.&quot;" created="Sun, 22 Aug 1999 05:08:53 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 21" created="Sat, 21 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Milestone: This morning I wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9763&quot;&gt;discuss.userland.com&lt;/a&gt; message using a new Frontier suite that allows me to write in a standard outliner window. When I save the window, it goes directly into the server's database. It's the fastest way yet to write for a server that's far away. I can always edit text in the web browser, but for more demanding writing jobs, there's nothing like having a smooth desktop writing app." created="Sat, 21 Aug 1999 05:01:56 GMT" name="milestoneThisMorningIWroteAAHrefhttpdiscussuserlandcommsgreader9763discussuserlandcomaMessageUsingANewFrontierSuiteThatAllowsMeToWriteInAStandardOutlinerWindowWhenISaveTheWindowItGoesDirectlyIntoTheServersDatabaseItsTheFastestWayYetToWriteForAServerThatsFarAwayICanAlwaysEditTextInTheWebBrowserButForMoreDemandingWritingJobsTheresNothingLikeHavingASmoothDesktopWritingApp" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.outliners.com/images/frontier6/suitesDg.gif&quot;&gt;screen shot&lt;/a&gt; of the Frontier suite in action, with its menu pulled down. This still is quite rough, we're planning changes to the Frontier kernel to support this new usage. It's a work in progress. We encourage other writing tool vendors to compete with us. The more compatible writing tools there are, the more fun we'll have on the server." created="Sat, 21 Aug 1999 05:02:38 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Next week we'll release the spec for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xmlrpc.com/stories/storyReader$7&quot;&gt;XML-RPC&lt;/a&gt; calls that connect the workstation with the server. The interface is cross-platform, and will be easily supported on all major operating systems." created="Sat, 21 Aug 1999 05:03:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Online Journalism Review: &lt;a href=&quot;http://ojr.usc.edu/indexf.htm?/sections/features/99_stories/stories_access_072399.htm&quot;&gt;The Mythical Press Box&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Billy Payne, the executive chairman of the Atlantic Olympic Committee, after explaining that there just weren't enough credentials to go around to include the masses of online reporters among the 10,000 or so other journalists, added ominously in 1996, 'We have our own Web site.'&quot;" created="Sat, 21 Aug 1999 05:04:55 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.suck.com/daily/99/08/20/daily.html&quot;&gt;Suck&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The fat guy down in MIS may love remote administration, but he'll end up suffering with Windows 2000 until StarOffice has that talking paper clip his users like so much.&quot;" created="Sat, 21 Aug 1999 05:05:41 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.rhbnc.ac.uk/Classics/NJL/more3ref.html&quot;&gt;Nick Lowe turned&lt;/a&gt; the MORE 3.1 refcard into a web page." created="Sat, 21 Aug 1999 05:07:00 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 20" created="Fri, 20 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Another incredible day and week at Scripting News. It's hard to believe how much we get done here. And it's a total community thing. &lt;i&gt;Thanks!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 20 Aug 1999 05:01:14 GMT" name="anotherIncredibleDayAndWeekAtScriptingNewsItsHardToBelieveHowMuchWeGetDoneHereAndItsATotalCommunityThingIthanksi" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xml-rpc.com/discuss/msgReader$136&quot;&gt;The next step for XML-RPC&lt;/a&gt;. We're going to specify a set of calls for hooking a desktop text editor into UserLand-hosted discussion groups. Of course the interfaces will be open so &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; collaborative content system can support them." created="Fri, 20 Aug 1999 05:02:42 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.evolt.org/index.cfm?menu=13&quot;&gt;Evolt.Org was created&lt;/a&gt; when Wired claimed copyright ownership of the WebMonkey mail list. It's a fascinating site, and was the source for yesterday's ultimate antique browser listing." created="Fri, 20 Aug 1999 05:03:06 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="WebMonkey has a different point of view on Evolt.Org, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9755&quot;&gt;Taylor expresses&lt;/a&gt; it here on Discuss.UserLand.Com." created="Fri, 20 Aug 1999 05:04:37 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9735&quot;&gt;Jakob Nielsen is&lt;/a&gt; a strong proponent of meta tags." created="Fri, 20 Aug 1999 05:05:26 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://palm.ddbniac.com/msgReader$1&quot;&gt;Mike Murry started&lt;/a&gt; a discussion group for Palm users. &lt;i&gt;Excellent!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 20 Aug 1999 05:06:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9752&quot;&gt;Microsoft's new Developer Division&lt;/a&gt; will hold a press briefing with Microsoft President Steve Ballmer and Group Vice President Paul Maritz on Monday, Sept. 13. " created="Fri, 20 Aug 1999 05:07:36 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.news.com/News/Item/0,4,40754,00.html?st.ne.fd.gif.d&quot;&gt;According to News.Com&lt;/a&gt;, Sun is buying application vendor Star Division. " created="Fri, 20 Aug 1999 05:08:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.outliners.com/msgReader$188&quot;&gt;Brad Pettit improved&lt;/a&gt; the MORE to XML converter app." created="Fri, 20 Aug 1999 05:09:27 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Outliners.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.outliners.com/more31.html&quot;&gt;MORE 3.1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.outliners.com/more30.html&quot;&gt;3.0&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 20 Aug 1999 05:10:06 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Wired: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/news/news/business/story/21355.html&quot;&gt;Chris Nolan Speaks for Herself&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;This has been a particularly difficult month for me. In the course of my more than 15 years as a reporter, I have landed more than my share of punches. And I can take a few. But these last few blows feel like rabbit punches; the hits are from behind and below.&quot;" created="Fri, 20 Aug 1999 05:11:38 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Bring on the next clonemaker, &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9720&quot;&gt;Compaq&lt;/a&gt;. They should pay me for helping them debug their customer service. " created="Fri, 20 Aug 1999 05:12:41 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1996/07/31/thecompaqofisps&quot;&gt;In 1996 I said&lt;/a&gt; I wanted an ISP that was as reliable and service-oriented as Compaq was in the 1980s. &quot;We standardized on Compaq. All new machines purchased by the company had to be Compaqs. When we made this choice, the service got even better.&quot;" created="Fri, 20 Aug 1999 05:13:22 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="From an anonymous source, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9733&quot;&gt;secret&lt;/a&gt; for getting good service from Compaq, in 1999." created="Fri, 20 Aug 1999 05:14:41 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW we found a great ISP. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.conxion.com/&quot;&gt;Conxion&lt;/a&gt; has been rock-solid, responsive and professional for two-plus years, thru lots of growth on both sides. I recommend them without reservation. &lt;i&gt;Bravo!&lt;/i&gt; " created="Fri, 20 Aug 1999 05:15:30 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="New channels: &lt;a href=&quot;http://my.userland.com/viewChannel$1230&quot;&gt;Hacker News Network&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://my.userland.com/viewChannel$1223&quot;&gt;Adobe Gallery&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 20 Aug 1999 05:16:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The next controversy? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/300506.asp&quot;&gt;Meta tag theft&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;I don't get it.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 20 Aug 1999 05:17:34 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.altavista.com/av/content/addurl_meta.htm&quot;&gt;AltaVista on Meta tags&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 20 Aug 1999 05:18:38 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 18" created="Wed, 18 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Dave Winer: &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9626&quot;&gt;What is Scripting News&lt;/a&gt;? &quot;I didn't just want a site that reported on what's happening in the web development world, I wanted to create a place where web development &lt;i&gt;happened.&lt;/i&gt;&quot;" created="Wed, 18 Aug 1999 05:01:41 GMT" name="daveWinerAHrefhttpdiscussuserlandcommsgreader9626whatIsScriptingNewsaIDidntJustWantASiteThatReportedOnWhatsHappeningInTheWebDevelopmentWorldIWantedToCreateAPlaceWhereWebDevelopmentIhappenedi" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9645&quot;&gt;James Spahr has&lt;/a&gt; an XML-RPC client for AppleScript." created="Wed, 18 Aug 1999 05:02:10 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edprint.demon.co.uk/se/macweb.html&quot;&gt;More antique web browsers&lt;/a&gt;, for Macs of the late 80s, like the Mac SE. I wonder if Frontier 1.0 runs on these machines. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.outliners.com/more11c.html&quot;&gt;MORE 1.1c&lt;/a&gt; surely did." created="Wed, 18 Aug 1999 05:03:41 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Chris Nolan: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pathfinder.com/fortune/technology/1999/09/06/tec.html&quot;&gt;How I Got a Chance at .Com Wealth&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 18 Aug 1999 05:04:02 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="MSNBC: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/302207.asp&quot;&gt;ICANN close to financial ruin&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;In the process of trying to secure funds, it may have violated federal law.&quot;" created="Wed, 18 Aug 1999 05:05:33 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Scott Rosenberg: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salonmagazine.com/tech/col/rose/1999/08/18/more_links/index.html&quot;&gt;More on Deep Links&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;While most Web sites crave links and depend on them to get the word out and garner new traffic, these companies have instead sicced their lawyers on the linkers.&quot;" created="Wed, 18 Aug 1999 05:06:26 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.news.com/News/Item/0,4,40637,00.html?scriptingNews&quot;&gt;According to News.Com&lt;/a&gt;, Microsoft will release a specification describing how their Instant Messaging server works. I can't wait to see it. I immediately want to have a server, running in Frontier, so we can flow chat conversations out to to the web. I think the IM clients would make an interesting weblog authoring tool." created="Wed, 18 Aug 1999 05:07:06 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9146&quot;&gt;On 8/5/99&lt;/a&gt;, Microsoft's Yusuf Mehdi, the marketing director for MSN, said: &quot;We will deliver an SDK for developers and we will have it out in the first quarter of next year. We're shooting to have it out before end of year.&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9147&quot;&gt;My response&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I didn't request an SDK. If you had an open and documented communication protocol no SDK would be necessary.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Moral of the story: Microsoft, unlike all the other 800-pound gorillas, listens, and sometimes they respond.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Wed, 18 Aug 1999 05:08:21 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://linux2.userland.com/users/admin/static/misc/timBrayOnSdk.html&quot;&gt;Tim Bray on SDKs&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;I grew up with networked minicomputers and (mostly) Unix, and maybe that's why, in the final analysis, I always want to see the bits on the wire.&quot;" created="Wed, 18 Aug 1999 05:09:21 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="MacCentral: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.maccentral.com/news/9908/18.briggs.shtml&quot;&gt;AppleScript Primer&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 18 Aug 1999 05:10:50 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Peterme: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.peterme.com/bvsucks/index.html&quot;&gt;Why Broadvision Sucks&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;For the past 3 years, I've had various clients that used Broadvision for their application server. And, in each case, Broadvision was a nightmare to deal with. The people who sell Broadvision know this, so what they do is head straight to the people with money but no tech savvy on the client side, and mesmerize them with tales of One To One Marketing and the people with money fork it over without bothering to learn that the system is bloated, slow, and pathetic.&quot;" created="Wed, 18 Aug 1999 05:11:32 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="USGS: &lt;a href=&quot;http://quake.wr.usgs.gov/recenteqs/Quakes/nc40104152.html&quot;&gt;Information on yesterday's California earthquake&lt;/a&gt;. The quake was centered in &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.yahoo.com/py/maps.py?Pyt=Tmap&amp;YY=29670&amp;city=Bolinas&amp;state=CA&amp;slt=37.9082&amp;sln=-122.6975&amp;mag=7&amp;cs=5&amp;newmag=6&quot;&gt;Bolinas&lt;/a&gt;, a hippie community on the ocean in Marin County, just north of San Francisco." created="Wed, 18 Aug 1999 05:12:23 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="A slice of life on the Internet. Inktomi's robot is crawling the &lt;a href=&quot;http://pointers.userland.com/configDomains/default/virgin.root/&quot;&gt;virgin root file&lt;/a&gt; that we keep on Nirvana. It's been doing it slowly for the last couple of days. Basically all the source we ship with Frontier will be accessible thru their search engine. It should be funny!" created="Wed, 18 Aug 1999 05:13:51 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="More life on the Internet. Now we're starting to get Y2K queries about &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$2916&quot;&gt;IdleTime&lt;/a&gt;. Does anyone know if it is Y2K compliant? I have no idea, and I don't care!" created="Wed, 18 Aug 1999 05:14:25 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;i&gt;Heads up!&lt;/i&gt; My old account, dwiner\@well.com, has gone inactive. I wasn't checking the account regularly. So, if that's the address you have for me, please change it to dave\@userland.com. Thanks!" created="Wed, 18 Aug 1999 05:15:21 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 17" created="Tue, 17 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="MSNBC: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/301678.asp&quot;&gt;Internet is Y2K ready.. maybe&lt;/a&gt;. Think about it. How many iterations did it take to shake out all the month rollover glitches in your site? How many problems were there *last* Jan 1? Were they horrible? Probably not. But the Internet will definitely have problems on Jan 1. Remember Murphy! (As if I have to tell *you*.)" created="Tue, 17 Aug 1999 05:01:43 GMT" name="msnbcAHrefhttpwwwmsnbccomnews301678aspinternetIsY2kReadyMaybeaThinkAboutItHowManyIterationsDidItTakeToShakeOutAllTheMonthRolloverGlitchesInYourSiteHowManyProblemsWereThereLastJan1WereTheyHorribleProbablyNotButTheInternetWillDefinitelyHaveProblemsOnJan1RememberMurphyAsIfIHaveToTellYou" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="We're running new software on our main server. By clicking on &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9591&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;, you are helping us test it. &lt;i&gt;Give my regards to Murphy!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Tue, 17 Aug 1999 05:02:15 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="This afternoon I felt the earth shake. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnn.com/US/9908/17/calif.quake.01.ap/&quot;&gt;I wasn't dreaming&lt;/a&gt;. I put on my shoes and bolted outdoors. It's been a while. &lt;i&gt;I hate earthquakes!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Tue, 17 Aug 1999 05:03:47 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://web.0sil8.com/episodes/98/01/14/index2.html&quot;&gt;Jason Kottke collects&lt;/a&gt; antique web browsers. &lt;i&gt;Excellent!&lt;/i&gt; " created="Tue, 17 Aug 1999 05:04:38 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;ftp://archive:oldies@archive.netscape.com/archive/index.html&quot;&gt;Netscape has&lt;/a&gt; an archive site." created="Tue, 17 Aug 1999 05:05:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9605&quot;&gt;Sten Linarsson believes&lt;/a&gt; he has found Tim Berners-Lee's original WWW application for NeXT. (1993)" created="Tue, 17 Aug 1999 05:06:21 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.herring.com/insider/1999/0818/cip-comaford.html&quot;&gt;According to Red Herring&lt;/a&gt; my friend Christine Comaford is a Big Fish. &lt;i&gt;Yeah I knew that!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Tue, 17 Aug 1999 05:07:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Yesterday I took &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.outliners.com/msgReader$159&quot;&gt;screen shots&lt;/a&gt; of Frontier 6/Win, focusing on the built-in outliner. Since re-releasing the Mac outliners, there's been a stream of questions from people wanting to know if there are any similar outliners on Windows. Yes there are. We have one. " created="Tue, 17 Aug 1999 05:08:21 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9608&quot;&gt;Seattle FUG Meeting&lt;/a&gt;, 8/24." created="Tue, 17 Aug 1999 05:09:42 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9593&quot;&gt;Macrobyte&lt;/a&gt; releases Tonto 1.0b7." created="Tue, 17 Aug 1999 05:10:26 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoworld.com/cgi-bin/displayStory.pl?990817.piwin2000.htm&quot;&gt;InfoWorld lists&lt;/a&gt; four versions of Windows 2000, all to ship later this year or early next. No prices." created="Tue, 17 Aug 1999 05:11:59 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="MSNBC: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/301169.asp&quot;&gt;We have You have Mail&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;AT&amp;T’s use of the phrase 'you have mail' dates back to the earliest days of the Unix programming language, which the company's research arm, Bell Labs, developed.&quot;" created="Tue, 17 Aug 1999 05:12:05 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Thanks to Ric Ford for pointing to Frontier 1.0 from his Mac Antiques &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macintouch.com/earlymac2.html#apps&quot;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;. One minor nit, Frontier 1.0 comes from UserLand, not &quot;Dave Winer&quot;. You might think they're the same thing, but they're not. ;-&gt;" created="Tue, 17 Aug 1999 05:13:45 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hartscientific.com/y2k.htm&quot;&gt;Hart Scientific on Y2K&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;If any banks are still operating after January 3, 2000, we want to be able to deposit our checks in them.&quot;" created="Tue, 17 Aug 1999 05:14:06 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 16" created="Mon, 16 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="DaveNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1999/08/16/antiquesInLondonAndWashington&quot;&gt;Antiques in London and Washington&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;As far as I know VisiCalc didn't create any patents, even though they surely could have. And we didn't register any patents for our early outliners at Living Videotext, the company that Symantec acquired.&quot;" created="Mon, 16 Aug 1999 05:01:36 GMT" name="davenetAHrefhttpdavenetuserlandcom19990816antiquesinlondonandwashingtonantiquesInLondonAndWashingtonaAsFarAsIKnowVisicalcDidntCreateAnyPatentsEvenThoughTheySurelyCouldHaveAndWeDidntRegisterAnyPatentsForOurEarlyOutlinersAtLivingVideotextTheCompanyThatSymantecAcquired" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/business/feed/a3591-1999aug16.htm&quot;&gt;Washington Post&lt;/a&gt; on antique software. &quot;How can anything be an 'antique' in a world that's only about 20 years old?&quot;" created="Mon, 16 Aug 1999 05:02:20 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.news.com/News/Item/0,4,40561,00.html?st.ne.fd.gif.d&quot;&gt;News.Com reports&lt;/a&gt; that Wal-Mart and K-Mart may be selling $299 PCs this Christmas running GEOS, not Windows. GEOS is an antique, for sure, that's apparently still ticking. &lt;i&gt;Yeah!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 16 Aug 1999 05:03:05 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9579&quot;&gt;Jim Whitehead&lt;/a&gt; on ShareMation, &quot;the first DAV-capable Internet storage site. In under 5 minutes, you can be up and running with 20 Meg of storage.&quot;" created="Mon, 16 Aug 1999 05:04:27 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Just for fun I added screen shots to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9458&quot;&gt;Frontier 1.0 page&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 16 Aug 1999 05:05:28 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;i&gt;Heads up! Just 23 days before 9/9/99, the dry run for Y2K. (In the old days, 'sentinel' records in data files were often given the value 99. Some people believe systems may fail, in a Y2K way, on September 9 this year.)&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 16 Aug 1999 05:06:22 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="CNN: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnn.com/TECH/space/9908/16/cassini.flyby/&quot;&gt;Nuclear-powered NASA craft to swing by Earth&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Cassini will probably execute a flawless mission around the Earth if it can make the last hurdle through 8,000 pieces of 'space junk' surrounding the Earth.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Dear Murphy!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 16 Aug 1999 05:07:28 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="WebReference.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://webreference.com/js/column46/index.html&quot;&gt;DOM-based Snakes&lt;/a&gt;. (Hint: &lt;a href=&quot;http://webreference.com/js/column46/puzzle.html&quot;&gt;Try&lt;/a&gt; the game first.)" created="Mon, 16 Aug 1999 05:08:28 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="InternetWeek: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techweb.com/se/directlink.cgi?INW19990816S0045&quot;&gt;XML Comes of Age&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 16 Aug 1999 05:09:31 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.outliners.com/msgReader$143&quot;&gt;Michael McCarthy&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;None of the PIMs have to-do list/project managers as good as a good outliner.&quot; &lt;i&gt;I agree!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 16 Aug 1999 05:10:41 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.news.com/News/Item/0,4,40531,00.html?st.ne.fd.gif.e&quot;&gt;Iona doesn't want to be a footnote&lt;/a&gt;. I'm co-chairing the distributed computing track at &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1999/07/10/distributedComputingWww9&quot;&gt;WWW9&lt;/a&gt; in Amsterdam next year with Iona's CTO. I'm going to send him a pointer to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xmlrpc.com/&quot;&gt;XML-RPC&lt;/a&gt;. It's even simpler than EJB." created="Mon, 16 Aug 1999 05:11:35 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/library/tech/99/08/biztech/articles/16digi.html&quot;&gt;Denise Caruso&lt;/a&gt; on infinite loops. &quot;Remember artificial intelligence? Pen computing? Both were the Next Big Thing -- hot investment targets that became big losers -- in the 1980s.&quot;" created="Mon, 16 Aug 1999 05:12:05 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="12/24/95: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1995/12/24/whiteboywelfare&quot;&gt;White Boy Welfare&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;I've known Denise Caruso, the media columnist for the New York Times, since we were both rookies in the software business back in the mid 80s. I've always admired her spirit and intelligence. She's irreverent and experienced. There's a spike in Caruso's curve, a sharp edge, a clean anger. She's a powerful person.&quot;" created="Mon, 16 Aug 1999 05:13:25 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appleinsider.com/articles/9908/internet-explorer-five.shtml&quot;&gt;AppleInsider reviews&lt;/a&gt; MSIE 5.0/Mac. &quot;Mac Internet Explorer 5.0 is in the mid-beta stages, and requires a PowerPC-based Macintosh and system 7.6.1 or greater. The release is expected sometime this Fall.&quot;" created="Mon, 16 Aug 1999 05:14:24 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 15" created="Sun, 15 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="London Times: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sunday-times.co.uk/news/pages/sti/99/08/15/stiinnsnd01001.html?999&quot;&gt;VisiCalc is how programs ought to be&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Back in the early days, programs tended to speak their own language and nothing else. To insert a spreadsheet into a word-processing document or presentation was no small feat. And e-mail, if it existed at all, was just a few words of text shared between people who happened to have compatible mail systems.&quot;" created="Sun, 15 Aug 1999 05:01:19 GMT" name="londonTimesAHrefhttpwwwsundaytimescouknewspagessti990815stiinnsnd01001html999visicalcIsHowProgramsOughtToBeaBackInTheEarlyDaysProgramsTendedToSpeakTheirOwnLanguageAndNothingElseToInsertASpreadsheetIntoAWordprocessingDocumentOrPresentationWasNoSmallFeatAndEmailIfItExistedAtAllWasJustAFewWordsOfTextSharedBetweenPeopleWhoHappenedToHaveCompatibleMailSystems" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, the London Times article points to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.outliners.com/&quot;&gt;outliners.com&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Thanks!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Sun, 15 Aug 1999 05:02:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="So, &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9534&quot;&gt;where are we&lt;/a&gt; going with antique software?" created="Sun, 15 Aug 1999 05:03:59 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Linux Journal: &lt;a href=&quot;http://linuxjournal.com:82/articles/currents/003.html&quot;&gt;Can Linux Survive Patents&lt;/a&gt;? &quot;The PTO has handed out thousands of patents for trivial software techniques that any developer working independently would discover. Little attempt is made to determine prior art. Increasingly, the agency is granting patents for obvious techniques that wouldn't surprise a 'Net-savvy sixth grader, let alone an expert.&quot;" created="Sun, 15 Aug 1999 05:04:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linuxworld.com/linuxworldtoday/lwt-indepth7.html&quot;&gt;LinuxWorld interviews&lt;/a&gt; Richard Stallman." created="Sun, 15 Aug 1999 05:05:48 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 14" created="Sat, 14 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Feature Request: &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9518&quot;&gt;Favorites Menu in Windows Explorer&lt;/a&gt;. When I posted this I wasn't aware that this feature is in Windows 98. I run NT4 Workstation SP4. I'm so confused. I thought I was using the OS MS wants me to?" created="Sat, 14 Aug 1999 05:01:03 GMT" name="featureRequestAHrefhttpdiscussuserlandcommsgreader9518favoritesMenuInWindowsExploreraWhenIPostedThisIWasntAwareThatThisFeatureIsInWindows98IRunNt4WorkstationSp4ImSoConfusedIThoughtIWasUsingTheOsMsWantsMeTo" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Even so, this begat another &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9520&quot;&gt;feature request&lt;/a&gt; for Windows Explorer. That's how it always seems to work, one new feature idea begets twelve others." created="Sat, 14 Aug 1999 05:02:48 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.news.com/SpecialFeatures/0,5,39916,00.html&quot;&gt;Resistance is Futile&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Borland was under siege, even as the company moved into a controversial $70 million headquarters in Scotts Valley, California, a sprawling high-tech campus that would later be described by visitors as a ghost town.&quot; " created="Sat, 14 Aug 1999 05:03:26 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/news/news/culture/story/21262.html&quot;&gt;Wired reviews Silicon Boys&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;For all his swashbuckling stature in the Valley, Larry Ellison's Ferrari-burning, skirt-chasing, jet-piloting antics are really just B-team rock star stuff. He may be the baddest boy in the Valley, but once you step outside of the pocket-protector set, he's really not that bad at all.&quot;" created="Sat, 14 Aug 1999 05:04:34 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Red Herring: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.herring.com/insider/1999/0814/vc-vcps.html&quot;&gt;August Capital opens its doors&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Some cynics might say Sand Hill Road is simply not given to this kind of self-promotion.&quot;" created="Sat, 14 Aug 1999 05:05:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 13" created="Fri, 13 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Antique: &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9458&quot;&gt;Frontier 1.0&lt;/a&gt;. (January 1992)" created="Fri, 13 Aug 1999 05:01:41 GMT" name="antiqueAHrefhttpdiscussuserlandcommsgreader9458frontier10aJanuary1992" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="New feature: &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/stats/mostReadMessages&quot;&gt;Top 25 Most-read DG Messages&lt;/a&gt;. Rankings are compiled every night shortly after midnight, Pacific." created="Fri, 13 Aug 1999 05:02:35 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Even newer: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/stats/mostReadMessages&quot;&gt;Top 50 Most-read DaveNet Pieces&lt;/a&gt;. We started tracking per-piece reads on the DaveNet site ten days ago. Already I have a better idea of how DaveNet pieces age. " created="Fri, 13 Aug 1999 05:03:40 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The most-read &quot;old&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/stories/storyReader$283&quot;&gt;piece&lt;/a&gt; is about HTML." created="Fri, 13 Aug 1999 05:04:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://my.userland.com/viewChannel$1053&quot;&gt;Jacob's Angst&lt;/a&gt; is back after a bout with the flu." created="Fri, 13 Aug 1999 05:05:40 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.news.com/News/Item/0,4,84-40456,00.html?tt.yfin..txt.ni&quot;&gt;What AOL Stands to Lose in Browser War&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;A Microsoft browser monopoly could spell disaster for the leading online service and other Microsoft competitors on the Web, as content and commerce ventures could be forced to deal with Microsoft for access to any consumer getting on the Web from a PC.&quot;" created="Fri, 13 Aug 1999 05:06:32 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="SF Chronicle: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?file=/chronicle/archive/1999/08/13/BU88344.DTL&amp;type=tech_article&quot;&gt;TV Firms Threaten to Sue TiVo, Replay&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 13 Aug 1999 05:07:36 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;i&gt;I received word that InfoWorld is changing their linking policy and will have an official statement shortly. I have read a synopsis of the new policy and support it wholeheartedly.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 13 Aug 1999 05:08:13 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.civic.com/services/trademark.html&quot;&gt;Civic.Com&lt;/a&gt;'s linking policy: &quot;We invite you to link to any/all of our web pages. We do not view this as duplication.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Civic.Com, like InfoWorld and ComputerWorld, is an IDG publication.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 13 Aug 1999 05:09:46 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="WebMonkey (1996): &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hotwired.com/webmonkey/geektalk/96/47/index4a.html?tw=backend&quot;&gt;Who's Linking to You&lt;/a&gt;?" created="Fri, 13 Aug 1999 05:10:07 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="WebMonkey: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hotwired.com/webmonkey/99/33/index4a.html?tw=frontdoor&quot;&gt;Choosing a Publishing System&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 13 Aug 1999 05:11:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="A middle-of-the-night thought. If open source projects are various kinds of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techweb.com/wire/story/TWB19990812S0003&quot;&gt;dictatorships&lt;/a&gt;, what happened to the bazaar? Was that just marketing hype? Sounds pretty cathedral-like to me. " created="Fri, 13 Aug 1999 05:12:25 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 12" created="Thu, 12 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="DaveNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1999/08/12/infoworldAndDeepLinking&quot;&gt;InfoWorld and Deep Linking&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Bottom-line, could the web get by without InfoWorld? Yes. Could InfoWorld exist without support from the web? I think not.&quot;" created="Thu, 12 Aug 1999 05:01:46 GMT" name="davenetAHrefhttpdavenetuserlandcom19990812infoworldanddeeplinkinginfoworldAndDeepLinkingaBottomlineCouldTheWebGetByWithoutInfoworldYesCouldInfoworldExistWithoutSupportFromTheWebIThinkNot" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="TechWeb: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techweb.com/wire/story/TWB19990812S0003&quot;&gt;Open Source Dictatorships&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;My workload is lower because I don't have to see the crazy ideas,&quot; Torvalds said. &quot;I see the end point of work done for a few months or even a year by other people.&quot; " created="Thu, 12 Aug 1999 05:02:23 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/unbound/digicult/dc990812.htm&quot;&gt;Atlantic Monthly&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Heads turned in June when Linus Torvalds's Linux operating system was awarded first prize by the judges of an international art festival. How far, one wonders, can the open source model go?&quot;" created="Thu, 12 Aug 1999 05:03:57 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Scott Rosenberg: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salon.com/tech/col/rose/1999/08/12/deep_links/index.html&quot;&gt;Don't Link or I'll Sue&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Objectors to deep linking, like Ticketmaster and Universal, want to have their Web businesses both ways: They put their services and content out on the public Web to attract users, but they also expect to be able to control every facet of how those users access their services and content.&quot;" created="Thu, 12 Aug 1999 05:04:37 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xmlrpc.com/discuss/msgReader$116&quot;&gt;Phil Wolff likes&lt;/a&gt; XML-RPC for Preferences, but wants to know about privacy." created="Thu, 12 Aug 1999 05:05:24 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Wired: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/news/news/culture/story/21243.html&quot;&gt;Firefly Snuffed&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;By mid-1997, the company had become a standard-bearer for 'Open Profiling,' and was working with Microsoft and Netscape, among others, to establish rules and regulations for how sites handled information about their users.&quot;" created="Thu, 12 Aug 1999 05:06:11 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Linking policies: &lt;a href=&quot;http://nasdaq-amex.com/sitespecific/IndexPromptDisclaimer.stm#copyright&quot;&gt;NASDAQ&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lasallebanks.com/disclaim.html&quot;&gt;LaSalle Banks&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 12 Aug 1999 05:07:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://llanfairpwllgwyngyllgogerychwyrndrobwllllantysiliogogogoch.co.uk/history.htm&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; that doesn't mind being linked to. They claim to have the longest domain name on the net!" created="Thu, 12 Aug 1999 05:08:40 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.netfunny.com/rhf/jokes/89q2/hat.488.html&quot;&gt;A funny joke&lt;/a&gt; linked to from an awkward &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.outliners.com/msgReader$115&quot;&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt; on Outliners.Com." created="Thu, 12 Aug 1999 05:09:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$9387&quot;&gt;Daniel Bushman&lt;/a&gt;, a Frontier user, witnessed yesterday's freak tornado in Salt Lake City.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Thu, 12 Aug 1999 05:10:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 11" created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="XML.COM: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xml.com/pub/1999/08/rpc/index.html&quot;&gt;Implementing XML-RPC in PHP&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;As some web sites become more like online applications, the advantages of offering a programmable API into their services are obvious.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Excellent!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:01:16 GMT" name="xmlcomAHrefhttpwwwxmlcompub199908rpcindexhtmlimplementingXmlrpcInPhpaAsSomeWebSitesBecomeMoreLikeOnlineApplicationsTheAdvantagesOfOfferingAProgrammableApiIntoTheirServicesAreObviousIexcellenti" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xmlrpc.com/discuss/msgReader$102&quot;&gt;XML-RPC for Preferences&lt;/a&gt;. User preferences can be shared among servers running in different environments on different operating systems anywhere in the world." created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:02:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.news.com/News/Item/0,4,40385,00.html?st.ne.fd.gif.e&quot;&gt;Microsoft's New APIs&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;To stem the flow of developers away from the fold, the company needs a development tool that does for Web development what its Visual Basic tool did to revolutionize Windows development back in 1991.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Interesting!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:03:42 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;i&gt;BTW, I heard from someone in the know at InfoWorld, and their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoworld.com/cgi-bin/displayStat.pl?/readerservices/permissions.htm#link2&quot;&gt;linking policy&lt;/a&gt; is for real. They really expect people to ask for permission to link to their stories. This is a big problem!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:04:26 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Matt Neuburg (1993): &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tidbits.com/tb-issues/TidBITS-198.html#lnk5&quot;&gt;MORE, MORE Dinosaur&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:05:19 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The Economist: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.economist.com/editorial/freeforall/current/wb1428.html&quot;&gt;Bill Joy, the Brains behind Sun&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;But whereas Bill Gates long ago said goodbye to geekdom (whatever Microsoft’s PR machine might say to the contrary), Mr Joy remains resolutely nerdy—a tall, rather shambling figure with a shock of ungovernable hair and a penchant for denim shirts worn with a slightly shiny suede waistcoat. True to form, Mr Joy can also be pretty hard to understand.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Don't feel bad, I'm a geek and I find him hard to understand too.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:06:49 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.simpletodo.com/more.html&quot;&gt;Simple ToDo&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Simple To Do has all the features you'd expect in a list manager -- you can prioritize items, sort them, mark them as Done, and it's even hierarchical so you can create sub-items to your main items.&quot; &lt;i&gt;It's an outliner!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:07:38 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Another excellent classic Mac outliner: &lt;a href=&quot;http://a-sharp.com/acta/download.html&quot;&gt;Acta&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:08:55 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Dan Bricklin: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bricklin.com/history/vcpostingreactions.htm&quot;&gt;Reactions to the posting of VisiCalc&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bricklin.com/history/othersites.htm&quot;&gt;Other History Sites&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:09:38 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="New Channel: &lt;a href=&quot;http://my.userland.com/viewChannel$1212&quot;&gt;Frontier News&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Excellent!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:10:51 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://jimfl.yi.org/~jimfl/throw.cgi&quot;&gt;Jim Flanagan shows&lt;/a&gt; how a simple CGI can prevent deep linking. The lawsuits can end now. All they have to do is upgrade their servers." created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:11:17 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.outliners.com/msgReader$87&quot;&gt;A script&lt;/a&gt; that reads text from a MORE file into a Frontier outline." created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:12:28 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://quote.yahoo.com/q?s=rhat&amp;d=v1&quot;&gt;Red Hat&lt;/a&gt; IPO a stunner. &lt;i&gt;Congrats!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:13:57 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.news.com/News/Item/0,4,84-40355,00.html?tt.yfin..txt.ni&quot;&gt;News.Com&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;It's not your ordinary high-tech IPO.&quot;" created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:14:28 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Motley Fool: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fool.com/news/1999/sgi990810.htm&quot;&gt;SGI Bids Farewell to NT&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:15:32 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="MSNBC: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/299530.asp&quot;&gt;Deadly Tornado Hits Salt Lake&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;A sudden tornado touched down without warning Wednesday in the downtown area of Salt Lake City, damaging buildings, killing four and causing dozens of injuries.&quot;" created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:16:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Upside: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.upside.com/texis/mvm/story?id=379de6b70&quot;&gt;The Man Behind Linux&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;I hope that in five years you'll see Linux being a desktop choice. Maybe not displacing Microsoft, but at least being a real choice so [that] when people go into computer stores and buy their computers in 2004, they'll have to [stop and ask themselves whether they] want Linux installed, or Apple, or Microsoft.&quot;" created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:17:39 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="ZDNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.co.uk//news/1999/31/ns-9266.html&quot;&gt;Microsoft Aims at Linux&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;At Microsoft we spend about $3 billion on development, so our operating system is tested in all environments. My concern is that if there are so many people developing Linux, customers will not have confidence that it will work so well.&quot; " created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:18:52 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Thanks to Wes Felter for a pointer to an &lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.apple.com/lists.taf?function=showlistsdetail&amp;Layout_0_uid1=32854&quot;&gt;Apple mail list about HTML Rendering&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:19:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;i&gt;Sadly, Jamis MacNiven, the owner of Buck's has remapped www.buckswoodside.com to a Best.Com server. We ran some great stories at and about Buck's. We wish Jamis and his team the very best.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Wed, 11 Aug 1999 05:20:05 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 10" created="Tue, 10 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="DaveNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1999/08/10/scriptingNewsBulletins&quot;&gt;Scripting News Bulletins&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 10 Aug 1999 05:01:53 GMT" name="davenetAHrefhttpdavenetuserlandcom19990810scriptingnewsbulletinsscriptingNewsBulletinsa" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="NY Times: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/library/tech/99/08/cyber/articles/10tickets.html&quot;&gt;Ticketmaster sues over deep links&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Ticketmaster Online said that the Tickets.com site featured links that went deep into its own site, bypassing introductory pages and advertising. It also said Tickets.com has repeatedly plagiarized editorial material from Ticketmaster Online and misled consumers about ticket availability at venues affiliated with Ticketmaster.&quot;" created="Tue, 10 Aug 1999 05:02:24 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="InfoWorld: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoworld.com/cgi-bin/displayStory.pl?99089.pintembed2.htm&quot;&gt;Microsoft takes wraps off Embedded NT&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;According to a study by the Gartner Group, Microsoft has taken great pains to ensure that NT Embedded does not 'cannibalize' its other operating system products.&quot; InfoWorld doesn't mention the price for the embedded versions." created="Tue, 10 Aug 1999 05:03:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;i&gt;We have been linking to InfoWorld.Com since the inception of Scripting News, we're going to keep doing it until we hear otherwise from InfoWorld. I assume their linking policy is an old not-updated page explaining an old not-enforced policy. However, if they object, we will stop linking to them in the future.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Tue, 10 Aug 1999 05:04:48 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="InfoWorld: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoworld.com/cgi-bin/displayStory.pl?990810.iigmcars.htm&quot;&gt;General Motors 'dot-coms' Itself&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;An automobile is just a Java browser with tires,&quot; quipped McNealy." created="Tue, 10 Aug 1999 05:05:48 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Bruce O'Neel: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$9294&quot;&gt;OOPSLA 99 and XML&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;A lot of these folks have used CORBA and one does get the feeling that a lot of them aren't completely happy about it.&quot;" created="Tue, 10 Aug 1999 05:06:55 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Outliners.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.outliners.com/msgReader$68&quot;&gt;Kevin Shay used Acta&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 10 Aug 1999 05:07:52 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Tico Times: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ticotimes.co.cr/business.html&quot;&gt;Mac Meets Mac in Cyber-Combo&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;MiMac joins McDonald's and Apple Computer — which is lending 10 new iMac computers to the project — in a strategic alliance. Radiográfica Costarricense (RACSA), Costa Rica's Internet provider, will supply Internet access.&quot;" created="Tue, 10 Aug 1999 05:08:53 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 9" created="Mon, 09 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="DaveNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1999/08/09/deepLinking&quot;&gt;Deep Linking&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 09 Aug 1999 05:01:38 GMT" name="davenetAHrefhttpdavenetuserlandcom19990809deeplinkingdeepLinkinga" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoworld.com/cgi-bin/displayStat.pl?/readerservices/permissions.htm#link2&quot;&gt;May I link to an article on InfoWorld.Com&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;i&gt;Hmmmm.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 09 Aug 1999 05:02:05 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Outliners.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.outliners.com/more31.html&quot;&gt;MORE 3.1&lt;/a&gt;. This was the final version of MORE, released in December 1991. From here we'll go back in time and fill in the missing pieces. " created="Mon, 09 Aug 1999 05:03:15 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="MORE 3.1 box: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.outliners.com/images/scans/bierman/more31boxfront.jpg&quot;&gt;Front&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.outliners.com/images/scans/bierman/more31boxback.jpg&quot;&gt;Back&lt;/a&gt;; more &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.outliners.com/msgReader$57&quot;&gt;MORE 3.1 scans&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 09 Aug 1999 05:04:03 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.userland.com/msgReader$9273&quot;&gt;Dan Bricklin&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Here I was visiting old castles and at the same time people from all over the world were trying out old software!&quot;" created="Mon, 09 Aug 1999 05:05:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Jakob Nielsen: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.useit.com/alertbox/990808.html&quot;&gt;Video and Streaming Media&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Most sites would improve if they replaced streaming video with an alternative format such as a comic strip-like sequence of photos with captions.&quot;" created="Mon, 09 Aug 1999 05:06:22 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.despair.com/demotivators/noname2.html&quot;&gt;Despair.Com&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Suzan Woods, a spokesman for Marimba, was quick to contest witnesses' characterizations, saying, 'Kim did not push anyone. She utilized an open-standard technique, developed at Marimba, called the Distributed Unilateral Momentum Protocol, or DUMP. If anyone prints that she pushed, we’ll sue.'&quot;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.despair.com/demotivators/noname2.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://206.204.24.3/snimages/kimSmile.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;" created="Mon, 09 Aug 1999 05:07:28 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Apologies for the outages over the weekend. See the &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$9234&quot;&gt;Dig We Must&lt;/a&gt; message from Friday. It was very prescient. There was corruption in our membership database. Now it's clean, so if that was the problem, it is no more. As they say, &lt;i&gt;Still diggin!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/img&gt;" created="Mon, 09 Aug 1999 05:08:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 8" created="Sun, 08 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Outliners.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.outliners.com/msgReader$38&quot;&gt;Clay Basket 1.0b8f Never Expires&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 08 Aug 1999 05:01:37 GMT" name="outlinerscomAHrefhttpdiscussoutlinerscommsgreader38clayBasket10b8fNeverExpiresa" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Outliners.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.outliners.com/msgReader$35&quot;&gt;Brad Pettit posts a MORE to XML converter&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 08 Aug 1999 05:02:41 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Jonathan Robie: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.texcel.no/whitepapers/xql-design.html&quot;&gt;The Design of XQL&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 08 Aug 1999 05:03:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.news.com/SpecialFeatures/0,5,39915,00.html&quot;&gt;Why open standards are a myth&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Let's not pretend that when we worship at the altar of open standards millions of average consumers are lined up behind us.&quot; " created="Sun, 08 Aug 1999 05:04:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Jodi Mardesich: &lt;a href=&quot;http://cgi.pathfinder.com/fortune/technology/daily/0,3467,617990804,00.html&quot;&gt;Behind FreeMac.Com&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 08 Aug 1999 05:05:02 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 7" created="Sat, 07 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Outliners.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.outliners.com/msgReader$22&quot;&gt;MORE 3.1 Early Download&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sat, 07 Aug 1999 05:01:28 GMT" name="outlinerscomAHrefhttpdiscussoutlinerscommsgreader22more31EarlyDownloada" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$9252&quot;&gt;Jacob Levy wonders&lt;/a&gt; if it's time to short AOL?" created="Sat, 07 Aug 1999 05:03:00 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="$&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$9255&quot;&gt;180 million&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;i&gt;The tiniest of drops in the bucket.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Sat, 07 Aug 1999 05:03:59 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Thanks to Brad Pettit, here are the &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.outliners.com/msgReader$23&quot;&gt;MORE 3.0 docs&lt;/a&gt;, in PageMaker 3.x format." created="Sat, 07 Aug 1999 05:04:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.outliners.com/msgReader$17&quot;&gt;Howard Hansen discusses&lt;/a&gt; using XML to store outlines. &lt;i&gt;It's logical!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Sat, 07 Aug 1999 05:05:25 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 6" created="Fri, 06 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$9234&quot;&gt;Dig we must&lt;/a&gt;! Over the weekend a new preferences server will come online. There may be glitches. UserLand.Com will run faster and will get new preferences-based features as a result of this change. &lt;i&gt;No pain no gain!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 06 Aug 1999 05:01:19 GMT" name="aHrefhttpnewsuserlandcomdiscussmsgreader9234digWeMustaOverTheWeekendANewPreferencesServerWillComeOnlineThereMayBeGlitchesUserlandcomWillRunFasterAndWillGetNewPreferencesbasedFeaturesAsAResultOfThisChangeInoPainNoGaini" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://statmarket.com/SM?c=WeekStat&quot;&gt;StatMarket reports&lt;/a&gt; that Microsoft now accounts for approximately 75% of all browsers used on the Internet." created="Fri, 06 Aug 1999 05:02:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Introducing &lt;a href=&quot;http://discuss.outliners.com/msgReader$7&quot;&gt;Discuss.Outliners.Com&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 06 Aug 1999 05:03:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cybergeography.org/atlas/atlas.html&quot;&gt;An atlas of cyberspaces&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;The cybermaps, like maps of the real-world, help us navigate the new information landscapes, as well being objects of aesthetic interest. They have been created by 'cyber-explorers' of many different disciplines, and from all corners of the world.&quot;" created="Fri, 06 Aug 1999 05:05:00 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The original weblog, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncsa.uiuc.edu/SDG/Software/Mosaic/Docs/whats-new.html&quot;&gt;NCSA's What's New page&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 06 Aug 1999 05:05:28 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$9226&quot;&gt;Dave Kopper approaches&lt;/a&gt; Tree Charts in HTML." created="Fri, 06 Aug 1999 05:06:11 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msgto.com/index.jsp&quot;&gt;MsgTo.Com&lt;/a&gt;: Spam-free email?" created="Fri, 06 Aug 1999 05:07:57 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Another angle: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$9218&quot;&gt;SpamWorld.Com&lt;/a&gt;&amp;trade; " created="Fri, 06 Aug 1999 05:08:22 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.news.com/SpecialFeatures/0,5,39911,00.html&quot;&gt;Is Gates pulling the Net's strings&lt;/a&gt;? &quot;For the first time, a complete product that is completely Microsoft-free is now within reach.&quot; &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.news.com/News/Item/0,4,39516,00.html&quot;&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/i&gt;" created="Fri, 06 Aug 1999 05:09:03 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macintouch.com/earlymac.html#aug06&quot;&gt;More antique software news&lt;/a&gt; on MacInTouch." created="Fri, 06 Aug 1999 05:10:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Eric Kidd: &lt;a href=&quot;http://linux.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$38&quot;&gt;Cobalt Qube needs more RAM&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;As best I can tell, Dave's Qube has only 16MB of RAM. This was enough for the rerelease of ThinkTank, but not enough for the rerelease of MORE 3.0.&quot;" created="Fri, 06 Aug 1999 05:11:03 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Wired: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/news/news/news/culture/story/21138.html&quot;&gt;Unix or Eunuchs&lt;/a&gt;? &quot;The long hours required to succeed in a booming industry mean few hours left over for dating and relationships, leaving many with raging careers and utterly flaccid personal lives.&quot; " created="Fri, 06 Aug 1999 05:12:30 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1996/12/02/AllIWantforChristmas&quot;&gt;12/2/96&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Here's a sure-fire way to create some new moves. Go for a walk. Come back. They're there. You just can't see them.&quot;" created="Fri, 06 Aug 1999 05:13:04 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 5" created="Thu, 05 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="AOL (1998): &lt;a href=&quot;http://linux2.userland.com/users/admin/static/misc/aolInstantMsgProtocol.txt&quot;&gt;Instant Messaging Protocol&lt;/a&gt;." created="Thu, 05 Aug 1999 05:01:32 GMT" name="aol1998AHrefhttplinux2userlandcomusersadminstaticmiscaolinstantmsgprotocoltxtinstantMessagingProtocola" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$9187&quot;&gt;Michael Mantel answers&lt;/a&gt; questions re the above protocol." created="Thu, 05 Aug 1999 05:02:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$9146&quot;&gt;Microsoft's response&lt;/a&gt; to yesterday's DaveNet piece. &quot;We will deliver an SDK for developers and we will have it out in the first quarter of next year.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Hmmm.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Thu, 05 Aug 1999 05:03:41 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$9178&quot;&gt;Jakob Nielsen on SDKs&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The 'S' in SDK would impose too large a burden on domain experts who are not programmers but simply want to add some functionality to their website.&quot;" created="Thu, 05 Aug 1999 05:04:34 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$9185&quot;&gt;John Robb&lt;/a&gt; president of Gomez chimes in. &quot;AOL would be stupid to actually cooperate with Microsoft et al on the IETF proposal. Why? They are about to get jammed by the bandwidth monopolists in cable.&quot;" created="Thu, 05 Aug 1999 05:05:50 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$9147&quot;&gt;Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I didn't request an SDK.&quot;" created="Thu, 05 Aug 1999 05:06:30 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buckswoodside.com/stories/storyReader$227&quot;&gt;Buck's&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Oxygen is no less than an entire redesign of today's hardware and software and the intention is that it be as pervasive as, well, air.&quot;" created="Thu, 05 Aug 1999 05:07:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="More cool antique software: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weblayout.com/witness/Moose.shtml&quot;&gt;The Talking Moose&lt;/a&gt;. This was the killer app of the early days of the Mac. I have very fond memories of the moose. If you have a Mac, go get it now!" created="Thu, 05 Aug 1999 05:08:55 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metamage.com/prod/tinymush-mac/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://206.204.24.3/snimages/netmush.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Antique software is the top item on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macintouch.com/&quot;&gt;MacInTouch&lt;/a&gt; today. More comments, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macintouch.com/earlymac.html#aug05&quot;&gt;updated today&lt;/a&gt;, including a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jmac.org/macos_oss/index.pl?recent=1&quot;&gt;pointer&lt;/a&gt; to a site cataloging Mac OS open source software. The Mac is coming alive again. &lt;i&gt;Cooool!&lt;/i&gt; " created="Thu, 05 Aug 1999 05:09:19 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Scripting challenge: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$9167&quot;&gt;Tree Charts in Frontier&lt;/a&gt;?" created="Thu, 05 Aug 1999 05:10:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news-beta.userland.com/&quot;&gt;Beta&lt;/a&gt; of the next Scripting News server. It's a dynamic page, you'll be able to set preferences for how many days you want, and you'll be able to configure RSS channels running down the right edge. You can bookmark this page, it's hooked into our news flow now, and should lag behind the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;static news&lt;/a&gt; by at most one minute." created="Thu, 05 Aug 1999 05:11:22 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="To prove that it's dynamic, &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/prefs/default$Bookmarks&quot;&gt;edit your bookmarks&lt;/a&gt;. (UserLand.Com membership required.) Then go to the Beta News &lt;a href=&quot;http://news-beta.userland.com/&quot;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;. Do you see the change? Our goal is to have your bookmarks on the home page of every sub-site on UserLand.Com. And then build features out from there that run on all of our servers." created="Thu, 05 Aug 1999 05:13:00 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, this is a heterogenous network of three NT4 machines, two Linux boxes, and one Mac. The servers are distributed geographically, some in Seattle and some in Silicon Valley. And it's cross-content-management-system too. The beta page is a Zope/Python app, and everything else is Frontier. The Mac is playing a non-trivial role. It's the &quot;offload server,&quot; doing email and the hourly RSS scans. It's busy about 5 percent of the time so there's lots of room for growth. It's an old old machine, but it serves a very good purpose. &lt;i&gt;Long live the Mac OS!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Thu, 05 Aug 1999 05:13:39 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Oh yes, this is all possible thru the magic of an open documented protocol, called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xmlrpc.com/&quot;&gt;XML-RPC&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 05 Aug 1999 05:14:13 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Could your servers hook into this flow? &lt;i&gt;Soon!&lt;/i&gt; Comment on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://linux.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$34&quot;&gt;Linux.UserLand.Com&lt;/a&gt; DG." created="Thu, 05 Aug 1999 05:15:47 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="MSNBC: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/297360.asp&quot;&gt;Microsoft-AOL Battle Heats Up&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;We intend to be aggressive with access,&quot; said Brad Chase, vice president of Microsoft's new consumer and commerce Group and the point man for Microsoft’s new strategy. &quot;AOL might think about it as a profit center. That’s not how we think about it.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Coool!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Thu, 05 Aug 1999 05:17:00 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;/img&gt;" created="Thu, 05 Aug 1999 05:17:06 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 4" created="Wed, 04 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="DaveNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1999/08/04/whyShouldAolOpenUp&quot;&gt;Why Should AOL Open Up&lt;/a&gt;?" created="Wed, 04 Aug 1999 05:01:29 GMT" name="davenetAHrefhttpdavenetuserlandcom19990804whyshouldaolopenupwhyShouldAolOpenUpa" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Outliners.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.outliners.com/thinkTank2Pc.html&quot;&gt;ThinkTank 2.41NP&lt;/a&gt;. (IBM PC, 1987) &quot;There's a routine that clicks the speaker, every time the software checks for the Escape key. Originally I put this in as a way to be sure that it was checking often enough during lengthy operations. I left the sounds in, people thought ThinkTank had a motor!&quot;" created="Wed, 04 Aug 1999 05:02:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Outliners.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.outliners.com/more30.html&quot;&gt;MORE 3.0&lt;/a&gt;. (Mac, 1990) &quot;All the other outliners were love affairs that were over quickly. On to the next thing. A new platform, a new way to sneak into memory with other apps, try out a graphic platform, try again, then again.&quot; &lt;i&gt;MORE 3.0 was different.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Wed, 04 Aug 1999 05:03:27 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="TechWeb: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techweb.com/wire/story/TWB19990804S0020&quot;&gt;Classic Software is Reborn on the Web&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;A handful of the pioneering developers of groundbreaking applications, such as VisiCalc, Turbo Pascal and C, ThinkTank, Ready! and MORE, are posting original versions that can be downloaded for free.&quot;" created="Wed, 04 Aug 1999 05:04:36 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.labmed.umn.edu/~john/more/index.html#MORE2Text&quot;&gt;Brad Pettit's MORE2Text&lt;/a&gt; translator. &lt;i&gt;Brad was on the MORE team, versions 2 and 3.&lt;/i&gt; " created="Wed, 04 Aug 1999 05:05:29 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="MacUser (1986): &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.com.au/macuser/eddy95/history/eddy1986.html&quot;&gt;Product of the Year&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 04 Aug 1999 05:06:31 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Scott Lawton: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.prefab.com/ssl/more1987.html&quot;&gt;MORE: As Revolutionary as Lotus 1-2-3&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 04 Aug 1999 05:07:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="MORE 1.1c retail box: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.outliners.com/images/scans/bierman/more11boxfront.jpg&quot;&gt;front&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.outliners.com/images/scans/bierman/more11boxback.jpg&quot;&gt;back&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 04 Aug 1999 05:08:58 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Our T1 line is getting swamped again! MORE 3.0 is a big download, 1755K. I'm glad so many people are downloading it. And Ric Ford is calling antique software a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macintouch.com/earlymac.html&quot;&gt;hot topic&lt;/a&gt;. Cooool! The Mac has an interesting history to explore and until now there hasn't been much of that." created="Wed, 04 Aug 1999 05:09:29 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 3" created="Tue, 03 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="Outliners.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.outliners.com/more11c.html&quot;&gt;MORE 1.1c&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Later products added major features, such as virtual storage, rules-based formatting, more complete presentation features, and multi-line headlines. But what was added in richness was traded against some of the simplicity of 1.1c, which many people remember as being more complete than it actually was (I certainly am guilty of that!).&quot; &lt;i&gt;1987, Mac.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Tue, 03 Aug 1999 05:01:41 GMT" name="outlinerscomAHrefhttpwwwoutlinerscommore11chtmlmore11caLaterProductsAddedMajorFeaturesSuchAsVirtualStorageRulesbasedFormattingMoreCompletePresentationFeaturesAndMultilineHeadlinesButWhatWasAddedInRichnessWasTradedAgainstSomeOfTheSimplicityOf11cWhichManyPeopleRememberAsBeingMoreCompleteThanItActuallyWasICertainlyAmGuiltyOfThatI1987Maci" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Release 1.0: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edventure.com/release1/abstracts/syndication.html&quot;&gt;The Web Goes Into Syndication&lt;/a&gt;. (Excerpt, the full report is available only to subscribers.)" created="Tue, 03 Aug 1999 05:02:59 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.outliners.com/images/tank241pc/outliner1.gif&quot;&gt;Screen shot&lt;/a&gt; of ThinkTank 2.41NP for the IBM-PC, 1987. This will be one of tomorrow's re-releases. The download also includes the OS/2 app. ThinkTank was one of the first apps for OS/2. " created="Tue, 03 Aug 1999 05:03:29 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="More Antique Software: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.support.lotus.com/ftp/pub/desktop/Agenda/dos/2.0/misc/&quot;&gt;Lotus Agenda 2.0&lt;/a&gt;. (1988)" created="Tue, 03 Aug 1999 05:04:58 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="News.Com: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.news.com/News/Item/0,4,40075,00.html&quot;&gt;Mattel is launching a computer line for children based on its most popular toys&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Starting in September, Barbie- and Hot Wheels-branded computers from Patriot will be available for $14.98 per month, or $599. These systems, while not offering the hottest technology or the lowest price available, will still probably find a market in parents looking for an entry-level second computer, analysts say.&quot;" created="Tue, 03 Aug 1999 05:06:00 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macintouch.com/earlymac.html&quot;&gt;Ric Ford posted&lt;/a&gt; an email I sent him yesterday. &lt;i&gt;Excellent!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Tue, 03 Aug 1999 05:06:54 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Dan Gillmor&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mercurycenter.com/svtech/columns/gillmor/docs/dg080399.htm&quot;&gt;Software pioneers post early works on Web&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 03 Aug 1999 05:07:57 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="DaveNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/&quot;&gt;MORE 1.1c (1987)&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;And now with the web as an inexpensive distribution system, the old software can speak for itself, and once again teach lessons, now with the benefit of hindsight.&quot;" created="Tue, 03 Aug 1999 05:08:25 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$9044&quot;&gt;Jim Stegman reports&lt;/a&gt; that MORE 1.1c runs on his new G3, System 8.6. " created="Tue, 03 Aug 1999 05:09:21 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Wired: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/news/news/business/story/21069.html&quot;&gt;Baratz resigns from Sun&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 03 Aug 1999 05:10:02 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="SF Chron: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?file=/chronicle/archive/1999/08/03/MN105739.DTL&quot;&gt;Nolan Exiled to Redwood City&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 03 Aug 1999 05:11:36 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="PC WEEK: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.com/pcweek/stories/news/0,4153,1015814,00.html&quot;&gt;Instant Messaging Gurus&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;The 38-year-old Saraswat, a senior researcher at AT&amp;T Shannon Laboratories at Florham Park, N.J., and the 37-year-old Marvit, an Internet strategy consultant for Fujitsu Labs America in Santa Clara, Calif., contend" created="Tue, 03 Aug 1999 05:12:55 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="that real-time chat and 'buddy lists' represent only a rudimentary implementation of the basic technology.&quot;" created="Tue, 03 Aug 1999 05:13:54 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$9034&quot;&gt;Jesse Estevez is looking&lt;/a&gt; for a Frontier guru. &quot;We currently render static pages to Apache. But oh, the sweet temptation of Edit This Page.&quot;" created="Tue, 03 Aug 1999 05:14:18 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webword.com/interviews/tog.html&quot;&gt;Tog continues&lt;/a&gt; his usability rant on WebWord. " created="Tue, 03 Aug 1999 05:15:04 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1996/12/05/ItsHTMLDummy&quot;&gt;Here's my next response&lt;/a&gt; to the venting of Tog." created="Tue, 03 Aug 1999 05:16:05 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="We are getting slammed! The MacDot Effect? Anyway. Sorry if you're having trouble getting thru, glad MORE 1.1c is only 233K! &lt;i&gt;For the next release we're going to have to move outliners.com upstream.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Tue, 03 Aug 1999 05:17:30 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, the Cobalt Qube that's running outliners.com is holding up great. I can still get great performance even though it's taking huge hits. Apache is good stuff! &lt;i&gt;Thanks Cobalt!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Tue, 03 Aug 1999 05:18:02 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 2" created="Mon, 02 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$9028&quot;&gt;Microsoft response&lt;/a&gt; to yesterday's DaveNet piece." created="Mon, 02 Aug 1999 05:01:34 GMT" name="aHrefhttpnewsuserlandcomdiscussmsgreader9028microsoftResponseaToYesterdaysDavenetPiece" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/library/tech/99/08/biztech/articles/02link.html&quot;&gt;NY Times discovers&lt;/a&gt; Scripting News! &quot;Rosenberg relies on about a dozen digests of links to technology coverage. These sites include Scripting News, which is published by Dave Winer, a software developer who has written for Hotwired.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Nice!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 02 Aug 1999 05:02:10 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="We got permission from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.symantec.com/&quot;&gt;Symantec&lt;/a&gt; to release early versions of ThinkTank, Ready! and MORE. We're working on the release site now, expect it to come on-line tomorrow. We're going to start with MORE 1.1c for the Macintosh, released exactly twelve years ago today on 8/2/87. &lt;i&gt;Thanks Symantec!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 02 Aug 1999 05:03:32 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Dan Bricklin: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$8583&quot;&gt;How I Got Permission to Post VisiCalc&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 02 Aug 1999 05:05:00 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Dave Winer: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$9025&quot;&gt;How I Got Permission to Post the Outliners&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 02 Aug 1999 05:05:06 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="AskTog: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.asktog.com/columns/028WebStealers.html&quot;&gt;How Programmers Stole the Web&lt;/a&gt;. A throwback to the hype that surrounded HyperCard. Tog is perhaps a bit more charitable to programmers than they were back in 1987, but notice how, even after all these years, you still have to be a programmer to write programs. It will always be that way. &lt;i&gt;It's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cogsci.princeton.edu/cgi-bin/webwn/?stage=1&amp;word=tautological&quot;&gt;tautological&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 02 Aug 1999 05:06:09 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.savetz.com/ku/ku/quick_genius_behind_hypercard_bill_atkinson_the_november_1987.html&quot;&gt;The Genius Behind HyperCard&lt;/a&gt; (1987): &quot;First, he gave all of us the power to create sophisticated graphics on a computer.  Now, he's given us the power to become software developers without having to know a single word of programming code.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Sounds like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christiananswers.net/kids/clrpg007.html&quot;&gt;Moses&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 02 Aug 1999 05:07:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Tom Christiansen: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.perl.com/pub/language/misc/fmproto.html?wwwrrr_rss&quot;&gt;Far More Than Everything You've Ever Wanted to Know about Prototypes in Perl&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;The major issue with 'prototypes' in Perl is that the experienced programmer comes to Perl bearing a pre-conceived but nevertheless completely rational notion of what a 'prototype' is and how it works, yet this notion has shockingly little in common with what they really do in Perl.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Maybe Tog was right after all??&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 02 Aug 1999 05:08:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="PythonWare: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pythonware.com/products/pil/&quot;&gt;Python Imaging Library&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 02 Aug 1999 05:09:34 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoworld.com/cgi-bin/displayTC.pl?/reviews/990802tclpro13.htm&quot;&gt;InfoWorld reviews&lt;/a&gt; Scriptics Tcl Pro." created="Mon, 02 Aug 1999 05:10:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://My.UserLand.Com/&quot;&gt;My.UserLand.Com&lt;/a&gt; now has preliminary support for &lt;a href=&quot;http://my.netscape.com/publish/help/mnn20/quickstart.html&quot;&gt;RSS 0.91&lt;/a&gt;. The first new channel it can read is &lt;a href=&quot;http://my.userland.com/viewChannel$909&quot;&gt;Chaos Network&lt;/a&gt;. Note that with item descriptions, RSS is approaching the expressiveness of ScriptingNews format. &lt;i&gt;Which is still supported.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 02 Aug 1999 05:11:13 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Ooops! The Chaos Network seems to be down. (Too chaotic?) So the runner-up, &lt;a href=&quot;http://my.userland.com/viewChannel$1173&quot;&gt;Internet Alchemy&lt;/a&gt;, wins the prize for first with a running RSS 0.91 My.UserLand.Com channel. &lt;i&gt;10 points for Ian Davis!&lt;/i&gt;" created="Mon, 02 Aug 1999 05:12:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="10 points for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://my.userland.com/viewChannel$510&quot;&gt;Pigdog Journal&lt;/a&gt;, another RSS 0.91 site. (BTW, the easiest way to upgrade is to start writing 0.91 format text in your already-registered channel file. My.UserLand.Com will pick up the format change automatically in the next hourly scan.)" created="Mon, 02 Aug 1999 05:13:05 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://my.userland.com/viewChannel$1174&quot;&gt;MozillaZine&lt;/a&gt; is coming online any minute now." created="Mon, 02 Aug 1999 05:14:03 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Netscape now has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://my.netscape.com/publish/help/validate.tmpl&quot;&gt;RSS channel validator app&lt;/a&gt;. The page says it's looking for RDF text, even though RSS 0.91 is not RDF." created="Mon, 02 Aug 1999 05:15:40 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$9005&quot;&gt;Amy Wohl&lt;/a&gt; on Instant Messaging. &quot;We could get away from the idea (which has nearly destroyed television) that everything on the Internet is about making money.&quot;" created="Mon, 02 Aug 1999 05:16:20 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="NY Times: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/library/tech/99/08/biztech/articles/02aol.html&quot;&gt;Showdown on Messaging&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;America Online did nothing to prevent someone from mimicking its software, as Microsoft has. Microsoft's own message program, by contrast, encrypts messages, so that no one can create backdoor links to its system, as it has done to America Online's.&quot;" created="Mon, 02 Aug 1999 05:17:28 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.ecst.csuchico.edu/~atman/attention-fat-bastards.html&quot;&gt;Attention&lt;/a&gt;: Fat Corporate Bastards!" created="Mon, 02 Aug 1999 05:18:10 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="MSNBC: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/news/292274.asp&quot;&gt;Build Your Brand with E-mail&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;E-mail newsletters provide an even playing field for online marketing. With virtually no production expenses, except for existing costs like Internet access and the writer’s time, all companies can use e-mail newsletters to bolster their brand, experts say.&quot;&lt;/a&gt;" created="Mon, 02 Aug 1999 05:19:48 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="August 1" created="Sun, 01 Aug 1999 05:00:01 GMT">
				<outline text="DaveNet: &lt;a href=&quot;http://davenet.userland.com/1999/08/01/instantMessaging&quot;&gt;Instant Messaging&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;In the struggle for Instant Messaging, the winner, if there is one, will control real-time access to Internet users.&quot;" created="Sun, 01 Aug 1999 05:01:21 GMT" name="davenetAHrefhttpdavenetuserlandcom19990801instantmessaginginstantMessagingaInTheStruggleForInstantMessagingTheWinnerIfThereIsOneWillControlRealtimeAccessToInternetUsers" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.frankston.com/public/Essays/Much%20Fuss%20About%20the%20DNS.asp&quot;&gt;Bob Frankston and David Reed&lt;/a&gt; on DNS." created="Sun, 01 Aug 1999 05:02:50 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://linuxtoday.com/stories/8242.html&quot;&gt;Eric Raymond issues&lt;/a&gt; a challenge. &quot;The day I wrote this, Freshmeat carried twenty-two release announcements, of which three appear they might push state of the art in some respect, This was a slow day for Freshmeat, but I will be astonished if any reader reports as many as three likely innovations a month ion any closed-source channel.&quot; " created="Sun, 01 Aug 1999 05:03:38 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Steve Blinn: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$8976&quot;&gt;Instant Messaging is Dead&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 01 Aug 1999 05:04:35 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.odigo.com/&quot;&gt;Odigo&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Find like minds. Pick up passengers. Give directions. Leave a mark.&quot; &lt;i&gt;Warning! I installed Odigo, and I lost my desktop. I immediately uninstalled it and was glad to see my desktop again. Of course your mileage may vary.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Sun, 01 Aug 1999 05:05:29 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Phil Wolff: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.userland.com/discuss/msgReader$8974&quot;&gt;Attention Constraints are the Driving Force&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sun, 01 Aug 1999 05:06:13 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Steven Levy on Dvorak: &amp;quot;That Dvorak is a cagey guy who knows recycling.  After the original Mac" created="Sun, 01 Aug 1999 05:07:34 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="came out he gave virtually the same gender-based criticism to it, dismissing not only the industrial design but the idea of using a mouse and pictures as girly stuff.  (I wrote about this in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0140232370/o/qid=933546091/sr=2-2/002-8929444-3513822&quot;&gt;Insanely Great&lt;/a&gt;.) His preference was the IBM AT computer, which he called 'a man's computer designed by men for men.'  Both times he knew that the over-the-top sexism would be controversal and attention-getting.  But it's interesting that his take in the original column was so wrong it can stand beside remarks like 'an individual has no use for a computer.' I wonder how this recent one will stand up.&amp;quot;" created="Sun, 01 Aug 1999 05:08:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.regretsonly.com/&quot;&gt;What is your biggest regret in life&lt;/a&gt;? Or, put another way: What would you do differently if you had another chance?" created="Sun, 01 Aug 1999 05:09:41 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Hey! I just &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.groksoup.com/wildBeatnikPie/&quot;&gt;started&lt;/a&gt; a new weblog on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.groksoup.com/&quot;&gt;GrokSoup&lt;/a&gt;. Not bad. It only too five minutes. They still need to do some more work, I hit a bunch of errors, not like we don't have a few here too. ;-&gt;" created="Sun, 01 Aug 1999 05:10:36 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			</outline>
		</body>
	</opml>
