<?xml version="1.0"?>
<opml version="2.0">
	<head>
		<title>Scripting News</title>
		<dateCreated>Sat, 06 May 2017 17:25:42 GMT</dateCreated>
		<dateModified>Sat, 01 May 2021 16:12:02 GMT</dateModified>
		<ownerId>https://twitter.com/davewiner/</ownerId>
		<ownerName>Dave Winer</ownerName>
		<ownerTwitterScreenName>davewiner</ownerTwitterScreenName>
		<expansionState>1</expansionState>
		<lastCursor>0</lastCursor>
		<urlPublic>http://electricserver.scripting.com/users/davewiner/electric/january2021.opml</urlPublic>
		<urlJson>http://electricserver.scripting.com/users/davewiner/electric/january2021.json</urlJson>
		<flPublic>true</flPublic>
		<copyright>&amp;copy; copyright 1994-2021 Dave Winer.</copyright>
		</head>
	<body>
		<outline text="April 2021" created="Thu, 01 Apr 2021 15:24:24 GMT" name="april2021" type="calendarMonth">
			<outline text="April 30" created="Fri, 30 Apr 2021 13:05:19 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="30">
				<outline text="People are amazed that Joe Biden has turned into a progressive president, with ambitions comparable to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Deal&quot;&gt;FDR&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Society&quot;&gt;LBJ&lt;/a&gt;, but he’s exactly the kind who can do that. Just as Richard Nixon, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alger_Hiss&quot;&gt;famous&lt;/a&gt; communist hater, was able to open relations with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Nixon%27s_1972_visit_to_China&quot;&gt;China&lt;/a&gt; in 1972. Biden has a reputation as a moderate, therefore he has credibility when calling for more radical approaches to recovery." created="Fri, 30 Apr 2021 19:22:04 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/youtube-tv-pulled-from-roku&quot;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; is what &quot;podcasting&quot; is going to be like once its spotification is complete." created="Fri, 30 Apr 2021 16:41:21 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Reporters generally miss why Reagan’s attacks on government were so well-received by Americans. The reason: Nixon, Vietnam and Watergate. Jimmy Carter was the first response to all that. A guy who was so clean he thought that having lust in his heart for women other than his wife was a sin. Then Reagan was the final eradication of Nixon, or so we felt. We had no trust of government, so our votes were all about hobbling government. The error was not realizing the role it played in American power. He went way too far. That became clear, to me, with the response to 9/11. We needed a smart government that used American power with care and respect. Dubya was what we had instead. " created="Fri, 30 Apr 2021 15:11:06 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2017/10/01/dubya.png"/>
				<outline text="I've been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.twitter.com/en/using-twitter/spaces&quot;&gt;Twitter Spaces&lt;/a&gt;, their new competitor to [%search: Clubhouse%], at the encouragement of [%search: Robert Scoble%], who has taken to it the way he gets involved in everything, head first and way over his head. Completely submerged. Fine. I'm vulnerable to media like this, so I spent a couple of hours there in the last few days. I've been recovering from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/04/28.html#a164755&quot;&gt;stomach thing&lt;/a&gt;, so there's no harm in wasting a bit of time I wasn't going to use productively anyway. One thing Scoble said to me, when we were discussing &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/04/28.html#a163250&quot;&gt;Basecamp&lt;/a&gt;, is that's fine but you're a white person. To which I said what I've always wanted to say to this. Yeah, but you're not refuting what I said, which has no race, age or gender. How about considering the ideas, where ever they might come from. In my experience, good ideas can come from places you're not expecting them. Sometimes I'm sure I've missed them altogether because of that. Other times I've almost missed them. It has happened enough that I consciously try to turn off that kind of judgement and just listen and consider regardless of who's speaking. This is one of the worst things about the current rage to discount anyone who isn't young, of color and/or female. What made me think about all this is the flack the kids who are upset about inaction among adults re climate change are getting. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://bigthink.com/politics-current-affairs/youth-climate-strike?rebelltitem=1#rebelltitem1&quot;&gt;adults are attacking&lt;/a&gt; them because they're children. They aren't even listening to what they say. " created="Fri, 30 Apr 2021 14:03:28 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2020/12/15/myOrangeJelloBox.png"/>
				<outline text="I've said this a million times. One more time won't hurt. Podcasting was created so &lt;i&gt;everyone&lt;/i&gt; can make media. It was designed, deliberately, without gatekeepers. To have a podcast, you have to have a public &quot;RSS&quot; feed with enclosures. That's why you hear at the end of podcasts, &quot;You can get this where ever you get podcasts.&quot; They may name one or two of those places, but you know, because it's a podcast, you can listen to it in any podcast client, or in a pinch just by entering the URL of the feed into a web browser. That's why when Spotify calls what &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1388053831733362691&quot;&gt;Joe Rogan&lt;/a&gt; does a &quot;podcast&quot; it's an insult to all the people who worked so hard to make podcasting the huge juggernaut it is today. They should be crucified and burned at the stake for being total corporate assholes. I don't use Spotify. Never have, never will. Luckily I don't give a shit about Joe Rogan. I hear he's mean and stupid. And if you make an exclusive deal with Spotify as he did, you can be sure I'll never hear what you say. There's nothing wrong with Spotify offering proprietary radio shows. Just don't call them podcasts. Same goes for Audible and all the other companies who think open networks don't matter." created="Fri, 30 Apr 2021 13:05:20 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2017/10/06/gunsDontKillPeople.png"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 29" created="Thu, 29 Apr 2021 11:42:22 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="29">
				<outline text="I'd love to hear a real explanation of why they won't release the patents for the vaccines. In plain English. No hemming or hawing. " created="Thu, 29 Apr 2021 18:05:43 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Later -- I learned that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://endpts.com/biontech-partners-with-bill-and-melinda-gates-foundation-scoring-55m-equity-investment-novartis-sells-china-unit/&quot;&gt;Gates Foundation has equity&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://biontech.de/covid-19&quot;&gt;company&lt;/a&gt; that makes the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines/different-vaccines/Pfizer-BioNTech.html&quot;&gt;Pfizer vaccine&lt;/a&gt;. So when he talks about not needing to share the patent with countries where the virus is running wild, like India, that's not really the new Bill Gates, philanthropist giving away all his money for the good of humanity speaking, rather it's the new Bill Gates, seeking world domination as always, posing as a philanthropist who's giving away all his money. :boom:" created="Thu, 29 Apr 2021 21:28:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2021/04/29/new-york-city-mayor-bill-de-blasio-says-the-city-will-re-open-100percent-on-july-1.html&quot;&gt;NYC is opening 100%&lt;/a&gt; on July 1. I wonder if they're aware what's happening &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2021/04/29/india/india-covid-crisis-world-problem/index.html&quot;&gt;in India&lt;/a&gt;. I don't see the US as disconnected, at all." created="Thu, 29 Apr 2021 17:37:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="A &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/04/28/154140.html?title=oyTheHumanity&quot;&gt;port of Frontier to Linux&lt;/a&gt; really &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tedchoward/Frontier/issues/10&quot;&gt;has to be in C&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 29 Apr 2021 14:52:29 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Belch water" created="Thu, 29 Apr 2021 11:42:23 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="&quot;Greps wasser&quot; is the Yiddish word for seltzer. " created="Thu, 29 Apr 2021 11:43:09 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It translates literally to &quot;belch water.&quot;" created="Thu, 29 Apr 2021 11:45:14 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Three_Stooges&quot;&gt;The Three Stooges&lt;/a&gt; playing with &lt;i&gt;greps wasser.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Thu, 29 Apr 2021 11:42:26 GMT" inlineImage="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/29/threeStoogesFightingWithSeltzerBottles.png"/>
					<outline text="&lt;b&gt;Mit gas&lt;/b&gt;" created="Thu, 29 Apr 2021 21:51:37 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Another story. First time I visited Switzerland in 2000, to go to the World Economic Forum conference in Davos, I was very impressed by many things, including the two types of bottled water that were available called 1. Still and 2. Mit gas. It still makes me laugh. You know in English &quot;mit gas&quot; is something you say when you're farting a lot. I am mit gas, I might have said to my German grandmother, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.greatvavavoom.com/stories/storyReader$124&quot;&gt;Lucy Kiesler&lt;/a&gt;. She thought I was a nice boy except when I said things like that. " created="Thu, 29 Apr 2021 21:47:14 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Three of my grandparents, Rudy Kiesler (her husband), Baruch and Sima Winer, were Jewish, but Lucy Kiesler was Lutheran from Hamburg in north Germany. Blonde hair and blue eyes. I think she was actually kind of anti-semitic, which is weird because she married a Jew. She might have done it to get back at her parents, the story went. Or she might have been confused. She died at 66, my first grandparent to go, when I was a grad student in Madison. I used to stay at her &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/@40.5735367,-73.863431,3a,75y,49.15h,87.25t/data=!3m6!1e1!3m4!1sH90kfd-HjSqxwYfJBxsdGQ!2e0!7i16384!8i8192&quot;&gt;house&lt;/a&gt; in Rockaway when my parents traveled. It was a nice place, just a few blocks from one of the &lt;a href=&quot;=!3m7!1e1!3m5!1smG2Z5B0rVCc-oDpPMiCurQ!2e0!6shttps:%2F%2Fstreetviewpixels-pa.googleapis.com%2Fv1%2Fthumbnail%3Fpanoid%3DmG2Z5B0rVCc-oDpPMiCurQ%26cb_client%3Dmaps_sv.tactile.gps%26w%3D203%26h%3D100%26yaw%3D95.56618%26pitch%3D0%26thumbfov%3D100!7i16384!8i8192&quot;&gt;best beaches&lt;/a&gt; anywhere. Really good waves. She was born over a hundred years ago (I could do the math, approximately, she was 66 in 1977, so I guess that says she was born in 1911? Her brother, my great uncle, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arno_Schmidt&quot;&gt;Arno Schmidt&lt;/a&gt;, is a famous German novelist, in intellectual circles. When I tell people from Germany that I'm related to Arno Schmidt, they either look at me like I'm an idiot (Schmidt is a common name in Germany!) or the they are impressed. I inherited a lot from her, for better or worse. :rocket:" created="Thu, 29 Apr 2021 21:52:36 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 28" created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:30:21 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="28">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1387513108936237060&quot;&gt;Poll&lt;/a&gt;: How do you feel about Rudy G's upcoming perp walk?" created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 21:05:23 GMT" type="outline" urltweet="https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1387513108936237060"/>
				<outline text="I wrote about &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/04/27/161858.html?title=makeTheInvisibleHandVisible&quot;&gt;Basecamp's controversy&lt;/a&gt; yesterday, and since then &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.platformer.news/p/-what-really-happened-at-basecamp&quot;&gt;more has come out&lt;/a&gt;. The company kept a list of customers with &quot;funny&quot; names, for years. Assuming this is true, they deserve all the grief they get. I understand that non-founders do stuff like that, I've seen it, I've fought against it -- it's the job of the founder to take the side of the users. And make it clear that showing anything but love and admiration for &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; customers, every damn one of them, is not only not optional, but will get you fired after not too many offenses. It's very hard to keep user-disrespect from taking over companies, so you always have to watch for it and be a complete fucking asshole about it. People who wade through all the confusion of the market and figure out that your product is the best are geniuses. They are your lifeblood. Also, I certainly would have been on their list. I have a &quot;funny&quot; last name. I know it. A product of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ellis_Island&quot;&gt;Ellis Island&lt;/a&gt;. But I am not a customer of theirs. " created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 16:32:50 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2020/07/03/tenTonWeight.png"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/brianstelter/status/1387449253434380290&quot;&gt;They're&lt;/a&gt; totally throwing Rudy under the bus. He's going to be blamed for everything. Perfect. Rudy the garbage can." created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 17:07:35 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Would love to see in President Biden's speech tonight a cash bonus to residents of blue states who relocate to Wyoming, Idaho, Montana or one of the Dakotas. We could add 10 senate seats and a bunch of electoral votes. Enough to keep the filibuster or tell Manchin to STFU. Maybe you pay no federal taxes for 25 years? That would be cool. I even have a slogan. Do a mitzvah for 'Merica." created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 15:31:34 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, I am mostly over the stomach bug. I went for an hour-long bike ride yesterday, and it felt wonderful. And look at all the writing I did today! Not wanting to return to development yet, the break has been worthwhile. I have been tending my todo list, and plotting out next steps. I left the software in a good place, it seems. I'm not worried about it at this time. More glad to have recovered my health. " created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 16:47:55 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Oy the humanity" created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 15:41:40 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I have to keep my desktop Mac not-upgraded so I can keep running &quot;Frontier&quot; on it, so now I can't use it with my iPhone because I foolishly updated it to the latest version of iOS. I wish somehow I could get a Linux version of Frontier so I could dump the Mac. It's the wrong desktop OS for me, now. Has been for a while. And Frontier would be a great addition to Linux, imho. The source is on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tedchoward/Frontier/releases&quot;&gt;Ted Howard's github&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 15:40:07 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Mac to Dave: You fucked up! Loser!! :smile:" created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 15:42:53 GMT" inlineImage="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/28/oyMacSux.png"/>
					<outline text="How different it would have been if Apple loved Frontier instead of steering people away from it. Their idea of programming back in the day was English. Program in natural language. Oy my god. What a tragic mess that was. Instead our approach was to factor until you can factor no more. Make it as simple as possible, but no simpler. " created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 15:53:10 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Imagine a machine that was not only the best end user machine but also the best developer and power user machine. Remove the barriers from users becoming more powerful. End the priesthood. And make it easy to create personalized suites of apps. For a while the Mac was all that. The best machine for everyone. Then at some point Apple gave up on the Mac and decided to start over with iOS. Leaving the Mac in cash cow mode. And Mac users without a home (imho, ymmv)." created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 15:54:24 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Blink's dishonest upsell" created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:33:48 GMT" type="outline" metaImage="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/21/minkHollow.png" description="If you have Blink cameras, skip the cloud service and add a thumb drive to the router and save a bunch.">
					<outline text="Earlier this month I &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/04/19.html#a142814&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/C5DECBBE-4F56-4C36-B933-E62144578691?maas=maas_adg_api_5916655800301_macro_1_1&amp;ref_=aa_maas&amp;aa_campaignid=9998093451&amp;aa_adgroupid=103704934271&amp;aa_creativeid=ad-460884485470_kwd-13303316_dev-c_ext-&amp;gclid=CjwKCAjwj6SEBhAOEiwAvFRuKGxwQjLXmrvLUgRWqgvHy6yXchcbpRUrAF1D02f-9t_MUSwlgfq3jxoChJwQAvD_BwE&quot;&gt;Blink&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2017/12/22/16810516/amazon-blink-acquisition-smart-camera-doorbell-company&quot;&gt;subsidiary&lt;/a&gt; of Amazon, that was trying to sell me a cloud service that up till then I had been receiving for free." created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:30:22 GMT"/>
					<outline text="First the background..." created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 15:22:46 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I have two battery powered Blink cameras outside my house. When someone arrives, or an animal crosses its view, or the wind blows a tree branch in front of the camera, it takes a short video, which is sent to an Amazon server, which then sends me a notification. If I click the link, the video opens in their mobile app. I could then look at the image to see who or what had woken the camera. It's nice to be able to monitor the comings and goings at my house even when I'm not there. I can tell when packages are delivered, for example. " created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:45:48 GMT"/>
					<outline text="But now there was a new deal. They wanted me to pay $3 a month per camera, not saying what I would be able to do with the cameras if I let the service lapse, implying that my cameras would be kind of useless if I didn't pay. " created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:48:56 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I decided to let the service lapse to see what would happen. " created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 15:10:26 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Yesterday the free service cut off. I was down in Kingston while people were working at the house. I wanted to see if they had arrived so I fired up Blink, and saw that something had triggered the camera at 9:08AM, but I couldn't view the video. I was told this was because I was cheap and didn't pay them the lousy money (paraphrasing).  I could if I wanted get a realtime look through the camera, and I could also talk to whoever was there (thus freaking them out I imagine). So there's the limit I thought. But then I remembered that there's a USB slot on the Sync Module (SM), which is a customized router that connects the cameras to the net. I had ordered a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B001XURP8Q?psc=1&amp;ref=ppx_yo2_dt_b_product_details&quot;&gt;32GB thumb drive&lt;/a&gt; for the SM, from Amazon of course, for $15, one time, for all cameras, no monthly fee. I could've gotten a cheaper one, but I decided to splurge and get &quot;Amazon's Choice.&quot; Now was the time to figure out how to use it. " created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:34:40 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.blinkforhome.com/sync-module-2/sync-module-2-local-storage-operation&quot;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt; are on the web, and are a bit confusing. They don't say how the drive should be formatted, so I took a guess that MS-DOS format would be the most likely to work. They also said it would automatically format the disk if it wasn't readable, and that it would confirm it with me, but there's no monitor or keyboard on the SM, so how the hell would it confirm it? I later figured out that this happens in the mobile app. " created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:37:56 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It works, &lt;i&gt;exactly as the cloud service works, &lt;/i&gt;with $0 monthly fee, and I can add more cameras without incurring a $3 a month fee. All of which says that their marketing of the cloud service is dishonest. Maybe accessing the images would be a little faster coming from the cloud instead of their server having to read them from my thumb drive and then send them to my mobile device. Their &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Upselling&quot;&gt;upsell&lt;/a&gt; continues in the Blink app, because they say that it's so slow because it's loading it off my local drive. I use the extra time (if it in fact takes longer, I couldn't tell) to curse them out for being such money-grubbers. I might've paid for the convenience of the cloud service if they had just been honest about the choices I had. And maybe if there were features like having my videos mirrored to one of my S3 buckets! Now that would be interesting." created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:39:33 GMT"/>
					<outline text="This is worth pointing out because they are, as I said earlier, an Amazon company, and Amazon is pretty good at is being clear about your choices. Sure they steer you to the most profitable choice for them, I expect that, but to omit vital information and make false claims about what they're doing for you? They should fix that. The advantages are not very clear, so maybe they should just add 32GB of memory to the SM itself and be done with the cloud service altogether. Memory is pretty cheap these days. " created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:41:55 GMT"/>
					<outline text="BTW, a nice feature, they cache the videos on the phone, so once downloaded you can view the video as many times as you like. " created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:55:13 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PS: Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nakedjen.com/&quot;&gt;NakedJen&lt;/a&gt; for finding out what the thumb drive on the SM does. " created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:43:10 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The Sync Module with the USB drive attached. " created="Wed, 28 Apr 2021 15:07:05 GMT" inlineImage="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/28/syncModule.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 27" created="Tue, 27 Apr 2021 15:57:50 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="27">
				<outline text="A &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/davenet/1996/08/28/BeeSeason.html&quot;&gt;favorite story&lt;/a&gt; from 1996 about bees." created="Tue, 27 Apr 2021 16:53:18 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1387115927188221952&quot;&gt;propose&lt;/a&gt; that the Democrats publish what they think would be fair districting for every state, including ones that Republicans control. That way we can see how they deviate from fairness. Give journalism a means to compare. Help people understand gerrymandering.  Another possibility -- maybe someone like Nate Silver could put together fair redistricting maps for all the states. It'd be an interesting idea to approach it as a non-partisan thing, using the best information and data tools we have. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jasonSaldo/status/1387121440789606401&quot;&gt;Update&lt;/a&gt;: They &lt;a href=&quot;https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/redistricting-maps/&quot;&gt;did&lt;/a&gt; it last time around.)" created="Tue, 27 Apr 2021 18:46:27 GMT" type="outline" urltweet="https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1387115927188221952" image="http://scripting.com/images/2020/08/09/gary.png"/>
				<outline text="Make the invisible hand visible" created="Tue, 27 Apr 2021 16:18:58 GMT" type="outline" metaImage="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/27/muppets.png" description="Basecamp and other companies are grappling with a new problem. ">
					<outline text="The idea of online users trying to get people fired, for me, goes back to the early 90s when UserLand was starting up. I was very active on [%search: Applelink%], which was kind of an early version of Facebook. Everyone who was anyone, even if they weren't an Apple user or developer, was there. Online systems were still a new thing." created="Tue, 27 Apr 2021 15:57:51 GMT"/>
					<outline text="One day we got a call at the office, back then companies, even mostly virtual ones, still had offices, demanding that they fire Dave Winer. The person who answered the phone tried to explain that Dave is the founder and majority owner of the company, and no one here can fire him, but the caller persisted. Even then I had too many opinions for some. " created="Tue, 27 Apr 2021 16:26:51 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Reading the &lt;a href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/jason/changes-at-basecamp-7f32afc5&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/a&gt; from Jason Fried, the founder of Basecamp, about changes at his company, I was impressed with how far this has gone. It's an incredible document. You can skip the preamble, head to the numbered parts where he describes the changes they're making. The infection of people feeling empowered to get people fired now has made it all the way &lt;i&gt;into&lt;/i&gt; companies. Back then, no employee of my company would consider the possibility that I, the founder, could be controlled. But now, that's not true. Clearly. " created="Tue, 27 Apr 2021 16:00:37 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Yesterday I &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/04/26.html#a140858&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; about how I don't trust the NYT on almost anything these days, because of what happened to Donald McNeil. But I think, from reading tea leaves, that I can see that something like what happened at Basecamp, has happened there. A committee of employees has formed, and they will decide who can stay at the company. A lot of it will have to do with age, gender and race. Someone who is young, a person of color, and not male will be able to express stronger ideas than one who doesn't check those boxes. " created="Tue, 27 Apr 2021 16:01:49 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Did anyone consider what this does to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/davenet/2001/01/08/whatIsIntegrity.html&quot;&gt;integrity&lt;/a&gt; of a news organization? And, what it does to the integrity of a software development company? " created="Tue, 27 Apr 2021 16:29:53 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Our companies, organizations of all kinds, have jobs to do, and fighting for your cause, unless that's what the organization was formed to do, is not what they're about. You may think a company can take on every cause you believe in, knowing that tomorrow they will be different causes. You should start a company to test your belief. A company like Basecamp was formed (I'm guessing) to serve Basecamp users, to make them happier with Basecamp than competitive products, to generate a profit so it can grow, and to make the shareholders rich for being smart enough to bet on the company. And that's pretty much it. Maybe they had other goals, but it seems from the letter they're letting go of those now. " created="Tue, 27 Apr 2021 16:04:27 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I know this has been said by many startup founders, &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/work/1915278/five-percent-of-coinbase-staff-rejected-its-apolitical-future/&quot;&gt;Coinbase&lt;/a&gt; went through something like this. You can shake your head all you want, but in the end your only recourse, as an employee, is to accept what the leadership of your company wants, or leave and find something better elsewhere, if it exists." created="Tue, 27 Apr 2021 16:07:34 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It's especially troubling in a time when there are so many looming crises, that journalism is being subjected to this opaque idiocracy. If this is really how the Times is going to operate going forward, they have an obligation to explain it, until the readers understand that the words of the Times are being controlled by an invisible hand. We need the NYT to have courage, to not flinch at the possibility that something they cover might offend their employees. And the best outcome imho is if the management of the Times fires the would-be controllers and lets them start the publication of their dreams which I predict approximately no one will subscribe to. " created="Tue, 27 Apr 2021 16:08:34 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 26" created="Mon, 26 Apr 2021 13:57:09 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="26">
				<outline text="I've been reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roots:_The_Saga_of_an_American_Family&quot;&gt;Roots&lt;/a&gt; while I've been waiting for this stomach thing to pass. Maybe not the best choice for reading material when you're feeling sick, but it's a gripping story, very well told. It's long. And the slaves the stories are about didn't have the luxury of switching to a different entertainment medium. Now I find as I poke around on the net and read what people say about prejudice and racism, I think no -- that's doesn't begin to cover it. I &lt;a href=&quot;https://thehill.com/homenews/state-watch/550179-almost-half-of-republicans-say-chauvin-jury-reached-wrong-verdict-poll&quot;&gt;read&lt;/a&gt; that 46% of Republicans polled feel the verdict in the Chauvin trial was wrong. The only universe that it was the wrong verdict was when black people, like George Floyd were slaves, and the only crime Chauvin would be guilty of was destroying another person's property. I wrote in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1386499946795393030&quot;&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;We were taught in school that slavery was over in the US but for millions of Americans it wasn’t and isn’t.&quot; So far no one has objected to that interpretation. " created="Mon, 26 Apr 2021 13:57:10 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/18/roots.png"/>
				<outline text="I did take a break from Roots to watch the Knicks win their 9th in a row. I love this team so much. Then I watched a couple of recommended movies on Netflix, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/80991400&quot;&gt;High Flying Bird&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/80091936&quot;&gt;Okja&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 26 Apr 2021 17:16:18 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="This is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2021/04/26/politics/supreme-court-second-amendment-case/&quot;&gt;what happens&lt;/a&gt; when a crazy minority takes control of the court. They want to make it legal to carry an unlicensed gun anywhere in the US, including urban states. This will get a lot of Americans hurt and killed. We have a huge gun problem in this country. It's like they're throwing around a nuke, we're hoping it won't go off. They're daring the Democrats to stop them. " created="Mon, 26 Apr 2021 18:02:20 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, as you may know I also have a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/?tab=links&quot;&gt;linkblog&lt;/a&gt;. I usually look for a link to a story on two sites: CNN and Axios. Neither site is overly cluttered with nonsense, and neither has a paywall. You can find out what the story is a few seconds and not use up any of your free allocation on other sites that do a good job but have paywalls. Thought I should get an endorsement in for this practice. They coud become the most-linked-to news sites. " created="Mon, 26 Apr 2021 18:05:04 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I'm having a lot of trouble understanding who the NY Times is, where they're coming from, and how I'm meant to understand what they're saying. Pretty sure they'd say, don't worry about these things, the Times just prints the truth, the whole truth, all sides well-represented. I don't think so. When I was a kid I believed that, I still knew they could make mistakes, but I thought they tried to get the actual story, that they weren't manipulating readers to believe things they wanted them to believe. The firing of [%search: Donald McNeil%] was a big deal for me. They never adequately explained why he couldn't continue as a senior reporter covering the story he had prepared for for decades. I don't believe the facts they presented. They were not adequate grounds for firing. Had something similar happened to a reporter of a different gender, race or age, nothing like that would have happened. Having exposed themselves so thoroughly, they have opened up a huge integrity issue. Remember &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/davenet/2001/01/08/whatIsIntegrity.html&quot;&gt;integrity&lt;/a&gt; is the difference between what you are and what you appear to be. There's a deeper story there, and they've buried it. " created="Mon, 26 Apr 2021 14:08:58 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2017/07/13/washingMachine.png"/>
				<outline text="Another subject the NYT has no credibility on is Facebook. These days I don't even bother reading their coverage. Often the facts behind their criticism could be interpreted in Facebook's favor, but the Times never does that. They criticize Facebook for making a bad choice where all there are are bad choices. Could their own work stand up to that kind of scrutiny? I'd love to see them take a chance, but they don't. For every article that talks about all the terrible things that happen on Facebook, they have never, that I have seen, reported on how Facebook is useful, even indispensible. I assume this is because this idea is abhorrent to them. If they acknowledge that people, on their own, can provide service to each other, with no salaried reporter acting as a go-between, what does this say about their future? Well, a real news organization would put that aside, and go where the story is. A news organization that has more of a sense of service than the supposedly great NY Times. " created="Mon, 26 Apr 2021 14:16:24 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 25" created="Sun, 25 Apr 2021 17:54:11 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="25">
				<outline text="My &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/04/24.html#a193908&quot;&gt;under-the-weatherness&lt;/a&gt; continues. Sleeping a lot, not eating much, drinking lots of water. A busy week coming up. It would be nice if this virus-like thing were to go away. And this is weird because I thought we weren't supposed to get virus-like things. Still maybe it's something I ate? Oy. Thanks for all the get well messages. " created="Sun, 25 Apr 2021 17:54:12 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="An easy way to make your writing better. Write the first draft as you think of the ideas. Then &lt;s&gt;go back and&lt;/s&gt; delete &lt;s&gt;all&lt;/s&gt; the connectives, &lt;s&gt;all&lt;/s&gt; the &lt;s&gt;things&lt;/s&gt; words you put in while your mind &lt;s&gt;plotted out&lt;/s&gt; plots where you're going &lt;s&gt;to take the writing&lt;/s&gt; next. And, delete every instance of the word &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/very&quot;&gt;very&lt;/a&gt;. Only leave &lt;s&gt;the ones&lt;/s&gt; it where it's &lt;s&gt;absolutely&lt;/s&gt; necessary to convey the veryness of the idea. Usually it adds nothing to the writing. " created="Sun, 25 Apr 2021 18:00:04 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 24" created="Sat, 24 Apr 2021 19:39:07 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="24">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dan_Kaminsky&quot;&gt;Dan Kaminsky&lt;/a&gt;, a security researcher, died today at 42. I didn't know him, but I followed him on Twitter. One of his &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dakami/status/1214041947406393349&quot;&gt;tweets&lt;/a&gt; is getting a lot of circulation now, and it's worth repeating. &quot;If somebody helped you — always feel free to let them know. They may not.  Really. There is no statute of limitations on being thankful. Years, decades, doesn’t matter. Now is always a good time.&quot;" created="Sat, 24 Apr 2021 19:46:46 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="With that in mind, thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Naughton&quot;&gt;John Naughton&lt;/a&gt;. He wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://johnnaughton.substack.com/p/friday-23-april-2021&quot;&gt;bit&lt;/a&gt; the other day about how that reporter at Vox said something totally wrong about the origin of podcasting, I'm sure the reporter knew it was wrong, and his editors knew it was wrong, but they published it anyway. Naughton thought I must've been furious, but I'm not, I'm exhausted. It's the norm. I'm not a billionaire. I let my ideas float around in the world, I don't lock them up. My goal with podcasting was to create a new medium that everyone could use, and that has worked. Reporters don't need to score any points with me, so they give credit for my work to others. I wrote Naughton an email saying &quot;That's the way journalism works, I'm afraid. They report conventional wisdom, not facts. You're the rare exception.&quot;" created="Sat, 24 Apr 2021 20:00:07 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2017/10/10/maude.png"/>
				<outline text="You can't trust Apple to act in your interests, whether you're a developer or a user. After so many years, it's amazing to me that some people who have been around for a while still expect them to be benevolent. And btw, I'm sure I've written this exact post before." created="Sat, 24 Apr 2021 19:56:01 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2017/10/04/goldenGirl.png"/>
				<outline text="It's been almost 19 years since I missed a day on the blog, and this isn't going to be one of them. Feeling a little under the weather, might be a cold, or maybe something I ate. Not conducive for having ideas. So that's it for today. Maybe I'll have something for y'all tomorrow. Keep on truckin. :smile:" created="Sat, 24 Apr 2021 19:39:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="PS: It turns out I &lt;i&gt;did&lt;/i&gt; have some ideas after all. Sitting down in front of a keyboard I guess pulls some words out of me. Kind of like putting a guitar in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r967lcA_rR8&quot;&gt;Prince's&lt;/a&gt; hands?" created="Sat, 24 Apr 2021 20:45:36 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Silos are computer networks that are walled off from everything else. Your ideas can go in there, they make that easy, even enticing, but they can't interact with ideas anywhere else. Ideas that can't interact are fairly useless. " created="Sat, 24 Apr 2021 19:57:20 GMT" type="outline" inlineImage="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/24/silos.png"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 23" created="Fri, 23 Apr 2021 13:39:08 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="23">
				<outline text="The other day I &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/04/18.html#a140711&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; that I had the project I'm working on &quot;stabilized&quot; after major brain surgery. In software it's always a good idea to be prepared for the worst possible outcome. In this case, I forgot that I hadn't deployed the new version to a server, and when I did that, nothing worked. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edge_case&quot;&gt;Edge cases&lt;/a&gt;. It is once again &quot;stabilized.&quot; But the list of new stuff to do is growing, not shrinking. And who knows what broke in the last round of changes. " created="Fri, 23 Apr 2021 16:31:31 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Now that cannabis is legal in New York State, where I live, I've been curious about how much prices vary around the country. I'm not aware of any comparison websites, but I've heard that Oregon is the least expensive, because they have an oversupply. I'm guessing that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.leafly.com/dispensaries/massachusetts/&quot;&gt;Massachusetts&lt;/a&gt;, the nearest state with retail sales, is still relatively high priced, because the business is so new. 1/8 ounce &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theorywellness.org/ma/great-barrington-recreational-cannabis-dispensary/?dtche%5Bcategory%5D=flower&quot;&gt;goes&lt;/a&gt; for about $50. I imagine that some of the aggregator sites have a good idea of this. I also wonder what kinds of plans there are for stores in various parts of New York. I imagine that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greenwich_Village&quot;&gt;Village&lt;/a&gt; in Manhattan will be a place where there are lots of stores. I expect that &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Woodstock,_New_York&quot;&gt;Woodstock&lt;/a&gt;, the nearest town to where I live, will also be a big spot. If you have any information, please leave a note in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/207&quot;&gt;this thread&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Fri, 23 Apr 2021 13:39:09 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/23/highTimes.png"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 22" created="Thu, 22 Apr 2021 14:15:14 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="22">
				<outline text="I think in general, to rise to a position of fame and wealth in our society, you have to strive to never say anything. I was watching the beginning of an academic conference today, about social media, and recognize the way of speaking, having spent some time in academia myself. My mind drifted, because people weren't saying anything other than how great, amazing and wonderful people in their midst are, and wondered what would've happened at the NYT if the managing editor had told the people who wanted [%search: Donald McNeil%] fired for using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Anytimes.com+nigger&quot;&gt;somewhat forbidden word&lt;/a&gt; in a discussion about using that word that &lt;i&gt;they&lt;/i&gt; could resign, but they would not fire McNeil. Then I wondered why the people wanted McNeil fired in the first place. Maybe because this is the only way they get to have an opinion that isn't nothing. I recognize the pattern. As a man, I know that the only emotion that people are comfortable with from me is anger. Fear, fun, love, generally speaking happiness, all seem to make people uncomfortable, if you have a penis. I don't know why this is. But I reject it. We all should accept each other as we are, especially ourselves. It's this frustration with being nothing that made people want Trump, imho. We should learn to stop punishing people for being individuals. The other option is not good, as we found out. " created="Thu, 22 Apr 2021 14:15:15 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2017/07/06/yourOpinionCounts.png"/>
				<outline text="BTW, hat's off to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elon_Musk&quot;&gt;Elon Musk&lt;/a&gt;. One of the rare exceptions of people who don't care enough to not tell you what they think. " created="Thu, 22 Apr 2021 14:32:52 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Back in 2015 the Mets were a blessed team, the way the Knicks are this year. You'd tune into a game in the 8th inning, the Mets down by 10, to see how they win. They had a few stars, pitchers and hitters who were all peaking at the same time, feeding off each others' energy, it seemed. Their run went all the way to the World Series, which they lost, unfortunately, but the charm was real. The Knicks are doing the same thing. As the fourth quarter starts to draw to a close in each game in the current run, you say that's it, no way the Knicks win this, but then Derek Rose finds Reggie Bullock, alone in a corner, he zips the ball to him and Bullock sinks a three, and we're off to overtime, which the Knicks dominate. This is sports that is charmed, not bought, like the Nets, Clippers or Lakers. Sure they have pedigree stars, they acquired a championship contender, but who cares about that. I love a team of nobodies who shine off each others' light and create an atmosphere of love, and they win because of it. People will soon forget the Nets, when the three stars go their way, to form some other super team in some other long-forgotten franchise. I think next year a few free agents will want to join up with the Knicks, but I hope the team resists. I want to see this team back again next year and the year after that. I want to watch Barrett and Quickley develop, and Rose be their mentors. I want Julius Randle to become the NBA star with a real heart, true to his squad. I feel about them as family, not acquisitions. All the years in the wilderness were worth it. " created="Thu, 22 Apr 2021 14:39:44 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/07/02/knicks.png"/>
				<outline text="The most common thing that stands between people working together is a dysfunctional kind of pride. People feel they are being put down if another person knows more about something than they do. There's an old management slogan that goes with this. &quot;A people hire A people, B people hire C people.&quot; The point is this -- to win, you have to &lt;i&gt;want&lt;/i&gt; to work with people who have developed skills, or even basic talent, that you don't have. That's how you form a team. If you have to do everything, you're going to have trouble making something useful." created="Thu, 22 Apr 2021 19:58:55 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 21" created="Wed, 21 Apr 2021 13:03:13 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="21">
				<outline text="I was &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2020/04/22/133706.html?title=mediaIdeaFindTheCovid&quot;&gt;begging MSNBC&lt;/a&gt; to have &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1385033949878145025&quot;&gt;Kornacki do Covid&lt;/a&gt; at the board. Now finally he's doing it. This. Will. Work." created="Thu, 22 Apr 2021 02:31:09 GMT" type="outline" urltweet="https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1385033949878145025"/>
				<outline text="Peter Kafka &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/recode/2021/4/20/22394032/apple-podcast-subscription-plans&quot;&gt;writing&lt;/a&gt; in Vox said today that Apple &quot;more or less invented podcasting.&quot; This is the kind of &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/21/lie.png&quot;&gt;dishonest&lt;/a&gt; bullshit reporting that I'm always railing about. Anyway this inspired a longish &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/grovesprof/status/1384871198933331968&quot;&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter this morning, All I can say is 1. Oy and 2. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/podcasts-a-storytelling-breakthrough/id1212045046?i=1000489182690&quot;&gt;Walter Isaacson's&lt;/a&gt; podcast about the origins of podcasting. Glad to finally have a credible historian on the record on this. Kafka and Vox you should run a retraction. What people don't get about podcasting, it was a product. Marketed as such. But not with a financial model attached to it. We wanted to create new media, without barriers to entry, so the people could participate. 20 years later and I have to say that actually worked. Reporters don't respect any tech accomplishment that didn't generate a few billionaires (they should, there might be more if they did), but I made a bunch of money in the early tech industry, and I didn't feel very motivated to make more. I &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/davenet/2000/10/19/transcendentalMoney.html&quot;&gt;learned&lt;/a&gt; about what money can and can't do. Up to a point it's great, it buys your freedom, after that, there are limits to consumption, having good friends and fun is more important. And &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/21/tedTurnerQuote.png&quot;&gt;sex&lt;/a&gt;, that's important &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quoteswise.com/ted-turner-quotes-2.html#:~:text=I%20bet%20you're%20all,as%20good%20as%20average%20sex.&amp;text=Being%20a%20billionaire%20or%20being,t%20make%20that%20much%20difference.&quot;&gt;too&lt;/a&gt;. Anyway, I'm proud of our accomplishments with podcasting, even if reporters and Apple generally don't care. " created="Thu, 22 Apr 2021 01:11:47 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2017/09/21/mask.png"/>
				<outline text="Another thing I'm proud of is having bet $50K on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=%24aapl&amp;rlz=1C5CHFA_enUS743US747&amp;oq=%24AAPL&amp;aqs=chrome.0.0i131i433j0l4j0i10j0l4.32287j0j4&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8&quot;&gt;$AAPL&lt;/a&gt; in 1998. " created="Thu, 22 Apr 2021 01:25:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Glad the jurors arrived at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/derek-chauvin-guilty-verdict-george-floyd-death-c01ef7d6-a027-4d77-bfa1-33586ca7734f.html&quot;&gt;correct verdict&lt;/a&gt;, and a white cop has been convicted of murdering a black citizen. I do think tech deserves some of the credit. In the past, without a witness with a phone, it would have been the cops' word against the people's. " created="Wed, 21 Apr 2021 13:20:53 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The press release appears to be gone from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.minneapolismn.gov/government/departments/police/&quot;&gt;MPD website&lt;/a&gt;, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20200526183652/https://www.insidempd.com/2020/05/26/man-dies-after-medical-incident-during-police-interaction/&quot;&gt;archive.org&lt;/a&gt; has a copy, via the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2021/04/20/how-first-statement-minneapolis-police-made-george-floyds-murder-seem-like-george-floyds-fault/&quot;&gt;WP&lt;/a&gt;, with a postscript saying the event was being investigated by the FBI. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-elder-44808121/&quot;&gt;John Elder&lt;/a&gt; is the author. " created="Wed, 21 Apr 2021 13:37:35 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="When you see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jaketapper/status/1384622849562873856/photo/1&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; on George Floyd's death, you can see evidence that the cops colluded to tell a lie. In other words, Chauvin should not be the only cop going to jail. " created="Wed, 21 Apr 2021 13:03:23 GMT" type="outline" urltweet="https://twitter.com/jaketapper/status/1384622849562873856"/>
				<outline text="Journalists are so down on tech, but once they were fans of the snake oil. They still are, selectively, blockchain can do no harm, of course it does, look at how much carbon it liberates. And tech is helping expose the criminality of police. An obvious good." created="Wed, 21 Apr 2021 13:03:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/djrothkopf/status/1384854899977039881&quot;&gt;David Rothkopf&lt;/a&gt;: The GOP is worried about cancel culture?  Wait until they hear about history." created="Wed, 21 Apr 2021 13:07:11 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 20" created="Tue, 20 Apr 2021 13:55:19 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="20">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vuO878gwWyw&quot;&gt;Today's song&lt;/a&gt;: Keep the Customer Satisfied. " created="Tue, 20 Apr 2021 15:52:35 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vuO878gwWyw"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mbk81X6WHA4&quot;&gt;Today's theme song&lt;/a&gt;: Green Acres." created="Tue, 20 Apr 2021 16:01:48 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mbk81X6WHA4"/>
				<outline text="What if the place you live became uninhabitable because of climate change?" created="Tue, 20 Apr 2021 16:23:11 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Some day someone in Silicon Valley will figure out how to get stock options to users in proportion to how early they signed on and the size of their contribution to the success of the platform. The ultimate tech gig. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1384418824536068096&quot;&gt;Users eat the world&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 20 Apr 2021 13:55:20 GMT" type="outline" urltweet="https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1384418824536068096"/>
				<outline text="Predicting the Chauvin verdict" created="Tue, 20 Apr 2021 20:23:27 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="&lt;i&gt;At 4:15 PM Eastern.&lt;/i&gt;" created="Tue, 20 Apr 2021 20:24:53 GMT"/>
					<outline text="That the verdict is coming in so quickly that imho means it's a guilty verdict. Here's why." created="Tue, 20 Apr 2021 20:23:47 GMT" flNumberedSubs="true">
						<outline text="Given the strength of the evidence and the fact that there are four black people on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2021/03/10/us/derek-chauvin-trial-jurors/index.html&quot;&gt;jury&lt;/a&gt;, it couldn't be unanimous acquittal." created="Tue, 20 Apr 2021 20:23:53 GMT"/>
						<outline text="If it was a divided jury, they couldn't be adjourning so quickly, the judge wouldn't let them." created="Tue, 20 Apr 2021 20:24:00 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Therefore the only situation that makes sense, at this point, is a unanimous decision to convict." created="Tue, 20 Apr 2021 20:24:08 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Happy 4/20" created="Tue, 20 Apr 2021 14:20:55 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Happy &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/420_(cannabis_culture)&quot;&gt;4/20&lt;/a&gt; to all my hippie dippie dope smoking friends celebrating the big holiday. And remember what Freewheelin Franklin of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Fabulous_Furry_Freak_Brothers&quot;&gt;Fabulous Furry Freak Brothers&lt;/a&gt; says." created="Tue, 20 Apr 2021 14:21:12 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Freewheelin Franklin." created="Tue, 20 Apr 2021 14:21:17 GMT" inlineImage="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/20/furryFreakBrother.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 19" created="Mon, 19 Apr 2021 13:03:08 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="19">
				<outline text="One of the best investments I've made is in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/S%26P_500&quot;&gt;S&amp;P 500&lt;/a&gt;. It's an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/i/indexfund.asp&quot;&gt;index fund&lt;/a&gt;, the less famous of the two big ones, the other being the Dow Jones. It's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_S%26P_500_companies&quot;&gt;collection of stocks&lt;/a&gt;, chosen by a company named &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/S%26P_Global&quot;&gt;S&amp;P Global&lt;/a&gt;. Simplifying just a little, they buy shares in those stocks and then in turn sell shares of the collection to everyone, people like you and me. The value of the fund is the totall of the value of all the stock it owns, and fluctuates as their prices change. Every day it goes up or down, like a stock. It means that even if one of these companies does badly, the collection doesn't crash. It's designed to reflect the value of the &quot;stock market.&quot; So why is the S&amp;P 500 such a good investment? This is what I think, everyone has an opinion about this. It's the way presidents are evaluated. If the stock market is doing well, then analysts say &quot;the economy&quot; is doing well, and the president's approval rating goes up. It doesn't make any sense, but that's how it works. So the president will work really hard to make sure that your bet on the S&amp;P 500 goes up and up and up, always, in good times and bad. Now, there are times when the S&amp;P 500 will go down, but usually it goes up. If you put some money there it will probably grow. Over time it will grow a lot. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/finance/quote/.INX:INDEXSP&quot;&gt;track&lt;/a&gt; the value of the S&amp;P 500 here. Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/19/sp500graph.png&quot;&gt;graph&lt;/a&gt; of the S&amp;P 500 from 1981 to now. You can see it does go up, but there are times it goes down. You can buy shares in the S&amp;P 500 from any brokerage firm. The list is open source, so any reputable broker can sell you an S&amp;P 500 fund. They all, by definition, behave exactly the same, though commissions on transactions differ according to brokers. That's why I say I &quot;simplified&quot; just a little." created="Mon, 19 Apr 2021 13:03:09 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/01/30/richieRich.png"/>
				<outline text="I still think &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eJ_xdirBsko&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; is the sexiest way to embed a tweet in a blog post. " created="Mon, 19 Apr 2021 14:59:46 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eJ_xdirBsko"/>
				<outline text="I got &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/19/vaccineScammer.png&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; in the mail. Obviously a scammer. Watch out for this. " created="Mon, 19 Apr 2021 13:59:17 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I have a couple of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/C5DECBBE-4F56-4C36-B933-E62144578691?maas=maas_adg_api_5916655800301_macro_1_1&amp;ref_=aa_maas&amp;aa_campaignid=9998093454&amp;aa_adgroupid=103704934791&amp;aa_creativeid=ad-460884485674_kwd-300896750599_dev-c_ext-&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjw1PSDBhDbARIsAPeTqrcQO8iXbbR0pkNn3Jz_0vUcTKYy4Ss2-gNWB0PLoNr3R2ww7D5K360aAmB1EALw_wcB&quot;&gt;Blink cameras&lt;/a&gt;. Blink is owned by Amazon. They're sending me &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/19/blinkPlan.png&quot;&gt;emails&lt;/a&gt; saying that my free plan is about to expire and that I should pay them, for something, they're not clear what, but it sounds like my cameras will be useless once they turn off the plan. In about a week. I don't like that they are so vague about what will happen if I don't pay the money. Amazon hasn't always been the most customer-friendly company, but this is unusual for them, not to be reasonably clear what the proposal is. This is the kind of slimy crap I expect from a cable tv company like Comcast or Spectrum. Or AOL back in the day. Companies that want your money and will do everything ot keep it coming, no matter how unprincipled. Of course I can and will let it expire to see what'll happen. I doubt seriously if, as they threaten, then it will be too late. Heh. This is the kind of campaign that just keeps coming. " created="Mon, 19 Apr 2021 14:28:14 GMT"/>
				<outline text="Has BitCoin been centralized? I don't really know enough to know the answer to that question. In other words, is Coinbase to Bitcoin as Facebook is to the open web?" created="Mon, 19 Apr 2021 14:50:00 GMT" type="tweet" tweetId="1384157503420702729" tweetUserName="davewiner"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 18" created="Sun, 18 Apr 2021 13:23:45 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="18">
				<outline text="They're having a &lt;a href=&quot;https://ide.mit.edu/events/the-social-media-summit-mit-smsmit/&quot;&gt;Social Media Summit&lt;/a&gt; at MIT next week. I have always been bothered by conferences that call themselves summits. Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/18/summit.png&quot;&gt;picture&lt;/a&gt; of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yalta_Conference&quot;&gt;summit&lt;/a&gt;. At the end of WWII, FDR sat down with Stalin. That's an actual summit. BTW, not sure why Churchill is there. :-)" created="Sun, 18 Apr 2021 13:52:00 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/10/18/jessePinkman.png"/>
				<outline text="BTW, if it's a summit, you don't have to say it's a summit. The conference with FDR, Stalin and Churchill was simply called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yalta_Conference&quot;&gt;Yalta Conference&lt;/a&gt;. My father once told me that a university doesn't have to say it's a university if they really are one. You don't see car window decals for proud parents that say Harvard &lt;i&gt;University&lt;/i&gt; or Stanford &lt;i&gt;University. &lt;/i&gt;Just Harvard and Stanford will do. He was putting down the window decal I got him for my &lt;a href=&quot;https://tulane.edu/&quot;&gt;school&lt;/a&gt;, which did proclaim itself a university. Even worse, they called themselves &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Jeopardy/comments/602l8x/the_harvard_of_the_south/&quot;&gt;The Harvard of the South&lt;/a&gt;. Oy! That's not a good sign. I wonder if they still do that. And doing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=%22harvard+of+the+south%22&quot;&gt;search&lt;/a&gt; today I learn that Duke, Rice, Emory and Vanderbilt also consider themselves THOTS. Maybe they should forget it and just try to love their students more." created="Sun, 18 Apr 2021 13:56:02 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW my father was an undergrad at Rutgers, which, while a fine school, isn't exactly &lt;i&gt;The Harvard of New Jersey.&lt;/i&gt; Just sayin. :smile:" created="Sun, 18 Apr 2021 14:04:23 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;i&gt;The&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Harvard of New Jersey&lt;/i&gt; is Princeton, another school that can leave off the University part. Some people think it's an even better school than the other top most prestigious schools in the US, which imho would be Harvard, Stanford, MIT, Yale.  " created="Sun, 18 Apr 2021 14:10:35 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I like to listen to audiobooks on my daily walks and bike rides, they're good to have around when podcasts aren't so interesting to me. It happens. Right now I'm listening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.audible.com/pd/Roots-Audiobook/B002V8H174&quot;&gt;Roots&lt;/a&gt;, narrated by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Avery_Brooks&quot;&gt;Avery Brooks&lt;/a&gt;. It's a beautifully crafted story, and the narration is among the best I've heard. I'm still at the beginning, but I love it, I'm even listening when I'm not out getting my exercise. " created="Sun, 18 Apr 2021 13:23:46 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/18/roots.png"/>
				<outline text="BTW, to follow up on &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/04/17.html&quot;&gt;yesterday's&lt;/a&gt; posts about tabs and bookmarks in the outliner part of &quot;Drummer&quot;. It looks like I did get it stabilized yesterday. I have to qualify that because I saw some problems before I shut down for the day yesterday, after fixing a huge number of really serious mistakes and omissions. But I feel confident that I can start the post corner-turn cleanup and get ready for more fun projects starting tomorrow. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1383828003013070850&quot;&gt;Update&lt;/a&gt;: Re the problems, oy there was a huge problem. In the main closure for a tab there's a background thread that I did not kill when the tab was closed. As a result it kept running. Whenever it saw a change in a file (not its file) it would save it, to the now-closed file, thus wiping out the contents of the closed file. This was hard to track down. Now everything is really smooth. Haha until I find the next horrible omission! Users never see these problems, hopefully, but this is what you have to deal with getting to the point where software is useful.)" created="Sun, 18 Apr 2021 14:07:11 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Hope you don't mind me saying this, but the Mac Finder should have a Bookmarks menu. " created="Sun, 18 Apr 2021 16:25:34 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I'm learning that more people from my &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ulster_County,_New_York&quot;&gt;Ulster County&lt;/a&gt; neighborhood are reading this blog. I find that exciting. Maybe we should have some meetups this summer? At the beer garden at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.colonywoodstock.com/&quot;&gt;the Colony&lt;/a&gt;? I love the idea of a beer garden in Woodstock, and as everyone knows, summers here are the best. There's a lot of planning to do now that cannabis is legal everywhere in NY State now. And Tuesday is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/420_(cannabis_culture)&quot;&gt;4/20&lt;/a&gt;. It looks like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=42.0426&amp;lon=-74.1183#.YHw_JRNKjUZ&quot;&gt;weather&lt;/a&gt; is going to be nice. " created="Sun, 18 Apr 2021 14:12:08 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I don't know if I've ever told this story about my &lt;a href=&quot;http://crimson1.scripting.com/kenKiesler&quot;&gt;uncle&lt;/a&gt; at his hippie commune outside St Augustine, FL. Once I went to visit, on vacation from my Silicon Valley startup. When I arrived at his little off-grid geodesic cottage in the woods, he showed me they had pinned up an article in Business Week with a picture of me, which labeled me as &lt;i&gt;President&lt;/i&gt; Dave Winer of Living Videotext. My uncle who claimed he had changed my diapers when I was an infant, thought this was insanely funny. He told me they started calling each other President Ken, or President Dorothy, or President Pumpkin (one of their dogs) or President Dump Kitty (one of the cats). I didn't object because in my mind I had a terrible case of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Impostor_syndrome&quot;&gt;impostor syndrome&lt;/a&gt;. No one in California dared make fun of it, but here in the woods with my dear uncle and friends, it seemed fine.  " created="Sun, 18 Apr 2021 14:17:31 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/09/25/blackLab.png"/>
				<outline text="BTW, there's a whole neighborhood on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Crescent+Beach,+FL+32080/@29.7519697,-81.2842847,4793m/data=!3m1!1e3!4m5!3m4!1s0x88e69977c882aea5:0xe61a1afbdfe01fae!8m2!3d29.76886!4d-81.2536786&quot;&gt;his 25 acres&lt;/a&gt;. Unbelievable how fast things grow, esp in Florida. " created="Sun, 18 Apr 2021 14:24:42 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The current-events-osphere" created="Sun, 18 Apr 2021 14:56:43 GMT" type="outline" metaImage="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/18/knuckleBiting.png">
					<outline text="I'd love to see an exercise bike that's tuned up for podcasts. Not sure exactly what that means. But I don't like competing on my bike rides. I more prefer to learn stuff. In a somewhat organized way. " created="Sun, 18 Apr 2021 14:56:50 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Most of the podcasts I listen to are suffering from the same problem CNN and MSNBC are. They had a great knuckle-biter story to cover for the last five years, amped up by another knuckle-biter, and now the first one is gone, and the second is waning. Leaving them without anything to talk about. " created="Mon, 19 Apr 2021 01:12:46 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I'm really not worried about Trump anymore, and I'm vaccinated, and I have mask-wearing and social distancing down. I don't travel and I'm fine with that. I enjoy my work, and summer is coming!" created="Mon, 19 Apr 2021 01:10:40 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I found for example that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=%22that+trippi+show%22&quot;&gt;Trippi podcast&lt;/a&gt; was fascinating in the run-up to the election, but now, I don't care so much about what's on the mind of a classical campaign runner (with apologies to Joe, who is a great guy).  It's a very specific thing he does, and only vitally interesting to me in-season. " created="Mon, 19 Apr 2021 01:10:49 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The whole current-events-osphere could use a re-think. " created="Mon, 19 Apr 2021 01:11:41 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Knuckle-biting, demonstrated by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leonardo_DiCaprio&quot;&gt;Leonardo DiCaprio&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 19 Apr 2021 01:12:51 GMT" inlineImage="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/18/knuckleBiting.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 17" created="Sat, 17 Apr 2021 13:31:42 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="17">
				<outline text="I've been reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pale_Blue_Dot_(book)&quot;&gt;Pale Blue Dot&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Sagan&quot;&gt;Carl Sagan&lt;/a&gt;. It's a great book, but already dated. The missions he talks about for the future have already happened. Our understanding of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saturn&quot;&gt;Saturn&lt;/a&gt;, for example, has greatly increased since 1994. Now that &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cassini%E2%80%93Huygens&quot;&gt;Cassini&lt;/a&gt; has visited, so much &lt;a href=&quot;https://stfc.ukri.org/news-events-and-publications/features/10-things-we-ve-learned-from-cassini-huygens/&quot;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt; is known. Sagan of course is not alive to do this for us. But it seems someone should. Next up I'm going to re-read &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cosmos:_A_Personal_Voyage&quot;&gt;Cosmos&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sat, 17 Apr 2021 16:53:35 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Just watched a bit of CNN. Overwhelming feeling — they have no reason to exist." created="Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:49:31 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&quot;Drummer&quot; has a feature that LO2 doesn't have -- [[Bookmarks]]. Here's how they work. There's a [[Bookmarks menu]]. When you choose the first command, Add Bookmark, a dialog confirms that you want to bookmark the current outline. If you click OK, the bookmarks file opens in a tab, and a link to the file you had open appears as the first item in the list. You can move the link where ever you like, and change the text. If you look in the Bookmarks menu, the changes are reflected. The menu can be hierarchic. As you have probably guessed the file is an outline, like any other outline. But it has this special UI. There are a number of other features like this. Anyway, Bookmarks are tricky because of the way asynchronous code works in JavaScript. If bookmarks.opml isn't already open, you have to wait until it is open to create the bookmark link. If you don't, weird things can happen. Now that I've changed how tabs work internally, this feature is broken. It drives me crazy because I depend on Bookmarks, and I'm starting to use Drummer for real work now. So today I must get this problem solved. I'm not getting up until it works. :boom:" created="Sat, 17 Apr 2021 13:31:43 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/09/10/drummer.png"/>
				<outline text="BTW, it's not &lt;i&gt;exactly&lt;/i&gt; true that no outliner I've shipped has had a Bookmarks menu. &quot;Electric Outliner&quot; has one. But I haven't exactly promoted it. I use it to write my blog, in fact I'm using it right now to write &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/04/17.html#a133713&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;. It has had a Bookmarks menu for years, and I've been able to manage lots of complex projects more easily because of it. EO is an Electron-based outliner that runs on the desktop. There will be a desktop version of Drummer, using lots of what's in EO, hopefully. It's possible we did a bookmarks feature for Frontier too. And &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/autowebdocs/menusharingwalkthru_148.html&quot;&gt;menu sharing&lt;/a&gt; is something like Bookmarks. My memory sucks. Sorry." created="Sat, 17 Apr 2021 13:37:13 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, there is a hair trimming &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/s?k=electric+outliner&amp;gclid=CjwKCAjwjuqDBhAGEiwAdX2cj6aRySEOLf2ozvlIG50TKy1OkBRR9CBiDRqbp9q92F3_4EXNFFXy9hoC7QIQAvD_BwE&amp;hvadid=431283316201&amp;hvdev=c&amp;hvlocphy=1023511&amp;hvnetw=g&amp;hvqmt=e&amp;hvrand=169534579424467690&amp;hvtargid=kwd-668587427709&amp;hydadcr=14907_9746130&amp;tag=googhydr-20&amp;ref=pd_sl_9mjtzhtw6e_e&quot;&gt;product&lt;/a&gt; called Electric Outliner. It's screwing up my search for mentions of my Electric Outliner outside this blog. " created="Sat, 17 Apr 2021 13:44:26 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Today I learned that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3schools.com/jquery/html_attr.asp&quot;&gt;jQuery attr&lt;/a&gt; function, if you pass it a function, it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/jquery-attr-method/&quot;&gt;calls the function&lt;/a&gt;. This. Is. A. Bug. It blew my mind when I figured out what was going on. Phewwww. That's the sound of my mind being blown. Back to work Davey." created="Sat, 17 Apr 2021 15:05:17 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 16" created="Fri, 16 Apr 2021 14:31:31 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="16">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1383078831796457486&quot;&gt;Poll&lt;/a&gt;: Will Derek Chauvin be convicted?" created="Fri, 16 Apr 2021 15:24:41 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I've been trying to watch the news on MSNBC and CNN, but it's really hard to get into. Their product transformed under [%search: Trump%], and now that he is gone, or so it seems, knock wood -- what's left for them to cover? Here's what I suggest. This requires that you put the heat on Biden and Judge Garland. First I've heard it said that January 6 could happen again, which I think is too meek. It &lt;i&gt;will&lt;/i&gt; happen again. And until the prosecutions begin, the news should be filling in the details the same way they were covering every detail of the Trump crime scene when he was in office. Who are the leaders? Their names, pictures, backgrounds, are they free, awaiting trial, on the run? These people, and the politicians that are covering for them, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/gop-senators-voted-against-bipartisan-bill-anti-asian-hate-crimes-2021-4#sen-tom-cotton-of-arkansas-1&quot;&gt;six sentators&lt;/a&gt; who voted against the Asian hate crimes bill, to name a few, are vying for the position of &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2017/03/06/howToPreventAnotherTrump.html&quot;&gt;The Next Hitler&lt;/a&gt; of the United States. We need a bunch of good enemies. And why aren't the Bidens prosecuting them. We need some bodies in cells for January 6, now. :balloon:" created="Fri, 16 Apr 2021 20:12:29 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2020/04/27/bidenActionFigure.png"/>
				<outline text="So, instead of watching the news from 6PM to 10PM every night, as I did during the Trump years, I've been reading books, watching the Mets and Knicks, watching British movies, also the Godfather I and II. On the whole this is a better deal. More variety, it's more personal, much less repetitive, and besides the Knicks are playing entertaining basketball, and that's more than I can say for whatever sport they're playing on MSNBC. " created="Fri, 16 Apr 2021 20:38:46 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="On the &quot;Drummer&quot; front, I decided to rewrite the tab code to use JavaScript closures. Much simpler code and hopefully more easily extended to add new functionality. But right now the app is a mess. I learned some new jQuery tricks with custom event handlers and triggers. You can have a very isolated function with persistent and private storage but you can still make calls into it, for the times when the outside world needs to know something about what's inside. " created="Fri, 16 Apr 2021 20:41:51 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Everyone above 16 in New York State can now get vaccinated, and where I live, without an appointment. So vaccination scarcity is over. All you need is ID. But people without ID can get and spread the virus. What’s the plan for such people?" created="Fri, 16 Apr 2021 14:31:32 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 15" created="Thu, 15 Apr 2021 21:50:16 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="15">
				<outline text="An unusual day is one where It's almost 6PM and I haven't posted anything to the blog. This is one of those days. I think I actually have to update at least once a day for the nightly mail app. Not sure what it would do if midnight came and there was nothing new. I don't really want to find out. Everything's fine, in the middle of a pretty heavy bit of development so my focus is there. See you tomorrow! ;-)" created="Thu, 15 Apr 2021 21:50:17 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 14" created="Wed, 14 Apr 2021 14:11:07 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="14">
				<outline text="Hello. My name is Dave and I'm addicted to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Granny_Smith&quot;&gt;Granny Smith&lt;/a&gt; apples." created="Wed, 14 Apr 2021 18:30:58 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I have to say, a consistent theme in my career has been, I create something, through a lot of work and trial and error, and years later it's out and people like it. And then people say thanks for doing that, now I'll take over. The first time I saw that in a huge way was with OPML. It came a couple of years after RSS's success, and a lot of people assumed OPML would be big and they could get rich if they owned it. I had a colleague at Harvard even tell me literally he was going to take over now. Those were the words he used. He had no idea what OPML was! I thought this is the height of ridiculousness. It got so awful I just dropped the project, to let them all fail, which is exactly what happened. These things aren't designed to get anyone rich. There is no lock-in possible so nothing to charge money for. How stupid can you be. Obviously, I learned the lesson that people can be very very very stupid. And unbelievably, larcenously, greedy. (BTW, the guy from Harvard was already very rich. He did not need more money. I had been to his house.)" created="Wed, 14 Apr 2021 15:39:50 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2017/08/05/loveRss.png"/>
				<outline text="So many more examples. Like the VCs and RSS. They all lost all their money because they thought a format can be owned. None of them were interested in where I thought the products were, they all created the same product, badly -- and failed. Podcasting, more of the same. My partner, Adam Curry, thought I was just a programmer, and therefore &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fungibility&quot;&gt;fungible&lt;/a&gt;. I am a programmer, for sure -- but I think about things in a different way, there's a part of the stack almost no one else gets into. I see new media before it exists. I work at it. You can't just hire someone to do what I do. That's why my consistent drumbeat is Let's Work Together. Instead of stopping here, there's much more to do and no one gets to do it all. The interchange format isn't ownable. But most people don't get that, and when they bet money that they can, they lose it all. " created="Wed, 14 Apr 2021 15:48:18 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2017/08/06/hippieBus.png"/>
				<outline text="Drummer is going to be the anti-silo, as Frontier was. What this meant for Frontier is when we saw a new protocol, our first impulse was to implement it. I wanted it to be able to communicate with anything. A silo'd outliner would instead usually not to support a protocol, and implement everything itself. Watching Roam, I'd say they are a half-silo. When it comes to exporting content from Roam they seem to be fairly liberal. They don't want to implement their own blogging software, for example, they'd prefer to export to a static site generator. But, they are fairly closed to allowing other editing tools to be able to push content into their graph. I wanted to see how at least &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/tree/master/blog/days&quot;&gt;some of my writing&lt;/a&gt; here on Scripting News, in outlines, would look in their graph. As far as I can tell, it might be possible to do, but it would require a lot of work by hand, and no one has time to do that. It would make more sense imho to support some kind of standard interchange format. Luckily, I &lt;a href=&quot;http://dev.opml.org/&quot;&gt;created one&lt;/a&gt;, in the 00s, for just this purpose, and it's pretty broadly supported. Anyway they certainly don't make it easy. They really want me to use their outliner. I'm sure it's very nice, but I already have one. Anyway, like all recent text products and services, you're pretty much locked into using their editor. " created="Wed, 14 Apr 2021 15:27:02 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2017/09/04/peterRojas.png"/>
				<outline text="Follow-up to yesterday's &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/206&quot;&gt;braintrust query&lt;/a&gt;. Apparently &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.wordpress.org/rest-api/&quot;&gt;WordPress still has an API&lt;/a&gt;, there's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WP-API/node-wpapi&quot;&gt;Node package&lt;/a&gt; to interface to it, and even better, they still have the &lt;a href=&quot;https://codex.wordpress.org/XML-RPC_Support&quot;&gt;XML-RPC interface&lt;/a&gt; and support the &lt;a href=&quot;https://codex.wordpress.org/XML-RPC_MetaWeblog_API&quot;&gt;Metaweblog API&lt;/a&gt;. So it should be possible to have WordPress support in &quot;Drummer&quot; and use the outliner to create and edit posts on a WordPress website, and who knows where that goes. What's especially cool about it is that in &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2019/12/&quot;&gt;December 2019&lt;/a&gt; I released a new &lt;a href=&quot;http://xmlrpc.com/&quot;&gt;reference implementation&lt;/a&gt; of XML-RPC in the form of a client and server for Node, in JavaScript of course, and a client that runs in the browser. So now there's a good reason to add &quot;XML-RPC&quot; support to Drummer, which I totally want to do. " created="Wed, 14 Apr 2021 14:11:08 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2017/09/01/mrFrog.png"/>
				<outline text="BTW, if someone is looking for an interesting not-too-huge project, hooking up the JavaScript XML-RPC package to WordPress via the MetaWeblog API is a totally self-contained project and would be very helpful. " created="Wed, 14 Apr 2021 14:24:39 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 13" created="Tue, 13 Apr 2021 17:07:55 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="13">
				<outline text="I'm glad the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fsf.org/news/statement-of-fsf-board-on-election-of-richard-stallman&quot;&gt;Free Software Foundation&lt;/a&gt; is standing with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ascripting.com+richard+stallman&quot;&gt;Richard Stallman&lt;/a&gt;. You don't get to destroy someone's life because you don't like him, or the questions he asks, or the things he says. This really is a question of freedom. " created="Tue, 13 Apr 2021 18:43:51 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/Scripting-News/issues/206&quot;&gt;Braintrust query&lt;/a&gt;: Is there a way to post to WordPress from an external app? If it has an API, I'd like to get support in the first release of &quot;Drummer&quot;. It's an important connection. For years they had an XML-RPC interface. I think that's gone now. Has something replaced it yet?  (Update: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WP-API/node-wpapi&quot;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; looks promising.)" created="Tue, 13 Apr 2021 17:07:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 12" created="Mon, 12 Apr 2021 11:55:22 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="12">
				<outline text="Earlier this month I wrote a piece called &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/04/04/174604.html?title=theLostAppsOfThe80s&quot;&gt;The Lost Apps of the 80s&lt;/a&gt;, wondering where the depth of early PC writing tools went. Also spreadsheets, databases, graphics programs. There were huge numbers of them. The reason imho is Microsoft and not just the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Browser_wars&quot;&gt;Browser Wars&lt;/a&gt; which threw all of software into chaos for a number of years. There's another reason, and it might have happened even if the web hadn't come along. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_Office&quot;&gt;Microsoft Office&lt;/a&gt;. So quickly I forgot. It used to be that a word processor cost $495 as did a database, spreadsheet, and various other software. When you added up the retail prices it could easily come to $2000. Then one day, Microsoft bundled &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_Word&quot;&gt;Word&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_Excel&quot;&gt;Excel&lt;/a&gt; and a few other apps, for the price of a single productivity app. And over the years, they added more software to the bundle. This alone might have reduced the productiving software business to one vendor. The competitors couldn't afford to do what Microsoft did, they didn't have the royalties from the OS to support their price-cutting in apps. So that's another theory on where the apps went. Today, that's no excuse. Writing tools would have a different purpose today, writing for the network, rather than for printing. Different requirements. " created="Mon, 12 Apr 2021 11:56:31 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/12/microsoftOffice.png"/>
				<outline text="Why doesn't Georgia get rid of the lines for voters? Isn't this the obvious question. Has anyone asked Gov Kemp? Is that something he can help with?" created="Mon, 12 Apr 2021 13:06:55 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Someday users of network services, having been burned by lock-in, will only choose a service when they’re sure there’s a way out." created="Mon, 12 Apr 2021 11:55:23 GMT" type="outline" urltweet="https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1381546106983682049"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 11" created="Sun, 11 Apr 2021 13:46:16 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="11">
				<outline text="We need a coach to get us through the pandemic. Whether or not you like him, Cuomo was doing that. That’s why I say Fauci should have a podcast. The interviews he does with various people isn’t enough. " created="Mon, 12 Apr 2021 02:11:49 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I just found a 1991 piece by Steven Levy at MacWorld about Frontier, which was still in development at the time. Really interesting read because now, only 30 years later (heh), I'm doing a smaller version of the same idea, not on the Mac but on the open web, once again using standard protocols to connect apps. It starts on page 51 of &lt;a href=&quot;https://vintageapple.org/macworld/pdf/MacWorld_9108_August_1991.pdf&quot;&gt;this PDF&lt;/a&gt; of the August 1991 MacWorld. Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/11/page51.png&quot;&gt;screen shot&lt;/a&gt; of the first page. " created="Sun, 11 Apr 2021 13:46:17 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/12/24/drummer.png"/>
				<outline text="What neither Levy or I understood, at the same time in Switzerland, Tim Berners-Lee was working on the world wide web. Frontier's importance in bootstrapping the web as a content management platform, via blogging, RSS and podcasting, was where the real growth would come. It would require a pivot, of course. The Mac &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; entering middle age, as Levy postulated. But a new shiny thing that worked really well with the Mac was coming along and would soon change everything. The same vacuum that existed on the Mac at the time, now exists on the web. There is no simple-enough scripting language designed for power users to integrate the functionality of many and disparate apps. Why do I like this so much? I guess I'm just a pipes and wires kind of guy. And I think lots of new media will emerge from the ecosystem we'll create here.  " created="Sun, 11 Apr 2021 13:53:04 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I know this is just math, but 1980 is to 1940 as 2020 is to 1980." created="Sun, 11 Apr 2021 15:07:25 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/447362219597369345&quot;&gt;Tweeted in 2014&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;We are just beginning to come to grips with how over-reliant we've been on the imagined ethics of tech companies.&quot; " created="Sun, 11 Apr 2021 14:10:49 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Embarrassing mistake. Yesterday, in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/04/10/142746.html?title=shouldNetflixHaveASchedule&quot;&gt;longish piece&lt;/a&gt; about bingewatching, I gave Kazuo Ishiguro credit for writing the novel Howard’s End.  He actually wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Remains_of_the_Day&quot;&gt;Remains of the Day&lt;/a&gt;. There is a connection. Both were made into movies starring &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emma_Thompson&quot;&gt;Emma Thompson&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anthony_Hopkins&quot;&gt;Anthony Hopkins&lt;/a&gt;. I corrected the piece, but here's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/11/theError.png&quot;&gt;screen shot&lt;/a&gt; of the error. BTW, interestingly, I received an &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/11/netflixemail.png&quot;&gt;email from Netflix&lt;/a&gt; last night suggesting I watch Howard's End. Is it a coincidence, or does their algorithm read my blog? That would be amazing if it did. (I'm sure it doesn't but it's an incredible source about my interests.)" created="Sun, 11 Apr 2021 14:22:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 10" created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 13:31:27 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="10">
				<outline text="I find the resurgence of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/athensresearch/athens&quot;&gt;outliners&lt;/a&gt; inspiring, I wonder about all the addons, and I’d like to see them support import and export standards, and most importantly, APIs. " created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 13:31:28 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, for people who are trying outliners for the first time, may I suggest my own &quot;Little Outliner&quot;. It's browser-based, easy to use, has lots of features, isn't world-encompassing, just a way to make lists, plan stuff, think into your computer screen. It's free to use, no gotchas, and the outlines are in a standard format, and there's a command to download all your work to your local system, for backup or to use in another outliner. So there's absolutely no lock-in. :rocket:" created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 22:39:06 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2020/06/29/alice.png"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://timeshifter.scripting.com/&quot;&gt;TimeShifter&lt;/a&gt; for vaccinators has a simple purpose. Instead of writing on someone's tag 30 Minutes or 15 minutes, you write the time at which they can leave if there are no complications from the vaccine. " created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 19:26:41 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I don’t understand why CNN reports on what Fox says. Isn’t there a risk of too many mirrors reflecting only on each other. News about news about news about news, etc." created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 19:25:34 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="A thread re NYT and the tech web" created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 16:17:55 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="&lt;i&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1380915375383138311&quot;&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt; from my Twitter account..&lt;/i&gt;" created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 16:21:03 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I was having a discussion with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TaylorLorenz&quot;&gt;Taylor Lorenz&lt;/a&gt; about the difference between online media brought to us by the tech industry, and the world of the NYT and other journalism orgs. Here's a concise version." created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 16:18:08 GMT" flBulletedSubs="true">
						<outline text="The NYT et al present packaged stories and opinion. The presenters are vetted, conform to standards that are understood, but not well documented. (This is all my opinion btw.)" created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 16:18:36 GMT"/>
						<outline text="The online tech media presents largely unpackaged stories, with little or no vetting, and the standards are hard to implement because the systems are so vast." created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 16:18:37 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="They're opposites. Night and day. And in conflict, but imho they need not be. "/>
					<outline text="I've long felt we need hybrids. Probably unknown to most people at the NYT, there was a time, between 2002 and 2005, or so -- when I personally worked with them on this stuff. So I had a strong opinion about what they should do. They did half of what I asked, and that was pretty bold, and very successful. " created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 16:19:04 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The other half they didn't do. It would have brought a lot more voices into the NYT, but they would have been vetted, by the reporters of the NYT, simply by quoting them in a NYT piece. So they couldn't avoid the vetting if their stories had sources. And the thought was that anyone who is a source for the NYT is worth listening to and could use a platform. "/>
					<outline text="What would have come out of it is something like what Substack is today. "/>
					<outline text="It's hard to know how that experiment would have turned out, but I believed in the idea. Unfortunately it was immediately turned down. "/>
					<outline text="My main contact at the NYT at the time was Martin Nisenholtz, so you can confirm this with him if you like. The first half of the deal resulted in the RSS standard for distributing news. Another little-known fact, imho RSS would have failed without the support from the NYT. Their trust in my small company was amazing, and we took good care of their brand and rep in the wild world of the web. This was in 2002. " created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 16:43:10 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PS: There's also the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2001/01.html&quot;&gt;story&lt;/a&gt; of how we found the cache of NYT syndicated content. That's what led to the deal we made a year later for RSS. " created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 16:43:11 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Should Netflix have a schedule?" created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 14:27:46 GMT" type="outline" description="Cable-cutting isn't the paradise we thought it would be." metaImage="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/10/bonacera.png">
					<outline text="About a year ago I decided to cut the cord and turn off the TV service from my cable provider, Spectrum. I returned my settop box, which I had never actually installed, because I used their Roku app instead. " created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 14:28:24 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I subscribed to YouTube TV so I could watch news and some sports. It concerned me that they didn't have MSG or SNY for the Knicks and Mets, but there wasn't much sports last year anyway, with the pandemic and lockdowns. " created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 15:04:28 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I went without HBO because I was getting that from Spectrum, and I binged on Netflix, Amazon, Hulu, and a few other services from time to time, but those were the main ones. " created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 14:30:03 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Then the Knicks season started. I could see from the highlights and news that this season they were actually an exciting team, very unusual, I wanted to watch, so I set out on a lengthy search, because the information out there is so poor, only to learn that there is literally no way to get MSG and SNY, the broadcasters of Knicks and Mets games, without Spectrum. The local sports teams are not available to cable-cutters, at least not where I live. " created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 14:30:54 GMT"/>
					<outline text="As I wrote about this on my blog, I got lots of emails saying that this service or that would give me what I wanted. I even tried using Spectrum's &quot;streaming&quot; service, which you can order online, but none of them had the Knicks. " created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 14:32:41 GMT"/>
					<outline text="So I decided to undo the grand cable-cutting experiment, called Spectrum and got back on board with the cable TV service, got a new settop box, which will never be unpacked and will stay in a closet, and happily watched the Knicks during this very interesting, exciting and fun season. " created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 14:33:28 GMT"/>
					<outline text="But this piece is about HBO, not the Knicks. " created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 14:35:02 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Now as a Spectrum user, I can use the HBO Max app. I've paid to access it. And at the same time, HBO appears in the Listings in the Spectrum app. So I added them to my &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/10/spectrumListing.png&quot;&gt;favorites&lt;/a&gt;. So now when I have to choose between something to watch, HBO is one of the choices. And the big difference here is that they pick what to offer me, just like the old days. They have a schedule. And guess what, I watch a lot more HBO this way than I did when I have full choice over what to watch through the streaming app. This is the point of the story. " created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 14:35:20 GMT"/>
					<outline text="An example. Last night just before Ari Melber comes on at 6PM, I got bored with the usual stuff on CNN and MSNBC, so I looked around, and saw that The Godfather had just started. I switched to it, and there's Don Corleone sitting behind his desk with the cat in his lap, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K6LKszIrDzo&quot;&gt;listening to Bonasera&lt;/a&gt;, the undertaker, completely blowing his pitch to the Don. It's a riveting scene. So much to watch. The performance of it. Comparing it to the boring plays they act out on CNN, for months, is ridiculous. One is a masterpiece, the other is completely lost, worthless, not even good for passing the time while playing games on my iPad." created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 14:37:34 GMT"/>
					<outline text="BTW, I watched The Godfather all the way to the end. I didn't get up once. It was the best couple of hours I had spent on entertainment in years.  " created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 14:57:49 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Browsing on HBO Max, I would never think to click on The Godfather as I'm bored looking for something to watch. I think other people have observed this too. Most of my time on these apps is spent looking for something to watch, as opposed to watching." created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 14:39:56 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The idea of scheduled broadcasts is actually very appealing, to my surprise! I thought for sure the revolution was permanent, that we would always be programming our TV-watching experience for ourselves once we had the chance. But there are real problems with that approach. " created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 14:41:06 GMT" flBulletedSubs="true">
						<outline text="How do I know if something is good? I have no idea. And to find out, I have to search for the title on Metacritic, see the total score, and then skim the reviews. A lot of typing and waiting and reading, so I don't do it very often. Much faster just to go on to the next one. " created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 14:41:32 GMT"/>
						<outline text="I might have heard of a show or movie I want to watch, but I have no idea if it's playing somewhere I can access. For example, I was looking for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Remains_of_the_Day_(film)&quot;&gt;Remains of the Day&lt;/a&gt;, because the story was written by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kazuo_Ishiguro&quot;&gt;author&lt;/a&gt; of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2021/03/03/972841445/klara-and-the-sun-is-a-masterpiece-about-life-love-and-mortality&quot;&gt;book I had just read&lt;/a&gt; and loved. Amazon has a big advantage here, you can get almost everything, but mostly they are not included in the video bundle, so you have to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Remains-Day-Anthony-Hopkins/dp/B00BZBDMWQ/ref=sr_1_2?dchild=1&amp;keywords=remains+of+the+day&amp;qid=1618151573&amp;sr=8-2&quot;&gt;pay extra&lt;/a&gt;. I figure I'm already paying enough to all the streaming services, I should watch something that's included, and eventually Howard's End will show up." created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 14:41:39 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="On the other hand, I guess I'll pretty much always watch The Godfather, Babe or Kill Bill 2 when given a chance to. There are actually a lot of movies like that. And now, unlike the past, there are no commercials, and they leave the sex and violence in. And the Knicks, which I watched instead of Maddow, oy! What a &lt;a href=&quot;https://nypost.com/2021/04/10/rj-barrett-doesnt-blink-in-clutch-knicks-moment/&quot;&gt;game&lt;/a&gt;. The ups and downs, tragedy and heroic play, the back-stories, the history -- all in just an hour. MSNBC, comparitively, is transparently nothing. The best they have is a powerless Congressperson who is ridiculously and obviously corrupt and popular (maybe) on Fox who has been caught. Nothing is at stake. They can't explain why anyone should care. They need a new purpose." created="Sat, 10 Apr 2021 14:44:40 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 9" created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 13:15:59 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="09">
				<outline text="Journalism is not accountable. We can’t impeach the NYT, or remove them from office in the next election. Yet they pretty much determine what we talk about, so much so that &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wolf_Blitzer&quot;&gt;Wolf Blitzer&lt;/a&gt; on CNN actually negotiates with politicians we do elect, who are accountable." created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 19:53:53 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="If Congress wants to get the attention of tech companies, make them liable for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.droid-life.com/2021/04/08/apple-android-imessage-lock-in/amp/&quot;&gt;lock-in&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 13:16:00 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I've been catching up on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2021/04/08/world/meanwhile-in-america-april-8-intl/index.html&quot;&gt;Chauvin trial&lt;/a&gt; every night on the news. The testimony is damning. He is obviously guilty of murder. But, the defense isn't trying to win all the votes of the jurors, they only have to convince one juror, and I'm pretty sure they'll do that." created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 13:16:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="One reason &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JRubinBlogger/status/1380510762515509249&quot;&gt;Manchin&lt;/a&gt; might want to vote to cancel the filibuster is that it would maintain his power to veto non-budget Democratic legislation. With the filibuster in place the only power he has is to keep the filibuster. If he sticks with that he might as well switch parties now. However, if Biden and the Dems sold the voting plan that the Repubs will certainly block, if 90 percent of West Virginians supported the reforms, I would imagine that Manchin &lt;i&gt;could&lt;/i&gt; change his mind. It all comes back to the same thing. &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/04/07/142155.html?title=theCampaignNeverStops&quot;&gt;The campaign never stops&lt;/a&gt;." created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 13:22:59 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="A Drummer example" created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 14:14:43 GMT" type="outline" description="Even though the script makes a dozen asynchronous calls to Twitter, it's written as if it were synchronous." metaImage="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/09/drummers.png">
					<outline text="Just for fun I wrote a &quot;Drummer&quot; script that lists the earlierst Twitter users in an outline.   " created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 14:14:14 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;b&gt;Here's the script:&lt;/b&gt;" created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 14:15:01 GMT" flCodeSubs="true">
						<outline text="var flfirst = true;" created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 14:15:19 GMT"/>
						<outline text="op.insert (&quot;Early Twitter signups&quot;, down);" created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 14:17:14 GMT"/>
						<outline text="for (var i = 12; i &lt; 25; i++) {" created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 14:16:46 GMT">
							<outline text="var name = twitter.getScreenname (i);" created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 19:05:46 GMT"/>
							<outline text="op.insert (name, (flfirst) ? &quot;right&quot; : &quot;down&quot;);" created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 19:05:53 GMT"/>
							<outline text="flfirst = false;"/>
							<outline text="}"/>
							</outline>
						<outline text="op.go (left, 1);"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="&lt;b&gt;The list it generates&lt;/b&gt;" created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 14:15:35 GMT" flCodeSubs="true">
						<outline text="&lt;img src=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/09/twitterUsersList.png&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom: 10px;&quot;&gt;" created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 14:24:09 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="&lt;b&gt;How the script works&lt;/b&gt;" created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 14:16:49 GMT" flNumberedSubs="true">
						<outline text="It inserts a headline in the current outline, &lt;i&gt;down&lt;/i&gt; from the bar cursor headline, with the text &quot;Early Twitter signups.&quot;   " created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 14:16:53 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Then it loops of users whose ids are 12 to 24. I picked 12 because I had figured out from an earlier script that it was the first-listed user. And 24 is a random value I picked out of thin air. ;-)" created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 14:17:23 GMT"/>
						<outline text="For each user, it calls the Drummer verb twitter.getScreenname, which takes one parameter, the id of the user whose name you want. Then it inserts the name either to the right or down from the cursor depending on whether this is the first user we're inserting. That's how &lt;a href=&quot;http://docserver.userland.com/op/insert&quot;&gt;op.insert&lt;/a&gt;, an old friend from Frontier, works. " created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 14:18:33 GMT"/>
						<outline text="When it's done looping, it moves the cursor to the left, onto the &quot;Early Twitter signups&quot; headline we created. " created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 14:19:46 GMT"/>
						<outline text="It leaves the list expanded. " created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 14:20:16 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					<outline text="&lt;b&gt;The killer feature&lt;/b&gt;" created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 14:20:49 GMT">
						<outline text="It's so humble you might actually miss it. " created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 14:20:52 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Even though the script makes a dozen asynchronous calls to Twitter, it's written as if it were synchronous. No weird code structures, you just write it as you think of it, and the system translates it into the complicated stuff, for you. Do I have to explain why this is good? Any time you can let the computer do the complex stuff for you is time you save, and errors you don't make. " created="Fri, 09 Apr 2021 14:21:04 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 8" created="Thu, 08 Apr 2021 15:16:20 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="08">
				<outline text="Today's song: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bJVWZy4QOy0&quot;&gt;For the benefit of Mr Kite&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 08 Apr 2021 16:57:58 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bJVWZy4QOy0"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1380196022270504964&quot;&gt;Twitter thread&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;These days I see twitter as an essential utility. Largely because the API is so good.&quot;" created="Thu, 08 Apr 2021 21:20:21 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, &quot;Drummer&quot; will have a collection of built-in Twitter verbs. " created="Thu, 08 Apr 2021 21:20:46 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 16px&quot;&gt;twitter.getScreenname (twitter.getUserProfile (&quot;jack&quot;).id) //example&lt;/span&gt;" created="Thu, 08 Apr 2021 22:31:31 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&quot;Use the product for its intended purpose.&quot; This is something I say to myself and people I work with, a lot. A steady drumbeat, to stay on track. " created="Thu, 08 Apr 2021 15:51:06 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I watched the beginning of President Biden's press conference today. Both VP Harris and the president gave very good talks.  Sometimes their cadence is wrong, they speak in typos,  and other times (like today) I say YEAH that's right, that's how you do it. " created="Thu, 08 Apr 2021 16:27:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="It would be amazing if all software developers used compatible back-end databases." created="Thu, 08 Apr 2021 17:00:17 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 7" created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 13:54:47 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="07">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1379837142336204800&quot;&gt;Poll&lt;/a&gt;: When Trump says Matt Gaetz never asked for a pardon, what percent chance is it he's telling the truth?" created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 16:44:32 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="If you use &quot;little outliner&quot; you should &lt;a href=&quot;http://this.how/littleoutliner/versions.opml#1586885920000&quot;&gt;download your files&lt;/a&gt; regularly, as a backup. It's saved my ass more than once. The &lt;i&gt;Download My Files&lt;/i&gt; command is in the Tools menu. You quickly get a zip archive of all your files.  " created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 23:36:06 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="After watching &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/04/03.html#a131856&quot;&gt;The Making of Sgt Pepper&lt;/a&gt;, I've listened to the album a few times, from beginning to end. They said it's a concept album, but it isn't really. There are four songs that are in keeping with the Sgt Pepper theme, but the rest are Beatles songs. A few that could have been from the pre-Pepper Beatles. But the album made another statement that did mark a turning point: We're going to try new ideas. We're really going to do it, not just talk about it. We're going to use the remarkable place we're in to innovate. Further, this isn't about fame or wealth, it's about creativity, human expression. For the rest of their careers, as a group and individuals, they continued to try new ideas. And they inspired a generation of us to believe in our own ingenuity as much as any tech hero did, more I think (though I wasn't inspired by them, I was of them). The beauty of Pepper is the lives of the people who created it and their ability to influence. " created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 17:18:09 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/07/harrison.png"/>
				<outline text="I wish there was a way in video conferences on a pc for your eye to be focused on the image of the other person talking. The camera is in the wrong place, in other words." created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 14:35:23 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The. Campaign. Never. Stops." created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 14:21:55 GMT" type="outline" description="The election is over, that does not mean that campaigning is over. The support of the people is essential to governing and maintaining power." metaImage="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/d/dd/FDR-January-11-1944.jpg">
					<outline text="If we want the Dems to stay in power, and we do -- they have to get a very simple idea. " created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 14:22:08 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The. Campaign. Never. Stops." created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 14:22:11 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It used to be that fund-raising never stops, but now more is required. Keep the connection between leadership and voters going all the time." created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 23:24:21 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The good thing -- our current president gets this. Biden is doing a fantastic job. Maybe his experience has something to do with it. Or maybe, as Nixon could open China, after being a rabid anti-communist, maybe Biden is uniquely capable of being a new LBJ or FDR, because he is known as a moderate. (As was LBJ, btw.)" created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 14:22:39 GMT"/>
					<outline text="BTW, add to this thread -- why has Lincoln Project stopped running ads? This happened the the HRC campaign in 2016. The election is over, that does not mean that campaigning is over. The support of the people is essential to governing and maintaining power." created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 14:23:00 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Email with John Naughton" created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 13:54:48 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="&lt;b&gt;Dave's intro&lt;/b&gt;" created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 14:04:18 GMT"/>
					<outline text="We used to have systems in blogging that better-enabled discourse like what's going on between &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Naughton&quot;&gt;John Naughton&lt;/a&gt; and myself. Primitive stuff like permalinks, which nowadays would seem like a huge innovation.  Interestingly, we're talking about making the web a better communication system for writers. " created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 13:55:00 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Back in the day, when blogging was new, when we had an idea like this, I could just write the software and post an upgrade. Even if JN wasn't using my software, the people who made the software he used would hear about it, and fairly quickly would match the feature. Who knows why, but I'd bet it was mostly the competitive impulse. There's Dave adding a feature for a user, we'd better add it too. But the writers' web doesn't work like that any more. We have to try to get the attention of young companies with billion dollar valuations, running a rocket ship three  feet off the ground. Even a small bump could blow them up. Believe me I know what it's like, somewhat. Been there. " created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 14:08:03 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Anyway, JN responded to my post with a post &lt;a href=&quot;https://memex.naughtons.org/tuesday-6-april-2021-2/33463/&quot;&gt;on his blog&lt;/a&gt;, and I wish I could point to it, but his software doesn't have permalinks, so I'll just reproduce it here. " created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 13:58:38 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;b&gt;Email from John Naughton&lt;/b&gt;" created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 14:00:29 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Many thanks for &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/04/06/150554.html?title=copypastetopublish&quot;&gt;writing&lt;/a&gt;. Funny coincidence: I was about to write to you about the email exchange you’ve embarked on with Ray Ozzie, but that can wait for another day. For now, I just wanted to say that I’m with you all the way in your view that the formulaic editing tools offered by platforms like Blogger, WordPress, Medium, Substack et al are, clumsy and restrictive to use. And I wholeheartedly agree that writers should be able to use whatever tool they find best for them, and that publishing platforms should make it easy to upload text and implement whatever formatting is needed." created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 14:00:34 GMT"/>
					<outline text="My own journey has taken me about 90% of the way towards that. I decided years ago that from henceforth everything I wrote would be composed as ASCII text rather than in a proprietary format (e.g. Microsoft Word) and stored as such. So I started doing that, relying on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pandoc.org/&quot;&gt;Pandoc&lt;/a&gt; to transform my text into pdf, Word, LaTex or whatever. (In doing that, I was of course harking back to when I first started writing on a Unix time-shared machine, producing plain marked-up text which was then fed into troff to produce beautifully typeset copy.) When John Gruber and Aaron Swartz (RIP) came up with Markdown in 2004 as a lightweight way of marking-up text, I adopted that. And eventually, thanks to Quentin I found a writing app that worked for me — &lt;a href=&quot;https://ulysses.app/&quot;&gt;Ulysses&lt;/a&gt; — and have used that ever since. Once WordPress started to accept Markdown text, all my blog posts (except the daily Substack version of the blog) have been written that way. Ulysses will also spit out a version of any text I write in a variety of proprietary formats and so looks like being the only writing tool I will need from now until I keel over." created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 14:01:17 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Now, to your point that “Basically, it should be possible to hook your writing tool directly to both WordPress and Substack”… It turns out that Ulysses eventually cracked the WordPress route, and so I can now hit a button and have it immediately uploaded to, and formatted on, &lt;a href=&quot;https://memex.naughtons.org/&quot;&gt;Memex 1.1&lt;/a&gt;. The HTML looks a bit verbose and clunky, but it renders just fine. And it’s efficient and quick. So getting Substack to create an API that enables Ulysses to upload as easily would that I would be nearly there." created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 14:02:52 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Nearly, but not quite — which is why I really appreciate your feature request to Substack to also enable paragraph-level permalinks."/>
					<outline text="Keep well."/>
					<outline text="John"/>
					<outline text="&lt;b&gt;FInal notes from Dave&lt;/b&gt;" created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 14:04:45 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Also, note to self, I have to make it so that when people copy the text of my posts, the # permalinks don't get copied. Every time JN quotes me I see them there, and it makes me cry because I work so hard on the words and the pound signs just do not belong there! Oy." created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 13:55:35 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Also, to John, I'd love to hear what you say re my conversation with &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/04/04/174604.html?title=theLostAppsOfThe80s&quot;&gt;Ray&lt;/a&gt;. We'll figure out how to make this work. Hosting a salon with great minds such as yourself and Ray is something I love to do. " created="Wed, 07 Apr 2021 14:06:21 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 6" created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 14:36:08 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="06">
				<outline text="Today's song: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3tqjXnMe0eM&quot;&gt;Dilly Dally&lt;/a&gt;." created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 14:36:09 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Don't wait for people to see things from your point of view, it'll never happen." created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 18:48:17 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Bernie Sanders on MSNBC last night talked about new Repub voter suppression. He  never said the thing I hoped he would. Repubs know they can't win a fair election, so they cheat." created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 16:42:23 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I was asked if I know that tech companies hate the web, and asking them to help the web is stupid. I can't defend that, it might be stupid, who knows. But it isn't taking a lot of time, and in talking about wanting to rekindle the writing tools category, I'm not just talking to the platform devs, I'm also talking to users, who may not have realized that they don't have to become copypaste machines just to have a newsletter, or cross-post to Facebook. There's no technical barrier. And if they wanted to use their favorite editor to write blog posts or newsletters, because they now understand that it's possible, that would create pressure for tech companies to do it. Now the big ones wouldn't, at first, but one of the also-rans might, as a way to get users to use their service. And if the feature is as sexy as I believe it is, they &lt;i&gt;will&lt;/i&gt; get more users, and in doing so might attract the other, bigger companies, to do it too. Also there are some idealists around, believe it or not, some tech founders who believe in the web, and even read this blog, and might respond to a friendly nudge. Anyway, what's the difference. It gives me pleasure to stand up for the web, and hope. I think the world can work better, and if I can help, you bet I'm going to say something. " created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 14:38:14 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2020/09/05/fauci.png"/>
				<outline text="This story isn't really about George O'Connor (a made-up name), it's about something else. Here's the story. Many years ago I was at a party at CES, only people with connections were invited. So you could walk around this big ballroom and every few minutes you'd run into someone you know from a long time ago. In this case I ran into George, a person I knew from the early Mac days because he worked at Anderson (also a made-up name), one of the networking hardware companies of the Mac. A respected company, and George was well-thought-of. But I had another connection to him, his sister had worked for my company, a few years before, and I wanted to ask how she was doing and to say hi for me. George started talking after I said hello, and he said he couldn't help get me into TED. He was a producer there, and presumably everyone in the room was hitting him up for tickets, I guess he was tired of it. I didn't want to go to TED, and I also didn't hold this against George. I think I see this all the time, but rarely is it so open as it was at that party. People assume you want something from them, when you just wanted to say hi because you have good memories of them. It's the flipside of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://threads2.scripting.com/2013/february/theguyatthegasstation/&quot;&gt;story I wrote in 2013&lt;/a&gt; about a clerk at a gas station having a bad day. " created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 14:48:38 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="With the Repubs openly threatening corporations, the question is who do they think they rep?" created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 15:17:37 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Copy/paste-to-publish" created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 15:05:54 GMT" type="outline" description="it should be possible to hook your writing tool directly to both WordPress and Substack.">
					<outline text="I started writing this email to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jjn1&quot;&gt;John Naughton&lt;/a&gt; re his recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://johnnaughton.substack.com/&quot;&gt;Memex&lt;/a&gt; daily posts, but I thought both of us being public writers, I should just post it here and send a pointer. So here goes. " created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 15:06:06 GMT">
						<outline text="John, I've been following the &lt;a href=&quot;https://johnnaughton.substack.com/p/monday-5-april-2021&quot;&gt;story of the strange URLs&lt;/a&gt; from your Substack newsletter. I also appreciated your telling how you produce your newsletter by &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/06/naughtonWorkflow.png&quot;&gt;copy/pasting&lt;/a&gt; from WordPress into Substack. I bet 90 percent of Substack's text comes in this way. And that's what this letter is about. " created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 15:06:44 GMT"/>
						<outline text="I've been asking them to automate that part for you via an API or RSS, or whatever they specify, to remove the copy/paste step from your publication workflow. I am deliberately being a squeaky wheel, hoping that writers who use Substack will join in." created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 15:08:03 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Basically, it should be possible to hook your writing tool directly to both WordPress and Substack." created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 15:20:35 GMT"/>
						<outline text="I would have used Substack myself if it weren't for this limit. As a writer, I want to eliminate steps, to make my writing more effortless. Publishing an idea takes too many steps, as a result, a lot of ideas don't get out. " created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 15:08:32 GMT"/>
						<outline text="I want to have a better flow on the web as a writer, and I think if other writers knew what was possible they'd want it too, and hopefully they would write about it. You wrote about it yesterday! ;-)" created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 15:21:36 GMT"/>
						<outline text="JN, writers have a lot more power imho than they think. Esp in the early days of a service like Substack. They are listening to you. They know they depend on you. If enough writers wanted a feature, they would implement it. That's how development works. " created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 15:22:07 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Please consider writing something yourself about eliminating copy/paste-to-publish step. There's a lot of power trapped in that limit. " created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 15:09:03 GMT"/>
						<outline text="Dave" created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 15:59:00 GMT"/>
						<outline text="PS: A &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1379453137963122688&quot;&gt;feature request&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Permalink&quot;&gt;permalinks&lt;/a&gt; in Substack." created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 15:59:01 GMT"/>
						</outline>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Al Franken ad" created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 16:25:00 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Al Franken ad from 2016." created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 16:21:27 GMT" inlineImage="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/06/alFrankenAd.png"/>
					<outline text="PS: A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2Kydr2a7Uy4&quot;&gt;Randy Rainbow song&lt;/a&gt; about Andrew Cuomo from a year ago. " created="Tue, 06 Apr 2021 16:27:47 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 5" created="Mon, 05 Apr 2021 15:26:52 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="05">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1378354894806061059&quot;&gt;Definition&lt;/a&gt;: An API makes it possible to do things with a piece of software from another piece of software." created="Mon, 05 Apr 2021 15:26:53 GMT" type="outline" urltweet="https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1378354894806061059"/>
				<outline text="Why is it interesting to think about what became of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/04/04/174604.html?title=theLostAppsOfThe80s&quot;&gt;Apps of the 80s&lt;/a&gt; -- because imho we still need what they do. I want to use one writing tool, the perfect one for me, and flow the text through various services. We know how to. Rather than just accept more and more editors, let's build interfaces that allow choice. APIs. We know how to do it. We just need one or two products to demo the concept and define the interfaces. Any blogging tool or newsletter mailer could take the next step. " created="Mon, 05 Apr 2021 15:27:39 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 4" created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 15:12:49 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="04">
				<outline text="I heard about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chia.net/&quot;&gt;Chia&lt;/a&gt; today. Sounds like it's a crypto currency, but what makes it interesting is that &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bram_Cohen&quot;&gt;Bram Cohen&lt;/a&gt; is involved, and he's the guy who brought us &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BitTorrent&quot;&gt;BitTorrent&lt;/a&gt;, and that works pretty well, and seemed really wild when it first came out. " created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 20:44:58 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Unless you're really sure the other person will get your humor, or appreciate it, it's usually better to say what you mean instead of trying to be funny." created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 18:31:46 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The lost apps of the 80s" created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 17:46:04 GMT" type="outline" description="In an email conversation, Ray Ozzie and I talked about all the writing tools of the 80s that didn't transiiton to the web." metaImage="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/04/byteCoverLaptops.png">
					<outline text="As you know I've been asking a question pretty persistently -- where did the apps go? Specifically where did the writing tools go? Before the web, there was a deep market for software writing tools, all kinds of word processors, text editors, desktop publishing tools, even spreadsheets and database software were used to write. Yet few of those tools transitioned to the web. " created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 17:46:21 GMT" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/09/27/todd.png"/>
					<outline text="In the early years of the web, we thought it was very innovative for browser-based apps to create and write for public websites, which eventually became blogs, entirely through web forms in the browers. It was such a miracle, look at how easy it is! -- that we overlooked that as a writing tool, the web browser is pretty awful. We know how to do it so much better! Why didn't we? Why don't we do it now?" created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 18:04:09 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;b&gt;Introducing Ray Ozzie...&lt;/b&gt;" created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 22:44:41 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I've been having an email conversation with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ray_Ozzie&quot;&gt;Ray Ozzie&lt;/a&gt;, a fellow productivity tools developer from the 80s. We never worked together but we worked with people who worked together. He did several products you might be familiar with. Lotus Symphony which was the height of the &quot;integrated software&quot; period in the mid-80s, and the corporate groupware product, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cio.com/article/2431837/7-things-it-managers-should-know-about-lotus-notes.html&quot;&gt;Lotus Notes&lt;/a&gt;. Since then he has been CTO of Microsoft, and has founded several successful startups. He was recently honored as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://computerhistory.org/events/building-a-better-world-through-tech-for-collaboration/&quot;&gt;fellow&lt;/a&gt; of the Computer History Museum. I asked if I could include some of his comments in a blog post here, and he agreed. I didn't do any editing, his words appear exactly as he typed them." created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 17:48:59 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;b&gt;Dave (me) kicks it off...&lt;/b&gt;" created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 17:53:53 GMT"/>
					<outline text="There used to be, as you know, a deep market for tools for writers. Highly customizable products, or products with UIs with character, people had something they don't have now -- choice. And that made it competitive." created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 17:54:20 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Now, we don't have choice. If I want to write on Facebook, I have to use their awful buggy editor. If I want a Substack newsletter or a Medium blog, or whatever -- I have to use their editors, which vary in quality, but none of them would have stood a chance in the 80s software market."/>
					<outline text="We could argue how this happened, but there's no question that it did happen."/>
					<outline text="Also there should be networked spreadsheets. And since it's 40 years later, there should be products we never imagined in the 80s. They aren't there."/>
					<outline text="That's the starting point. I'm not saying we should fix it, I don't want to take that on, but I want to focus the tech world on the fact that this happened. "/>
					<outline text="&lt;b&gt;Now Ray opines on the lost apps of the 80s...&lt;/b&gt;" created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 17:54:42 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I agree wholeheartedly that there are things that we were incredibly fortunate to have experienced, and they seem to be gone.  Seemingly forever." created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 17:55:05 GMT"/>
					<outline text="ThinkTank and outliners in general is one of them.  I don’t understand this because I think there are many outliner-type people out there who would enjoy them, but because they never became mainstream they aren’t being given a chance to be mainstream once again."/>
					<outline text="I also think that there were calendar-centric PIM-centric extensions to the outlining concept that were in Agenda that were worth saving; they’re gone."/>
					<outline text="Pito Salas’s spreadsheet &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/pito-s-blog/why-improv-didnt-succeed-3e06a43acf73&quot;&gt;Improv&lt;/a&gt; had incredible things – far more than just the pivot table – and yet the world is now deprived because the world seems comfortable with a simpler concept of a spreadsheet.  And yes, networked spreadsheets of one form or another would be amazing – especially given that many real-world spreadsheet scenarios involve periodic consolidation/roll-up involving multiple people and processes." created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 18:02:06 GMT"/>
					<outline text="A VC friend told me several years ago that it was incredible that even though there is now a wave of “low code” tools such as Airtable, that there is nothing out there with the power and usability that Lotus Notes had back-in-the-day.  And so we cobble together many tools, ignoring the fact that there was a better answer that we’ve chosen to discard."/>
					<outline text="As you said, I can’t fix it.  I can’t even explain it.  I’ve put an incredible amount of energy and love into products that have commercially failed, and it has made me a bit more cautious.  I’m fortunate that I don’t tend to descend into cynicism, but it remains perplexing."/>
					<outline text="As a writer and an analyst, I do think this would be a great topic to explore: why have so many great ideas been discarded?  Even if their initial implementation was destined never to withstand the test of time, why do we choose to ignore those aspects that were good?  In an internet that was supposed to allow us to have ‘bubbles’ of special interest groups, why haven’t we created a thriving environment that might support the creation and maintenance of bespoke power tools for creativity and productivity?" created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 17:57:14 GMT"/>
					<outline text="That's where I'd like to leave it for now, there will be more. " created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 17:57:19 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PS: I wrote my side of the conversation in GMail. A pretty standard browser-based text browser and editor. In Chrome on my Mac. I don't know what email app Ray used. ;-)" created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 18:01:29 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PPS: There's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26692308&quot;&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt; about this piece on Hacker News." created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 22:52:37 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="How today's computers looked in 1981" created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 18:08:30 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="A BYTE magazine cover from 1981." created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 18:07:11 GMT" inlineImage="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/04/byteCover.png"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Yes, journalism is a thing" created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 22:34:19 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/04/03.html#a131835&quot;&gt;Journalism is a thing&lt;/a&gt;, a whole, it makes sense to talk about in the way I talk about it. I don't need a lecture at this level, although people often do it for some reason." created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 22:36:41 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I read a piece recently somewhere, I forget where, that said people who think rapid universal change can't take place -- they aren't paying attention. The example they cited was that not too long ago people were smoking everywhere. Now there are severe limits on where you can smoke, and people seem to respect the limits. We made a decision as a society to change our behavior and it happened quickly. And you could have made the same kinds of arguments, that there is no such thing as a &quot;smoker&quot; -- but there was. " created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 22:37:31 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It also happened with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Same-sex_marriage#Legal_recognition&quot;&gt;same-sex marriage&lt;/a&gt;. Hard to believe it first became legal in the US in 2015! Had you asked me in 2014 if that was possible I would have said no. Then it changed, just like that. " created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 22:38:03 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Covid is another one. Who would have thought that people could hibernate for more than a year in the US. I recorded a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2020/03/05.html#a181825&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; in March last year, just to mark how ludicrous I thought it was yet at the same time inevitable. We do go through real transitions. I expect there will be plenty more. " created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 22:38:34 GMT"/>
					<outline text="And at some point some journalism org will trip over the idea that repping the people's interest makes their art work as a business like nothing else before. Sometimes I think that's all we're arguing about in the US. The elites talk to the elites and ignore the rest of us. So remind me, why are we supporting this?" created="Sun, 04 Apr 2021 22:39:26 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 3" created="Sat, 03 Apr 2021 13:18:34 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="03">
				<outline text="Today's song: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WLiIe0KQ_lY&quot;&gt;Chuck E's In Love&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sat, 03 Apr 2021 14:09:46 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WLiIe0KQ_lY"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/remotely_ruth/status/1377988413832392706&quot;&gt;Ruth&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Explain APIs to me like I’m 45 (and new to tech).&quot; " created="Sat, 03 Apr 2021 14:33:49 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="President Biden does something I thought Democrats forgot how to do. He goes around the obstruction in DC, bringing his ideas to the people. Journalism could learn from this. If they understood and took the side of the people more, they'd have more support from the people." created="Sat, 03 Apr 2021 13:18:35 GMT" type="tweet" tweetId="1378336171168825345" tweetUserName="davewiner"/>
				<outline text="I'm thinking about &lt;a href=&quot;https://gothamist.com/news/ny-and-nj-both-legalized-marijuana-this-year-but-theres-one-big-difference&quot;&gt;legal weed&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Woodstock,_New_York&quot;&gt;Woodstock&lt;/a&gt;." created="Sat, 03 Apr 2021 20:45:48 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I've thought more about &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/03/31.html#a004613&quot;&gt;Making of Sgt Pepper&lt;/a&gt;. It's amazing to hear the Beatles' perspective on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sgt._Pepper%27s_Lonely_Hearts_Club_Band&quot;&gt;album&lt;/a&gt;, I had never really thought how it was created, yet as a creative person myself, I’m often surprised and even offended that people don’t consider my point of view about the things I created. But at one time, Sgt Pepper was their thing, their secret. That's why the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/04/01.html#a155654&quot;&gt;final quote&lt;/a&gt; was so strong for me. &quot;You just wait,&quot; says McCartney -- echoing the feeling in 1967 when he knew he had something great, that was going to shake the world (as it did) and no one but he and a few others knew what it was. And the lesson of the Making of Sgt Pepper is that you and I will never know Sgt Pepper the way McCartney does. And one more thought, if only John Lennon could have been there, what would we have learned. " created="Sat, 03 Apr 2021 13:18:56 GMT" type="outline" image="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/03/lennon.png"/>
				<outline text="The Making of Drummer" created="Sat, 03 Apr 2021 13:30:21 GMT" type="outline" description="Why I'm striving to keep it small, based on experience with Frontier. " metaImage="http://scripting.com/2016/10/31/auroraBridge.png">
					<outline text="I wear a lot of hats. One of them is as a developer of scripting systems. I did a big one, Frontier, developed mostly in the late 80s and 90s. People seem to refer to it in the past tense, but I use Frontier as do others. it does things no other product can. It works. " created="Sat, 03 Apr 2021 16:39:02 GMT" image="http://scripting.com/images/2019/09/10/drummer.png"/>
					<outline text="As you may know, &quot;Drummer&quot; is my new outliner-based scripting system for the web. It's still at least a few months from shipping, maybe more. But I'm making big decisions about how it works right now. " created="Sat, 03 Apr 2021 13:30:27 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The same way Frontier was designed around an &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontier.userland.com/manual/objectDatabase&quot;&gt;object database&lt;/a&gt; and the Mac filesystem (and later Windows), Drummer works with public and private files on a server." created="Sat, 03 Apr 2021 16:42:39 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Frontier is a very broad and deep product, but it wasn't originally designed to be so big. The initial idea was to integrate it with the Finder, add a Scripts menu, and have it do things with the file system, and provide a way to program and connect scriptable apps. That was it. Simple.  I offered it to Apple. At the time, the early 90s, I knew all the decision-makers there, but I asked for too much money, they thought they could do it for less. So now I had tipped my hand, showed them my product, I figured to be competitive I'd have to add more stuff, which I did have available to me, since I always try out ideas that don't make it into the final product. The product got deeper, but it also got more complicated." created="Sat, 03 Apr 2021 13:31:49 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I always wondered if it would have worked better if we had started with the small product. We could have shipped sooner. It would have been more approachable, more immediately useful. I think there is a good chance it would have worked better, but it didn't go that way. " created="Sat, 03 Apr 2021 13:34:06 GMT"/>
					<outline text="This time, I'm trying to keep Drummer small, focus on a few innovations, and make a lot of the parts replaceable. " created="Sat, 03 Apr 2021 13:51:52 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I am creating a product, but as with Radio UserLand, I also want to try to create a new use for our computers. With Radio it was blogging and RSS. This time it's a richer, better connected working environment on the net for power users and devs. " created="Sat, 03 Apr 2021 13:42:41 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PS: Power users is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Power_user&quot;&gt;concept&lt;/a&gt; that has fallen into disuse, but they still exist, and you can design for them. Some users are very skilled with the technology." created="Sat, 03 Apr 2021 13:43:20 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PPS: The &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/03/24/161331.html?title=drummersKeyInnovation&quot;&gt;key innovation&lt;/a&gt; in Drummer is JavaScript without the callbacks." created="Sat, 03 Apr 2021 13:43:40 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PPPS: I posted something about Drummer &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davewiner/status/1378357655874498561&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Sat, 03 Apr 2021 15:37:40 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Calling off the pandemic?" created="Sat, 03 Apr 2021 14:00:20 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="A gathering for 50 people? Oy." created="Sat, 03 Apr 2021 14:00:33 GMT" inlineImage="http://scripting.com/images/2021/04/03/pandemicPostComments.png"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 2" created="Fri, 02 Apr 2021 14:55:48 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="02">
				<outline text="I can always watch &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metacritic.com/movie/babe&quot;&gt;Babe&lt;/a&gt;. Total feel-good movie. " created="Fri, 02 Apr 2021 15:31:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="A proposal for newsletter tools" created="Fri, 02 Apr 2021 15:32:08 GMT" type="outline" description="Writing tools for the web have been languishing. This is easy to fix, it just requires a little leadership.">
					<outline text="I wonder if we could help one of the newsletter distribution companies support the &lt;a href=&quot;http://1998.xmlrpc.com/metaWeblogApi.html&quot;&gt;Metaweblog API&lt;/a&gt; or  equivalent.  " created="Fri, 02 Apr 2021 15:32:47 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I'd be happy to help design it, and would implement an editor as open source example code to help seed the market. " created="Fri, 02 Apr 2021 15:32:49 GMT"/>
					<outline text="This would be an easy upgrade for the web, and good publicity for an innovative platform. Let's create a great new market for writing tools for the web. All it takes is one developer to get this going. It's something I would support with all the influence I have.  " created="Fri, 02 Apr 2021 15:33:04 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Writing tools for the web have been languishing. This is easy to fix, it just requires a little leadership." created="Fri, 02 Apr 2021 15:33:05 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				<outline text="Pleading for Stallman" created="Fri, 02 Apr 2021 14:55:49 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I feel so sad about what's happening to Stallman." created="Fri, 02 Apr 2021 14:55:53 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Stallman&quot;&gt;He's 68&lt;/a&gt;. I know what that's like, I'm 65. " created="Fri, 02 Apr 2021 15:13:56 GMT"/>
					<outline text="He has fixed his whole existence on a single idea that software should be free. Not free of charge, but free to use and to adapt. It's not that far from the kind of openness I believe in, that I believe is an ethical responsiblity for developers. " created="Fri, 02 Apr 2021 14:56:07 GMT"/>
					<outline text="It's useful to have a person like Stallman around, consistently marking an extreme view. It's like knowing there's a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backpacker.com/survival/how-to-navigate-by-the-stars/&quot;&gt;North Star&lt;/a&gt;, you may not be going to it, exactly, but knowing where it is makes it possible to go other places. And some people agree with Stallman in total, and to them he's their leader." created="Fri, 02 Apr 2021 15:25:44 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Now, if you step back and look at what's being said about him, basically people don't like things he says or the questions he asks. I read these things completely factoring out the non-factual stuff, where they tell you what his questions mean in some pure sense, when what they're really saying is what these questions mean to them. To a reasonable person imho they're just questions. Some people don't argue with questions, they just ask them. For the people who attack him, it's the opposite, their questions are accusations. " created="Fri, 02 Apr 2021 14:57:43 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I think Stallman is actually a naive innocent, almost child-like &lt;i&gt;harmless&lt;/i&gt; person. That's based on years of observing him, being connected through communities. Maybe he did terrible things I don't know about. But maybe you have too.  Is this how we're going to coexist? All of us worrying about who's going to make a credible case for destroying each others' lives? This isn't about Stallman, it's about your sense of justice and how far it extends, and how unfair that is for the rest of us who fear being judged by you. " created="Fri, 02 Apr 2021 14:59:38 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PS: A quote from a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/davenet/1994/11/05/randombreathlessstuff.html#2&quot;&gt;1994 blog post&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;I try not to get offended on principle.&quot; I was quoting someone else, but I've remembered that. Just because I should be offended, doesn't mean, if I'm not actually offended, that I have to pretend I was. " created="Fri, 02 Apr 2021 15:18:55 GMT"/>
					<outline text="PPS: If you still think Stallman should be destroyed, go see &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lives_of_Others&quot;&gt;Lives of Others&lt;/a&gt;, a wonderful film about intellectuals in East Germany during the Cold War. " created="Fri, 02 Apr 2021 15:24:01 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 1" created="Thu, 01 Apr 2021 15:24:25 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="01">
				<outline text="The best part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2021/03/31.html#a004613&quot;&gt;The Making of Sgt Pepper&lt;/a&gt; is the very last line, with Paul McCartney. &quot;The musical papers which you used to read, started to slag us off because we hadn't done anything, because it took five months to record. And I remember with great glee seeing in one of the papers 'ohh the Beatles have dried up, there's nothing going on, they've been in the studio, can't think, what are they doing. And I was sort of sitting rubbing my hands just saying Oh you just wait.&quot;" created="Thu, 01 Apr 2021 15:56:54 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="A famous John Lennon quote. He was asked if Ringo was the best drummer he knew. “Ringo wasn’t the best drummer in the world,&quot; Lennon is said to have said. &quot;Let’s face it, he wasn’t even the best drummer in The Beatles.” Ringo complains about that in the video. He says all the other Beatles wish they were drummers. I think we were having our legs pulled. " created="Thu, 01 Apr 2021 19:56:33 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gLlWIfKO0sU&amp;t=84s&quot;&gt;Sgt Pepper&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;You're such a lovely audience, we'd like to take you home with us.&quot;" created="Thu, 01 Apr 2021 15:24:26 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gLlWIfKO0sU&amp;t=84s"/>
				<outline text="Another great Beatles demo. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZBgtzwE-FTA&quot;&gt;Get Back&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 01 Apr 2021 15:54:59 GMT" type="outline" urlvideo="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZBgtzwE-FTA"/>
				</outline>
			</outline>
		</body>
	</opml>
